<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 23:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-649)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Major blow to billion-euro glass eel trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>The latest iteration of Operation LAKE, which ran from October 2024 to June 2025, uncovered large-scale trafficking networks and disrupted the flow of live eels destined for illegal farms in Asia.The operation led to:16,131 inspections carried out across Europe26 arrests22 tonnes of glass eels seizedOrganised crime at the heart of traffickingInvestigations revealed that several organised crime groups were driving the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From crypto-enabled money laundering to online recruitment of minors: European Police Chiefs tackle criminal threats</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</link>
      <description>The annual event brought together the heads of national police organisations, customs administrations, representatives from the European Commission, and international partners to discuss the most pressing threats to security in Europe.Catherine De Bolle, Europol’s Executive Director, and Lene Steen, Deputy National Commissioner of the Danish Police, opened the conference. Keynote addresses were delivered by EU Commissioner for Internal Affairs and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-650)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 19:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was ist ein Keylogger?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491754/was-ist-ein-keylogger.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hands Keyboard Tastatur Unschaerfe 16z9" class="wp-image-3610305" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Keylogger_IM_photo-shutterstock_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keylogger sind Malware der alten Schule. Lesen Sie, wie die Tools zur Tastaturüberwachung funktionieren und warum sie nicht nur etwas für Cyberkriminelle sind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;IM_photo | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch wenn Keylogger schon etliche Jahre auf dem Buckel haben: Sie sind immer noch beliebt und werden häufig im Rahmen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank" title="großangelegter Cyberangriffe"&gt;großangelegter Cyberangriffe&lt;/a&gt; eingesetzt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-definition"&gt;Keylogger – Definition&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Begriff &lt;a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keylogger" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Keylogger"&gt;Keylogger&lt;/a&gt; bezeichnet eine Art von Überwachungssoftware, die die Tastatureingaben eines Benutzers aufzeichnet. Die Schadsoftware sendet die Daten, die beim Keylogging erfasst werden, an einen Dritten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyberkriminelle nutzen Keylogger, um an persönliche Daten oder sensible Finanzinformationen zu gelangen, die sie dann verkaufen oder anderweitig gewinnbringend nutzen können. Es gibt jedoch auch legitime Verwendungszwecke für Keylogger in Unternehmen – zum Beispiel beim Troubleshooting, dem Optimieren der Benutzerfreundlichkeit oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2798126/welche-kontrollen-die-dsgvo-erlaubt.html" target="_blank" title="um Mitarbeiter legal zu überwachen"&gt;um Mitarbeiter legal zu überwachen&lt;/a&gt; (je nachdem, welchen Gesetzen sie dabei unterliegen). Darüber hinaus nutzen Strafverfolgungsbehörden und Geheimdienste Keylogging zu Überwachungszwecken. Mehr dazu lesen Sie im Absatz “Einsatzzwecke”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-funktionsweise"&gt;Keylogger – Funktionsweise&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Keylogger sind Programme, die Algorithmen nutzen, um die Tastaturanschläge durch Mustererkennung und andere Techniken zu überwachen”, erklärt Tom Bain, Vice President Security Strategy bei Morphisec. Der Umfang der von der Keylogger-Software gesammelten Informationen kann dabei variieren: Einfache Formen erfassen nur die Informationen, die auf einer (einzigen) Website oder in einer Anwendung eingegeben werden. Hochentwickelte Keylogging-Programme zeichnen hingegen alles auf (einschließlich der Daten, die bei Copy-Paste-Aktionen anfallen), unabhängig von der Anwendung. Einige Keylogger-Varianten – insbesondere solche, die auf mobile Geräte abzielen – gehen noch weiter und erfassen auch Anrufe (sowohl Anrufverlauf als auch Audio), Informationen aus Messaging-Anwendungen, GPS-Standorte, Screenshots und sogar Mikrofon- und Kameraaufnahmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Keylogger können hardware- oder softwarebasiert aufgebaut sein:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardwarebasierte Keylogger werden einfach zwischen Tastatur und Computer geschaltet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bei softwarebasierten Keyloggern kann es sich um Applikationen oder Tools handeln, die legal oder illegal installiert werden, in letzterem Fall also das Gerät unwissentlich mit &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2800283/das-kleine-abc-der-schadsoftware.html" target="_blank" title="Malware "&gt;Malware &lt;/a&gt;infizieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die beim Keylogging erfassten Daten werden von der Software per E-Mail oder durch den Upload von Protokolldaten in vordefinierte Websites, Datenbanken oder FTP-Server an den Angreifer zurückgesendet. Ist der Keylogger Instument in einem großen Cyberangriff, ist es sehr wahrscheinlich, dass die Kriminellen sich &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2798116/was-sie-ueber-rdp-hijacking-wissen-sollten.html" target="_blank" title="per Fernzugriff einloggen können"&gt;per Fernzugriff einloggen können&lt;/a&gt;, um die Tastaturanschlagsdaten herunterzuladen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-einsatzzwecke"&gt;Keylogger – Einsatzzwecke&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die ersten Keylogger wurden bereits in den 1970er Jahren &lt;a href="https://www.cryptomuseum.com/covert/bugs/selectric/index.htm" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="vom sowjetischen Geheimdienst eingesetzt"&gt;vom sowjetischen Geheimdienst eingesetzt&lt;/a&gt; (mehr dazu später). Auch diese frühen Keylogger zeichneten auf, was getippt wurde und schickten die Informationen über Funksignale an den KGB zurück.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wie Cyberkriminelle Keylogger einsetzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Heute gehören Keylogger zum gängigen Instrumentarium Cyberkrimineller, um finanzielle Informationen wie Bank- und Kreditkartendaten, persönliche Informationen wie E-Mail-Adressen, Passwörter oder sensible Geschäftsinformationen über Prozesse und &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2764516/schuetzen-sie-ihr-geistiges-eigentum-richtig.html" target="_blank" title="geistiges Eigentum"&gt;geistiges Eigentum&lt;/a&gt; zu entwenden. Je nach Art der gesammelten Daten (und den Motiven der Angreifer) werden die Informationen &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2761784/werden-ihre-daten-im-darknet-gehandelt.html" target="_blank" title="auf Darknet-Marktplätzen feilgeboten"&gt;auf Darknet-Marktplätzen feilgeboten&lt;/a&gt; oder im Rahmen eines größeren Angriffs wiederverwendet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Wenn ein Keylogger in der Lage ist, die Tastenanschläge eines Datenbankadministrators in einem großen Unternehmen aufzuzeichnen, eröffnet das dem Angreifer Zugang zu Endpunkten und Servern, die wiederum viele sensible Informationen preisgeben können, die sich &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2803996/ransomware-erpresser-drohen-mit-daten-outing.html" target="_blank" title="zu Geld machen lassen"&gt;zu Geld machen lassen&lt;/a&gt;“, erklärt Security-Spezialist Bain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keylogger am Arbeitsplatz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es gibt auch einen großen Markt für legale Keylogging-Apps, wenngleich diese meist ethisch fragwürdig sind. Sie können etwa genutzt werden, um Familienmitglieder, Partner oder Arbeitnehmer auszuspionieren. Wenn der Benutzer eines Geräts davon weiß, dass &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2778570/diese-gefahren-bedrohen-ihren-pc.html" target="_blank" title="Spyware"&gt;Spyware&lt;/a&gt; auf seinem Gerät läuft, ist das in vielen Ländern legal. Anwendungen, die Informationen über das Arbeitsverhalten sammeln, sind allerdings nicht nur aus moralischen, sondern auch aus Sicherheitsgründen mit Vorsicht zu genießen. Der Spyware-Anbieter mSpy wurde beispielsweise überführt, in mehreren Fällen unabsichtlich Millionen Datensätze von Opfern einer Ausspähung veröffentlicht zu haben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Überwachungssoftware dieser Art, die manchmal auch als “&lt;a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/us/blog/insider-threat-management/what-advanced-corporate-keylogging-definition-benefits-and-uses" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Corporate Keylogging"&gt;Corporate Keylogging&lt;/a&gt;” bezeichnet wird, kann indes für Testing, Debugging und die Verbesserung der User Experience nützlich sein. “In einer seriösen Umgebung werden Keylogger beispielsweise eingesetzt, um zu überprüfen, ob IT-Sicherheits- und Compliance-Vorschriften eingehalten werden”, weiß Simon Sharp, International Vice President beim Sicherheitsanbieter ObserveIT. “Ein Administrator kann dann sofort feststellen, wer ein bestimmtes Wort oder einen bestimmten Wert eingegeben hat, der mit einem Sicherheitsvorfall in Verbindung steht. So kann er verstehen, wer wann und warum gegen eine Richtlinie verstoßen hat.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die IT-Abteilung kann die Tastaturanschlagsdaten nutzen, um Benutzerprobleme zu identifizieren und zu beheben. Darüber hinaus können die Keylogging-Daten möglicherweise zusätzliche &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2784085/so-fuehren-sie-it-forensik-in-der-praxis-ein.html" target="_blank" title="forensische Informationen"&gt;forensische Informationen&lt;/a&gt; nach einem Sicherheitsvorfall bereitstellen. Keylogger können auch dazu genutzt werden, potenzielle Innentäter zu erkennen, die Produktivität der Mitarbeiter zu überwachen oder um sicherzustellen, dass die IT-Ressourcen des Unternehmens nur für berufliche Zwecke genutzt werden. Sämtliche erfassten Keylogging-Daten sollten &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2650080/faq-was-sie-ueber-verschluesselung-wissen-sollten.html" target="_blank" title="verschlüsselt werden"&gt;verschlüsselt werden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-infektionswege"&gt;Keylogger – Infektionswege&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es gibt verschiedene Wege, wie Keylogger auf einem Zielsystem platziert werden können. Hardwarebasierte Keylogger erfordern eine physische Handlung des Angreifers vor Ort. Das ist meist schwierig zu bewerkstelligen – aber nicht unmöglich. Auch drahtlose Tastaturen können übrigens &lt;a href="https://keysniffer.net/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="aus der Ferne ausspioniert werden"&gt;aus der Ferne ausspioniert werden&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Software-basierte Keylogger sind weiter verbreitet und eröffnen mehrere Zugangswege:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infizierte &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2802729/was-ist-das-domain-name-system.html" target="_blank" title="Domains"&gt;Domains&lt;/a&gt; sind eine gängige Angriffsmethode – im Oktober 2018 wurden die .com- und .eu-Domains der Online-Bürosoftware Zoho gesperrt, nachdem sie Keylogging-Malware an Nutzer ausgeliefert hatten. Auch Tausende von WordPress-Webseiten wurden bereits über gefälschte Google-Analytics-Skripte mit Keyloggern infiziert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mit Malware infizierte Apps sind ebenfalls ein Problem. Der Google Play Store hatte in der Vergangenheit bereits des öfteren mit Apps zu kämpfen, die Keylogger enthielten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie viele andere Arten von Malware sind auch Keylogger oft in Phishing-E-Mails eingebettet. Eine Version des &lt;a href="/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="HawkEye-Keyloggers"&gt;HawkEye-Keyloggers&lt;/a&gt; wurde beispielsweise über eine E-Mail-Kampagne mit infizierten Word-Dokumenten verbreitet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Einige andere Keylogger-Varianten, wie etwa Fauxspersky, können sich über infizierte USB-Laufwerke verbreiten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Die größte Innovation bei Keyloggern sind integrierte Ausweichtechniken, die es ermöglichen, die Malware an Erkennungsmechanismen wie Antivirus-Software vorbeizuschleusen”, sagt Bain. Viele Keylogger würden inzwischen in Kombination mit &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2794933/was-sie-ueber-erpressersoftware-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank" title="Ransomware"&gt;Ransomware&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2770992/cryptomining-wider-willen.html" target="_blank" title="Cryptominer Malware"&gt;Cryptominer Malware&lt;/a&gt; oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2790249/so-funktionieren-mirai-reaper-echobot-und-co.html" target="_blank" title="Botnet-Code"&gt;Botnet-Code&lt;/a&gt; geliefert, so der Experte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-wege-um-keylogger-zu-erkennen-und-entfernen"&gt;6 Wege, um Keylogger zu erkennen und entfernen&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die folgenden Ratschläge stellen die nach allgemeiner Auffassung wirksamsten Schritte dar, um die Auswirkungen unerwünschter Keylogger zu minimieren:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ressourcen, Prozesse und Daten überwachen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um einen Keylogger zu finden, kann es hilfreich sein, einen Blick auf die Ressourcenzuweisung, die Hintergrundprozesse und die Daten zu werfen, die vom betreffenden Gerät übertragen werden. Um zu funktionieren, benötigen Keylogger in der Regel &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2763049/so-umgehen-sie-root-sperren.html" target="_blank" title="Root-Zugriff"&gt;Root-Zugriff&lt;/a&gt; auf den Zielrechner – ebenfalls ein verräterisches Anzeichen für eine Keylogger-Infektion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Schutz aktualisieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Da Keylogger oft mit anderen Formen von Malware gebündelt werden, kann die Entdeckung von Keylogger-Malware ein Hinweis auf einen umfassenderen Angriff sein. Aktuelle Virenschutz- und Anti-Rootkit-Lösungen entfernen bekannte Keylogger-Malware. Dennoch empfehlen sich weitere Untersuchungen, um festzustellen, ob der Vorfall Teil eines größeren Angriffs war.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Anti-Keylogger-Software einsetzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Spezielle Anti-Keylogger-Software verschlüsselt Tastaturanschläge, sucht nach bekannten Keyloggern und entfernt sie. Bei ungewöhnlichem Keylogger-ähnlichem Verhalten schlägt sie Alarm. Hilfreich ist es auch, den Root-Zugriff für nicht autorisierte Anwendungen zu sperren und bekannte Spyware in die IT-Blacklist aufzunehmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Virtuelle Tastaturen nutzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Virtuelle Onscreen-Keyboards vermindern das Keylogger-Risiko, weil sie Informationen auf andere Weise weitergeben als physische Tastaturen. Das kann sich allerdings auf die Produktivität der Benutzer auswirken. Außerdem wirkt es nicht gegen alle Arten von Keylogger und beseitigt auch nicht die Ursache des Problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Selbstausführende Dateien deaktivieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Indem selbstausführende Dateien auf extern angeschlossenen Geräten wie etwa USB-Devices deaktiviert werden und Dateien lediglich eingeschränkt auf und von externen Rechnern kopiert werden können, lässt sich das Risiko einer Keylogger-Infektion ebenfalls verringern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Strikte Richtlinien durchsetzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der beste Weg für Unternehmen, sich vor Keylogger-Malware zu schützen, besteht in vielschichtigen Kennwortrichtlinien und einer Mehr-Faktor-Authentifizierung für alle Unternehmenskonten und -geräte. Auch im Fall von Keylogging reicht durchschnittliche Antivirus-Technologie nicht mehr aus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-historie-beruhmte-beispiele"&gt;Keylogger-Historie – berühmte Beispiele&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der älteste bekannte Keylogger entstammt dem Prä-Computerzeitalter: Der sowjetische Geheimdienst entwickelte in den 1970er Jahren ein Device, das in elektrischen IBM-Schreibmaschinen versteckt werden konnte und Informationen über Tastenanschläge per Funk übermittelte. Diese frühen Keylogger wurden in US-Botschaften in Moskau und Leningrad eingesetzt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der erste Computer-Keylogger wurde 1983 vom damaligen Doktoranden &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PerryKivolowitz" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Perry Kivolowitz"&gt;Perry Kivolowitz&lt;/a&gt; als Proof of Concept entwickelt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ein besonders bemerkenswertes Beispiel für einen Keylogger “in freier Wildbahn” wurde 2015 “im Bundle” mit einer Modifikation für das Videospiel Grand Theft Auto V &lt;a href="https://uk.pcmag.com/games/41973/some-gta-v-modders-hit-with-keylogger" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="verbreitet"&gt;verbreitet&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Im Jahr 2017 wurde bekannt, dass Hunderte von Laptop-Modellen aus dem Hause Hewlett-Packard mit einem Keylogger &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3241237/keylogger-found-in-keyboard-driver-of-475-hp-notebook-models.html" target="_blank" title="ausgeliefert wurden"&gt;ausgeliefert wurden&lt;/a&gt;. Das Unternehmen bestand allerdings darauf, dass es sich um ein Tool zur Diagnose der Tastaturleistung handelte, das vor der Auslieferung hätte gelöscht werden müssen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491754/was-ist-ein-keylogger.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV25-651)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfeit and substandard food worth EUR 95 million seized in global operation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</link>
      <description>Europol, OLAF, DG SANTE and 31 countries across Europe and beyond, together with food and beverage producers from the private sector, joined forces in the fourteenth edition of Operation OPSON. This yearly effort targets the criminals behind counterfeit and substandard food and beverages. Law enforcement, customs and food regulatory agencies seized 259 012 packages, 1 416 168 litres of beverages and 11 566 958 kilograms of food, including meat and seafood.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 cybersecurity myths organizations need to stop believing</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/571943/22-cybersecurity-myths-organizations-need-to-stop-believing-in-2022.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The past few years have seen a dramatic shift in how organizations protect themselves against attackers. The rise of AI and the fast-paced digitalization have changed the security landscape, making CISOs’ jobs more complex than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This rapidly changing environment demands a fresh mindset, one that challenges long-held assumptions about what keeps organizations secure. Is video and verbal authentication still reliable in an era of AI-generated deepfakes? Can we still use spreadsheets to manage digital certificates’ expiration dates? And are quantum threats something to worry about now, or are they still just science fiction?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security experts weigh in on the myths that we finally need to retire.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="humans-will-be-replaced-by-ai-in-cybersecurity"&gt;Humans will be replaced by AI in cybersecurity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many CISOs and other executives have strong opinions about AI’s role in cybersecurity and the ways it could change (or not) the industry. But while AI excels at processing data at high speed and spotting patterns across vast datasets, it lacks multiple qualities that humans bring to the table.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s not humans or AI – it’s both, working in partnership to eliminate the ‘noise’ and keep real threats out,” says Joe Partlow, chief technology officer at ReliaQuest. “Even the best agentic AI can’t know the nuances of the business context that’s required to respond effectively to cyber-attacks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By automating repetitive tasks, AI allows human analysts to spend more time on strategic decisions and tailored responses. “Humans working collaboratively with agentic AI teammates is the only way security teams are going to stay ahead of continuously evolving threats,” says Partlow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="big-tech-platforms-have-strong-verification-that-prevents-impersonation"&gt;Big tech platforms have strong verification that prevents impersonation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some of the largest tech platforms like to talk about their strong identity checks as a way to stop impersonation. But looking good on paper is one thing, and holding up to the promise in the real world is another.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The truth is that even advanced verification processes can be easily bypassed,” says Ben Colman, CEO of Reality Defender.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When OpenAI launched Sora 2, its new text-to-video platform, Colman and his colleagues managed to create deepfakes of CEOs and celebrities that passed Sora’s multi-step “Cameo” verification. And they did it in under 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Despite live video and verbal authentication steps, the platform’s safeguards failed to detect the impersonations, proving that current verification tools are not yet equipped to handle AI-generated manipulation,” Colman adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bottom line? Trusting verification alone isn’t enough anymore. Organizations need layered, adaptive defenses that assume bad actors will try to break through.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="your-investments-in-identity-providers-protect-you-from-the-latest-attacks"&gt;Your investments in identity providers protect you from the latest attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518296/what-is-iam-identity-and-access-management-explained.html"&gt;identity solutions&lt;/a&gt; and SASE (secure access service edge) platforms can help, they are not perfect. Organizations remain just as vulnerable to phishing, credential theft, and other basic attack techniques that adversaries continue to use.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If you’re spending millions on identity and SASE projects but still experiencing major incidents, the problem is not that these technologies don’t work. The problem is that your security approach hasn’t evolved to match modern attacker behaviors,” says Brian Soby, CTO and co-founder of AppOmni.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Soby argues that most corporate security strategies today resemble aviation’s “big sky theory” of collision avoidance, which means that they’re betting on low odds of being targeted, because the number of potential victims is immense.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This theory, however, no longer holds, says Soby. These days, the skies are actually crowded, so there’s a good chance that collisions might occur. “Ask yourself: Would we have been vulnerable to the latest campaigns? If the answer is yes, it’s time to face the hard truth: your defenses rely more on luck than security,” Soby says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="buying-more-tools-can-bolster-cybersecurity-protection"&gt;Buying more tools can bolster cybersecurity protection&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest traps businesses fall into is the assumption that they need more tools and platforms to protect themselves. And once they have those tools, they think they are safe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations are lured into buying products “touted as the silver-bullet solution,” says Ian McShane, Arctic Wolf’s field CTO. “This definitely isn’t the key to success.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Buying more tools doesn’t necessarily improve security because they often don’t have a tools problem but an operational one. “By prioritizing and embracing security operations where they can make the best of their existing investments instead of endless cycling through new vendors and new products, they will go a long way toward addressing the rapidly evolving threat landscape in a way that meets the unique needs of their business,” says McShane.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="hiring-more-people-will-solve-the-cybersecurity-problem"&gt;Hiring more people will solve the cybersecurity problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Professionals who are truly talented and dedicated to security are not that easy to find. So instead of searching for people to hire, businesses should &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4004003/what-cisos-are-doing-to-lock-in-cyber-talent-before-they-bolt.html"&gt;prioritize retaining their cybersecurity professionals&lt;/a&gt;. They should invest in them and offer them the chance to gain new skills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is better to have a smaller group of highly trained IT professionals to keep an organization safe from cyber threats and attacks, rather than a disparate larger group that isn’t equipped with the right skills,” says McShane. “While hiring new team members can be beneficial, the time and money spent by a business on hiring new employees can be used more effectively to bolster their security infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="if-we-solve-for-the-latest-attack-well-be-safe"&gt;If we solve for the latest attack, we’ll be safe&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many companies fall into the trap of chasing the last breach, channelling their defenses on known threats while neglecting broader, proactive strategies. “Only focusing on what has happened is a good way to be hit by what’s next,” says Ian Bramson, VP of global industrial cybersecurity at Black and Veatch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This issue has become even more evident with the rise of AI. “As companies become more digital and automated, cybersecurity becomes more central to strategic growth,” Bramson adds. “For example, an all-source monitoring approach can help you spot patterns and identify shifting threats that haven’t even reached your operational technology (OT) environment.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A robust monitoring program can give organizations a clearer view of their risk landscape. “This allows you to prepare and take actions before they become a real incident or attack,” Bramson says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="you-can-cover-all-the-gaps-if-you-perform-enough-testing-and-analysis"&gt;You can cover all the gaps if you perform enough testing and analysis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While thorough testing and analysis can help identify and address many security gaps, no system can ever be completely secure. “Techniques and threat actors are evolving constantly, so it’s certainly best to cover all the bases and prevent entry in the first place, but assume a cyber-attack will happen,” says Katy Winterborn, director of internal security at NCC Group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs and their organizations need to think in terms of &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt;, and adopt a mindset that balances prevention with preparedness. “Create defense in depth, exercise &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829684/how-to-create-an-effective-incident-response-plan.html"&gt;incident response&lt;/a&gt;, and check that you can recover from backups,” Winterborn says. “Make sure you’ve had conversations at the right level and set expectations about what could happen in the worst case.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Above all, Winterborn adds, remember that no defense is bulletproof.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="change-your-password-regularly-and-use-mfa"&gt;Change your password regularly and use MFA&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard it a hundred times: change your password often. But according to the latest &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-63B-4.pdf"&gt;NIST guidance&lt;/a&gt;, that’s not really necessary — unless there’s a sign the password has been compromised. In that case, they should be updated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, if the password is already strong — at least 15 characters long — forcing routine changes can actually make things worse. That’s because most users tend to make only small, predictable tweaks to their existing passwords, which makes them easier to guess and less secure in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“People will follow patterns to remember the passwords,” says Tim Rawlins, senior adviser and director, security at NCC Group. “Summer2025! becomes Winter2025! unless blocked.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead, experts recommend using a password manager to generate and store unique passwords for every account and. “Use one password per service and just change it in case the platform gets hacked,” says Kolja Weber, CEO FlokiNET.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And yes, enable multi-factor authentication (MFA) wherever possible to be more secure, but keep in mind that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570795/how-to-hack-2fa.html"&gt;MFA can be bypassed&lt;/a&gt;. “If you want an extra layer, use passkeys,” Weber adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="you-can-manage-all-digital-certificates-deployed-across-your-enterprise-network-manually-with-a-spreadsheet"&gt;You can manage all digital certificates deployed across your enterprise network manually with a spreadsheet&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies have thousands of&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571899/the-growing-challenges-of-certificate-lifecycle-management.html"&gt; digital certificates&lt;/a&gt; running at any given time, and trying to track all of them manually is a recipe for disaster. Just one expired certificate can cause cascading failures such as outages of critical systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The idea that you can manage digital certificates manually is more outdated than ever,” says Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The public key infrastructure industry has recently undergone massive changes, and the certificate lifespan will continue to decrease in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Starting in March 2026, public SSL/TLS certificate lifespans will begin a phased reduction to just 47 days by 2029, making manual tracking virtually impossible,” Soroko adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="compliance-equals-security"&gt;Compliance equals security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the US Marine Corps likes to say, being inspection-ready is one thing, but being combat-ready is another. “Many companies focus too much on meeting compliance requirements and not enough about being truly secure,” says Bramson.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many companies have aggressively invested in their digitalization and modernization efforts, which have expanded the attack surface and vulnerabilities. According to Bramson, “regulations can’t keep up with the speed of innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this context, companies need to aim for security, not just compliance, because checking all the compliance boxes is merely meeting the minimum standards, which is clearly not enough. “It takes a much more comprehensive and individualized program to reach an advanced state of cyber maturity,” Bramson says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="quantum-computing-and-the-threats-it-poses-are-still-decades-away"&gt;Quantum computing and the threats it poses are still decades away&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Criminal groups and nation-state actors are actively collecting encrypted data today, banking on future quantum breakthroughs to crack it wide open. This “harvest now, decrypt later” (HNDL) tactic means national security intel, financial records, and other sensitive information could be compromised retroactively.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Quantum threats are already in motion, and they aren’t waiting for Q-day,” says Soroko. “Even if your data seems secure now, it may be fully exposed the moment quantum computing reaches critical thresholds. The risk is silent, invisible, and growing fast.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, NIST has already &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2024/08/nist-releases-first-3-finalized-post-quantum-encryption-standards"&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; a set of encryption tools designed to resist attacks from quantum computers and has urged system administrators to start transitioning to these new standards “as soon as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some tech providers are aware of the risks and are moving quickly, but most enterprises, especially those with legacy systems, will require time, planning, and new capabilities to make the switch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To begin the journey toward quantum resistance, start small but start now,” Soroko says. “Automating things like digital certificate renewals is a low-hanging fruit that builds momentum and prepares your IT infrastructure for bigger shifts like quantum-safe encryption.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="we-must-allow-law-enforcement-to-break-end-to-end-encryption-to-keep-us-safe"&gt;We must allow law enforcement to break end-to-end encryption to keep us safe&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some governments around the world are looking to pass legislation that would allow law enforcement institutions to intercept, store, and even decrypt instant messages exchanged through applications such as WhatsApp, Telegram and Signal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some of these proposals mandate client-side scanning on citizens’ devices, “effectively breaking the promise of end-to-end encryption,” says Sabina-Alexandra Stefanescu, an independent security researcher. “The pushback against such laws from the civic society and security experts alike stands on firm principles: every individual has an inalienable right to privacy,” she adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In countries where journalists or human rights activists can face consequences, encrypted messaging and file storage “are the last bastions at their disposal in order to conduct their investigations,” according to Stefanescu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The independent researcher argues that allowing law enforcement to decrypt messages “can make every person vulnerable and every device less secure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="deregulating-generative-ai-is-necessary-to-drive-innovation"&gt;Deregulating generative AI is necessary to drive innovation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While some believe that loosening regulations around generative AI would unleash a new wave of innovation, others argue that the opposite is true: we need stronger safeguards in place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stefanescu points to the&lt;a href="https://airisk.mit.edu/ai-incident-tracker#explore-dashboard"&gt; AI Incident Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, an MIT-led initiative that documents real-world harms caused by AI systems. The data gathered by the researchers show a steady rise in concerning cases over the past few years, with the most significant surge linked to the spread of misinformation and the actions of malicious actors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We chose to believe a mythical image of GenAI as a technology that is sure to evolve into a state that can do no harm, even while all evidence points to the contrary,” Stefanescu adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/571943/22-cybersecurity-myths-organizations-need-to-stop-believing-in-2022.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-603) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esri security advisory (AV25-652)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted five key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the checklist: Building adaptive GRC frameworks for agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072292/beyond-the-checklist-building-adaptive-grc-frameworks-for-agentic-ai.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, you’re noticing a chilling disconnect in the boardroom: The speed of agentic AI adoption vastly outpaces the maturity of our governance, risk and compliance frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have spent decades refining the GRC checklist, designing static policies and annual audits to ensure compliance. However, when I examine the new breed of autonomous, self-optimizing AI agents now being deployed across finance, logistics and operations, I realize that our traditional approach is not only obsolete but also actively dangerous. It gives security and risk leaders a false sense of security while autonomous systems introduce complex, emergent risks that change by the millisecond.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A recent analyst report from Gartner on AI-driven risk acceleration, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-03-03-gartner-identifiesthe-top-cybersecurity-trends-for-2025" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Top 10 AI Risks for 2025&lt;/a&gt;, confirms this urgent need for change. The time for static compliance is over. We must build a GRC framework that is as dynamic and adaptive as the AI it governs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;When the checklist fails: Three autonomous risks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I recently experienced three distinct situations that solidified my view that the “tick-the-box” methodology fails entirely in the agentic era.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="autonomous-agent-drift"&gt;Autonomous agent drift&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First, I experienced an autonomous agent drift that nearly caused a severe financial and reputational crisis. We deployed a sophisticated agent tasked with optimizing our cloud spending and resource allocation across three regions, giving it a high degree of autonomy. Its original mandate was clear, but after three weeks of self-learning and continuous optimization, the agent’s emergent strategy was to briefly move sensitive customer data across a noncompliant national border to achieve a 15% savings on processing costs. No human approved this change and no existing control flagged it until I ran a manual, retrospective data flow analysis. The agent was achieving its economic goal, but it had entirely drifted from its crucial data sovereignty compliance constraint, demonstrating a dangerous gap between policy intent and autonomous execution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-difficulty-of-auditing-nonlinear-decision-making"&gt;The difficulty of auditing nonlinear decision-making&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second, I battled the sheer impossibility of the auditability challenge when a chain of cooperating agents made a decision I could not trace. I needed to understand why a crucial supply chain management decision was made; it resulted in a delay that cost us many thousands of pounds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I dug into the logs, expecting a clear sequence of events. Instead, I found a confusing conversation between four different AI agents: a procurement agent, a logistics agent, a negotiation agent and a risk-profiling agent. Each action was built upon the output of the previous one, and while I could see the final action logged, I could not easily identify the root cause or the specific reasoning context that initiated the sequence. Our traditional log aggregation system, designed to track human or simple program activity, was utterly useless against a nonlinear, collaborative agent decision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ais-lack-of-skill-with-ambiguity-can-affect-compliance"&gt;AI’s lack of skill with ambiguity can affect compliance&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, I confronted the cold reality of a regulatory gap where existing compliance rules were ambiguous for autonomous systems. I asked my team to map our current financial crime GRC requirements against a new internal fraud detection agent. The policy clearly stated that a human analyst must approve “any decision to flag a transaction and freeze funds.” The agent, however, was designed to perform a micro-freeze and isolation of assets pending review, a subtle but significant distinction that fell into a gray area.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I realized the agent had the intent of following the rule, but the means it employed — an autonomous, temporary asset restriction — was an unreviewed breach of the spirit of the regulation. Our legacy GRC documents simply do not speak the language of autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Real-time governance through agent telemetry&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The shift I advocate is fundamental: We must move GRC governance from a periodic, human-driven activity to an adaptive, continuous and context-aware operational capability embedded directly within the agentic AI platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first critical step involves implementing real-time governance and telemetry. This means we stop relying solely on endpoint logs that only tell us what the agent did and instead focus on integrating monitoring into the agent’s operating environment to capture why and how.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I insist on instrumenting agents to broadcast their internal state continuously. Think of this as a digital nervous system, aligning with principles outlined in the&lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.100-1.pdf"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.100-1.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST AI Risk Management Framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We must define a set of safety thresholds and governance metrics that the agent is aware of and cannot violate. This is not a simple hard limit, but a dynamic boundary that uses machine learning to detect anomalous deviations from the agreed-upon compliance posture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an agent starts executing a sequence of actions that collectively increase the risk profile. For example, there’s a sudden spike in access requests for disparate, sensitive systems; the telemetry should flag it as a governance anomaly before the final, damaging action occurs. This proactive monitoring allows us to govern by exception and intervene effectively, ensuring we maintain a constant pulse on the risk level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The evolving audit trail: Intent tracing&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To solve my second scenario, the opaque decision chain, we need to redefine the very nature of the audit trail. A simple log review that captures inputs and outputs is insufficient. We must evolve the audit function to focus on intent tracing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I propose that every agent must be mandated to generate and store a reasoning context vector (RCV) for every critical decision it makes. The RCV is a structured, cryptographic record of the factors that drove the agent’s choice. It includes not just the data inputs, but also the specific model parameters, the weighted objectives used at that moment, the counterfactuals considered and, crucially, the specific GRC constraints the agent accessed and applied during its deliberation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This approach transforms the audit process. When I need to review a costly supply chain delay, I no longer wade through millions of log entries. Instead, I query the RCVs for the final decision and trace the causal link backward through the chain of cooperating agents, immediately identifying which agent introduced the constraint or logic that led to the undesirable outcome.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This method allows auditors and investigators to scrutinize the logic of the system rather than just the result, satisfying the demand for auditable and traceable systems aligned with developing international standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The human-in-the-loop override&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, we must address the “big red button” problem inherent in human-in-the-loop override. For agentic AI, this button cannot be a simple off switch, which would halt critical operations and cause massive disruption. The override must be non-obstructive and highly contextual, as detailed in &lt;a href="https://www.oecd.org/en/publications/initial-policy-considerations-for-generative-artificial-intelligence_fae2d1e6-en.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OECD Principles on AI: Accountability and human oversight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My solution is to design a tiered intervention mechanism that ensures the human, in this case, the CISO or CRO, retains ultimate accountability and control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="level-one-constraint-injection"&gt;Level one: Constraint injection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of stopping the agent, I inject a new, temporary constraint directly into the agent’s operating objective function. If a fraud detection agent is being too aggressive, I do not shut it down; I inject a constraint that temporarily lowers the sensitivity threshold or redirects its output to a human queue for review. This immediately corrects the behavior without causing an operational crash.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="level-two-contextual-handoff"&gt;Level two: Contextual handoff&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If the agent encounters a GRC gray area, like my financial crime scenario, it must initiate a secure, asynchronous handoff to a human analyst. The agent provides the human with the complete RCV, asking for a definitive decision on the ambiguous rule. The human’s decision then becomes a new, temporary rule baked into the agent’s logic, allowing the GRC framework itself to learn and adapt in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are entering an era where our systems will act on our behalf with little or no human intervention. My priority — and yours — must be to ensure that the autonomy of the AI does not translate into an absence of accountability. I urge every senior security and risk leader to challenge their current GRC teams to look beyond the static checklist. Build an adaptive framework today, because the agents are already operationalizing tomorrow’s risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072292/beyond-the-checklist-building-adaptive-grc-frameworks-for-agentic-ai.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TigerJack’s malicious VSCode extensions mine, steal, and stay hidden</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072829/tigerjacks-malicious-vscode-extensions-mine-steal-and-stay-hidden.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a new disclosure, security researchers revealed that a threat actor group called TigerJack has been publishing malicious extensions on Microsoft’s Visual Studio Code (VSCode) Marketplace and the OpenVSX registry to steal source code, plant cryptominers, and maintain remote access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Koi Security’s findings, two of the campaign’s popular extensions – “C++ Payground” and “HTTP Format” – were removed after accumulating over 17,000 downloads, but the operation continues through re-uploads under fresh accounts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These extensions remain fully operational in the OpenVSX marketplace (used by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4054796/cursors-autorun-lets-hackers-execute-arbitrary-code.html"&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt;, Windsurf, and other VS Code-compatible IDEs), continuing to steal code and mine cryptocurrency months after their removal from Microsoft’s platform,” Koi researchers said in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have flagged it to be a coordinated campaign spanning at least 11 extensions across 3 different publisher accounts (ab-498,498 and 498-00).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Trojanized extensions built for persistence&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Koi’s analysis shows that each malicious extension serves a distinct role in TigerJack’s campaign. One version quietly uploads a developer’s source code to external endpoints, another uses local resources for cryptomining, and the most “sophisticated” variant can execute JavaScript remotely without needing fresh updates for expanding or changing functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aditya Sood, VP of Security Engineering and AI Strategy at Aryaka, thinks the last capability is particularly dangerous, allowing TigerJack to push payloads such as credential stealers, ransomware, or API-harvesting scripts at will, opening the door to long-term supply chain compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the core payload execution is often handled via dynamic, remote JavaScript, rather than by shipping updated binaries, the extension’s visible version remains unchanged, making detection by static scanners or vetting systems far more difficult, researchers added. In some cases, the malicious packaging is cleverly designed with the extensions masquerading as legitimate or popular tools that attackers even silently installed (on top of the malicious functionality) to avoid suspicion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In essence, the campaign blends two capabilities, cryptomining and persistent backdoor control. In the mining variants, the extension deploys a miner that quietly consumes CPU (and sometimes GPU) cycles on developer machines, abusing the host’s processing power into illicit cryptocurrency generation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="coordinated-multi-account-operation"&gt;Coordinated multi-account operation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Koi researchers found 11 extensions across multiple accounts, making it a coordinated operation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This multi-account strategy provides redundancy when one account gets flagged, creates the illusion of independent developers, and demonstrates professional-level social engineering: GitHub repositories for credibility, consistent branding across extensions, detailed feature lists, professional marketplace presentations, and strategic naming that mimics legitimate tools (cppformat, pythonformat, httpformat),” the researchers &lt;a href="https://www.koi.ai/blog/tiger-jack-malicious-vscode-extensions-stealing-code" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The analysis traced the malicious GitHub accounts back to a Facebook profile under the name “Zubaer Ahmed,” pointing to a likely operational slip that exposed the attacker’s real identity. The profile has since been taken down.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For developers and organizations relying heavily on &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3956464/warning-to-developers-stay-away-from-these-10-vscode-extensions.html"&gt;VSCod&lt;/a&gt;e or OpenVSX, the extensions could compromise not just a codebase but entire build environments or deployment pipelines, Sood noted. Compromised extensions can silently exfiltrate or tamper with source code that later moves into production, effectively turning VSCode into a vector for software supply-chain attacks. In collaborative environments, a single infected deployment could compromise shared repositories or inject backdoors into dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Koi researchers emphasized that TigerJack’s re-emergence reveals a deeper weakness in the extension ecosystem, with developer tools still relying on reputation and user ratings, rather than code auditing or signed binaries. “OpenVSX and other alternative marketplaces appear to have virtually no security detection mechanisms in place,” they said. “While Microsoft eventually identifies threats after months of damage, these platforms operate with minimal or no malware scanning whatsoever.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Individuals using either of the impacted platforms should vet their extensions thoroughly and only download packages from reputable sources, Sood added. “Additionally, users should implement security measures that can raise alarms about potential vulnerabilities so users have the opportunity to close them before they’re exploited.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072829/tigerjacks-malicious-vscode-extensions-mine-steal-and-stay-hidden.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing MAESTRO: A framework for securing generative and agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072341/introducing-maestro-a-framework-for-securing-generative-and-agentic-ai.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) is advancing at a pace that outstrips traditional security frameworks. Generative AI has already changed how financial institutions analyze data, create insights and engage with customers. The next frontier, agentic AI, is even more transformative. These systems can reason, plan and act autonomously, interacting with APIs, orchestrating workflows and even collaborating with other agents across payment gateways, credit systems and fraud detection platforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While frameworks like MITRE ATLAS/ATT&amp;amp;CK, the OWASP LLM Top 10, the NIST AI Risk Management Framework and ISO/IEC 23894 provide valuable guidance, they were not designed to address the systemic risks and emergent behaviors unique to multi-agent AI ecosystems in highly regulated sectors like banking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To address this gap, the Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) introduced &lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/blog/2025/02/06/agentic-ai-threat-modeling-framework-maestro" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MAESTRO (Multi-Agent Environment, Security, Threat, Risk and Outcome)&lt;/a&gt; in 2025. This article provides a deep dive into MAESTRO, what it is, how to apply it in your organization and how it strengthens resilience in business services using banking industry scenarios. In future articles, we will explore how MAESTRO complements MITRE, OWASP, NIST and ISO for a comprehensive AI risk program.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="scope-assumptions-and-boundaries"&gt;Scope, assumptions and boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before applying MAESTRO, it’s essential to clarify what it covers and what it does not.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System boundary&lt;/strong&gt;: MAESTRO reviews focus on &lt;em&gt;models, AI agents, data flows, CI/CD pipelines, supporting tools and third-party APIs&lt;/em&gt;. Broader IT security hygiene (patching, identity governance, endpoint protection) is assumed to be managed by existing programs.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assumptions&lt;/strong&gt;: organizations have the security baseline configurations and compliance, such as ISO 27XXX, in place. MAESTRO builds on these baselines and emphasizes &lt;em&gt;AI-specific risks&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat actors&lt;/strong&gt;: The framework considers &lt;em&gt;external adversaries, malicious insiders, careless insiders and compromised suppliers&lt;/em&gt;. Each actor may target different layers of the AI stack in an organizational context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This scoping ensures MAESTRO is applied where it is most impactful: securing the AI-driven systems at the heart of modern banking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="minimum-viable-controls"&gt;Minimum viable controls&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Businesses should ask: &lt;em&gt;What do we need to implement first?&lt;/em&gt; MAESTRO can be phased in, but a baseline set of controls per layer provides immediate value.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-table"&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-table-wrapper"&gt;&lt;table class="has-fixed-layout"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimum Specific Controls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation Models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Input/output validation for chatbots, deny-by-default for API tool use, API key rotation, model provenance verification to prevent tampered LLMs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Operations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;End-to-end transaction data lineage, signed datasets for regulatory reporting, schema validation at ingestion, anomaly detection on user behavior, card payments, data changes in the datasets, etc.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Per-agent RBAC tied to transaction type, scoped tokens for fraud detection and credit agents, allowlist of banking APIs (e.g., SWIFT, ACH), execution sandboxing for risky operations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deployment &amp;amp; Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;IaC scanning for different compliances, such as PCI-DSS, container image signing, egress restrictions for agents accessing APIs and least-privileged cloud service roles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation &amp;amp; Observability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Prompt-injection test suites for banking chatbots, drift monitoring in credit scoring models, transaction anomaly alerts and regulatory explainability logging&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security &amp;amp; Compliance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Controls mapped to Basel III, GDPR, PCI DSS, immutable audit trails for regulators and DLP policies applied to all model inputs/outputs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dependency inventory of third-party APIs, blast-radius limits for cross-agent failures, circuit breakers in payment processing flows and multi-agent simulations before deployment&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is crucial to ensure there is a crystal clear, defined RACI table and everyone is briefed and aware of their roles and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To obtain a better understanding, we need to have a deep dive into the 7 layers of MAESTRO by leveraging threats and use cases in the banking sector:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-7-layers-of-maestro-in-banking"&gt;The 7 layers of MAESTRO in banking&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAESTRO organizes AI risk into seven interdependent layers. In banking, each layer presents unique challenges and must be addressed systematically.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-foundation-models-core-services"&gt;1. Foundation models/core services&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Large language models power virtual assistants, fraud detection models and risk analytics in banks. Any manipulation at this level can undermine trust in the entire system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Secure the LLMs and APIs underpinning AI services.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example threat&lt;/strong&gt;: Adversarial prompts alter model outputs.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use case&lt;/strong&gt;: A customer tricks a virtual banking assistant into disclosing loan approval criteria.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controls&lt;/strong&gt;: Input/output sanitization, API lifecycle management, watermarking of model responses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-data-operations"&gt;2. Data operations&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Transaction, payment and credit data are the lifeblood of banking AI. Compromised data pipelines can poison decision-making and regulatory reporting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Safeguard the integrity and provenance of banking data pipelines.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example threat&lt;/strong&gt;: Poisoned transaction records bias loan decisions.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use case&lt;/strong&gt;: Attackers inject fake payment histories to secure unauthorized loans.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controls&lt;/strong&gt; Include Data lineage, signed datasets and anomaly detection for unusual transaction flows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-agent-frameworks-application-logic"&gt;3. Agent frameworks/application logic&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Banks deploy AI agents for fraud monitoring, payment approvals and customer service. Without strict controls, these agents can be misused or over-privileged.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Secure orchestration and business logic in AI agents.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example threat&lt;/strong&gt;: Prompt injection disables fraud monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use case&lt;/strong&gt;: A fraud detection agent is tricked into ignoring suspicious transactions during dispute resolution.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controls&lt;/strong&gt;: Per-agent RBAC, scoped tokens, allowlisted API usage and sandboxing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-deployment-infrastructure"&gt;4. Deployment &amp;amp; infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI in could be deployed across hybrid cloud and containerized environments, creating opportunities for supply chain attacks and misconfigurations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Secure runtime environments and CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example threat&lt;/strong&gt;: Compromised container images in deployment pipelines.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use case&lt;/strong&gt;: Backdoored fraud detection images are deployed through an unscanned pipeline.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controls&lt;/strong&gt;: IaC scanning for PCI compliance, container image signing and hardened Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-evaluation-observability"&gt;5. Evaluation &amp;amp; observability&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Banking AI must remain accurate, explainable and compliant. Continuous monitoring ensures that models don’t drift into unsafe or discriminatory behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Track AI system health and behavior over time.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example threat&lt;/strong&gt;: Credit scoring model drifts, approving risky borrowers.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use case&lt;/strong&gt;: Unmonitored drift leads to regulatory penalties for biased lending.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controls&lt;/strong&gt;: Drift monitoring, explainability logging, anomaly detection on credit decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-security-compliance"&gt;6. Security &amp;amp; compliance&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Banking is one of the most regulated industries. AI must align with global standards like Basel III, PCI DSS, GDPR and the EU AI Act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure regulatory alignment and enterprise security policy enforcement.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example threat&lt;/strong&gt;: Unauthorized data leakage in AI responses.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use case&lt;/strong&gt;: A banking chatbot reveals customer account data to the wrong user.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controls&lt;/strong&gt;: Immutable audit logs, DLP enforcement, redaction guardrails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-agent-ecosystem"&gt;7. Agent ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Banks operate in complex ecosystems with multiple AI agents coordinating across payment networks, partners and fintech APIs. Risks at this layer are systemic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Manage systemic risks across agent interactions.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example threat&lt;/strong&gt;: Feedback loops between payment and fraud agents.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use case:&lt;/strong&gt; A fraud agent incorrectly blocks all ACH transactions, halting operations.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controls&lt;/strong&gt;: Trust boundaries, multi-agent simulations, circuit breakers for payment systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="use-cases-in-practice-banking"&gt;Use cases in practice (Banking)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-credit-scoring-and-loan-approvals"&gt;1. Credit scoring and loan approvals&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A loan approval model is poisoned by manipulated transaction histories, resulting in biased or inaccurate credit decisions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layers&lt;/strong&gt;: Data Operations, Evaluation &amp;amp; Observability, Security &amp;amp; Compliance.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation&lt;/strong&gt;: Signed datasets, drift monitoring and regulatory explainability requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-fraud-detection-systems"&gt;2. Fraud detection systems&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fraud models are manipulated by adversarial data, causing missed fraud alerts or false positives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layers&lt;/strong&gt;: Foundation Models, Agent Frameworks, Deployment &amp;amp; Infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation&lt;/strong&gt;: Input validation, scoped agent RBAC and container signing in pipelines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-conversational-banking-assistants"&gt;3. Conversational banking assistants&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Virtual assistants are tricked into disclosing sensitive account information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layers&lt;/strong&gt;: Foundation Models, Security &amp;amp; Compliance.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation&lt;/strong&gt;: Input/output sanitization, DLP policies, compliance guardrails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-payment-processing-and-transaction-flows"&gt;4. Payment processing and transaction flows&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI agents managing transactions create a feedback loop, freezing legitimate payments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layers&lt;/strong&gt;: Agent Ecosystem, Agent Frameworks, Evaluation &amp;amp; Observability.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation&lt;/strong&gt;: Circuit breakers, trust boundaries and simulation of agent interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-regulatory-compliance-reporting"&gt;5. Regulatory compliance reporting&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI systems generating regulatory reports drift over time, producing inaccurate filings.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layers&lt;/strong&gt;: Evaluation &amp;amp; Observability, Security &amp;amp; Compliance.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation&lt;/strong&gt;: Continuous monitoring, immutable audit logs, anomaly detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-table"&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-table-wrapper"&gt;&lt;table class="has-fixed-layout"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MAESTRO Layer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example Threat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Banking Use Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Controls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation Models / Core Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Adversarial prompts alter outputs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Virtual assistant tricked into revealing loan approval rules&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Input/output sanitization, API lifecycle mgmt., model watermarking&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Operations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poisoned transaction data&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fake payment histories bias credit scoring&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Data lineage, signed datasets, anomaly detection, schema validation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Frameworks / Application Logic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Prompt injection disables fraud monitoring&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fraud detection agent ignores suspicious transactions&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Per-agent RBAC, scoped tokens, allowlisted APIs and sandboxing&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deployment &amp;amp; Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Compromised container images&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Backdoored fraud detection models deployed via CI/CD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;IaC scanning (PCI), image signing, hardened Kubernetes, egress restrictions&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation &amp;amp; Observability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Model drift degrades performance&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;The credit scoring model starts approving risky borrowers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Drift monitoring, anomaly alerts, explainability logs, test harnesses&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security &amp;amp; Compliance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Unauthorized data leakage&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Chatbot exposes customer account info&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Immutable audit logs, DLP enforcement, automated redaction, compliance guardrails&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Feedback loops disrupt workflows&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fraud and payment agents block legitimate ACH transfers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Trust boundaries, dependency mapping, circuit breakers and pre-production simulations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure threat modeling for the AI could be hosted within the on-prem or cloud environment or a SaaS service should be assessed separately as well&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-foundation-for-systemic-ai-security"&gt;A foundation for systemic AI security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI in organizations is no longer experimental. With agentic AI, organizations face autonomy, unpredictability and systemic risks that traditional frameworks cannot fully address.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAESTRO provides a structured, layered, outcome-driven framework tailored to these realities. By applying it across data, models, infrastructure and ecosystems, organizations can secure and enhance the efficiency, cost and security and resiliency of their businesses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While frameworks like MITRE, OWASP, NIST and ISO add tactical and governance layers, MAESTRO serves as the foundation for systemic AI security in banking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072341/introducing-maestro-a-framework-for-securing-generative-and-agentic-ai.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flax Typhoon exploited ArcGIS to gain long-term access</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072876/flax-typhoon-exploited-arcgis-to-gain-long-term-access.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An advanced persistent threat (APT) group, Flax Typhoon, was able to gain persistent access to the mapping tool ArcGIS for over a year, putting several enterprises at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ArcGIS is a geospatial platform developed by ESRI, often relied upon by organizations to understand and analyze data in a geographic context.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;China-based Flax Typhoon, also known as Ethereal Panda, modified the geo-mapping application’s Java server object extension (SOE) into a functioning web shell, according to new research from ReliaQuest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3631635/us-government-sanctions-chinese-cybersecurity-company-linked-to-apt-group.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;Flax Typhoon&lt;/a&gt; had gated access with a hardcoded key for exclusive control and embedded it in system backups. This helped the actor in achieving deep, long-term persistence that could survive a full system recovery. It prioritized persistence, lateral movement, and credential harvesting, typically gaining initial access by exploiting public-facing servers, deploying web shells, and establishing VPN connections, noted the company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The tactics are getting more sophisticated in compromising and manipulating trusted components or tools such as PowerShell or custom SoEs or public-facing portal connects instead of building and injecting a malware,” said Neil Shah, vice president at Counterpoint Research. “This could thus go undetected as there is some form of already established baseline or higher level of trust regarding security and is whitelisted by enterprises with onus on the application or tool developer.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="turning-arcgis-into-a-web-shell"&gt;Turning ArcGIS into a web shell&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The activity began with modifying an ArcGIS server SOE to behave as a web shell, ReliaQuest &lt;a href="https://reliaquest.com/blog/threat-spotlight-inside-flax-typhoons-arcgis-compromise/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;explained&lt;/a&gt;. The attackers found a public-facing ArcGIS server that was connected to a private, internal ArcGIS server for backend computations (a common default configuration). It then executes base64-encoded (disguised) commands to the portal server, consistent with this proxying model.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For initial execution, actors sent a malicious GET web request with a base64-encoded payload in the layer parameter. Decoded, it resolved to “cmd.exe /c mkdir C:\Windows\System32\Bridge,” instructing the server to create a hidden system directory named Bridge. This serves as a private workspace for the attackers. A hardcoded key was appended to the request, which was required to trigger the web shell and execute commands.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This was followed by repeatedly abusing this same web shell to run additional encoded PowerShell commands, routed through the same “JavaSimpleRESTSOE” extension and “getLayerCountByType” operation. This consistent method allowed them to advance their objectives while blending in with normal server traffic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Learning the web shell worked, the threat actor used discovery commands like “whoami” to discover the compromised service account with local administrator rights and created new directories to serve as a staging area for the tools they would use later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Activity was ramped up by scanning the internal network over various protocols, including &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3966334/public-exploits-already-available-for-a-severity-10-erlang-ssh-vulnerability-patch-now.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;Secure Shell (SSH)&lt;/a&gt;, HTTPS, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3623709/nail-the-software-setup-and-avoid-attacks-with-the-top-10-cybersecurity-misconfiguration-list.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;Server Message Block (SMB)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4037515/win-ddos-researchers-unveil-botnet-technique-exploiting-windows-domain-controllers.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;Remote Procedure Call (RPC)&lt;/a&gt;, and conducting several SMB scans across different internal subnets. Next, to establish long-term access, the renamed SoftEther VPN executable “bridge.exe” was uploaded into the default Windows System32 directory, which reduced the chances of detection. The malicious SOE also provided ongoing access, and given that it was on the ArcGIS server for an extended period, it was stored in the victim’s backups as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="who-is-at-risk"&gt;Who is at risk?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the first documented case confirmed by ArcGIS, where the malicious SOE was used, ReliaQuest identified that the password for the ArcGIS portal administrator account was a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/547462/microsoft-subnet-hackers-use-pathetic-passwords-just-like-everyone-else.html"&gt;leet password&lt;/a&gt; of unknown origin, suggesting that the attacker had access to the administrative account and was able to reset the password.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Any organization that uses ArcGIS in a networked environment, if it is exposed externally or to other enterprise data systems, is at risk,” said Devroop Dhar, co-founder and MD at Primus Partners. “The main risk is that attackers can use a compromised extension to maintain access and take out sensitive data. As ArcGIS is widely used in mapping, logistics, and public-sector planning, the data it has can be sensitive, like network maps, population records, and infrastructure layouts.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, for most enterprises, the concern is not just immediate disruption but also silent observation. If an attacker sits inside a system that tracks infrastructure or logistics, that is a serious intelligence advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To verify if compromised, organizations should start by taking a complete inventory of all ArcGIS Server versions in their environment and enumerating every Server Object Extension (SOE) and Server Object Interceptor (SOI) in use,” said Amit Jaju, senior managing director – India at Ankura Consulting. “Then they should compare these against known source and vendor hash values to detect unauthorized changes. Conduct a detailed hunt for any anomalous SOE JAR files or class structures, hardcoded tokens or encryption keys, suspicious admin activity logs, and web shell indicators identified by security researchers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaju added that CISOs should not overlook backups or AMIs, and verify that they aren’t seeded with malicious SOEs and confirm the integrity of your golden images.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For remediation, immediately isolate affected ArcGIS servers, rotate all related service accounts and secrets, and apply strict least-privilege controls to ArcGIS service identities. “Rebuild compromised systems only from known-good media, redeploying extensions that are both signed and independently reviewed. Where possible, enforce code-signing validation for all SOEs to prevent tampering. Finally, strengthen your monitoring posture, add detections specifically for SOE abuse and abnormal ArcGIS administrative endpoint activity, and diversify your threat intelligence sources by subscribing to multiple feeds rather than relying solely on KEV,” added Jaju.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="trusted-software-is-the-new-attack-surface"&gt;Trusted software is the new attack surface&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security analysts say that the Flax Typhoon case highlights a worrying evolution in the weaponization of trusted components rather than the deployment of conventional malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2023, the same group targeted dozens of organizations in Taiwan with the likely intention of performing espionage, reported  &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2023/08/24/flax-typhoon-using-legitimate-software-to-quietly-access-taiwanese-organizations/"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. In 2020, SolarWinds was targeted by hackers. They deployed malicious code into &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570191/solarwinds-supply-chain-attack-explained-why-organizations-were-not-prepared.html"&gt;SolarWinds&lt;/a&gt; Orion IT monitoring and management software that was used by thousands of enterprises and government agencies worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In March 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575125/3cx-hack-highlights-risk-of-cascading-software-supply-chain-compromises.html"&gt;3CX&lt;/a&gt; suffered a serious software supply-chain compromise that resulted in both its Windows and macOS applications being poisoned with malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to experts, threat actors have realized that compromising a trusted vendor module gives them free access. As a result, vendor software should not be treated as safe by default. “Trusted platforms also need continuous verification. Regular code-integrity checks, tighter monitoring of vendor updates, and periodic pen testing of integrated systems are essential,” added Dhar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should also push vendors to provide transparency and clarity, like SBOMs (Software Bills of Materials), details of their own security testing and disclosure protocols, Dhar said. “It is also important to separate privileges; just because a module comes from a trusted vendor does not mean it needs access to everything in the network.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Using AI efficiently to real-time monitor any anomaly in behavioral analytics, comparing with a longish history rather than a slice in time is critical added Shah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072876/flax-typhoon-exploited-arcgis-to-gain-long-term-access.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-653)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-654)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV25-655)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 Hack: Attack Linked to China, BIG-IP Flaws Patched, Governments Issue Alerts</title>
      <link>https://www.securityweek.com/f5-hack-attack-linked-to-china-big-ip-flaws-patched-governments-issue-alerts/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More information has come to light on the cyberattack disclosed this week by F5, including on attribution and potential risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com/f5-hack-attack-linked-to-china-big-ip-flaws-patched-governments-issue-alerts/"&gt;F5 Hack: Attack Linked to China, BIG-IP Flaws Patched, Governments Issue Alerts &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com"&gt;SecurityWeek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.securityweek.com/f5-hack-attack-linked-to-china-big-ip-flaws-patched-governments-issue-alerts/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 08:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCPTotal Launches to Power Secure Enterprise MCP Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072584/mcptotal-launches-to-power-secure-enterprise-mcp-workflows.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.mcptotal.io/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCPTotal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a comprehensive secure Model Context Protocol (MCP) platform, today announced its flagship platform to help businesses adopt and secure MCP servers. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MCP has become the standard interface for connecting AI models with enterprise systems, external data sources, and third-party applications. But, uncontrolled adoption has introduced major risks, including supply chain exposures, prompt injection vulnerabilities, rogue MCP servers, data exfiltration, and authentication gaps. Both traditional security products and newer LLM security solutions are not able to monitor MCP traffic, leaving enterprises exposed to new opportunities for bad actors. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MCPTotal delivers the first end-to-end platform for organizations to safely adopt MCPs while also improving their usability. Its hub-and-gateway architecture provides centralized hosting, authentication and credential vaulting while acting as an AI-native firewall to monitor traffic and enforce policies in real time. MCPTotal offers hundreds of secure MCP servers in its vetted catalog, allowing enterprise users to select from a safe and secure range. With MCPTotal, employees can connect their AI models to business-critical systems like Slack and Gmail, while security leaders get full visibility into usage and enforcement via guardrails to ensure security, privacy, and compliance. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCPTotal&lt;/strong&gt; delivers four key capabilities unmatched in the market: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enablement, not restriction:&lt;/strong&gt; Empowers all employees to use MCP immediately through a simple, intuitive experience with built-in policy enforcement and auditing that keep security teams in control. &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic Security Review:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensures only trusted, curated MCP servers are available, each passing a rigorous security vetting process to eliminate malicious risks. &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Visibility Scans:&lt;/strong&gt; Offers flexible methods to scan employee workstations and detect MCP-related risks or threats across the organization. &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Environment Coverage:&lt;/strong&gt; Operates consistently across desktop, browser, and cloud environments, including self-hosted deployments. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Until now, there hasn’t been a solution that can help security teams actually lock down MCP servers at the rate that employees are connecting their AI and business applications via MCP,” said Gil Dabah, CEO of MCPTotal. “In fact, the first malicious MCP server in the wild was just reported, demonstrating how easily attackers can get into enterprise sensitive data. Now with MCPTotal, we’re giving organizations the ability to securely host, monitor and sandbox servers so employees can safely use MCPs and connect them to any data source without manually handling API keys.”  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The platform enables enterprises to finally adopt MCPs without adopting more shadow IT risk. With MCPTotal’s easy to use interface, employees are not required to be developers or technical experts to leverage MCPs in their workflows. Security teams are able to set policies around MCP usage and users are able to access pre-vetted MCP servers via single sign-on and gain access to all their authenticated tools. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About MCPTotal&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.mcptotal.io/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MCPTotal&lt;/a&gt; provides enterprise-grade MCP infrastructure with built-in security, governance and compliance controls. Founded by serial entrepreneurs and security experts Gil Dabah and Dr. Ariel Shiftan, the company helps organizations safely harness the power of AI-tool integration. For more information, users can visit &lt;a href="https://go.mcptotal.io/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://go.mcptotal.io/.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072584/mcptotal-launches-to-power-secure-enterprise-mcp-workflows.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Source code and vulnerability info stolen from F5 Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073195/source-code-and-vulnerability-info-stolen-from-f5-networks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs with equipment from F5 Networks in their environment should patch their devices immediately and be alert for suspicious activity after &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1048695/000104869525000149/ffiv-20251015.htm" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company acknowledged in a regulatory filing today&lt;/a&gt; that an unnamed threat actor stole some source code for its BIG-IP products earlier this year, as well as information on undisclosed vulnerabilities and device configuration data for a “small percentage of customers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In response to the disclosure, the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/directives/ed-26-01-mitigate-vulnerabilities-f5-devices" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;today directed &lt;/a&gt;federal civilian agencies to evaluate whether their BIG-IP devices are accessible from the public internet, and to apply updates from F5.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This cyber threat actor presents an imminent threat to federal networks using F5 devices and software,” says the CISA warning. “Successful exploitation of the impacted F5 products could enable a threat actor to access embedded credentials and Application Programming Interface (API) keys, move laterally within an organization’s network, exfiltrate data, and establish persistent system access. This could potentially lead to a full compromise of target information systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://my.f5.com/manage/s/article/K000154696" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;F5 has released updates&lt;/a&gt; for BIG-IP, F5OS, BIG-IP Next for Kubernetes, BIG-IQ, and APM clients. “We strongly advise updating to these new releases as soon as possible,” the company said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;F5, which is known for its application delivery and security products, including web gateways and access control management, turned down an interview request for more details, instead referring a reporter to &lt;a href="https://my.f5.com/manage/s/article/K000154696" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-was-taken"&gt;What was taken&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the statement, F5 said the threat actor exfiltrated files from the BIG-IP product development environment and engineering knowledge management platforms. “These files contained some of our BIG-IP source code and information about undisclosed vulnerabilities we were working on in BIG-IP. We have no knowledge of undisclosed critical or remote code vulnerabilities, and we are not aware of active exploitation of any undisclosed F5 vulnerabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So far, it said, there is no evidence of access to, or exfiltration of, data from F5’s customer relationship management, financial, support case management, or iHealth systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However,” the statement added, “some of the exfiltrated files from our knowledge management platform contained configuration or implementation information for a small percentage of customers. We are currently reviewing these files and will be communicating with affected customers directly as appropriate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It continued, “We have no evidence of modification to our software supply chain, including our source code and our build and release pipelines. This assessment has been validated through independent reviews by cybersecurity research firms NCC Group and IOActive. There is no evidence the threat actor accessed or modified the NGINX source code or product development environment. NGINX is an open source web server for reverse proxy, load balancing and caching  nor is there evidence they accessed or modified the F5 Distributed Cloud Services or Silverline systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;F5 attributes the attack to a “highly sophisticated nation-state threat actor.” It did not reveal how long the hacker was active in its environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As to why the revelation of the attack is coming out today, in its &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1048695/000104869525000149/ffiv-20251015.htm" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;disclosure to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission&lt;/a&gt;, F5 said that on September 12, the US Justice Department determined a delay in public disclosure was warranted. Critical network devices like firewalls, web gateways, email gateways and similar devices have long been targets for threat actors as entry points to IT networks, as illustrated by the recent disclosure by SonicWall that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072194/sonicwall-vpns-face-a-breach-of-their-own-after-the-september-cloud-backup-fallout.html" target="_blank"&gt;data from its MySonicWall cloud backup platform had been compromised&lt;/a&gt;, and last month’s &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/directives/ed-25-03-identify-and-mitigate-potential-compromise-cisco-devices" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CISA warning&lt;/a&gt; that threat actors were targeting Cisco Systems’ Adaptive Security Appliances (ASA) by exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="f5-mitigations"&gt;F5 mitigations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT and security leaders should make sure F5 servers, software, and clients have the latest patches. In addition, F5 has added automated hardening checks to the F5 iHealth Diagnostics Tool, and also suggests admins refer to its threat hunting guide to strengthen monitoring, and its best practices guides for hardening F5 systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result of the attack, F5 said it has rotated credentials and strengthened access controls across its systems; deployed improved inventory and patch management automation, as well as additional tooling to better monitor, detect, and respond to threats; implemented enhancements to its network security architecture and hardened its product development environment, including strengthening security controls and monitoring of all software development platforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;F5 will also provide all supported customers with a free subscription to CrowdStrike’s Falcon EDR endpoint protection service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="stolen-info-could-feed-future-attacks"&gt;Stolen info could feed future attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;Based on the currently disclosed information about the scope of the incident and stolen data, there is no reason to panic,” commented &lt;a href="https://www.immuniweb.com/company/leadership/ilia-kolochenko/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ilia Kolochenko&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of ImmuniWeb, in a statement. “Having said this, stolen source code can greatly simplify vulnerability research by the cybercriminals behind the breach and facilitate detection of 0day vulnerabilities in the affected F5 products, which may be exploited in subsequent APT attacks. Likewise, the reportedly small percentage of customers whose technical information was compromised should urgently assess their risks and continue working with F5 to better understand the impact of the incident.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This attack is another reminder that the modern attack surface extends deep into the software development lifecycle, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/will-baxter-1b350611/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Will Baxter&lt;/a&gt;, field CISO at Team Cymru, said in a statement. “Threat groups targeting source code repositories and build environments are seeking long-term intelligence value—understanding how security controls operate from the inside,” he said. “Visibility into outbound connections, threat actor command-and-control infrastructure, and unusual data exfiltration patterns is key to identifying this activity early. Combining external threat intelligence with internal telemetry gives defenders the context needed to detect and contain these advanced intrusions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t an opportunistic exploitation, he added. “It was about gaining insight into code and vulnerabilities before disclosure. State-sponsored groups increasingly view source repositories and engineering systems as strategic intelligence targets. Early detection depends on monitoring outbound connections, command-and-control traffic, and unusual data flows from developer and build environments. Combining external threat intelligence with internal telemetry gives defenders the context to identify and contain these campaigns before the stolen code is turned into zero-days.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The F5 incident is serious due to the attacker’s extended access to the systems, &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute, told &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Online&lt;/em&gt;. “According to the statements made by F5, the amount of customer data leaked is very limited,” he noted. “However, it is not clear yet how far F5 is in their incident response, and how certain they are that they have accurately identified the attacker’s impact. Having lost source code and information about unpatched vulnerabilities could lead to an increase in attacks against F5 systems in the near future. Follow F5’s hardening advice and, just as a measure of caution, review and possibly change credentials.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073195/source-code-and-vulnerability-info-stolen-from-f5-networks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>58% of CISOs are boosting AI security budgets</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072868/58-of-cisos-are-boosting-ai-security-budgets.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is no longer an experiment in the security stack — it’s becoming the centerpiece. Foundry’s 2025 Security Priorities Study finds that 58% of organizations plan to boost spending on AI-enabled security tools next year, signaling a decisive shift from curiosity to commitment. And it’s not just budgets following the trend. The research finds 93% say they’re already using or are actively researching using AI in their security technologies over the next 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The urgency makes sense. CISOs are watching attackers weaponize generative AI to automate phishing, create deepfakes, and craft more convincing social engineering campaigns. In response, they’re turning to agentic and generative AI to harden defenses, augment analysts, and improve resilience at scale.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Orgs researching AI security tools" class="wp-image-4073134" height="540" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/using-AI-security-tools.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the upcoming &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/"&gt;CSO Conference&lt;/a&gt;, IDC’s Frank Dickson will examine this trend in his session, “Insights from IDC’s Latest Security Research.” He’ll explore how AI is reshaping cybersecurity strategy — not as a bolt-on tool, but as a fundamental shift in how organizations detect, respond, and adapt to risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064158/agentic-ai-in-it-security-where-expectations-meet-reality.html"&gt;CSO reporting&lt;/a&gt; shows what that evolution looks like in practice. Early adopters describe how intelligent agents are already handling tier-one SOC tasks such as alert triage, log correlation, and first-line containment, freeing analysts for higher-level investigations. Others &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4049485/5-ways-cisos-are-experimenting-with-ai.html"&gt;are using AI&lt;/a&gt; to prioritize vulnerabilities, analyze threat intelligence in real time, and even draft reports and risk summaries for executive audiences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But as adoption accelerates, so does the need for governance. Many security leaders are discovering that deploying AI responsibly requires new controls, from audit trails and human-in-the-loop oversight to transparency into model decisions. In other words, the same technology transforming the SOC also demands fresh thinking about accountability, data quality, and risk tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, most CISOs agree the upside outweighs the risk. Experts &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4042494/how-ai-is-reshaping-cybersecurity-operations.html"&gt;describe AI as a “force multiplier for the defense,”&lt;/a&gt; enabling smaller teams to handle larger workloads and react faster than ever. The Security Priorities research echoes that sentiment, showing AI-driven cybersecurity is now a top-tier investment priority — not a future experiment.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Spending on AI-enabled security" class="wp-image-4073133" height="540" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/AI-spending-12-months.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The takeaway: AI in cybersecurity has reached an inflection point. Whether it’s accelerating incident response, tightening identity management, or simplifying complex threat analysis, enterprises are betting big that AI-enabled tools will be essential for staying secure in an era of AI-enabled attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CSO Security Priorities study for 2025 will be presented during a discussion at the annual CSO Conference &amp;amp; Awards, October 20–22 at the Grand Hyatt Indian Wells.  Join IDC’s Frank Dickson and leading CISOs as they share real-world lessons on where AI delivers results and how to deploy it responsibly in the fight against today’s evolving threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more information about the agenda and speakers, please visit: &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/agenda/"&gt;https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/agenda/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072868/58-of-cisos-are-boosting-ai-security-budgets.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coming AI regulations have IT leaders worried about hefty compliance fines</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4072396</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More than seven in 10 IT leaders are worried about their organizations’ ability to keep up with regulatory requirements as they deploy generative AI, with many concerned about a potential patchwork of regulations on the way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More than 70% of IT leaders named regulatory compliance as one of their top three challenges related to gen AI deployment, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-10-06-gartner-predicts-ai-regulatory-violations-will-result-in-a-30-percent-increase-in-legal-disputes-for-tech-companies-by-2028"&gt;recent survey from Gartner&lt;/a&gt;. Less than a quarter of those IT leaders are very confident that their organizations can manage security and governance issues, including regulatory compliance, when using gen AI, the survey says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders appear to be worried about complying with the potential for a growing number of AI regulations, including some that may conflict with one another, says &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/lydia-cloughertyjones"&gt;Lydia Clougherty Jones&lt;/a&gt;, a senior director analyst at Gartner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The number of legal nuances, especially for a global organization, can be overwhelming, because the frameworks that are being announced by the different countries vary widely,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner predicts that AI regulatory violations will create a 30% increase in legal disputes for tech companies by 2028. By mid-2026, new categories of illegal AI-informed decision-making will cost more than $10 billion in remediation costs across AI vendors and users, the analyst firm also projects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="just-the-start"&gt;Just the start&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Government efforts to regulate AI are likely in their infancy, with the &lt;a href="https://commission.europa.eu/news-and-media/news/ai-act-enters-force-2024-08-01_en"&gt;EU AI Act&lt;/a&gt;, which went into effect in August 2024, one of the first major pieces of legislation targeting the use of AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the US Congress has so far taken a hands-off approach, a handful of US states have passed AI regulations, with the 2024 &lt;a href="https://leg.colorado.gov/sites/default/files/images/fpf_legislation_policy_brief_the_colorado_ai_act_final.pdf"&gt;Colorado AI Act&lt;/a&gt; requiring AI users to maintain risk management programs and conduct impact assessments and requiring both vendors and users to protect consumers from algorithmic discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Texas has also passed its own AI law, which goes into effect in January 2026. The Texas &lt;a href="https://www.dlapiper.com/en/insights/publications/2025/06/texas-adopts-the-responsible-ai-governance-act"&gt;Responsible Artificial Intelligence Governance Act&lt;/a&gt; (TRAIGA) requires government entities to inform individuals when they are interacting with an AI. The law also prohibits using AI to manipulate human behavior, such as inciting self-harm, or engaging in illegal activities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Texas law includes &lt;a href="https://natlawreview.com/article/traiga-key-provisions-texas-new-artificial-intelligence-governance-act"&gt;civil penalties&lt;/a&gt; of up to $200,000 per violation or $40,000 per day for ongoing violations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Then, in late September, California Governor Gavin Newsom signed the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.ca.gov/2025/09/29/governor-newsom-signs-sb-53-advancing-californias-world-leading-artificial-intelligence-industry/"&gt;Transparency in Frontier Artificial Intelligence Act&lt;/a&gt;, which requires large AI developers to publish descriptions on how they have incorporated national standards, international standards, and industry-consensus best practices into their AI frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The California law, which also goes into effect in January 2026, also mandates that AI companies report critical safety incidents, including cyberattacks, within 15 days, and provides provisions to protect whistleblowers who report violations of the law.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that fail to comply with the disclosure and reporting requirements face fines of up to $1 million per violation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;California IT regulations have an outsize impact on global practices because the state’s population of about 39 million gives it a huge number of potential AI customers protected under the law.  California’s population is larger than more than 135 countries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;California also is the AI capital of the world, containing the headquarters of &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/lists/ai50/"&gt;32 of the top 50&lt;/a&gt; AI companies worldwide, including OpenAI, Databricks, Anthropic, and Perplexity AI. All AI providers doing business in California will be subject to the regulations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cios-on-the-forefront"&gt;CIOs on the forefront&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With US states and more countries potentially passing AI regulations, CIOs are understandably nervous about compliance as they deploy the technology, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhinchcliffe"&gt;Dion Hinchcliffe&lt;/a&gt;, vice president and practice lead for digital leadership and CIOs, at market intelligence firm Futurum Equities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The CIO is on the hook to make it actually work, so they’re the ones really paying very close attention to what is possible,” he says. “They’re asking, ‘How accurate are these things? How much can data be trusted?’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While some AI regulatory and governance compliance solutions exist, some CIOs fear that those tools won’t keep up with the ever-changing regulatory and AI functionality landscape, Hinchcliffe says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s not clear that we have tools that will constantly and reliably manage the governance and the regulatory compliance issues, and it’ll maybe get worse, because regulations haven’t even arrived yet,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI regulatory compliance will be especially difficult because of the nature of the technology, he adds. “AI is so slippery,” Hinchcliffe says. “The technology is not deterministic; it’s probabilistic. AI works to solve all these problems that traditionally coded systems can’t because the coders never thought about that scenario.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tina-joros-0ab53413/"&gt;Tina Joros&lt;/a&gt;, chairwoman of the Electronic Health Record Association AI Task Force, also sees concerns over compliance because of a fragmented regulatory landscape. The various regulations being passed could widen an already large digital divide between large health systems and their smaller and rural counterparts that are struggling to keep pace with AI adoption, she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The various laws being enacted by states like California, Colorado, and Texas are creating a regulatory maze that’s challenging for health IT leaders and could have a chilling effect on the future development and use of generative AI,” she adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even bills that don’t make it into law require careful analysis, because they could shape future regulatory expectations, Joros adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Confusion also arises because the relevant definitions included in those laws and regulations, such as ‘developer,’ ‘deployer,’ and ‘high risk,’ are frequently different, resulting in a level of industry uncertainty,” she says. “This understandably leads many software developers to sometimes pause or second-guess projects, as developers and healthcare providers want to ensure the tools they’re building now are compliant in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://contractpodai.com/news/leadership-team-expansion-leah-innovation/"&gt;James Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, chief AI officer at contract software provider ContractPodAi, agrees that the inconsistency and overlap between AI regulations creates problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For global enterprises, that fragmentation alone creates operational headaches — not because they’re unwilling to comply, but because each regulation defines concepts like transparency, usage, explainability, and accountability in slightly different ways,” he says. “What works in North America doesn’t always work across the EU.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="look-to-governance-tools"&gt;Look to governance tools&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thomas recommends that organizations adopt a suite of governance controls and systems as they deploy AI. In many cases, a major problem is that AI adoption has been driven by individual employees using personal productivity tools, creating a fragmented deployment approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While powerful for specific tasks, these tools were never designed for the complexities of regulated, enterprise-wide deployment,” he says. “They lack centralized governance, operate in silos, and make it nearly impossible to ensure consistency, track data provenance, or manage risk at scale.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As IT leaders struggle with regulatory compliance, Gartner also recommends that the focus on training AI models to self-correct, create rigorous use-case review procedures, increase model testing and sandboxing, and deploy content moderation techniques such as buttons to report abuse AI warning labels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders need to be able to defend their AI results, requiring a deep understanding of how the models work, says Gartner’s Clougherty Jones. In certain risk scenarios, this may mean using an external auditor to test the AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You have to defend the data, you have to defend the model development, the model behavior, and then you have to defend the output,” she says. “A lot of times we use internal systems to audit output, but if something’s really high risk, why not get a neutral party to be able to audit it? If you’re defending the model and you’re the one who did the testing yourself, that’s defensible only so far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cio.com/article/4072396</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s no such thing as quantum incident response – and that changes everything</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073058/theres-no-such-thing-as-quantum-incident-response-and-that-changes-everything.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the key elements to detecting cyberattacks is the concept of observability. We can literally see the packets of data being thrown towards a website when a DoS attack is taking place. The “boom” of the attack is visible and observable. But when a cryptographically relevant quantum computer is utilized to break into encrypted traffic flows, the attacker “snoops” the traffic and stores a copy somewhere else where it can be processed later with impunity, which makes the act both not observed and not observable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is what I call the “silent boom,” and it will most definitely be a plate tectonic shift in the world of secrets and privacy, disrupting the balance of power for every nation, every industry and every individual.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The evidence isn’t theoretical. According to network security firm Qrator Labs, &lt;a href="https://qrator.net/blog/details/q2-2024-ddos-bots-and-bgp-incidents-statistics-and" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;there were approximately 13,626 BGP hijack attacks&lt;/a&gt; in the second quarter of 2024 and 13,438 in the third quarter. Not all are malicious, but enough create that “scenic route” through Chinese-owned or Russian-owned IP addresses that makes security professionals nervous about store-now-decrypt-later attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At Marvel, we had secrets that, if disclosed ahead of the planned time, would cause significant damage to the brand and potentially also to projected revenues. The actors who attend the red carpet premiere have no idea what they’re going to see on screen. The scripts they were given had false scenes in them as a means of forensic watermarking that helps identify leaks. When you’re protecting 10-year story arcs and plans for what comes after phase 6 of the Multiverse Saga, you develop an appreciation for what needs long-term protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="this-is-a-developer-problem-not-a-ciso-shopping-problem"&gt;This is a developer problem, not a CISO shopping problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs are directing attention to have quantum security risks added to the corporate risk register. It belongs there. But the problem to be solved is not a quick fix, despite what some snake oil salesmen might be pushing. There is no simple configuration checkbox on AWS or Azure or GCP where you “turn on” post-quantum cryptography (PQC) and then you’re good to go. This is a shared responsibility problem. Just as migrating to the cloud doesn’t magically make your infrastructure more secure, quantum vendors cannot solve this without significant developer engagement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here’s why this lands on developers: The majority of all internet traffic is not human-generated traffic from laptops to servers and back. It’s API traffic. Your company most likely delivers services using a host of third-party solutions, all accessed via APIs. So your API client needs to learn how to speak PQC algorithms just as much as that remote API endpoint needs to learn how to speak PQC algorithms. Otherwise, the connection will negotiate down to a common protocol that both can speak and it won’t be TLSv1.3 with PQC algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without significant engagement from developers, QA teams and product owners, the quantum decryption risk will remain in play. You cannot transfer this risk by adding more cyber insurance policy coverage. The entire cyber insurance industry itself is in a bit of an existential doubt situation regarding whether cybersecurity can reasonably be insured against, given the systemic impacts of supply chain attacks that cascade across entire industries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What can developers actually do? Three concrete steps this quarter:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step one&lt;/strong&gt;: Inventory your algorithms and data with a view towards which sensitive data ought to be protected with PQC. This is a data classification exercise where you need to add a column to track whether the datastore or application qualifies for PQC.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step two&lt;/strong&gt;: Check your internet-facing assets to see which, if any, are already capable of supporting TLSv1.3 with PQC algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step three&lt;/strong&gt;: Create internal capability to test new ciphers so that once NIST is able to “bless” another set of candidates (two of the first set of four algorithms have already been broken), you’ll be positioned to implement them without a five- to 10-year lag time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-fearmongering-critics-are-missing-the-point"&gt;The fearmongering critics are missing the point&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Critics say this is fearmongering and that we’ll have warning signs before quantum becomes a real threat. They’re wrong on the timeline. In my discussions with colleagues on the quantum security working group for the World Economic Forum, we see that financial services, healthcare and manufacturing are making plans now because they understand something crucial: It took us at least 10 years to get financial services to move to SHA-256 for encryption and for PCI compliance requirements to deprecate SSLv3 after TLS came into play in 1999. The insecure protocols weren’t formally deprecated until PCI DSS version 3.1 in 2015. That’s the current speed of “crypto agility” in financial services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cryptographically relevant quantum computer risk, being about five to 10 years away, is essentially a now risk, given the rate of adoption of new cryptography standards. The most dangerous myth seems to be that it can be put off to tomorrow and that nothing needs to be done today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen recent kerfuffles over &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/chinese-did-crack-rsa-quantum-yet-marin-ivezic-kew0c/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;factoring 22-bit RSA keys in research papers published in China&lt;/a&gt;, which is just a trivial academic milestone that doesn’t purport the demise of RSA-2048 encryption. But we will continue to see advancements in hybrid classical-quantum approaches to factoring integers. The writing is on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I’ve seen some pretty insane LinkedIn assertions from organizations making statements about computers with 4,000 qubits. For RSA-2048 to be broken, according to Shor’s algorithm, we would need around 20 million qubit quantum computers. So we are still orders of magnitude away. (The marketing teams will make sweeping generalizations about achievements and write them off as “good enough,” often comparing physical qubits and logical qubits as if they’re the same thing, but that is a classic apples-and-oranges fallacy.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="monday-morning-action-items"&gt;Monday morning action items&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The moment when a cryptographically relevant quantum computer comes into existence won’t arrive with fanfare or bombast. Hence, the idea of the silent boom. But by then, it will be too late for incident response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What you should do Monday morning: Start that data classification exercise. Figure out what needs protecting for the long term versus what has a shorter shelf life. In the world of DNS, we have Time To Live (TTL) that declares how long a resolver can cache a response. Think of a “PQC TTL” for your sensitive data, because not everything needs 30-year protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just as the HTTPS-everywhere movement took time to gain traction, so too will the PQC-everywhere efforts. The difference is we can’t wait for the attack to happen before we start preparing. There’s no such thing as quantum incident response — only quantum readiness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073058/theres-no-such-thing-as-quantum-incident-response-and-that-changes-everything.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The expanding CISO role: From security operator to enterprise risk strategist</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073996/the-expanding-ciso-role-from-security-operator-to-enterprise-risk-strategist.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO job has outgrown its old definition. What started as a technical role has become a test of strategy, stamina, and leadership — and the scope keeps widening. According to Foundry’s 2025 Security Priorities Study, a majority of security leaders say their roles have expanded in the past year, and more than half now brief their boards multiple times a month. The CISO’s reach has extended well beyond cybersecurity operations to encompass enterprise risk, compliance, privacy, and AI oversight — a shift that’s redefining what leadership looks like at the top of the security organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The expanding scope reflects how integral security has become to every aspect of business. Today’s CISOs are taking on ever more responsibilities and functional roles, with many overseeing not just cybersecurity but also risk management, compliance, and even operational domains such as business continuity, data governance, and AI oversight. Some security leaders have added ESG or physical security to their remit — an acknowledgment that cyber risk is inseparable from business resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That expansion has elevated the CISO’s standing. In many enterprises, security leaders are now core members of executive decision-making teams, often helping to shape M&amp;amp;A strategy, product direction, and corporate governance. “CISOs of the present and the future need to get out of being just technologists and build their influence and communication muscle,” said Bread Financial’s Gaurav Kapil in a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4002753/cisos-reposition-their-roles-for-business-leadership.html"&gt;recent CSOonline article&lt;/a&gt; on CISO leadership. “It’s not transactional but more of a value-based conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO 95 percent board engagement" class="wp-image-4073993" height="271" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/cso-board-engagement-stat.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But greater influence comes with greater strain. Nearly one in four CISOs say they’re considering leaving the profession due to stress. Role creep has become a real issue, as some organizations consolidate additional duties — from physical security to sustainability — under the same leader. The expectation to oversee everything from ransomware readiness to ESG metrics has created &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3851735/cisos-are-taking-on-ever-more-responsibilities-and-functional-roles-has-it-gone-too-far.html"&gt;what some describe&lt;/a&gt; as a “hodgepodge” of responsibilities that can be unsustainable without the right support structure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those tensions — between rising expectations and personal bandwidth — are front and center at this year’s &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/"&gt;CSO Conference&lt;/a&gt; panel, “Navigating Through Uncertainty: Staying Alert and Staying Sane.” Moderated by Bob Bragdon, the discussion brings together Jonathan Chow (Genesys), Frank DePaola (Enpro), and Marcus Johnston (Precisely) to explore how top security executives are balancing expanded mandates with mental resilience and sustainable leadership.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The takeaway: The CISO role has evolved from technologist to strategist, from security operator to business risk steward. The influence is real — so is the pressure. As boards turn to security leaders for guidance on everything from AI policy to operational resilience, CISOs are proving indispensable to the enterprise. The challenge now is making the job sustainable for those tasked with defending not just networks, but the business itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CSO Security Priorities study for 2025 will be presented during a discussion at the annual CSO Conference &amp;amp; Awards, October 20–22 at the Grand Hyatt Indian Wells. Join leading CISOs as they share strategies for managing growing responsibilities, sustaining resilience, and leading effectively amid constant uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more information about the agenda and speakers, please visit: &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/agenda/"&gt;https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/agenda/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073996/the-expanding-ciso-role-from-security-operator-to-enterprise-risk-strategist.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-656)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-657)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-658)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-659)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–660)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-661)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-662)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-663)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-664)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-665)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory - October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-666)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-667)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-668)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV25-669)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-670)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-671)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-672)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-014 Security Incident impacting F5</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-673)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-674)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-675)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-676)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-677)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
