<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 23:18:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>New routes and concealment methods identified in cocaine crackdowns in Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-routes-and-concealment-methods-identified-in-cocaine-crackdowns-in-spain</link>
      <description>Europol supported Portuguese and Spanish authorities in two major investigations against cocaine trafficking involving law enforcement on both sides of the Atlantic. These operations exemplified a shifting landscape of global trafficking routes and innovative concealment methods.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-routes-and-concealment-methods-identified-in-cocaine-crackdowns-in-spain</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-606)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-606</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-606</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-607)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-607</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-607</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-608)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-608</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-608</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 13:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-609)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-609</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-609</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–610)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-610</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-610</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-611)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-611</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-611</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s most innovative law enforcement projects honoured at Europol’s 2025 Excellence Awards</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-most-innovative-law-enforcement-projects-honoured-europol’s-2025-excellence-awards</link>
      <description>At the annual European Police Chiefs Convention (EPCC) in The Hague, Europol announced the winners of the 2025 Europol Excellence Awards in Innovation. These awards recognise outstanding projects that demonstrate how innovation can strengthen operational effectiveness, ethical policing, and cross-border cooperation in Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-most-innovative-law-enforcement-projects-honoured-europol’s-2025-excellence-awards</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol supports operation leading to 12 arrests in Ecuador</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-operation-leading-to-12-arrests-in-ecuador</link>
      <description>Belgian law enforcement authorities together with their colleagues from the Ecuadorian National Police performed two waves of arrests and seized over 9.3 tonnes of cocaine over the course of the investigation. In total, the multi-phase operation, supported by Europol, led to 26 arrests across several countries.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-operation-leading-to-12-arrests-in-ecuador</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-612)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-612</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-612</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 12:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-613)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-613</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-613</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-614)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-614</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-614</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 19:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New fugitive uploaded to EU Most Wanted list for major ransomware attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-fugitive-uploaded-to-eu-most-wanted-list-for-major-ransomware-attacks</link>
      <description>A high-value cybercrime suspect has been added to the EU Most Wanted list. The individual, a Ukrainian national, is believed to be a leading figure in an organised crime network responsible for the 2019 ransomware attack against a major Norwegian aluminium company, as well as a series of other global cyber-attacks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-fugitive-uploaded-to-eu-most-wanted-list-for-major-ransomware-attacks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-615)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-615</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-615</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t drink or drive, say cyberattackers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065991/dont-drink-or-drive-say-cyberattackers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When cybercriminals can shut down both a luxury carmaker and a major beer producer in the same month, it’s clear that no sector is safe from operational disruption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaguar Land Rover (JLR), now backed by emergency government funding, is preparing to &lt;a href="https://media.jaguarlandrover.com/news/2025/09/statement-cyber-incident-6" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;resume production&lt;/a&gt; after what’s been called &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4050298/jaguar-land-rover-nach-cyberattacke-lahmgelegt.html" target="_blank"&gt;one of the UK’s worst cyber incidents&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, Japanese brewer Asahi is grappling with a production halt due to a malicious cyberattack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts say the attackers’ goal is no longer just about stealing sensitive data; threat actors are aiming for all-out paralysis of a business, resulting in tangible, real-world consequences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These recent incidents exemplify how supply chain compromises are now being targeted in the critical manufacturing sector with an explicit goal of shutting down production, sales, or logistics until the target victim pays or folds,” said &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/erik-avakian" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Erik Avakian&lt;/a&gt;, a technical counselor at &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Info-Tech Research Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="protecting-jlrs-greatly-impacted-supply-chain"&gt;Protecting JLR’s “greatly impacted” supply chain&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack on JLR began on August 31, prompting the company to &lt;a href="https://media.jaguarlandrover.com/news/2025/09/statement-cyber-incident" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pause production&lt;/a&gt; the next day (September 1). Tens of thousands of workers have been temporarily laid off due to the attack, and the company is estimated to be losing &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwyrqxj3eqqo" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;₤50 million ($67.3 million) a week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters group has claimed responsibility and is believed to have employed voice phishing (vishing) to trick employees into handing over system credentials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JLR is one of the UK’s largest exporters and operates the biggest supply chain in the UK automotive sector, which employs around 120,000 workers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company’s supply chain has been “greatly impacted” by the shutdown, prompting the UK government to float JLR £1.5 billion ($2 billion) via a loan guarantee. The money comes from a commercial bank, and JLR is required to pay it back over five years. JLR has confirmed that it will restart car production in the “coming days” thanks to the financial boost.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This cyberattack was not only an assault on an iconic British brand, but on our world-leading automotive sector and the men and women whose livelihoods depend on it,” said UK Business and Trade Secretary Peter Kyle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JLR says it continues to “work around the clock” with cybersecurity specialists, the UK Government’s National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC), and law enforcement to ensure that the restart is completed in a “safe and secure manner.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="taps-no-longer-flowing-at-asahi"&gt;Taps no longer flowing at Asahi&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Asahi Group Holdings this week announced a “&lt;a href="https://www.asahigroup-holdings.com/en/newsroom/detail/20250929-0202.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;system failure&lt;/a&gt;” caused by a cyberattack. The beer brewer has suspended order, shipment, and call center operations, including customer service desks, at group companies in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asahi said that, as of now, there has been “no confirmed leakage” of personal information or customer data. The company is actively investigating the cause and is working to restore operations, but has no estimated recovery timeline.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attacker-feeding-frenzy"&gt;Attacker ‘feeding frenzy’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.beauceronsecurity.com/blog/tag/David+Shipley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.beauceronsecurity.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beauceron Security&lt;/a&gt; called these incidents “symptoms,” rather than root causes, of cyber risk trends in manufacturing; it is essentially the “cost of the global cybercrime tax” and is what happens when companies declare “cyber defense bankruptcy,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT and security spending is being cut, causing organizations to “fall off the threat treadmill, and injury results,” he said. Firms are pouring capital investment into automation to make themselves more competitive, but that also makes them even more vulnerable to cyber disruption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These organizations’ defenses are being lowered at the worst possible time because they can’t afford to keep them up,” he said. “Threat actors see the opportunity to hit these organizations, and there’s a bit of a feeding frenzy happening now as they realize many firms are in the same situation as JLR.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rogeragrimes" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Roger Grimes&lt;/a&gt;, CISO advisor at human risk management platform &lt;a href="https://www.knowbe4.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;KnowBe4&lt;/a&gt;, agreed that there is a concerning lack of cybersecurity investment. “After over three decades of watching malicious hacking get worse and worse, I can’t even imagine what ‘tipping point event’ would have to happen for the world to wake up and finally implement truly better cybersecurity,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attackers-still-succeed-with-common-attack-methods"&gt;Attackers still succeed with common attack methods&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although Asahi has not yet revealed how attackers penetrated its systems, JLR was the victim of a tried-and-true phishing attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors continue to use phishing and spear phishing simply because they work, exploiting human psychology and error, Info-Tech’s Avakian noted. When layered controls are not in place, “one click on a malicious attachment is still really all it takes for a successful compromise, without the targeted user even knowing what has occurred.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Ransomware can be quite disruptive,” agreed KnowBe4’s Grimes. Between 70% and 90% of successful hacks involve social engineering, he claimed, yet companies aren’t motivated to improve cybersecurity and human risk management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The same goes for patching; Google Mandiant has reported that unpatched software and firmware are involved in &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/m-trends-2025" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;33% of successful hacks&lt;/a&gt; (often blended with social engineering), he pointed out, yet companies still have thousands of unpatched elements across networks and critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hackers continue to focus on unpatched VPNs, network security devices, and middleware, and perform privileged escalation through Active Directory modifications, Avakian noted. Further, they are increasingly exploiting third-party software supply chain compromises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once they gain unauthorized access, attackers can hide their presence and cover their tracks, and wait patiently “just for the right time” to further penetrate systems. “Some groups sit for weeks to map the business, ensuring maximum disruption,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprises-need-a-multi-layered-approach"&gt;Enterprises need a multi-layered approach&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises must adopt a robust, multi-layered approach to security controls, response, and cyber hygiene, and embrace zero trust where access is “isolated, monitored, and revocable,” said Avakian. Map ERP, logistics, warehouse, and other business-critical systems, he advised, and apply safeguards like micro-segmentation, privileged user management (PAM), and multi-factor authentication (MFA).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4063708/how-to-restructure-a-security-program.html" target="_blank"&gt;An “assume breach” mindset&lt;/a&gt; is critical; this means conducting regular tabletop exercises, continuous monitoring, and threat hunting. Resilience also means reviewing incident response plans and playbooks, and employing air-gapped backups, said Avakian.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“At the end of the day, attackers are still able to succeed because they can target the chokepoints in business operations and leverage ransomware/extortion to force quick business decisions,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI brings even more sophistication, he noted, allowing attackers to work at “tremendous speed and scale,” whether it’s faster generation of phishes, scanning, or control weakness testing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, Grimes estimate that by 2026, nearly all &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064158/agentic-ai-in-it-security-where-expectations-meet-reality.html" target="_blank"&gt;hacking will be AI-enabled&lt;/a&gt;. Organizations must meet hackers on this turf with the use of agentic AI-enabled cyber defense tools. “Good actors’ AI bots against bad actors’ AI bots, and the best algorithms will win,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065991/dont-drink-or-drive-say-cyberattackers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 02:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-616)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:57:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Major blow to billion-euro glass eel trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>The latest iteration of Operation LAKE, which ran from October 2024 to June 2025, uncovered large-scale trafficking networks and disrupted the flow of live eels destined for illegal farms in Asia.The operation led to:16,131 inspections carried out across Europe26 arrests22 tonnes of glass eels seizedOrganised crime at the heart of traffickingInvestigations revealed that several organised crime groups were driving the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>51 children identified during international taskforce against child sexual exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/51-children-identified-during-international-taskforce-against-child-sexual-exploitation</link>
      <description>The experts participating in the task force analysed over 300 datasets depicting victims of child sexual exploitation (CSE). The analysts saw victims of both genders, from toddlers to teenagers, with a variety of ethnic backgrounds and of many different nationalities. Following the operation, national authorities were sent 213 leads for further investigation.Catherine De BolleEuropol Executive DirectorChild sexual abuse material may...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/51-children-identified-during-international-taskforce-against-child-sexual-exploitation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From crypto-enabled money laundering to online recruitment of minors: European Police Chiefs tackle criminal threats</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</link>
      <description>The annual event brought together the heads of national police organisations, customs administrations, representatives from the European Commission, and international partners to discuss the most pressing threats to security in Europe.Catherine De Bolle, Europol’s Executive Director, and Lene Steen, Deputy National Commissioner of the Danish Police, opened the conference. Keynote addresses were delivered by EU Commissioner for Internal Affairs and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-617)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-617</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-617</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-618)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-618</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-618</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 19:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wie CISOs schlechte Produkte enttarnen</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4063809/wie-cisos-schlechte-produkte-enttarnen.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Contract Signing 16z9" class="wp-image-4063812" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Ground-Picture-shutterstock_2014536974_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Drum prüfe…&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Ground Picture | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security-Anbietern stehen viele Wege offen, um CISOs und Sicherheitsentscheider mit Lobpreisungen und Angeboten zu ihren jeweils aktuellen Produkten und Lösungen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495241/manager-burnout-wenn-cisos-ausbrennen.html" target="_blank"&gt;zu penetrieren&lt;/a&gt;. Und die nutzen sie auch: Manche Sicherheitsverantwortliche erhalten mehr als 30 solcher Anfragen pro Woche – per Telefon, E-Mail oder auch über LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um erkennen zu können, ob das potenzielle neue Produkt auch &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2823104/9-strategien-gegen-ki-anbieterluegen.html" target="_blank"&gt;tatsächlich geeignet ist&lt;/a&gt;, müssen CISOs vor allem eines tun: die richtigen Fragen stellen. Für diesen Artikel haben wir mit mehreren erfahrenen Security-Entscheidern gesprochen, die genau wissen, welche das sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-fragen-die-sie-security-anbietern-stellen-sollten"&gt;5 Fragen, die Sie (Security-)Anbietern stellen sollten&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Wissen Sie über mein Business Bescheid?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Potenzielle Anbieter zu fragen, ob sie die spezifischen Herausforderungen des jeweiligen Unternehmens verstehen, gibt Aufschluss darüber, ob diese ihre “Hausaufgaben” erledigt haben, erklärt &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/amitbasu" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amit Basu&lt;/a&gt;, CISO und CIO beim Logistikdienstleister International Seaways: “Ich erwarte, dass ein Anbieter Lösungen für die geschäftlichen Probleme meines Unternehmens vorweisen kann – und nicht nur eine Reihe generischer Funktionen für Probleme, mit denen andere Unternehmen konfrontiert sind.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dabei legt Basu nicht nur besonderen Wert darauf, dass die Anforderungen seines Unternehmens erfüllt werden. Für ihn sei auch essenziell, dass ein neues Tool keine &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4035024/it-security-jobs-5-bittere-wahrheiten.html" target="_blank"&gt;technische Überlastung&lt;/a&gt; verursache: “Ein neues Produkt ist nur dann relevant, wenn es die Sicherheit eindeutig verbessert, vorzugsweise ein oder mehrere bestehende Tools ersetzt und einen echten betrieblichen Bedarf erfüllt.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In der Wahrnehmung des Sicherheitsentscheiders verlagerten sich viele Anbieter eher darauf, magische Features anzupreisen, statt zu demonstrieren, wie ihr Produkt reale Security-Probleme löst: “Ich schätze Klarheit und Ehrlichkeit. Wenn ein Tool zwei Anwendungsfälle gut löst, ist das überzeugender als die vage Behauptung, es könne zwanzig lösen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In seiner Doppelrolle als CISO und CIO von International Seaways fokussiert sich Basu nach eigener Aussage vor allem darauf, sicherzustellen, dass Security integraler Bestandteil jeder neuen Technologie ist – und keine &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493061/positiv-denken-fur-sicherheitsentscheider-6-mindsets-die-sie-sofort-ablegen-sollten.html" target="_blank"&gt;nachträgliche Überlegung&lt;/a&gt;. “Sie können mir kein Security-Produkt verkaufen, das auf veralteter Technologie basiert, die unser Tech-Stack nicht unterstützt. Die Integration muss nahtlos sein”, hält Basu fest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ist Ihr Produkt in der Lage, zu entlasten und den Betrieb zu optimieren?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wichtig zu wissen ist für CISOs außerdem, ob und wie ein potenzielles neues Tool die Arbeitsbelastung für die Mitarbeiter reduzieren, Risiken minimieren, die Ausfallsicherheit verbessern oder Prozesse vereinfachen kann. So fragt Basu etwa konkret bei Anbietern nach, ob ihr Produkt in der Lage ist, Funktionen zu konsolideren: “Ist das nicht der Fall, handelt es sich nur um eine weitere, punktuelle Lösung, die die Kosten treibt und den Wartungsaufwand erhöht”, erklärt der Sicherheits- und IT-Chef.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuascott" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Joshua Scott&lt;/a&gt;, CISO beim Plattformanbieter Hydrolix, kennt dieses Problem: “Ich sehe allzu oft Produkte, die scheinbar Mehrwert bieten, aber letztendlich nur Lärm verursachen. Etwa Tools, um Schwachstellen zu erkennen oder andere Scan-Werkzeuge, die dem Team letztlich nur mehr Arbeit bescheren.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Entsprechend fokussiert Scott nach eigener Aussage seine Fragen an Anbieter insbesondere auf die Bereiche:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494359/der-grose-ki-risiko-guide.html" target="_blank"&gt;Risikominimierung&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Ausfallsicherheit, und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Business Impact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das war jedoch nicht immer so, wie der CISO zugibt: “Anfangs habe ich solche Fragen nicht gestellt. Das kann dazu führen, dass Sie am Ende eine technisch beeindruckende Lösung haben, die kein Problem löst.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Wie hoch ist der Integrations- und Wartungsaufwand?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vasanthmadhure" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Vasanth Madhure&lt;/a&gt;, CISO beim Softwareunternehmen Couchbase, zählen mit Blick auf neue Tools nicht nur die anfallenden Lizenzkosten, sondern auch die Implementierungs- und Schulungsanforderungen für das Security-Team. Deshalb möchte der Sicherheitsentscheider es ganz genau wissen: “Ich frage nach, wieviel Zeit und Aufwand für Konfiguration und Betrieb des Produkts konkret einzuplanen sind. Einige Produkte sind recht unkompliziert, andere erfordern jedoch umfangreiche Konfigurationen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie Madhure hinzufügt, sei es auch wichtig zu wissen, ob Updates automatisiert oder manuell erfolgen – schließlich wirke sich die laufende Wartung direkt auf die Arbeitsbelastung für die Mitarbeiter aus. “Ich schätze vor allem Tools, die klare, umsetzbare Reportings und aussagekraftige Dashboards bieten – und es idealerweise ermöglichen, den &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492322/cybersecurity-messen-10-kennzahlen-die-cisos-weiterbringen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Reifegrad&lt;/a&gt; des Sicherheitsprogramms im Zeitverlauf zu tracken”, erklärt der CISO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus stellt der Couchbase-Manager auch sicher, keine bösen Überraschungen im Nachgang zu erleben: “Man will nicht in eine Lösung investieren, nur um dann navchträglich festzustellen, dass ein Upgrade auf eine Enterprise-Version nötig ist oder ein zusätzliches Produkt angeschafft werden muss, damit ein bestimmtes Feature funktioniert.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Wie sieht Ihr Update-Zyklus aus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hydrolix-CISO Scott befragt Anbieter ausgiebig zu ihren Update-Zyklen – und das aus gutem Grund, wie er erklärt: “Ich möchte verstehen, wie Anbieter mit neuen Frameworks, Compliance-Vorschriften und Security-Herausforderungen Schritt halten. Insbesondere in sich schnell verändernden Bereichen wie &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495294/schwachstellen-managen-die-6-besten-vulnerability-management-tools.html" target="_blank"&gt;Vulnerability Scanning&lt;/a&gt; oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/4057811/als-quereinsteiger-zum-security-job-ein-erfahrungsbericht.html" target="_blank"&gt;GRC&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Können Sie Ihre Aussagen mit praktischen Anwendungsfällen belegen?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es empfiehlt sich zudem, Anbieter nach konkreten Beispielen dafür zu fragen, wie ihre Lösung bereits die Probleme gelöst hat, mit denen Sie selbst konfrontiert sind. “Support für etablierte Frameworks wie NIST CSF oder &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493162/vom-aufstieg-eines-frameworks-mitre-attck-wird-strategisch-wichtig.html" target="_blank"&gt;MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK&lt;/a&gt; sind zwar nützlich. Noch wichtiger ist allerdings ein Nachweis über optimierten Schutz, verkürzte Erkennungs- und schnellere Reaktionszeiten oder auch geringere Kosten”, konstatiert Basu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um sicherzustellen, dass das potenzielle neue Tool keine Vaporware ist, eine &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2834420/der-niedergang-des-user-interface.html" target="_blank"&gt;schlechte Benutzeroberfläche&lt;/a&gt; aufweist oder mit umständlichen Funktionen enttäuscht, setzt Scott in erster Linie auf Live-Demos – und bezieht dabei auch sein Team mit ein: “CISOs verstehen vielleicht auf einer höheren Ebene, warum ein Produkt einen Mehrwert bietet. Aber es kann technische Details geben, die wir übersehen haben – oder etwas anderes, dass die Praktiker einfach besser einordnen können.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-warnsignale-auf-die-sie-achten-sollten"&gt;4 Warnsignale, auf die Sie achten sollten&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In einer Sache sind sich alle CISOs, mit denen wir gesprochen haben, einig: Es gibt Dinge, die im Rahmen von Sales Pitches oder anderen Angeboten sofort die Alarmglocken schrillen lassen sollten.Dazu zählen demnach insbesondere:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vage oder abwegige Behauptungen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Panikmache, die darauf beruht Angst, Unsicherheit und Zweifel zu schüren (etwa, wenn ein &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494678/panik-wut-schuldgefuhle-die-emotionalen-phasen-eines-cyberangriffs.html" target="_blank"&gt;Sicherheitsvorfall&lt;/a&gt; zur Verkaufstaktik wird),&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;die gehäufte Verwendung von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492310/security-buzzword-bingo-10-schlagworter-zum-abgewohnen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Buzzwords&lt;/a&gt; ohne wirkliche Erklärung, und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine mangelnde Bereitschaft des Anbieters, Feedback zu seinen Verkaufsgesprächen anzunehmen (kein gutes Signal für die künftige Zusammenarbeit).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4063809/wie-cisos-schlechte-produkte-enttarnen.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA 2015 cyber threat info-sharing law lapses amid government shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065998/cisa-2015-cyber-threat-info-sharing-law-lapses-amid-government-shutdown.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, Congress passed a &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Cybersecurity%2520Information%2520Sharing%2520Act%2520of%25202015.pdf"&gt;major cybersecurity bill&lt;/a&gt; called the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (CISA 2015) to empower the federal government to collect and disseminate threat information, while allowing private sector entities to voluntarily share that information with the government and among themselves, protected from adverse legal or regulatory ramifications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA 2015 was slated to expire on Sept. 30, 2025. Now, despite &lt;a href="https://cyberscoop.com/cyber-threat-information-law-hurtles-toward-expiration-with-poor-prospects-for-renewal/"&gt;many efforts&lt;/a&gt; in both the House and Senate, and even with the support of the Trump administration, the cybersecurity sector, and both sides of the aisle, CISA 2015 has expired because it was not extended amid the legislative and political chaos that led to a US government shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consequently, cybersecurity defenders have lost the information-sharing liability protection the bill provided, and the government has lost a lot of visibility into threats emerging across the private sector. Given the overheated partisan environment in Washington, it’s unclear how quickly or when Congress will revisit extending CISA 2015 or for how long.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If the law remains lapsed “for a lengthy period, that will diminish capabilities across the industry to share and enhance real-time sharing of cyber threat indicators,” &lt;a href="https://www.darktrace.com/people/nathaniel-jones"&gt;Nathaniel Jones&lt;/a&gt;, VP of security and AI strategy at Darktrace, who, until two years ago, was a CISA veteran who had served as a section chief and operations officer, tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The whole purpose of this was to provide an insulating layer over communications that are made by the critical sectors when they need to share information,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/seattlemkh/"&gt;Mike Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;, field CISO of Lumifi Cyber and former CISO of Seattle, tells CSO. “Now, the private sector is going to be very reluctant to tell anybody what happens to them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-cisa-2015-provided"&gt;What CISA 2015 provided&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA 2015 explicitly authorized private entities to take certain defensive measures to stop cyberattacks, to monitor their own and customers’ networks for cyber threats — with written authorization and consent — and share cyber threat indicators to provide better detection and response to cyber threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It provided legal liability protection for how the private sector, which owns most of the critical infrastructure in the US, shares threat information with the US government and private sector peers. Moreover, it placed limits on how shared information can be used and provided several protections against unwanted disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the protections offered by the legislation &lt;a href="https://www.venable.com/insights/publications/2025/09/cyber-threat-information-sharing-at-risk-what?utm_source=vuture&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20250929%20-%20cyber%20threat%20information%20sharing%20at%20risk%3a%20what%20companies%20should%20consider%20if%20the%20cybersecurity%20information%20sharing%20act%20of%202015%20is%20not%20renewed"&gt;were&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exemptions from anti-trust liability&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Exemptions from disclosure under FOIA and state sunshine laws&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Continued applicability of privileges and protections, including trade secret protections for shared information&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Continued protection of shared information as the commercial, financial, and proprietary information of a non-federal entity when so designated&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Exemptions from rules limiting &lt;em&gt;ex parte&lt;/em&gt; or informal communications with federal officials&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Broad liability protections for information sharing efforts undertaken that are consistent with the laws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We always talked about the barriers in the way and the roadblocks to sharing, and that’s what CISA 2015 was supposed to be doing: removing the barriers,” &lt;a href="https://www.venable.com/professionals/s/ari-schwartz"&gt;Ari Schwartz&lt;/a&gt;, executive director at the Center for Cybersecurity Law and Policy and partner at law firm Venable, tells CSO. “But what it was really doing was getting easy legal approval for information sharing. CISA 2015 made it so that the lawyers did not have to do a review.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-happens-next-and-what-should-cisos-do"&gt;What happens next, and what should CISOs do?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most Capitol Hill observers believe that, given the broad support that CISA 2015 has received, Congress will inevitably find a solution that ends the government shutdown and, in so doing, pass at least a temporary extension of CISA 2015.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In both the short and long term, I am committed to finding the best path forward alongside my colleagues in the House and Senate to reauthorize and enhance these essential authorities,” &lt;a href="https://garbarino.house.gov/"&gt;Andrew Garbarino (R-NY)&lt;/a&gt;, chairman of the House Committee on Homeland Security, told CSO in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There might be just a short-term window where they’ll disconnect it and then try to figure out the longer extension,” Darktrace’s Jones says. “At the moment, the proposal is 10 years, which I think makes more sense, but I think people will look to give it a temporary stopgap.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The real question is how long it will take Congress to extend CISA 2015. Experts stress that the damage to US cybersecurity from a lapse in CISA 2015 is directly correlated with just how long it stays lapsed. “If it’s a short window, I don’t think there’s going to be a lot of impact,” Lumifi’s Hamilton says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Venable’s Schwartz thinks that the situation will become increasingly problematic the longer Congress waits to act. “If it’s two days, it’s not going to be that impactful for companies,” he says. “If it goes for some period of time, not having this provision is going to have an impact.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s one thing if there’s an incident and people aren’t sharing information about the incident for one day because their lawyers said, ‘Let’s just hold on and see what happens tomorrow,’” Schwartz says. “If everyone starts doing that over a month, that becomes more problematic.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Schwartz also thinks that organizations that operated under negotiated information-sharing arrangements prior to CISA’s 2015 passage might fare better because they have existing legal frameworks to fall back on. “If it was done before 2015, then you have some sharing agreements that are probably still in place for the ISACs,” he says, referring to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567485/what-is-an-isac-or-isao-how-these-cyber-threat-information-sharing-organizations-improve-security.html"&gt;Information Sharing and Analysis Centers&lt;/a&gt;. “There may be some things that they have to update a little bit, but it’s not that much.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The impact of the law’s lapse will also vary sector by sector. “For some sectors, it’s going to be a lot less than other sectors that weren’t sharing before, didn’t have the agreements in place, or weren’t working on the agreements,” Schwartz emphasizes. “That’s going to be quite a lot of work for them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, Schwartz advises CISOs to work closely with in-house or external counsel prior to any future information-sharing efforts lest they be held liable for any legal missteps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You need to go to the lawyers,” he says. “You need legal reviews. If you’re a CISO, you have to go to your inside counsel and tell them, ‘We heard this law is not passing, and we want to make sure that we’re not doing anything that’s going to give the company liability down the road.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This level of legal review will no doubt slow down any sharing of threats of possible defense techniques. “The lawyers are going to look into it and review the types of sharing that have been going on, what laws might be violated, and whether there are agreements in place for what happens to it on the other side,” Schwartz says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He adds, “There will still be information sharing, but we’ve gone multiple steps backwards.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, Sept. 1: &lt;/strong&gt;A CISA spokesperson told CSO in a statement, “As America’s cyber defense agency, CISA remains fully committed to safeguarding the nation’s critical infrastructure. While a government shutdown can disrupt federal operations, CISA will sustain essential functions and provide timely guidance to minimize disruptions.” The spokesperson added. “The Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 remains vital to this mission and allowing it to lapse would be a serious blow. CISA will continue its mission, but America’s defenders deserve both the tools and the support to meet growing threats.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065998/cisa-2015-cyber-threat-info-sharing-law-lapses-amid-government-shutdown.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 arrests for smuggling over 600 migrants across the Western Balkans</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/4-arrests-for-smuggling-over-600-migrants-across-western-balkans</link>
      <description>A large investigation, involving law enforcement and judicial authorities from Bosnia and Herzegovina, Croatia and Slovenia, has led to the dismantling of criminal network smuggling migrants from Bosnia and Herzegovina to Croatia and towards other EU countries. The investigation into this network active across the Western Balkans route was conducted under Europol’s dedicated Operational Task Force (OTF). Further arrests already took place in previous operational actions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/4-arrests-for-smuggling-over-600-migrants-across-western-balkans</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-012 - Vulnerabilities impacting Cisco ASA and FTD devices – CVE-2025-20333, CVE-2025-20362 and CVE-2025-20363</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-012-vulnerabilities-impacting-cisco-asa-ftd-devices-cve-2025-20333-cve-2025-20362-cve-2025-20363</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-012-vulnerabilities-impacting-cisco-asa-ftd-devices-cve-2025-20333-cve-2025-20362-cve-2025-20363</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISOs advised to rethink vulnerability management as exploits sharply rise</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065137/cisos-advised-to-rethink-vulnerability-management-as-exploits-sharply-rise.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprise attack surfaces continue to expand rapidly, with more than 20,000 new vulnerabilities disclosed in the first half of 2025, straining already hard-pressed security teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly 35% (6,992) of these vulnerabilities have publicly available exploit code, according to the &lt;a href="https://flashpoint.io/resources/report/flashpoint-global-threat-intelligence-index-midyear/"&gt;Global Threat Intelligence Index study&lt;/a&gt; by threat intel firm Flashpoint.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The volume of disclosed vulnerabilities has more than tripled while the amount of exploit code has more than doubled since the end of February 2025 alone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These increases make it no longer feasible for most organizations to triage, remediate, or mitigate every vulnerability, Flashpoint argues, suggesting enterprises need to apply a risk-based patching framework. But some experts quizzed by CSO went further — arguing a complete operational overhaul of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3853759/10-best-practices-for-vulnerability-management-according-to-cisos.html"&gt;vulnerability management&lt;/a&gt; practices is needed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risk-based-patching-a-rising-necessity"&gt;Risk-based patching: A rising necessity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-lefkowitz-b9a12b2/"&gt;Josh Lefkowitz&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Flashpoint, says that surges in disclosed vulnerabilities and publicly available exploit code reflect a shift in the threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attackers are operationalizing exploits as soon as vulnerabilities surface, often within hours, and well before defenders can access reliable data from public sources,” Lefkowitz tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The widening gap between exposure and response makes it impractical for security teams to rely on traditional approaches. The countermeasure is not “patch everything faster,” but “patch smarter” by taking advantage of security intelligence, according to Lefkowitz.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises should evolve beyond reactive patch cycles and embrace risk-based, intelligence-led vulnerability remediation. “That means prioritizing vulnerabilities that are remotely exploitable, actively exploited in the wild, or tied to active adversary campaigns while factoring in business context and likely attacker behaviors,” Lefkowitz says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="focus-on-exploitable-vulnerabilities"&gt;Focus on exploitable vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Third-party security experts agree that enterprises need to apply a risk-based patching framework.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Organizations that try to patch everything are fighting an impossible battle,” says IEEE senior member &lt;a href="https://transmitter.ieee.org/young-creator/shaila-rana/"&gt;Shaila Rana&lt;/a&gt;. “But the silver lining here is that this shift is actually forcing smarter and more strategic approaches to emerge.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rana adds: “This pressure is creating better risk-based frameworks that help teams focus their limited resources on prioritized areas, or what matters most.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.picussecurity.com/resource/author/huseyin-can-yuceel"&gt;Hüseyin Can Yüceel&lt;/a&gt;, security research lead at security validation company Picus Security, says that although the growing volume of vulnerabilities disclosed may be daunting, only some will affect any particular enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You may not even own the product with a vulnerability or already have some security mitigations in place to prevent exploitation,” Yüceel explains. “The most important thing is deciding what’s relevant and important to you, which is why prioritization based on context is important.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yüceel adds: “A risk-based approach helps organizations focus on the threats that will most likely affect their infrastructure and operations. This means organizations should prioritize vulnerabilities that can be considered exploitable, while de-prioritizing vulnerabilities that can be effectively mitigated or defended against, even if their CVSS [Common Vulnerability Scoring System] score is rated critical.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="relying-on-cves-alone-is-becoming-untenable"&gt;Relying on CVEs alone is becoming ‘untenable’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams relying heavily on public sources of vulnerability intelligence, such as the Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) and the National Vulnerability Database (NVD), are at a severe disadvantage, Flashpoint warns. The average latency between CVE publication and NVD enrichment now spans into weeks and months — &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4008708/beyond-cve-the-hunt-for-other-sources-of-vulnerability-intel.html"&gt;creating critical intelligence gaps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3963190/cve-program-faces-swift-end-after-dhs-fails-to-renew-contract-leaving-security-flaw-tracking-in-limbo.html"&gt;instability in the CVE program fundin&lt;/a&gt;g earlier this year creates additional doubts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Relying solely on CVE or the National Vulnerability Database has become untenable,” Flashpoint’s Lefkowitz says. “The delays, inconsistencies, and persistent backlog mean that critical intelligence often arrives after attackers are already active, leaving defenders blind to high-risk exposures.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fortra.com/profile/tyler-reguly"&gt;Tyler Reguly&lt;/a&gt;, senior manager of security R&amp;amp;D at offensive and defensive security firm Fortra, dismissed concerns that relying on public sources of vulnerability intelligence puts organizations at a “severe disadvantage” as overblown. Vendor reports, exploit databases, and the CISA Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV) list all offer valuable sources of intelligence, Reguly says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The reality is that public sources of intelligence are critical to managing your vulnerabilities,” Reguly argues. “That’s not to say that proprietary data isn’t beneficial, but there’s a lot of data out there available for anyone to gather.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rana argues that public vulnerability intelligence works best when combined with contextual threat intelligence and business risk assessments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Smart organizations are layering CVE data with real-time threat intelligence to create more nuanced and actionable security strategies,” Rana says. Instead of abandoning these trusted sources, effective teams are getting better at using them as part of a broader intelligence picture that helps them stay ahead of the threats that actually matter to their specific environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="third-party-risk-yet-again"&gt;Third-party risk — yet again&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://tokyo.cybertechconference.com/node/2121"&gt;Galit Lubetzky Sharon&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at application attack surface protection firm Wing Security, says that the surge in vulnerabilities and exploit code is only part of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises increasingly depend on third-party SaaS vendors that dictate the patching cycle —when those vendors patch slowly or fail to disclose, customers inherit the risk blindly,” Sharon says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is amplifying this threat: Attackers &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4014238/cybercriminals-take-malicious-ai-to-the-next-level.html"&gt;weaponize exploits at unprecedented speed&lt;/a&gt;, while “SaaS vendors race to release AI features often without mature security controls,” according to Sharon.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The real challenge isn’t just keeping pace with patches but gaining visibility into third-party risk — making continuous SaaS, AI, and general third-party security essential,” Sharon concluded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-simplifying-exploit-development"&gt;AI simplifying exploit development&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sassrami/"&gt;Rami Sass&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at application security firm Mend, says the time between vulnerability discovery and exploitation has shrunk from weeks to days if not hours over the past two years, partly because of the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3632268/gen-ai-is-transforming-the-cyber-threat-landscape-by-democratizing-vulnerability-hunting.html"&gt;increased abuse of AI technologies by attackers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are three main drivers behind increasingly turbulent threat landscape, according to Sass:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better tools to discover vulnerabilities, especially in legacy code&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A hungry and growing commercial market for exploits&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;AI tools are making the production of exploits easier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attackers are now using AI to move faster than defenders,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/backdream/"&gt;Federico Simonetti&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at zero knowledge networking firm Xiid. “AI is highly effective at finding vulnerabilities and crafting exploits, while at the same time, it’s horribly ineffective at applying any significant level of protection.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="exposure-management"&gt;Exposure management&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/peledeldan/?originalSubdomain=il"&gt;Peled Eldan&lt;/a&gt;, head of research at cloud security firm XM Cyber, believes the surge of vulnerabilities and exploits is a “byproduct of sprawling cloud estates, rapid migrations, deployment mishaps, misconfigurations, and more.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While the NVD is still a foundational pillar of cybersecurity, SOC teams need far more than CVE IDs and CVSS scores to meaningfully reduce risk,” Eldan says. “Even if NVD enrichment speeds up, it won’t fix the bigger problem: understanding how vulnerabilities connect with other exposures to create exploitable attack paths.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This dynamic is fueling vulnerability management’s evolution into exposure management, which treats identity issues and misconfigurations as seriously as code flaws.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When paired with attack surface tools such as breach simulations, pen tests, and red teaming, companies can build attack graphs that visualize how an adversary could reach crown-jewel assets,” Eldan explains. “Attack graphs are often used in conjunction with digital twins to simulate and validate that a given remediation strategy eliminates the exposure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="navigating-a-minefield-with-a-pogo-stick"&gt;Navigating a minefield with a pogo stick&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivanmilenkovic/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Ivan Milenkovic&lt;/a&gt;, vice president of risk technology for EMEA at cloud security vendor Qualys, says the idea that any organization could, or should, attempt to patch every vulnerability was “always a fallacy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The explosion in disclosures and the glaring unreliability of public feeds like the NVD haven’t created a new problem; they’ve simply exposed the intellectual bankruptcy of the traditional approach,” Milenkovic tells CSO. “Relying on CVSS scores and chasing CVEs is like trying to navigate a minefield with a pogo stick.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rather than relying on a risk-based patching framework, enterprises need a complete operational overhaul based on a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3979418/what-is-ctem.html"&gt;continuous threat exposure management (CTEM)&lt;/a&gt; program, Milenkovic advises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/how-to-manage-cybersecurity-threats-not-episodes"&gt;Frameworks like Gartner’s CTEM&lt;/a&gt; provide security operations center teams with a road map on how to mature their processes to prioritize exposures based on exploitability and business impact — not just raw severity scores.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The fundamental question isn’t, ‘Is this vulnerability severe?’ But rather, ‘What is the value at risk to the business, and what is the most capital-efficient way to reduce it?’” Milenkovic, a former CISO, explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The objective of what Ivan Milenkovic describes a “risk operations center” approach based on the CTEM concept is to align security with genuine business outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Your goal is to use a money-minded framework to surgically remediate the 2% of vulnerabilities that pose over 90% of the actual, material risk to your organization,” Milenkovic says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065137/cisos-advised-to-rethink-vulnerability-management-as-exploits-sharply-rise.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-619)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-620)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-620</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-620</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-621)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-621</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-621</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-622)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-622</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-622</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foxit security advisory (AV25-623)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/foxit-security-advisory-av25-623</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/foxit-security-advisory-av25-623</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dozens of sex trafficking victims in Austria – five arrests in Colombia</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/dozens-of-sex-trafficking-victims-in-austria-–-five-arrests-in-colombia</link>
      <description>Austrian and Colombian law enforcement authorities, supported by Europol, have rescued dozens of Colombian women from violent sexual exploitation in Europe. The raids performed on 5 September 2025 in Medellin, Colombia, saw the arrest of five suspected Colombian human traffickers on international arrest warrants. One Uruguayan man and one Colombian woman were already arrested in August 2025 in Spain, while two Austrian women and a Romanian woman remain detained in Austria. The criminal network headed by an Austrian-Turkish suspect, who at the moment remains at large, exploited its victims by means of coercion, deception, and abusing their vulnerabilities. In many instances, the criminals relied on severe physical violence towards the women, as well as threats against their family members back home.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/dozens-of-sex-trafficking-victims-in-austria-–-five-arrests-in-colombia</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Kennzahlen, die CISOs weiterbringen</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492322/cybersecurity-messen-10-kennzahlen-die-cisos-weiterbringen.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Geht es um Security-Kennzahlen, sollten CISOs sich auf das Wesentliche fokussieren. " src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3376394/1200x.jpg" title="Geht es um Security-Kennzahlen, sollten CISOs sich auf das Wesentliche fokussieren. " width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Geht es um Security-Kennzahlen, sollten CISOs sich auf das Wesentliche fokussieren. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Vadym Nechyporenko – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Security-Performance &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495619/security-kpis-und-kris-so-messen-sie-cybersicherheit.html" target="_blank" title="zu messen"&gt;zu messen&lt;/a&gt;, gehört vielleicht nicht zu den aufregendsten Aufgaben eines CISOs – kann allerdings sehr nützlich sein, um eine ganze Reihe von Herausforderungen zu bewältigen. Neben der Erkenntnis darüber, wie effektiv ihre Security-Bemühungen sind, können Sicherheitsentscheider mit den richtigen Kennzahlen unter anderem auch &lt;a href="https://www.cio.de/a/wie-cisos-security-ausgaben-am-business-ausrichten,3712271" target="_blank" title="strategisches Alignment"&gt;strategisches Alignment&lt;/a&gt; mit dem Business demonstrieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um jedoch einen echten Nutzen aus den Metriken ziehen zu können, ist das oberste Gebot, sich auf diejenigen zu konzentrieren, die belegen, dass die Security das Business stützt. Kennzahlen, denen es an Bedeutung oder Kontext mangelt, sind hingegen zu vernachlässigen, wie Richard Absalom, Principal Research Analyst beim Information Security Forum, unterstreicht: “Man kann unzählige Dinge in Sachen Security Performance &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493962/kennzahlen-die-weiterhelfen-so-uberzeugen-sie-ihre-geschaftsfuhrer-von-security-investitionen.html" target="_blank" title="messen"&gt;messen&lt;/a&gt; – was mit Blick auf Extraktion und Reporting viel Zeit, Mühe und Ressourcen kostet. Fragen Sie sich: Warum messen wir das? Wie hilft uns das? Welche Frage können wir damit beantworten? Wenn die Messung nicht dazu beiträgt, Stakeholdern oder Entscheidern wichtige Informationen zu liefern, wird sie sehr wahrscheinlich ignoriert.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="10-security-metriken-von-denen-cisos-profitieren"&gt;10 Security-Metriken, von denen CISOs profitieren&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Folgenden haben wir im Gespräch mit Experten und Entscheidern zehn Benefits identifiziert, die CISOs mit den jeweils richtigen Security-Metriken realisieren können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Incident-Response-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mean Time to Detect (&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/webcasts/the-future-is-now-embracing-detection-engineering-for-incident-response/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="MTTD"&gt;MTTD&lt;/a&gt;) oder Mean Time to Respond (&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/webcasts/the-future-is-now-embracing-detection-engineering-for-incident-response/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="MTTR"&gt;MTTR&lt;/a&gt;) liefern beispielsweise quantitative Daten, die CISOs dabei unterstützen, objektive Entscheidungen zu treffen. Frank Kim, Fellow am SANS Institute, erklärt: “Indem sie wichtige Sicherheitsindikatoren analysieren und nachverfolgen, können CISOs Prioritäten setzen, Ressourcen zuweisen und sich auf die Bereiche konzentrieren, die am dringendsten optimiert werden müssen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Security-Investment-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beispielsweise zu wissen, wie hoch der Prozentsatz wichtiger Business-Initiativen mit eingebetteten Sicherheitsprozessen ist, kann CISOs dabei unterstützen, den &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2767483/mehr-roi-durch-gezielte-trainings.html" target="_blank" title="Return on Investment"&gt;Return on Investment&lt;/a&gt; (ROI) von Security-Initiativen gegenüber der Geschäftsleitung und den Stakeholdern nachzuweisen. Insofern aufgezeigt wird, wie diese Bemühungen zur Risikominderung und dazu beitragen, Zwischenfälle zu verhindern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Die Stakeholder interessieren sich nicht für die Cyberrisiken, sondern die Geschäftsrisiken, die sich aus dem Cyberbereich ergeben”, konstatiert Brian Contos, CSO bei Sevco Security. Er fügt hinzu: “Genauer gesagt geht es dabei um Risiken im Zusammenhang mit Umsatz, Brands, Operations sowie ESG – Environmental, Social, Governance.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Security-Awareness-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In diesen Bereich fällt beispielsweise der Prozentsatz der Fachabteilungen, die an entsprechenden Programmen beteiligt sind. Diese Kennzahlen unterstützen dabei, zu ermitteln, ob im Unternehmen eine &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492707/it-sicherheit-bei-otto-it-sicherheit-muss-teil-der-kultur-sein.html" target="_blank" title="Security-Kultur"&gt;Security-Kultur&lt;/a&gt; existiert – oder entsteht. So lässt sich darstellen, wie effektiv entsprechende Initiativen auf die allgemeine Sicherheitslage des Unternehmens einzahlen – was für Sicherheitsentscheider traditionell eine Herausforderung darstellt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fred Rica, ehemals Head of Cyber Practice bei KPMG und Partner beim Wirtschaftsprüfungsunternehmen BPM, erläutert: “CISOs, die dem Vorstand technische Kennzahlen präsentieren, schießen oft am Ziel vorbei, weil der Kontext fehlt. Dem Board mitzuteilen, dass 100.000 Events per Firewall blockiert wurden, wird ohne entsprechenden Kontext nicht fruchten.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Vulnerability-Management-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Metriken im Bereich &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495294/schwachstellen-managen-die-6-besten-vulnerability-management-tools.html" target="_blank" title="Schwachstellenmanagement"&gt;Schwachstellenmanagement&lt;/a&gt;, wie das “Window of Exposure”, können CISOs dabei unterstützen, das Risikoprofil ihrer Organisationen besser zu verstehen und Bedrohungen aktiv zu begegnen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Letztlich geht es darum, die zerbrochenen Fenster und unverschlossenen Türen eines Unternehmens anzugehen”, verbildlicht SANS-Experte Kim. “Vulnerability-Management-Metriken geben Aufschluss darüber, wie lange die Türen potenziell offenstehen und unterstützen dabei, tägliche Arbeitsabläufe zu etablieren, zum Beispiel im Bereich Scanning oder &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491785/aktuelle-sicherheitslucken-diese-schwachstellen-sollten-sie-sofort-patchen.html" target="_blank" title="Patching"&gt;Patching&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Security-Process-Improvement-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Metriken zur Verbesserung von Sicherheitsprozessen erfassen den Fortschritt im Zeitverlauf und ermöglichen CISOs, spezifische Ziele zu setzen beziehungsweise zu verfolgen. Ein Beispiel für eine Kennzahl in diesem Bereich wäre der Prozentsatz von Vorfällen mit derselben wiederkehrenden Grundursache.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Dieser datengesteuerte Ansatz trägt zur kontinuierlichen Verbesserung der Sicherheitspraktiken bei und fördert eine Kultur der Verantwortlichkeit”, hält Kim fest. Anschließend könnten risikobasierte Metriken in Jahresberichte oder Corporate-Governance-Dokumente einfließen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Security-Maturity-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Metriken zum Security-Reifegrad – beispielsweise Capability Maturity Scores – lassen sich mit Branchen-Benchmarks (beispielsweise &lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/cis-benchmarks" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="denen des Center for Internet Security"&gt;denen des Center for Internet Security&lt;/a&gt;) oder auch früheren Ergebnissen abgleichen. Das ermöglicht Sicherheitsentscheidern, den Security-Reifegrad ihrer Organisation zu verstehen, um im Anschluss realistische Sicherheitsziele und -strategien zu entwickeln.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut ISF-Chefanalyst Absalom sollten Sicherheitsverantwortliche nach Indikatoren und Metriken Ausschau halten, die Aufschluss darüber geben, wie gut die Organisation:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bedrohungen und gefährdete Assets identifiziert;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;die identifizierten Assets schützt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bedrohungsereignisse erkennt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;auf erkannte Ereignisse reagiert;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;sich nach Vorfällen erholt und deren Auswirkungen begrenzen kann.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Compliance-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Da viele Vorschriften und Standards auch ein Reporting zu bestimmten Security-Metriken erfordern, ist es sinnvoll, über Compliance-Metriken zu verfügen – beispielsweise den Prozentsatz der Systeme, die mit bestimmten Anforderungen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491936/cloud-controls-framework-wie-cisco-in-uber-100-landern-compliant-bleibt.html" target="_blank" title="im Einklang stehen"&gt;im Einklang stehen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kim bringt es auf den Punkt: “Das erleichtert es, Compliance-Anforderungen zu erfüllen und potenzieller Strafzahlungen zu vermeiden.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Threat-Detection-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kennzahlen im Bereich Bedrohungserkennung – wie die Anzahl der erkannten Vorfälle oder False-Positive/Negative-Raten – können als Frühwarnzeichen für &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493090/bottlenecks-auflosen-threat-intelligence-problemen-auf-der-spur.html" target="_blank" title="potenzielle Sicherheitsvorfälle"&gt;potenzielle Sicherheitsvorfälle&lt;/a&gt; oder Schwachstellen in der Infrastruktur dienen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das ermöglicht CISOs, Probleme aktiv anzugehen und größeren Sicherheitsverletzungen vorzubeugen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Ressource-Utilization-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Metriken zur Ressourcennutzung wie der prozentuale Anteil der Zeit, der für aktive gegenüber reaktiven Sicherheitsaufgaben aufgewendet wird, können CISOs in die Lage versetzen, ineffiziente Bereiche oder redundante Sicherheitskontrollen zu identifizieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das kann in der Konsequenz zu einer besseren Ressourcenzuweisung und damit zu Kostenoptimierungen führen. In Zeiten des immer noch ausgeprägten &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493528/5-masnahmen-so-finden-sie-cybersecurity-experten.html" target="_blank" title="Security-Fachkräftemangels"&gt;Security-Fachkräftemangels&lt;/a&gt; könnte das eine entscheidende Unterstützung für Sicherheitsverantwortliche darstellen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Security-Transparency-Metriken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kennzahlen zur Security-Transparenz – etwa die Anzahl der dem Unternehmen mitgeteilten Sicherheitsvorfälle oder die Bewertungen der internen Stakeholder zur Security-Kommunikation – können das Vertrauen zwischen Security-Team und anderen Geschäftseinheiten stärken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Wenn die Wirksamkeit von Sicherheitsmaßnahmen quantifiziert und transparent kommuniziert wird, stärkt das das Vertrauen in das Sicherheitsprogramm”, konstatiert SANS-Experte Kim. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492322/cybersecurity-messen-10-kennzahlen-die-cisos-weiterbringen.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disaster recovery and business continuity: How to create an effective plan</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/515730/business-continuity-and-disaster-recovery-planning-the-basics.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The core principles of disaster recovery (DR) and business continuity have remained relatively unchanged for decades: identify risks, conduct a business impact analysis, set recovery time objectives (RTOs), create a backup and restore plan, perform periodic testing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In simpler times, data lived on-prem, cyberthreats were less sophisticated, natural disasters were rare, organizations could probably get by with an outage that lasted hours, even days, weekly backups were sufficient, and regulations regarding data breaches were virtually nonexistent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, the volume of enterprise data has exploded and that data is everywhere (public cloud, SaaS, edge, IoT, OT, LLMs); &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053251/ai-powered-autonomous-ransomware-campaigns-are-coming-say-experts.html"&gt;AI-generated ransomware attacks&lt;/a&gt; are on the horizon; natural disasters are occurring far more often due to climate change; business units want to be up and running within minutes; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3725463/sec-rule-confusion-continues-to-put-cisos-in-a-bind-a-year-after-a-major-revision.html"&gt;penalties for not reporting a cyberattack&lt;/a&gt; in a timely manner or failing to protect customer data are severe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your disaster recovery and &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/288554/best-practices-how-to-create-an-effective-business-continuity-plan.html"&gt;business continuity plan&lt;/a&gt; has been gathering dust on the shelf, it’s time for a full rebuild from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Key components include strategies such as minimum viable business (MVB); emerging technologies such as AI and generative AI; and tactical processes and approaches such as integrated threat hunting, automated data discovery and classification, continuous backups, immutable data, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518982/tabletop-exercise-scenarios.html"&gt;gamified tabletop testing exercises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3999424/backup-as-a-service-explained-your-guide-to-cloud-data-protection.html"&gt;Backup-as-a-service (BaaS)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/970954/what-is-draas-and-how-it-can-save-your-business-from-disaster.html"&gt;disaster recovery-as-a-service (DRaaS)&lt;/a&gt; are also becoming more popular, as enterprises look to take advantage of the scalability, cloud storage options, and ease-of-use associated with the “as-a-service” model. In fact, Gartner predicts that by 2029, 85% of large enterprises will adopt BaaS, alongside customer-managed deployments, to back up cloud and on-premises workloads, compared with 25% in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps CISOs need to take to build out a successful DR/business continuity plan in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-1-build-c-level-support-obtain-funding-create-a-team"&gt;Step 1: Build C-level support, obtain funding, create a team&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effective disaster recovery/business continuity requires significant upfront work and constant attention. It’s also costly in terms of additional storage resources, software tools, and staff time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/t-ryan-whelan-1156ab5/"&gt;Ryan Whelan&lt;/a&gt;, global head of cyber intelligence at Accenture, says he recently surveyed CISOs in the retail and hospitality verticals on their priorities, and found that disaster recovery and business continuity skyrocketed from “not even in the top 10” in 2024 to No. 3 in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whelan says this shift is being driven at the C-suite and board level, where concerns over regulatory compliance, legal ramifications, and brand damage loom large. Whereas DR/business continuity was in the past primarily the domain of risk management and legal departments, with security playing a background role, CISOs are now at the forefront of these efforts, says Whelan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That prioritization of DR/business continuity is translating into increased funding. According to Forrester’s &lt;a href="https://reprint.forrester.com/reports/the-state-of-resilience-2025-60ea1dfb/index.html"&gt;State of Resilience 2025 report&lt;/a&gt;, 37% of respondents expect funding to increase over the next 12 months, while only 4% expect it to decrease. The rest anticipated level funding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.fticonsulting.com/experts/todd-renner"&gt;Todd Renner&lt;/a&gt;, senior managing director in the cybersecurity practice at FTI Consulting, puts it, “Before something bad happens it’s harder to get the money; after something bad happens, it’s easier to get the money.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once C-level support has been obtained, the next critical step is building a standing team that includes security, data center, storage, compliance, legal, risk management, business process, and internal and external communications. Organizations need to break down silos and create an interdisciplinary group that will continue to function as an ongoing entity, continually evolving to meet new threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Specific roles include incident reporter, the person responsible for communicating with stakeholders; a plan manager, whose role is to make sure everyone performs the tasks assigned to them; and an asset manager, who is responsible for securing and protecting critical assets and reporting back on their status throughout the incident.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-2-identify-risk-and-locate-all-your-data"&gt;Step 2: Identify risk — and locate all your data&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identifying risk in a large, distributed enterprise is a complex task. Risks are everywhere, starting with cyberattacks (including insider attacks), and encompass human error, system failures (hardware, software, network), natural disasters, and third-party vulnerabilities associated with supply chains, cloud service providers, and SaaS providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When Forrester asked survey respondents to identify the root cause of invocations of their DR/business continuity plans, the top causes were IT failure, natural disaster, IT security incident, supply chain disruption, and power outage. Each type of risk calls for a different response plan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Renner says that organizations often struggle to answer basic questions such as “Where is my data?” and “Who owns the data?” He adds, “The more complex the system is, the harder it is to identify system owners and to identify where the data is residing, including structured and unstructured data.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The good news is that there are AI-driven software tools that can scan structured and unstructured enterprise data to identify vulnerabilities, perform data discovery, and classify the data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner predicts that by 2029, 90% of backup and data protection platforms products will integrate genAI to improve management and support operations, compared with fewer than 25% in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-3-conduct-a-business-impact-analysis"&gt;Step 3: Conduct a business impact analysis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data doesn’t exist for its own sake; it’s there to support the business, so enterprises need to understand the business impact of a disaster and back up only what’s necessary. Still, when organizations go through the exercise of identifying all the bits and pieces of a complex business process, it can become overwhelming, particularly in a hybrid or multicloud environment rife with microservices, containers, APIs, identity and access controls, SaaS applications, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Accenture’s Whelan says that rather than try to restore the entire business in the event of a disaster, a better approach might be to create a skeletal replica of the business, an MVB, that can be spun up immediately to keep mission-critical processes going while traditional backup and recovery efforts are under way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This type of “out-of-the-box” fail-over system could include a core functions such as email, which would enable the organization to communicate internally and externally, while other, less time-sensitive functions like ERP are recovered.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This MVB approach requires tight integration between business units and technology teams, Whelan says. They need to work together to conduct dependency mapping aimed at identifying critical business functions and the technology components associated with that function.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-4-backups-strategies-shift-from-3-2-1-to-3-2-1-1-0"&gt;Step 4: Backups strategies shift from 3-2-1 to 3-2-1-1-0&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The basic 3-2-1 backup strategy that has been standard for many years is no longer sufficient. The idea of having three copies of data on two different backup formats, with one copy located offsite, is being replaced with 3-2-1-1-0.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The two additional elements are: one offline, immutable, or air-gapped backup that will enable organizations to get back on their feet in the event of a ransomware attack, and a goal of zero errors. Immutable data is “the gold standard,” Whelan says, but there are complexities associated with proper implementation. For example, in the event of a disaster, how does an enterprise know when the last snapshot occurred? And how does an enterprise verify that the data being saved in an immutable data store is accurate and not corrupted? &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’re still finding that data cleanliness and providence is a major issue for organizations,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FTI’s Renner points out that AI-driven backup and restore platforms can continuously scan enterprise data for accuracy, and develop recommendations for how often snapshots should be taken, where data should be stored, and what data needs to be backed up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And Gartner estimates that 35% of enterprises will implement agentic AI to perform autonomous backup operations by 2029, up from less than 2% in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-5-create-the-plan-and-test-it"&gt;Step 5: Create the plan and test it&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are many templates for creating the actual plan document, and AI systems can automate the process. The plan needs to be clear, and it needs to document procedures for incident detection and reporting, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3851840/prepared-for-cyberattacks-crisis-communication-according-to-plan.html"&gt;communication with internal and external stakeholders&lt;/a&gt;, emergency response in the event of a natural disaster, IT recovery, business continuity, and roles and responsibilities for relevant parties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the plan must be tested.  According to the Forrester report, “Unfortunately, the testing situation is largely unchanged since 2008. For all test types, most organizations only test once per year with plan walk-throughs and tabletop exercises, and as tests become more extensive, test frequency declines — 41% of respondents said that they never performed a full simulation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forward-thinking companies are trying to make tabletop exercises more effective by switching from a static PowerPoint presentation to interactive, gamified experiences that are more realistic and compelling, Renner says. “I’ve never seen a tabletop not be effective in teaching someone a portion of their business they weren’t thinking about ahead of time,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-6-managing-the-aftermath"&gt;Step 6: Managing the aftermath&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The final piece of the puzzle is the post-mortem, taking stock in the aftermath of a disaster. Organizations need to pinpoint what went wrong and determine how it can be prevented in the future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And Gartner analyst &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/michael-hoeck"&gt;Michael Hoeck&lt;/a&gt; argues that backup copies of enterprise data don’t have to just sit there; they can be put to good use. He predicts that by 2029, 30% of enterprises will make use of backup copies of data for analytics and inference, up from less than 5% in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/515730/business-continuity-and-disaster-recovery-planning-the-basics.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-624)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-624</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-624</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-625)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-625</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-625</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-626)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-626</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-626</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–627)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-627</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-627</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-628)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-628</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-628</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-629)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-630)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudo security advisory (AV25-631)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sudo-security-advisory-av25-631</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sudo-security-advisory-av25-631</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-632)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-632</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-632</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-633)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-633</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-633</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-634)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-634</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-634</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-635)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-635</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-635</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] SSL security advisory (AV25-636)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-ssl-security-advisory-av25-636</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-ssl-security-advisory-av25-636</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-637)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-637</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-637</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV25-638)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-638</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-638</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Dark Reading Virtual Event] Know Your Enemy: How cybercriminals and nation-state hackers operate</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/-dark-reading-virtual-event-know-your-enemy-how-cybercriminals-and-nation-state-hackers-operate</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/-dark-reading-virtual-event-know-your-enemy-how-cybercriminals-and-nation-state-hackers-operate</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 134607.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
