<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:20:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Six arrests in a kidnap plot against an Albanian drug trafficker</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/six-arrests-in-kidnap-plot-against-albanian-drug-trafficker</link>
      <description>On 12 November 2025, Europol supported a German-led investigation targeting a group of mercenaries hired by a criminal network to kidnap the leader of a rival drug trafficking gang. The operation involved law enforcement authorities from Denmark, France, Latvia and the United Kingdom..</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/six-arrests-in-kidnap-plot-against-albanian-drug-trafficker</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-725)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the checklist: Shifting from compliance frameworks to real-time risk assessments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088198/beyond-the-checklist-shifting-from-compliance-frameworks-to-real-time-risk-assessments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To keep up with a quickly changing threat environment, organizations are reassessing how they assess risk. They no longer view them only as a once-a-year exercise. They recognize their value as important tools for making informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While many still confuse gap analysis with risk assessment, the difference is important. A &lt;a href="https://www.knbbs.com/why-conduct-information-security-gap-analysis-and-how-to-do-it-effectively/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gap analysis&lt;/a&gt; measures how well a company follows a specific set of controls, often linked to frameworks like &lt;a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/iso-iec-27000-family" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ISO&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt;. A risk assessment, on the other hand, can be customized to look at any threat. This allows security leaders to focus their assessments where they are most needed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I had just started a new role as a CISO and quickly realized that access control was a big issue. Every user in every system seemed to have admin privileges. I decided to assess every critical system for the threat of unauthorized access and tailored the assessment by focusing on that threat. We asked questions like:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What types of data does your system store?” (for impact calculation)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“How many users have administrative permissions?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Can granular user access be assigned based on need?” (RBAC)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“What authentication methods are used?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Are there audit logs?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Combine the access control assessment results with a well-written report that assigns the risk to the business owner, and I had an effective tool for bringing awareness and change to the organization around managing access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="beyond-frameworks-why-static-models-fall-short"&gt;Beyond frameworks: Why static models fall short&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity frameworks provide necessary structure, but they are largely static and cannot substitute for real-time risk processes. Most compliance frameworks require an annual risk assessment because they often lag behind in covering rapidly evolving threats. Relying only on framework-based assessments risks overlooking important issues. This includes matters that go beyond static controls, such as AI adoption, cloud service updates and third-party dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These gaps highlight the importance of combining a solid compliance stance while regularly tailoring assessments to current realities. Frameworks are updated on multi-year cycles, while threats evolve daily. Organizations must focus on what really matters: key business assets, changing technologies and real-world operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="focused-risk-assessments-less-is-more"&gt;Focused risk assessments: Less is more&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional framework reviews can involve hundreds of controls and questions, which may be appropriate for large compliance engagements but are often impractical for smaller teams or fast-moving environments. A focused risk assessment, by contrast, can be built around 20–40 targeted questions. These assessments concentrate on high-probability, high-impact threats and the few controls that materially reduce risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one real-world example, I designed a 26-question assessment that helped a mid-sized organization zero in on its most pressing vulnerabilities. The result was a clear, actionable roadmap that delivered immediate value without the overhead of a full framework review.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This method is particularly beneficial when resources are scarce for organizations. By narrowing the scope, teams are able to rapidly identify and solve the highest priority risks, providing a good foundation for further action like targeted remediation or complete framework alignment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="frequency-over-formality"&gt;Frequency over formality&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the most overlooked aspects of risk assessments is cadence. While gap analyses are sometimes done yearly or to prepare for large-scale audits, risk assessments need to be continuous or performed on a regular schedule. Threats do not respect calendar cycles. Major changes, including new technologies, mergers, regulatory changes or implementing AI, need to trigger reassessments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Integrating risk assessments into regular governance practices, such as quarterly reviews of high-risk assets, evaluations after significant changes and annual assessments, helps organizations stay ahead of evolving threats. Moving to a dynamic approach to risk management from a static one is essential for developing long-term strength.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="designing-an-effective-risk-assessment"&gt;Designing an effective risk assessment&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A modern risk assessment begins with business context. What are the critical assets, processes and outcomes that must be protected? From there, organizations can identify the most likely threat paths and the controls that reduce those risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rather than cataloging every control in a framework, the focus should be on threat-and-control alignment. For example, if ransomware is a major concern, the assessment should focus on controls related to backups, restores, authentication and user awareness. Many organizations regularly back up their data, but they often neglect to test their restoration process. This leaves them at risk when it really counts. In this context, relying solely on backups provides a false sense of security; the real value lies in the ability to restore. A good assessment can uncover these issues and put focus on their priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Emerging vectors such as AI, cloud misconfigurations and software vulnerabilities should be explicitly included. These areas often fall outside traditional frameworks but represent significant risk. To assess AI risk for example, ask these questions:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“How do you use AI?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“What data does your AI have access to?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Do you make business decisions using AI?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Is AI used for automation?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With these simple questions, you can uncover hidden exposures, which are especially critical when sensitive data is involved or decision-making is automated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A simple, repeatable scoring model that rates likelihood and impact helps turn findings into remediation priorities. Consistency across assessments enables trend analysis and supports executive decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="executive-grade-outputs"&gt;Executive-grade outputs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk assessments should culminate in outputs that business leaders can act on. This includes a concise risk heat map, a prioritized remediation roadmap and clear asks, such as budget, ownership and timelines. These deliverables convert technical findings into strategic decisions. They also help build trust with stakeholders, especially in organizations that may be new to formal risk management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="target-for-smaller-teams"&gt;Target for smaller teams&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Targeted risk assessments can be viewed as a low-cost, fundamental option. They are best suited to companies that have limited budget or are not prepared for a full review of the framework. With reduced scope, shorter turnaround and transparent business value, such assessments enable rapid establishment of trust, delivering prioritized outcomes. They help to create a roadmap for deeper engagement and make cybersecurity accessible to smaller teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By starting small, organizations can build credibility and expand into broader programs, such as continuous monitoring, remediation or full framework alignment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-pragmatic-mindset"&gt;A pragmatic mindset&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk assessments are not just checkboxes. They are tools for making decisions. The best programs are aligned with the business, focused, consistent and made to change over time. For many organizations, a short, focused assessment gives executives the evidence they need to justify budgets and demonstrate due diligence. It delivers immediate value and creates a pathway to sustained risk management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088198/beyond-the-checklist-shifting-from-compliance-frameworks-to-real-time-risk-assessments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malicious npm package sneaks into GitHub Actions builds</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088529/malicious-npm-package-sneaks-into-github-actions-builds.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A malicious npm package named “@acitons/artifact” was found impersonating the legitimate “@actions/artifact” module, directly targeting the CI/CD pipelines within GitHub Actions workflows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Veracode findings, the package was uploaded on November 7 and was designed to trigger during the build process of GitHub-owned repositories. Once executed inside a CI/CD runner, the payload captures any tokens available to that build environment and then uses those credentials to publish malicious artifacts–effectively impersonating GitHub itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This incident isn’t just about a malicious npm package, it is about the blind trust many organizations place in the modern supply chain,” said Randolph Barr, CISO at Cequence Security. “Most organizations focus their controls on runtime environments, yet the CI/CD pipeline often runs with higher privilege than any developer. A single typosquatted dependency can silently execute code during a build, access repository tokens, and impersonate an organization, just as this attack attempted to do with GitHub’s own repositories.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malicious package picked up over 260k downloads before detection, and a total of six versions were uploaded–none detectable by “any popular anti-virus” products, Veracode researchers noted in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GitHub says that the packages were uploaded internally as part of its red teaming efforts. “The packages referenced in Veracode’s blog were part of a tightly controlled exercise conducted by GitHub’s Red Team,” a GitHub spokesperson told CSO. “GitHub takes security seriously and regularly tests its security posture through rigorous, realistic Red Team exercises to ensure resilience against current threat actor techniques. At no point were GitHub systems or data at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hijacking the GitHub Actions build process&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the surface, @acitons/artifact package looked normal with its metadata describing it as “actions artifact lib,” and its homepage and repository URLs closely mirroring those of the legitimate GitHub project. But embedded inside was a post-install hook that downloaded and executed an obfuscated shell script named “harness.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veracode’s &lt;a href="https://www.veracode.com/blog/malicious-npm-package-targeting-github-actions/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; showed that this script, compiled with a shell-script compiler tool, contained a time-based kill switch set to deactivate after November 6, 2025–likely to evade detection after a brief active window. Once invoked, the harness would fetch a JavaScript file (“verify.js” meant to check whether the build environment belonged to GitHub and, if so, exfiltrate &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4052826/ghostaction-campaign-steals-3325-secrets-in-github-supply-chain-attack.html"&gt;GitHub Action&lt;/a&gt; tokens. These tokens could then be misused to impersonate GitHub and publish malicious releases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Typosquatting is a well-known and growing threat vector in software supply chains whereby attackers publish packages with similar names as legitimate ones and then wait for a mistake to happen, bringing the victim to their repository to install malicious code by mistake,” explained Boris Cipot, Senior Security Engineer at Black Duck. “This attack strategy is designed to exploit typos and to leverage the automated nature of CI/CD pipelines.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cipot added that the use of a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081790/typo-hackers-sneak-cross-platform-credential-stealer-into-10-npm-packages.html?utm=hybrid_search#:~:text=npm%20postinstall%20script"&gt;post-install hook&lt;/a&gt; and a short-lived obfuscated payload shows a deliberate attempt to blend in with normal build activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="lessons-in-defense"&gt;Lessons in defense&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Barr pointed out that higher privileges in CI/CD pipelines make them an ideal target. Attackers who compromise a build runner can inject code at the source, sign releases with legitimate credentials, or push authentic-looking artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mitigations, Cipot recommended, would include short-lived, scoped tokens with regular secret rotations. Automated scanning for suspicious packages using tools like Socket.dev or Phylum might also help stay ahead of the threat. Other ways to verify package authenticity include checksum validation and emerging standards like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572893/sigstore-explained-how-it-helps-secure-the-software-supply-chain.html"&gt;Sigstore&lt;/a&gt;, he added. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, advises an immediate response for teams potentially affected. “Search source code, lockfiles, caches, and registries for @acitons and 8jfiesaf83 then quarantine any runners that fetched them,” he said. “Rotate all tokens and review artifacts and package publish history for the period from October 29 to November 6, 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088529/malicious-npm-package-sneaks-into-github-actions-builds.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-724) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK authorities propose law to set minimum cyber standards for critical sectors</title>
      <link>https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/uk-authorities-law-cyber-standards-critical-sectors/805416/</link>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgproxy.divecdn.com/JcjduVoJT7ohbP1so2xe1kHGmJB0gc3vd7k8V092mE4/g:ce/rs:fill:1600:900:1/Z3M6Ly9kaXZlc2l0ZS1zdG9yYWdlL2RpdmVpbWFnZS8zNDNBMTU0MC5qcGc=.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legislation follows a wave of social engineering attacks that rocked the nation&amp;rsquo;s retail and automotive supply chains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/uk-authorities-law-cyber-standards-critical-sectors/805416/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-726)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global experts advance the joint fight against crypto-enabled crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</link>
      <description>The criminal use of cryptocurrency is becoming increasingly professionalised, but so too is the global response. Participants at the 9th Global Conference on Criminal Finances and Cryptoassets emphasised three priorities: developing common standards, deepening cooperation and investing in capacity. These are essential if authorities and industry are to keep pace with evolving threats and recover illicit cryptoassets at scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and UEFA united for fair and safe football</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</link>
      <description>Today, 5 November 2025, Europol and UEFA have renewed and extended their Memorandum of Understanding, focused on preventing and combating crime while protecting the integrity of European football. The memorandum was signed at UEFA headquarters in Nyon by the Executive Director of Europol, Catherine De Bolle, and by the President of UEFA, Aleksander Čeferin. Europol and UEFA committed to cooperate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years on: remembering the victims of the 13 November terrorist attack in Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</link>
      <description>Today marks ten years since one of the deadliest terrorist attacks in recent European history was carried out in Paris - at the Stade de France, in the streets and inside the Bataclan concert hall. On 13 November 2015, 132 people lost their lives and many more were injured during what became a night of profound tragedy for France and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-619) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End of the game for cybercrime infrastructure: 1025 servers taken down</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November 2025, the latest phase of Operation Endgame was coordinated from Europol’s headquarters in The Hague. The actions targeted one of the biggest infostealers (Rhadamanthys), the Remote Access Trojan VenomRAT, and the botnet Elysium, all of which played a key role in international cybercrime. Authorities took down these three large cybercrime enablers. The main suspect for VenomRAT was also arrested in Greece on 3 November 2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-727)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-728)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-729)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-730)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-731)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google asks US court to shut down Lighthouse phishing-as-a-service operation</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088993/google-asks-us-court-to-shut-down-lighthouse-phishing-as-a-service-operation.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google is asking to a US court for help in dismantling the infrastructure behind the Lighthouse phishing-as-a-service operation, the latest effort by a technology company to use the legal system to put a dent in cybercrime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whether it will do more than that is an open question.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a blog Monday, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/legal-action-and-legislation-fight-scammers/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google’s general counsel Halimah DeLaine Prado said&lt;/a&gt; the court action is needed because the gang behind this scam exploits Google and other brands by illegally displaying their trademarks and services on fraudulent websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We found at least 107 website templates featuring Google’s branding on sign-in screens specifically designed to trick people into believing the sites are legitimate,” she wrote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors who buy access to the Lighthouse service send text messages to people, including employees of organizations, with branding appearing to come from a legitimate provider. They hope the branding is convincing enough to induce an unwary person to click a link and share information such as email credentials, banking information and more. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="many-court-orders-sought"&gt;Many court orders sought&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google’s action follows that of other technology companies, most notably Microsoft, as well as some countries, to dampen the efforts of threat actors through the courts. For example, &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/09/16/microsoft-seizes-338-websites-to-disrupt-rapidly-growing-raccoono365-phishing-service/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in September, Microsoft got a court order allowing it to seize 338 websites &lt;/a&gt;associated with the distribution of RacoonO365, a phishing kit used to steal Microsoft 365 credentials. Since July 2024, RaccoonO365’s kits have been used to steal at least 5,000 Microsoft credentials from people in 94 countries, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In January, Microsoft &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/01/10/taking-legal-action-to-protect-the-public-from-abusive-ai-generated-content/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;got a US court order allowing it to seize a website&lt;/a&gt; behind a foreign-based threat actor distributing tools for bypassing safety guardrails of generative AI services of several tech companies, including its own. The threat actor’s software exploited exposed customer credentials scraped from public websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And in August, &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-coordinated-disruption-actions-against-blacksuit-royal" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the US Justice Department announced coordinated actions&lt;/a&gt; against the BlackSuit (Royal) Ransomware group which included the takedown of four servers and nine domains, with the help of the FBI and international law enforcement agencies in the United Kingdom, Germany, Ireland, France, Canada, Ukraine, and Lithuania. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, threat actors can be resilient. For example, in 2020 Microsoft, Symantec, ESET, communications provider NTT, and Lumen Technologies combined with others to&lt;a href="https://www.security.com/threat-intelligence/trickbot-botnet-ransomware-disruption" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt; get a US court order&lt;/a&gt; directing web hosting providers to take down the IT infrastructure distributing the Trickbot botnet. But a&lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/cybersecurity-101/what-is-trickbot" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ccording to researchers at Huntress&lt;/a&gt;, TrickBot is still being used by threat actors for remote access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Google blog also said the company is urging the US Congress to adopt the Guarding Unprotected Aging Retirees from Deception (GUARD) Act, which would enable state and local law enforcement to utilize federal grant funding to investigate financial fraud and scams specifically targeting retirees; the Foreign Robocall Elimination Act, which would establish a taskforce focused on how to best block foreign-originated illegal robocalls before they ever reach American consumers; and the &lt;a href="https://www.cbo.gov/publication/61864" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Scam Compound Accountability and Mobilization&lt;/a&gt; (SCAM) Act, which would develop a national strategy to counter scam compounds, enhance sanctions, and support survivors of human trafficking within these compounds. Scam compounds are physical installations where significant transnational criminal organizations carry out cyber-enabled fraud operations, frequently using the forced labor of victims of human trafficking&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google refused a request for an interview to get more details about its announcement, explaining it had nothing more to say beyond DeLaine Prado’s blog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="will-have-minimal-impact"&gt;Will have ‘minimal impact’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/ed-dubrovsky/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ed Dubrovsky&lt;/a&gt;, chief operating officer of incident response firm Cypher, is skeptical of the effectiveness of court action. Phishing-as-a-service operations don’t have to be on American soil, he explained, so court orders and legislation will likely have minimal impact on smishing or phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However,” he added, “I can understand that even small steps can lead to broader impact, and that might be why Google is taking these steps.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But this and similar court actions won’t change threat actor behavior or the need for IT departments to have controls to face cyber risks, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellman/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kellman Meghu,&lt;/a&gt; principal security architect at Canadian incident response firm DeepCove Cybersecurity, believes Google and other tech firms around the world are looking to the courts and legislatures in part to stop scams, but also to protect themselves from being sued if they can shut down a criminal online service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The reality now is that there is very little to no risk to running scams,” he told CSO in an email, “since the chance of suffering any ramifications is barely a reality. [Running a malicious online operation] gives attackers the chance to just keep trying things until eventually something works. Driving real legislation and legal impacts that can span borders would be very valuable to reduce this threat, if in fact they can build legislation that is effective, and could go a long way in reducing the risk of constant attempts to compromise users.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But global efforts to fight cybercrime can only be effective if tech companies around the world work with governments to share information on cyber crime, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, he doubts many competitive technology suppliers would join an effort because they have a vested interest in saying that they are safer, better, faster than the competition, so they can sell more services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="any-reduction-in-scams-would-help-it-departments"&gt;‘Any reduction in scams would help IT departments’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich,&lt;/a&gt; dean of research at the SANS Institute, said Google has a huge problem with scammers paying for ads that direct victims to fraudulent websites and malware. “Any reduction in these scams would be a significant help to IT departments,” he said, “making it easier to defend networks against these scams.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposed US legislation doesn’t necessarily add any substantial new barriers for scammers, he added, but it would provide more funding for state and local law enforcement agencies that are often overwhelmed by complaints from victims of cybercrime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, he argued that robocalls could be fought more effectively by telecommunication providers, without new legislation, and they have taken some steps to do so.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue of scam compounds is likely not going to be significantly affected by any legislation, as they are too ephemeral and agile and would easily evade sanctions, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Among the issues mentioned, the paid-for Google ads advertising malicious resources is by far the most significant problem for security teams,” Ullrich said. “Google must step up its game in blocking them, and finding legal ways to eradicate the origin may be more effective than the current ‘whack the mole’ tactic, which is not working.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088993/google-asks-us-court-to-shut-down-lighthouse-phishing-as-a-service-operation.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What CISOs need to know about new tools for securing MCP servers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087656/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-new-tools-for-securing-mcp-servers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Model Context Protocol allows AI agents to connect to data sources but the first iteration of this standard &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4015222/mcp-uses-and-risks.html"&gt;lacked serious security&lt;/a&gt;. Over the past few months, a multitude of vendors appeared to help solve the problem. Is the technology now ready for prime-time, or is it still too early to put into production?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some progress has been made on the core protocol side. In March, support was added for OAuth authentication, and in June, the protocol added support for third-party authentication servers such as Auth0, Okta, or a company’s own identity management system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The MCP standards body also launched an official &lt;a href="https://modelcontextprotocol.info/tools/registry/"&gt;MCP registry&lt;/a&gt; in September, in order to address the problem of malicious MCP servers masquerading as legitimate ones.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But significant security gaps remain. For example, authentication is optional, and the systems are vulnerable to prompt injections, tool poisoning, token theft, cross-server attacks, message tampering and more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies looking to get ahead of the competition when it comes to building agentic AI systems have to do a lot of security heavy lifting to keep these tools from exposing all their corporate secrets and sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, over the past few months, vendors have been stepping up. Today, the major AI platforms have added security infrastructure, as have core technology providers, existing cybersecurity vendors, and a fleet of emerging players.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="challenges-of-different-uses-of-mcp-servers"&gt;Challenges of different uses of MCP servers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are three main types of MCP server deployments, and each one has their own security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When a company sets up an internal MCP server, on infrastructure they control, to access internal data or tools, to be used by AI agents that they also control. First, a low-risk use of this might be to allow employees to use AI agents to search through non-sensitive documents or databases, such as product descriptions. A higher-risk use case might be to allow access to customer data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second, a company might allow their AI agents to access external data sources or tools via MCP servers. Here, one concern might be that the information the AI agents get back might include malicious instructions because either the server or the data source is compromised by an attacker.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The third deployment type is that of an internal MCP server exposing a company’s data or tools to the outside world. Again, this could be a low-risk use case if the MCP server provides access to product descriptions or user manuals. But it could also be extremely risky if MCP servers that allow external partners to connect in and place orders, submit invoices, and change their payment addresses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are ways to ease into MCP deployments, says Anh Hatzopoulos, co-founder and CEO at PepperMill, a no-code AI platform. For example, an MCP server that goes and gets public LinkedIn information is going to be safer than one that handles financial transactions, she says. “With moving money, I’m surprised that people are going hard at it right now, given the security problems with MCPs. But someone has to do it — and someone will discover those security problems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, for many tech companies, especially SaaS vendors, MCP servers are already a must-have. “They can’t wait,” says Peter Nebel, chief strategy officer at cloud consultancy AllCloud. “If they wait, their competition will be there before them and have the MCP advantage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that have already released official MCP servers for public use include PayPal, Notion, HubSpot, CloudFlare, Atlassian, Slack, and GitHub. There are also third-party providers building MCP servers. Zapier, for example, currently offers MCP connections to 8,000 different apps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If a vendor doesn’t offer their own, official MCP server, someone else might set up unofficial ones that use the vendor’s APIs. For example, there are already MCP servers out there for LinkedIn, Spotify, eBay, YouTube, AWS, Zillow, and many other platforms, some more trustworthy than others. Developers and power users are downloading them and using them to give their AI agents access to those platforms, but it’s not always obvious where some of these less-than-official MCP servers are coming from, who’s maintaining them, and what else they do under the covers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pulse MCP &lt;a href="https://www.pulsemcp.com/servers"&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt; over 6,000 servers. MCP marketplace MCP.so currently &lt;a href="https://mcp.so/"&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt; more than 16,000. And a GitHub search for “MCP server” produces more than 45,000 results.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-look-for-in-an-mcp-security-platform"&gt;What to look for in an MCP security platform&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whether a company connects their own agents to third-party MCP servers, their own MCP servers to third-party agents, or their own servers to their own agents, there’s going to be the potential for data leakage, prompt injections and other security threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That means companies will need to check for authorizations and permissions, implement fine-grained access controls, and log everything, says AllCloud’s Nevel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are some other MCP security tools that vendors are offering today:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCP server detection&lt;/strong&gt;: It’s easy for company employees to download and run their own MCP servers. These servers could boost their productivity or they could be a new attack vector. Some MCP security vendors are offering scanning services to help companies find all instances of shadow MCP servers in their environments.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runtime protection&lt;/strong&gt;: AI agents communicate with MCP servers in plain English. That creates the potential for prompt injections, data leaks and other security issues. Many MCP security vendors offer tools to monitor all communications for these and similar problems.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication and access controls&lt;/strong&gt;: The core MCP protocol now supports OAuth, but that’s just the start. For additional security, vendors offer zero trust and least privilege control frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logging and observability&lt;/strong&gt;: Vendors can provide platforms to collect MCP logs, alert security teams about security events or policy violations, collect compliance data, or feed logs into existing security infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="vedors-offering-mcp-security-tools"&gt;Vedors offering MCP security tools&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Below, we divide in three sections the list of vendors offering MCP security tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="hyperscalers"&gt;Hyperscalers&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For companies all-in on a particular cloud platform, going with the MCP tools provided by that particular hyperscaler can be an easy way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AWS launched its own agentic AI platform in July. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore includes a gateway that supports multiple protocols, including MCP, an identity management system and observability. In October, AWS followed this up with a set of guidelines for securing MCP servers with &lt;a href="https://builder.aws.com/content/33oERPjcEutnPmaud1BvlPRP9zR/security-guidelines-for-model-context-protocol-in-aws"&gt;zero trust&lt;/a&gt; best practices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft announced a basic Azure MCP server in April, added support for the Azure Key Vault in May, announced MCP support in the Azure AI Foundry Agent Service in June, and announced Azure API Management support in August. Azure API Management means that MCP servers can have secure and governed access to resources, with observability and control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In October, Microsoft announced the Microsoft Agent Framework, which includes support for both MCP and the Agent2Agent protocol, protection against prompt injection, PII detection, and multi-agent observability to ensure that the systems are doing what they’re supposed to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud announced its MCP Toolbox for Databases in April with authentication and observability built in. In September, it released a reference architecture for securing MCP servers on the Google Cloud Platform, based around a centralized MCP proxy architecture. It uses the Google Identity Platform to validate identities and issue OAuth tokens, uses Model Armor to check messages for prompt injections, jailbreaks, or sensitive data, and a Secret Manager to store API keys, credentials, and sensitive configuration values. Its Artifact Registry can store MCP server images and scan them for vulnerabilities before they are deployed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google also recommends using network-level security controls to isolate MCP servers and reduce the risk of lateral movement. Finally, Google’s Security Command Center can identify unauthorized access and data exfiltration attempts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="major-technology-providers"&gt;Major technology providers&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare: Cloudflare announced &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/zero-trust-mcp-server-portals/"&gt;MCP Server Portals&lt;/a&gt;, which enable enterprises to centralize, secure, and observe every MCP connection. This feature is part of Cloudflare One, the company’s secure access service edge (SASE) platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks: The company launched the &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/blog/2025/06/securing-ai-agent-innovation-prisma-airs-mcp-server/"&gt;Prisma AIRS MCP Server&lt;/a&gt; in June. It sits between the AI agent and the MCP server and detects malicious content in data, helping protect against prompt injection attacks, as well as web and DNS attacks. Another tool, MCP Security in Cortex Cloud WAAS, sits at the network boundary, and inspects MCP communications for malicious activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne: &lt;a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/avoiding-mcp-mania-how-to-secure-the-next-frontier-of-ai/"&gt;SentinelOne Singularity Platform&lt;/a&gt; offers visibility into the MCP interaction chain, as well as alerts and automated incident response, for both local and remote MCP servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VMware: In August, parent company Broadcom &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4045708/vmware-explore-2025-broadcom-tackles-agentic-ai-security-challenges.html"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that VMware Cloud Foundation will offer more security for agentic workflows, including MCP servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="startups"&gt;Startups&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Acuvity: &lt;a href="https://acuvity.ai/"&gt;Acuvity&lt;/a&gt; secures MCP servers by hardening them with least-privilege execution, immutable runtimes, continuous vulnerability scanning, authentication, and threat detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Akto: API security company Akto launched an &lt;a href="https://www.akto.io/mcp-security"&gt;MCP security&lt;/a&gt; solution in June, claiming to be the first dedicated security solution specifically built to protect MCP servers. It includes a discovery tool for finding the MCP servers deployed in corporate environments, security testing tools, and monitoring and threat detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Invariant Labs: Their &lt;a href="https://github.com/invariantlabs-ai/mcp-scan"&gt;MCP-Scan&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source scanner that performs static analysis of MCP servers and does real-time monitoring to detect tool poisoning attacks, rug pulls, and prompt injection attacks. A commercial product, Invariant Guardrails, is a proxy that sits between AI agents and MCP servers and protects against project injections and other MCP security threats, and allows companies to impose rules such as prohibiting PII from going to external email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Javelin: The company’s &lt;a href="https://www.getjavelin.com/ai-security"&gt;AI Security Fabric platform&lt;/a&gt; includes MCP security, such as functionality to scan for risky servers, or to block or require review of agent tools or data requests. In addition, MCP guardrails stop unsafe calls and poisoned inputs in real-time and prevent prompt injections and data leakage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lasso Security: Open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/lasso-security/mcp-gateway"&gt;MCP gateway&lt;/a&gt; that allows configuration and lifecycle management of MCP servers and sanitizes sensitive information in MCP messages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.mcptotal.io/"&gt;MCPTotal&lt;/a&gt;: Offers a hub to manage, run and monitor MCP servers in a secure, sandboxed environment, as well as a gateway to protect AI workflows interacting with both internal and external MCP servers, and a governance tool to monitor and enforce AI tool use policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Noma: Recently launched &lt;a href="https://noma.security/solutions/ai-agent-security/"&gt;AI Agent Security&lt;/a&gt; solution offers support for discovery of MCP connections, vulnerability scanning, access policy enforcement, real-time prompt guardrails, and audit trails.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obot: The &lt;a href="https://obot.ai/"&gt;Obot MCP gateway&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source platform to manage MCP servers, define security access policies, and track usage and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operant: Operant &lt;a href="https://www.operant.ai/solutions/mcp-gateway"&gt;MCP Gateway&lt;/a&gt; automatically catalogs MCP tools, discovers AI agents, and tracks traffic between agents and servers to eliminate MCP blind spots. It can also identify threat vectors such as tool poisoning, jailbreaks and unauthorized access, prevent data leaks, and establish a centralized governance framework for agents and tools across the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Solo: The company’s &lt;a href="https://www.solo.io/products/agentgateway-enterprise"&gt;Agent Gateway&lt;/a&gt; was overhauled in August to support MCP and A2A protocols and protects against malicious prompts and data leaks, enforces strong authentication, and centralizes logging and tracing for every interaction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Teleport: Its &lt;a href="https://goteleport.com/use-cases/secure-model-context-protocol/"&gt;Secure MCP&lt;/a&gt; tool for its Infrastructure Identity Platform allows companies to unify how they govern human, machine, workload, device, and AI identities. MCP Security provides identity, access control, governance, and audit tools in a zero trust and least privilege environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087656/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-new-tools-for-securing-mcp-servers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Chargeback: 4.3 million cardholders affected, EUR 300 million in damages</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</link>
      <description>On 4 November 2025, an international coordinated action day targeted three major fraud and money laundering networks as part of Operation “Chargeback.” Led by the Cybercrime Department (Landeszentralstelle Cybercrime) of the General Prosecutor's Office (Generalstaatsanwaltschaft) in Koblenz, Germany, and the German Federal Criminal Police Office (Bundeskriminalamt), the operation has been investigating these networks since December 2020. More than 60 house searches were conducted and a total of 18 arrest warrants executed. The criminal networks are suspected of misusing credit card data from over 4.3 million cardholders across 193 countries. In total, the estimated damage from the fraud scheme exceeds EUR 300 million, with attempted damages amounting to over EUR 750 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>54 individuals arrested in action against labour exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</link>
      <description>Over the last weeks, law enforcement, border guards and labour and tax authorities across Europe joined forces to identify and tackle labour exploitation. This recent edition of the EMPACT Joint Action Days targeted trafficking in human beings for labour exploitation purposes, with a special emphasis on the agricultural sector, gastronomy, and temporary work agencies. In particular, the involved authorities also took measures against the exploitation of non-EU nationals and refugees. Led by France and the Netherlands, and carried out by authorities from 32 countries with support from Europol and the European Labour Authority (ELA), the action days resulted in the arrest of 54 individuals and identification of 404 potential victims of human trafficking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rogue MCP servers can take over Cursor’s built-in browser</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089046/rogue-mcp-servers-can-take-over-cursors-built-in-browser.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI agents and coding copilots are shaking up how — and what — developers code. But they’re also rapidly expanding the attack surface of developer machines&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest example: Security researchers have shown how a rogue Model Context Protocol (MCP) server can inject malicious code into the built-in browser feature of Cursor, a popular AI-powered code editor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We demonstrate how a single malicious MCP server can replace login pages inside Cursor’s internal browser with an attacker-controlled page that harvests credentials and sends them to a remote attacker,” researchers from AI cybersecurity firm Knostic.ai wrote in &lt;a href="https://www.knostic.ai/blog/mcp-hijacked-cursor-browser"&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; shared with CSO. “We also show how that same capability allows an attacker to fully compromise the victim’s workstation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Originally developed by Anthropic to facilitate communication between large language models (LLMs) and external data sources or applications to improve workflow context, MCP has become a key component for developing AI agents that automate tasks by leveraging external tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The protocol uses a client-server architecture, in which applications expose functionality to LLMs through an MCP server and AI agents or applications connect to those services through an MCP client. Integrated development environments (IDEs) such as Microsoft’s Visual Studio Code — and those based on it, like Cursor and Windsurf — natively support integration with MCP servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To enhance security, most IDE vendors maintain repositories with vetted MCP servers, but IDE users can also deploy custom servers manually. Such servers can be found all over the internet, including GitHub. Earlier this year, researchers found hundreds of MCP servers in public GitHub repositories that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4012712/misconfigured-mcp-servers-expose-ai-agent-systems-to-compromise.html"&gt;had dangerous misconfigurations&lt;/a&gt;, including default exposure to untrusted networks and OS command injection paths.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attacking-cursor-and-other-vs-code-based-ides"&gt;Attacking Cursor and other VS Code-based IDEs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cursor is essentially a fork of VS Code with code added to turn it into an AI-assisted coding tool, whereas VS Code gets its AI capabilities through extensions. Knostic researcher Dor Munis, who developed the MCP attack against Cursor, told CSO that unlike VS Code, which performs integrity checks of its own files, Cursor does not. As a result, any modification of its own code will not present the user with a warning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VS Code, and by extension Cursor and other VS Code forks, is built on Electron, a framework used to develop cross-platform applications with Node.js and the Blink browser engine from Chrome. Because of this, these applications employ a JavaScript interpreter. As IDEs, they also have file system access and elevated permissions to perform tasks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Knostic researchers recently published &lt;a href="https://www.knostic.ai/blog/demonstrating-code-injection-vscode-cursor"&gt;a proof-of-concept attack against Cursor implemented through a malicious extension&lt;/a&gt; that injected malicious JavaScript into the running IDE to execute actions and manipulate its user interface. Malicious extensions have also been found &lt;a href="http://csoonline.com/article/4072829/tigerjacks-malicious-vscode-extensions-mine-steal-and-stay-hidden.html"&gt;in the VSCode Marketplace and the OpenVSX registry&lt;/a&gt;, which Cursor also uses, including &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076718/self-propagating-worm-found-in-marketplaces-for-visual-studio-code-extensions-2.html"&gt;a self-propagating worm that harvests credentials&lt;/a&gt; from developer machines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Knostic’s newly unveiled attack is similar in concept, but delivered via a malicious MCP server, it expands the attack surface beyond extensions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“An MCP server should be treated exactly like VS Code extensions in terms of security,” Munis said. That’s because MCP servers are essentially downloaded to run on your computer, and inherit the permissions of the IDE you use, he explained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In his proof-of-concept attack, Munis shows that an MCP server can inject JavaScript code into &lt;a href="https://cursor.com/docs/agent/browser"&gt;the built-in browser&lt;/a&gt; that Cursor recently added to allow developers to visually test changes to their application code and to allow Cursor’s AI agent to automatically perform tasks that require browsing. Using this technique, Munis replaced the browser’s actively displayed page with a log-in prompt, like in a phishing scenario, but without the URL ever changing — in other words, injected code’s changes happen on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, the impact of such an attack would depend on what the victim is doing in the browser. Developers might be displaying sensitive data from the web app they’re working on, or they might be logged into a service. It’s worth noting that the internal browser saves authentication cookies for the session and those could also be targeted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack was developed to prove successful JavaScript code injection via an MCP server, but just like with the extension attack, it could be expanded to perform other malicious actions inside the Cursor IDE itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="defenses"&gt;Defenses&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations must review and control, both through policy and access controls, the IDE extensions and MCP servers their developers use. They should do this just like they should be vetting application dependencies from package registries such as npm or PyPI to prevent the compromise of developer machines or inheriting vulnerabilities in their code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers are increasingly using VS Code extensions as an attack vector to target developers and it’s only a matter of time before they’ll start abusing MCP servers more widely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Try to find the project’s GitHub repo and review the code,” the Knostic team advised. “This is a program you install on your computer that can do anything. If there’s doubt about its credibility, DO NOT USE IT.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Using auto-run modes, in which agents are allowed to perform tasks automatically inside the IDE without a human approving the steps, also known as YOLO mode, should also be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Never blindly enable anything, especially MCP functionality,” the team warned. “Don’t assume that everything your AI agent generated is as you expected. Read through the code before you perform actions in the embedded browser.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cursor.com/docs/context/mcp#security-considerations"&gt;In its MCP documentation&lt;/a&gt;, Cursor itself warns developers to:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify an MCP server’s source and only install from trusted developers and repositories&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Check what data and APIs the server is supposed to access&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Use API keys with restricted permissions&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Audit the server’s code for critical integrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089046/rogue-mcp-servers-can-take-over-cursors-built-in-browser.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK cybersecurity bill brings tougher rules for critical infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088549/uk-cybersecurity-bill-brings-tougher-rules-for-critical-infrastructure.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The UK government has introduced a new legislation to harden national cyber defenses across critical infrastructure, imposing turnover-based penalties and granting ministers emergency powers to intervene during major cyber incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Cyber Security and Resilience Bill, unveiled Tuesday, would require organizations in healthcare, energy, water, transport, and digital services to meet mandatory security standards and report significant cyber incidents within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that fail to comply could face daily fines of up to $132,000 (£100,000) or penalties tied to annual turnover, the Department for Science, Innovation and Technology (DSIT) &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tough-new-laws-to-strengthen-the-uks-defences-against-cyber-attacks-on-nhs-transport-and-energy" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill, expected to receive Royal Assent in 2026, updates the UK’s Network and Information Systems Regulations (NIS) 2018, expanding coverage to include managed service providers (MSPs), data centers, and key suppliers for the first time. It supports the government’s &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/missions" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Plan for Change&lt;/a&gt; strategy aimed at strengthening national resilience while driving economic growth, the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="turnover-linked-penalties-and-a-behavioural-shift"&gt;Turnover-linked penalties and a behavioural shift&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill marks a turning point in how the UK enforces cybersecurity compliance. “The penalties change behaviour in a way flat fines never could,” said Sanchit Vir Gogia, chief analyst and CEO at Greyhound Research. “For large operators, every breach now carries a cost proportionate to their market reach. That link between impact and liability forces investment before the incident, not after it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The legislation introduced significantly tougher enforcement powers than those found in the EU’s NIS2 Directive or GDPR, said Madelein van der Hout, senior analyst at Forrester. “The bill sets a precedent for stricter cybersecurity enforcement by combining turnover-based penalties with emergency government powers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposal followed a series of damaging cyber incidents that exposed vulnerabilities in UK infrastructure. In 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2099498/suspected-chinese-hack-of-britains-ministry-of-defence-payroll-linked-to-government-contractor-minister-confirms.html"&gt;hackers compromised&lt;/a&gt; a Ministry of Defence payroll system via a contractor, exposing data of 270,000 armed services members. The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2138778/london-hospitals-face-days-of-disruption-after-ransomware-attack-on-supply-chain-partner.html"&gt;Synnovis ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt; on an NHS pathology provider disrupted more than 11,000 medical appointments, costing roughly $43 million (£32.7 million). The British Library breach in late 2023 caused losses of up to $9 million (£7 million), and recent attacks on Marks &amp;amp; Spencer and Jaguar Land Rover have renewed pressure on policymakers to act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An independent &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/independent-research-on-the-economic-impact-of-cyber-attacks-on-the-uk"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; cited by DSIT estimated that cyberattacks cost the UK economy about $19.4 billion (£14.7 billion) each year or about 0.5% of the GDP.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="msps-and-data-centers-under-scrutiny"&gt;MSPs and data centers under scrutiny&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, medium and large managed service providers (MSPs) would fall within the scope of cybersecurity regulation. They must report significant incidents promptly to both government and customers, maintain detailed response plans, and demonstrate readiness to handle cascading impacts, the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hout said the new framework will “reshape the MSP sector,” creating stronger detection and faster response cycles. “For enterprise clients, it promises earlier alerts and greater assurance that their providers adhere to minimum security standards.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill’s 24-hour reporting mandate will pressure MSPs and digital service providers to upgrade operations. “Many organisations will find their processes too slow and fragmented to meet that clock,” Gogia warned. Shivraj Borade, senior analyst at Everest Group, added that the rule will prompt MSPs to “invest in SOC maturity, rapid triage, and legal alignment,” which will fundamentally alter pricing and client relationships.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The legislation also shifted accountability between enterprises and their service partners. “For the first time, we place more responsibility with the MSSP where it normally lies with the enterprise,” said Hout. “It raises expectations for both parties: MSSPs will carry greater legal accountability, and enterprises must perform tighter due diligence.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the bill, data centers will also come under direct regulatory oversight for the first time, joining a broader group of operators responsible for managing power flow to smart devices and electric vehicle chargers. Organizations in scope must notify regulators and the National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) within 24 hours of a significant cyber incident and submit a full report within 72 hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="emergency-powers-and-expanded-oversight"&gt;Emergency powers and expanded oversight&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Under the bill, the technology secretary would gain authority to direct regulators and organizations, including NHS trusts and utilities, to take “specific, proportionate steps” to prevent or mitigate cyberattacks where national security is threatened. These interventions could include enhanced monitoring or temporary network isolation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The emergency powers recognize that cyber incidents evolve faster than committees can respond,” Gogia said. “Allowing the government to instruct critical sectors during live threats makes the system capable of acting in minutes, not weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regulators would also be empowered to designate critical suppliers, such as diagnostics providers or chemical manufacturers, to ensure they meet baseline cybersecurity standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088549/uk-cybersecurity-bill-brings-tougher-rules-for-critical-infrastructure.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-732)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-732</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-732</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-733)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-733</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-733</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-734)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-734</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-734</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-735)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-735</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-735</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–736)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-736</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-736</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-677) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 20:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI opens door to new ID challenges: Report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089682/agentic-ai-opens-door-to-new-id-challenges-report.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;New research released Thursday by Rubrik Zero Labs finds that the AI wave, and in particular agentic AI, has created a “troubling gap between the expanding identity attack surface and organizations’ ability to recover from resulting compromises.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the report, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://zerolabs.rubrik.com/reports/the-identity-crisis" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Identity Crisis: Understanding &amp;amp; Building Resilience Against Identity-Driven Threats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the result is a surge of both non-human identities (NHIs) and agentic identities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Key findings revealed:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;89% of organizations have “fully or partially incorporated AI agents into their identity infrastructure, and an additional 10% have plans to.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Of those polled, 58% estimate that, in the next 12 months, half or more of the cyberattacks they must deal with will be “driven by agentic AI.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Industry &lt;a href="https://www.cyberark.com/press/machine-identities-outnumber-humans-by-more-than-80-to-1-new-report-exposes-the-exponential-threats-of-fragmented-identity-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; contend that NHIs now outnumber human users by 82-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, a &lt;a href="https://www.rubrik.com/company/newsroom/press-releases/25/new-rubrik-research-finds-identity-resilience-is-imperative-as-ai-wave-floods-the-workplace-with-ai-agents" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;release&lt;/a&gt; from Rubrik states, as organizations integrate agents into their workflows, the increase in NHIs will continue to outpace the growth of human identities,  and securing them “will become as essential — if not more so — as securing human identities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, authors of the report state, “as traditional network boundaries have dissolved amid cloud migrations, remote work adoption, and now agentic AI, identity is no longer merely a control layer. It has become the primary attack surface, which threat actors weaponize to gain access to IT environments and ‘live off of the land’ over the course of an attack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The overwhelming majority of today’s breaches, they write, are predicated on exploiting trust and valid credentials rather than circumventing network defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;‘Under-the-radar crisis exists&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kmariappan" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kavitha Mariappan&lt;/a&gt;, chief transformation officer at Rubrik, said, “the rise of identity-driven attacks is changing the face of cyber defense. Managing identities in the era of AI has become a complex endeavor, especially with the labyrinth of NHIs. We have an under-the-radar crisis on our hands where a single compromised credential can grant full access to an organization’s most sensitive data.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She added, “comprehensive Identity Resilience is absolutely critical to cyber recovery in this new landscape.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The research was prompted, she said in an email to &lt;em&gt;CSOonline,&lt;/em&gt; because “the cyber defense landscape has fundamentally changed, creating a significant gap between the expanding identity attack surface and an organization’s ability to recover [from an attack]. As traditional network boundaries have dissolved due to cloud migration, remote work, and the accelerating adoption of agentic AI, identity has become a primary vulnerability.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors “are overwhelmingly exploiting trusted and valid credentials to &lt;em&gt;log&lt;/em&gt; in, not break in,” Mariappan explained. “These attacks are further complicated by the labyrinth of non-human identities, like API keys and AI agents, which are surging across the enterprise and are proving difficult to manage. Unlike with human identities, these NHIs can be difficult to revoke and often slip through the cracks, leading to poor lifecycle governance.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ca.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian security awareness training provider firm Beauceron Security, said he agrees with the report’s findings for a key reason: “[While] phishing and social engineering overall are where attacks start, identity and access management (IAM) practices are where the fire gets roaring.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations, he said, “need modern approaches to IAM and employee cyber education and engagement. The employee education doesn’t just help them spot and stop threats, you can help them understand why good IAM processing technology is required.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He pointed out, “[there is] a reason why &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/648894/identity-based-security-threats-are-growing-rapidly-report.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank"&gt;identity and access management&lt;/a&gt; is the foundation of a security program. When it’s done poorly, the impacts reverberate throughout an organization during an attack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley said that he often tells clients, “IAM is the bottom of the cyber equivalent of &lt;a href="https://www.simplypsychology.org/maslow.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Maslow’s hierarchy of needs&lt;/a&gt;. Where humans need food and shelter to survive, digital systems need strong IAM practices to survive.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In our work around the world, we’ve seen that as organizations get larger and more complex, it’s far more likely they have huge issues in identity management,” he said. “This isn’t the kind of problem that technology alone can fix, regardless of the vendor. It takes understanding people, process, culture, and technology.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="agentic-ai-like-a-stick-of-dynamite-thrown-into-a-fishpond"&gt;Agentic AI ‘like a stick of dynamite thrown into a fishpond’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, said Shipley, “it doesn’t matter what AI-powered IAM tool you have if you allow people to bypass processes to grant, remove, or change access because the process for approvals is [seen] as too slow or cumbersome.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The least favourite thing to find when you’re investigating a cyber incident, he said, “is no way to trace who did what because there’s nothing in the logs. The second worst is to find a bunch of identities that no one knows how they got there or how they had the access they did.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley described agentic AI as “basically a stick of dynamite thrown into a fishpond when it comes to identity, and the results look the same. If organizations can’t tell if a human or their agent performed a set of actions, they can’t properly understand if they have a software vulnerability, an issue with employee awareness or motivation on security, or even worse, an insider threat.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Worse yet, he said, “the whole concept of zero trust just got wiped out. Agents rely on huge amounts of trust and frankly, they haven’t earned it and have done everything they can possibly do to show they shouldn’t be trusted. From hallucinations to hijacking, this technology is not ready for prime time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/thomas-randall" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Thomas Randall&lt;/a&gt;, research lead at Info-Tech Research Group, added that most of the Rubrik Zero Labs report “validates what the industry already knows. For years, Info-Tech research has shown that identity is a prime attack surface, that zero trust/least privilege/continuous verification are best practices, and that security training is imperative.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attack-surface-to-drastically-increase"&gt;Attack surface to drastically increase&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He said that two elements stood out to him: “First is bridging human and non-human identity under a single umbrella; typically, we might understand these under separate domains of IAM vs DevOps secrets management, respectively. The report’s point is that attackers don’t respect those org-chart boundaries, so security teams should think beyond those boundaries, too.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, said Randall, “this framing overlooks that these identities are operationally different. While both authenticate and authorize, the tooling, telemetry, RACI, and risk models differ. A single ‘identity plane’ may be the goal conceptually, but practically, it’s hard to implement across those divergent ecosystems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second element is, he said, “the stark claim that non-human identities now outnumber human users by around 82:1. As organizations start developing more AI agents (especially if individuals have free rein to develop their own copilots or GPTs), the attack surface drastically increases.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Randall noted, “each copilot or GPT can hold API keys, OAuth tokens, or delegated permissions (for example, ‘read SharePoint docs, query CRM data, send emails.’). This is certainly where I think organizations need to be concerned: the gap between agentic AI rollout and AI governance grows increasingly wider.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations, he said, “have to be disciplined in controlling agent creation, credentialing, and lifecycle management; otherwise, the attack surface potentially increases drastically.” Security leaders must understand that IAM tools alone won’t protect against or help them restore the integrity of their identity infrastructure in the event of a compromise, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, said Mariappan, they must also understand that IAM tools alone won’t protect against or help them restore the integrity of their identity infrastructure in the event of a compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, she said, “while 87% of IT and security leaders plan to change their IAM providers, 60% have already switched providers in the last three years, signaling the industry’s dissatisfaction with current solutions for tackling identity-based threats. Our research reveals that a comprehensive identity resilience strategy is needed for when, not if, an attack strikes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089682/agentic-ai-opens-door-to-new-id-challenges-report.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Press Release: CIO100 and CSO30 ASEAN Awards Gala 2025 Celebrate Regional Excellence in Technology Leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089848/press-release-cio100-and-cso30-asean-awards-2025-celebrate-regional-excellence-in-technology-leadership.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 14, 2025: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a&gt;The CIO100 and CSO30 ASEAN and Hong Kong Awards Gala on November 12, 2025, delivered a powerful validation of the region’s technology leadership maturity. CIO ASEAN and CSO ASEAN had the privilege of hosting an evening that brought together the most elite CIO100 and CSO30 award winners, and technology teams from Singapore, Malaysia, Indonesia, Vietnam, Cambodia, Thailand, Hong Kong, and the Philippines&lt;/a&gt;. They demonstrate that this region is firmly established as a strategic technology hub driving global digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rigor in Judging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The awards maintained editorial independence through a select panel of CIO and CSOonline.com executive editors who evaluated all nominations against a single consistent measure: clear, measurable business impact. The best submissions demonstrated business value realization, not just technology deployment&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSO30 Awards: Recognizing Excellence Across Three Dimensions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The CSO30 Leadership &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; Business Value Awards&lt;/strong&gt; demonstrated remarkable breadth across the region’s cybersecurity landscape and a diverse cohort spanning financial services, healthcare, energy, telecommunications, and insurance sectors. These individuals exemplified two critical competencies: first, embedding security as a strategic business enabler, and second, fostering collaborative ownership of cyber resilience across technical and business leadership. Their recognition underscores the regional shift toward security as a business transformation lever, a maturation that distinguishes leading organizations from their peers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winners for the CSO30 Leadership Individual Awards&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a&gt;&lt;em&gt;(in alphabetical order)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-table"&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-table-wrapper"&gt;&lt;table class="has-fixed-layout"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adj. Prof. Jason Lau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Crypto.com&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Athikom Kanchanavibhu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mitr Phol Group&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chatchawat Asawarakwong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kasikorn Business – Technology Group&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Chan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mastercard International Inc.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frankie Shuai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;DWS Group (subsidiary of Deutsche Bank)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irfan Amer bin Mohd Ismail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;AEON Bank (M) Berhad&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Saw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Siemens Energy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mohammad Raihan Mohamed Sultan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Banking Computer Services Pte Ltd, subsidiary of NETS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primitivo “Jojo” Nufable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;St. Luke’s Medical Center&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephanie Liew&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;BAT&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Willis Yung&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;PAOBank&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yohannes Glen Dwipajana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Indosat Ooredoo Hutchison&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winners for the CSO30 Business Value Individual Awards&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(in alphabetical order)&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-table"&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-table-wrapper"&gt;&lt;table class="has-fixed-layout"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adj. Prof. Jason Lau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Crypto.com&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allan Wong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hong Kong Baptist University&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danny Chan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mastercard International Inc.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Lam Wai Leong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kuwait Finance House&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Esther Soh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cyber Security Agency of Singapore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hafizzudin Mohd Sabi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;KPS Berhad&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joseph Ong Sheng Cai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Trip.Biz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leonard Ong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Synapxe&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Saw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Siemens Energy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mohammad Raihan Mohamed Sultan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Banking Computer Services Pte Ltd, subsidiary of NETS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primitivo “Jojo” Nufable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;St. Luke’s Medical Center&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sasanka De Silva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Transnational Company Pte Ltd&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shishir Kumar Singh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Advance Intelligence Group&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suresh Sankaran Srinivasan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Axiata Group Berhad&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terrence Chock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Zurich Insurance&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victor Yeo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dentons Rodyk &amp;amp; Davidson LLP&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xerxes Philip Kiok Kan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Anglo-Eastern Ship Management Ltd.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yaroth Chhay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;ACLEDA Bank Plc., Cambodia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yohannes Glen Dwipajana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Indosat Ooredoo Hutchison&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The CSO Public-Private Partnership Team Award&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Celebrates initiatives that transcend organizational boundaries, leveraging cross-sector partnerships to strengthen collective cyber defense posture and establish national-level cybersecurity improvements that benefit the broader ecosystem&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner:           ACLEDA Bank Plc., Cambodia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ACLEDA Bank Plc., Cambodia is recognized for advancing the national cybersecurity agenda through effective collaboration between public and private sectors. This signals the critical importance of coordinated security frameworks and multi-stakeholder commitment to regional resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The event was made possible by the following partners:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Headline sponsor:       AWS&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Welcome reception partner:   Workday&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Category sponsors:    Anunta Tech., Claroty, NetApp and SAS&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Table hosts:     Red Hat and Veeam&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CSO30 Awards celebrate achievement, and more significantly, the region’s capacity to generate, recognize, and disseminate excellence. This shapes expectations, signals capability, and influences how boards, investors, and peers calibrate technology and cybersecurity investment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations once again to all 2025 winners, finalists and nominees. Your achievements have set the bar for the year ahead!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSO ASEAN Contact:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Estelle Quek&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Editorial Director, CIO ASEAN &amp;amp; CSO ASEAN &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="ASEAN" class="wp-image-4089815" height="683" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Group-Pic-Awards-Gala-.jpeg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;About the CIO100 and CSO30 ASEAN Awards&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The CIO100 Awards recognize technology leaders driving business transformation across the ASEAN and Hong Kong region. Now in its fifth year, the program maintains editorial independence through rigorous judging panels focused on measurable business impact. The CSO30 Awards recognize exceptional cybersecurity leadership across individual and team-based categories. Together, these Awards represent the most comprehensive recognition of technology and security excellence in the region.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089848/press-release-cio100-and-cso30-asean-awards-2025-celebrate-regional-excellence-in-technology-leadership.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 06:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The books shaping today’s cybersecurity leaders</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4027000/the-books-shaping-todays-cybersecurity-leaders.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From strategy and psychology to history and decision-making, these are the books CISOs recommend to sharpen your thinking, influence your leadership style, and help navigate the complexity of modern security careers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="exploring-risk-from-different-angles"&gt;Exploring risk from different angles&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs, not surprisingly, are interested in risk as it relates to cybersecurity, with some keen to understand future risk measurement and how to make better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/superintelligence-9780199678112?cc=au&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;"&gt;Superintelligence&lt;/a&gt; by Nick Bostrom and &lt;a href="https://www.thegrayrhino.com/"&gt;The Gray Rhino&lt;/a&gt; by Michele Wucker were put forward by Cribl CISO Mike Lyons. “Superintelligence is a very interesting look at the risks and rewards of AI and how to secure it. It can invoke an existential crisis as AI continues to play a larger role in our daily lives,” says Lyons.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Gray Rhino invites readers to rethink their priorities. “It highlights how ‘highly probable, high impact, yet neglected threats plague us every day and it takes grit and resolve to reduce their impact by making change happen,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/the-ai-mirror-9780197759066?cc=au&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;"&gt;The AI Mirror&lt;/a&gt; by Shannon Vallor was recommended by Grammarly CISO &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gidouglas"&gt;Giles Douglas&lt;/a&gt; “although probably not for the reason you might expect”. The central thesis is that generative AI is trained on backwards-looking data and Vallor is deeply skeptical of artificial general intelligence. “However, what struck me most is how this analysis applies to how generative AI is being embedded into security products,” Douglas says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI integration has allowed us to find anomalous patterns and analyze data at scale, but the book’s focus on the flaws of this approach highlights the ethical implications of doing so. It demonstrates that these systems still need judgment — a human in the loop — and can struggle to find truly novel exploits of systems that fall outside of their training data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The book considers the implications of feeding massive amounts of security data into such systems can also have a side effect of building surveillance technology where there is pervasive monitoring, blurring the lines between robust monitoring and invasive practices. “My key takeaway: We still need humans to oversee security systems. The most effective programs will be those that thoughtfully integrate AI capabilities while maintaining strong human oversight and ethical guardrails.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hubbardresearch.com/shop/how-to-measure-anything-in-cybersecurity-risk-2e-signed-by-doug-hubbard/"&gt;How to Measure Anything in Cybersecurity Risk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;by Douglas W. Hubbard and Richard Seiersen, was recommended by several CISOs including Daniel Schatz, Qiagen’s CISO, and Wolfgang Goerlich, faculty IANS and Oakland County’s CISO. James Blake, Cohesity’s CISO, said it’s a useful resource that provides spreadsheets and methods for semi-quantitative risk assessment. Similar to FAIR (factor analysis of information risk), this book provides tools and approaches for more accurate risk measurement beyond the traditional risk matrix. “I’d recommend this book to anyone working in cyber risk because it offers meaningful ways to analyze and communicate risk to business leaders,” Blake says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/227815/superforecasting-by-philip-e-tetlock-and-dan-gardner/"&gt;Superforecasting: The Art and Science of Prediction&lt;/a&gt; by Philip E. Tetlock and Dan Gardner, was also recommended by Schatz. The book takes a closer look at what makes or breaks good forecasts in a well-written and entertaining manner. “I think this is a useful book for anyone trying to wrap their head around what the future might bring and consequently it should be of particular interest to risk managers,” tells Schatz. “Along with the fundamentals of good forecasts and many examples, the authors provide good guidance on how to get to better estimates based on some basic steps.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="improving-focus-and-decision-making-in-complex-environments"&gt;Improving focus and decision making in complex environments&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a role defined by continual alerts and competing priorities, CISOs need to rely on their decision-making skills and an ability to find focus. These books explore how to reduce digital noise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Daniel Schatz suggested &lt;a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780374533557/thinkingfastandslow/"&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Kahneman that explores the dual systems of the brain — fast, intuitive thinking, and slow, rational thinking — how the human mind can be tripped up by error and prejudice, and strategies for making better decisions. Schatz recommended the book for the insights into how humans make decisions and when they’re most vulnerable to mistakes. “This understanding is essential for effectively managing human risk and selecting security strategies that account for real-world behavior,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On a related topic and co-written by Daniel Kahneman, &lt;a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/daniel-kahneman/noise/9780316451406/"&gt;Noise&lt;/a&gt; explores why humans are so susceptible to noise in judgment — and what we can do about it. It was recommended by Wolfgang Goerlich. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Elliott Franklin, CISO at Fortitude Re, recommended &lt;a href="https://www.marcawolfe.com/yeah-but-book/"&gt;Yeah, But: Cut Through The Noise To Live, Learn, And Lead Better&lt;/a&gt; by Marc Wolfe because it provides readers with strategies to find clear headspace for thinking and making better decisions — something that’s important for busy CISOs. “Wolfe speaks directly to the internal dialogue that often holds leaders back — those rationalizations that delay change or innovation. It encourages cutting through noise, both external and internal, to lead with clarity and confidence,” Franklin says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gretchen Rubin’s &lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/225164/better-than-before-by-gretchen-rubin/"&gt;Better Than Before&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and Cal Newport’s &lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/575667/digital-minimalism-by-cal-newport/"&gt;Digital Minimalism&lt;/a&gt; offer tools to protect what matters most — your time, focus, and well-being, says Franklin. “Security leaders often operate in “always on” mode, but Cal Newport’s push toward intentional tech use is a vital reminder: your attention is a resource, and boundaries are not a luxury, they’re a necessity. Meanwhile, Rubin’s habit framework helps leaders design systems to support their goals, whether that’s better sleep, less email, or more presence at home. Together, these books form a toolkit for leading better — not just at work, but in life,” adds Franklin.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Human+Hacked:+My+Life+and+Lessons+as+the+World's+First+Augmented+Ethical+Hacker-p-9781394269167"&gt;Human Hacked: My Life and Lessons as the World’s First Augmented Ethical Hacker&lt;/a&gt; by Len Noe was recommended by George Gerchow, faculty at IANS Research and Bedrock Security’s CSO. The book goes beyond the hype to explore the complexity of augmented decision-making and the unintended consequences we’re already seeing. “Len pulls back the curtain on how humans, not just machines, are being reshaped by AI. His point of view is grounded, provocative, and seriously worth reading. Full disclosure: Len is a good friend. People like him are rare and, honestly, a little scary. I’m just glad he’s on our side,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="understanding-human-risk-in-cybersecurity"&gt;Understanding human risk in cybersecurity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When it comes to security, CISOs know better than most that managing risks and vulnerabilities lies in human behaviour as much as technical tools. These books provide expert insights into the human side of cybersecurity, such as social engineering.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/The-Cuckoos-Egg/Cliff-Stoll/9781668048160"&gt;The Cuckoo’s Egg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;by Cliff Stoll was recommended by International Seaways CIO/CISO Amit Basu as one of the most important early narratives of cyber intrusion and defense.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cliff Stoll’s meticulous pursuit of a 75-cent accounting anomaly exposed an international espionage ring long before cybersecurity became a defined discipline,” says Basu. “His story demonstrates enduring principles of our field: pay attention to small signals, follow the evidence with rigor, and build partnerships across technical teams, telecom providers, and law enforcement.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At a time when automated detection and AI-driven analytics dominate, the book is a reminder that patient investigation, detailed logging, and curiosity often provide the first clues to a major breach. For cybersecurity professionals, it also highlights the human side of defense. “Stoll faced skepticism, shifting priorities, and bureaucratic delays, challenges still familiar to CISOs and security teams,” he says. “His persistence and ability to translate technical findings into action across institutions underscore the leadership and communication skills that remain essential. I recommend this book because it combines the excitement of a real-life thriller with lessons on vigilance, collaboration, and creative problem solving that continue to guide effective cyber defense.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiley.com/en-us/The+Art+of+Deception:+Controlling+the+Human+Element+of+Security-p-9780764542800"&gt;The Art of Deception&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/646741/infamous-hacker-kevin-mitnick-dead-at-59.html" target="_blank"&gt;Kevin Mitnick&lt;/a&gt;, was recommended by Gaurav Kapil, CISO at Bread Financial, because its core message remains relevant today. “One of the original and most well-known hackers, Kevin Mitnick shares fascinating real-world examples of social engineering and the human side of cybersecurity vulnerabilities. While it’s an older book, it remains a foundational read for anyone interested in understanding how attackers exploit trust to breach systems,” Kapil says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Secrets+and+Lies:+Digital+Security+in+a+Networked+World-p-9780471453802"&gt;Secrets and Lies: Digital Security in a Networked World&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier is also recommended by Kapil because it breaks down technical concepts in an accessible way. “A highly respected voice in cybersecurity, Bruce Schneier offers timeless insights into the complexities of digital security. It also explores why focusing solely on technology isn’t enough and requires addressing human behavior, in addition to reevaluating organizational practices,” Kapil says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/611687/the-art-thief-by-michael-finkel/"&gt;The Art Thief&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Finkel, about the world’s most prolific art thief who stole hundreds of valuable pieces from museums and evaded law enforcement for years, had a remarkable number of connections to cybersecurity, according to Katie Jenkins, CISO at Liberty Mutual. “The overarching theme of theft in plain sight had connections to social engineering and how — similar to cyber adversaries — skill in deceiving others can yield remarkable gain for the criminal actor,” says Jenkins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It also highlights the critical role in identifying and managing vulnerabilities — whether it’s physical security in museums and galleries or virtual security in the case of cybersecurity. “In both this literary world and the world of a cybersecurity professional, the core connection is about protecting valuable assets from resourceful, motivated adversaries. Both highlight human elements — trust, psychology, ingenuity — as well as technical/physical controls,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="rethinking-what-effective-leadership-means"&gt;Rethinking what effective leadership means&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It takes dedication to be the best leader. Cybersecurity leaders can turn to books that offer guidance and lessons on developing strong leadership skills, but they’re not always the standard management books.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/How-to-Win-Friends-and-Influence-People/Dale-Carnegie/9781982171452"&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt; by Dale Carnegie and &lt;a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/malcolm-gladwell/david-and-goliath/9780316204361/?lens=little-brown"&gt;David and Goliath&lt;/a&gt; by Malcolm Gladwell are two books that Christina Cruz, director of cybersecurity at Advance, returns to again and again. “Carnegie’s book has shaped how I lead and communicate, especially in cybersecurity where influence often matters more than authority. It’s helped me build trust across teams, navigate tough conversations with empathy, and connect with stakeholders who don’t live in the technical weeds,” Cruz says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gladwell’s David and Goliath reframed how Cruz thinks about risk and resilience. “In our field, we’re constantly facing outsized threats with limited resources, and this book reminded me that being the underdog can be an advantage — if you’re willing to think differently and act boldly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Both books have challenged and expanded my perspective — not just as a cybersecurity leader, but as a person. They’ve helped me approach problems with more creativity, lead with more intention, and stay grounded in the human side of what we do.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/304046/start-with-why-15th-anniversary-edition-by-simon-sinek/"&gt;Start with Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action&lt;/a&gt; by Simon Sinek is another pick by Amit Basu because it’s a powerful framework for leading teams and shaping strategy that is relevant to cybersecurity and technology leadership. “Simon Sinek shows that enduring success begins with a clear purpose, your ‘why’ before focusing on ‘how’ or ‘what’,” says Basu. “It helps transform security from a compliance obligation into a shared strategic advantage. The book also reinforces how purpose drives trust and resilience,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sinek illustrates that people follow leaders who inspire, not just those who manage. In cybersecurity, where pressure and burnout are constant risks, a clearly stated ‘why’ keeps teams motivated and engaged through crises and long-term initiatives. “I recommend Start with Why because it offers a clear and practical model for connecting daily operations to a larger vision, enabling leaders to inspire commitment and foster a culture where security and innovation thrive together,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tablegroup.com/topics-and-resources/teamwork-5-dysfunctions/?srsltid=AfmBOopPEnQSxGO9rGPyQ9ko6a5bNfCvn95yCPS8yx_g19NsFzw9UB-B"&gt;The Five Dysfunctions of a Team&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Lencioni comes highly recommend by Vasanth Madhure, Couchbase CISO. “It completely changed my perspective on what makes a team work.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The book breaks down why so many teams struggle, starting with the most basic issue: a lack of trust. When a team can’t be vulnerable with each other, they avoid healthy conflict, which leads to a lack of real buy-in and accountability. This all adds up to a team that simply isn’t getting meaningful results. “Ultimately, the book’s core message is that trust is the bedrock of any successful team or relationship—not just at work, but in everyday life. For me, this is a daily practice, especially in security, where building trust with everyone, from my team to our customers, is absolutely crucial,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As a CISO, I’ve learned that effective cybersecurity leadership isn’t just about technical experience or even business strategy. It’s also about possessing the necessary skills to be a trusted and empathic leader,” says Vanta CISO Jadee Hanson. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hanson nominated &lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/557595/dare-to-lead-by-brene-brown-phd-msw/"&gt;Dare to Lead&lt;/a&gt; by Brené Brown because it challenges the traditional notion of leadership by emphasizing emotional intelligence and resilience — qualities that are essential for leading in high-stakes environments. “The book helps leaders foster cultures of accountability and openness, which are crucial for building transparent and adaptive organizations. It’s a must-read for leaders looking to cultivate trust through genuine connection and authenticity, within their teams and across their organizations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Good leadership is also about providing the right feedback and with this in mind, &lt;a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250245786/radicalcandorfullyrevisedupdatededition/"&gt;Radical Candor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;by Kim Scott was recommended by Bethany DeLude, Carlyle Group’s CISO. The book highlights the value of honest, specific and direct feedback delivered in an empathetic, timely and respectful manner. “Her use of a practical and actionable framework, bolstered by real world examples, creates an instructive and compelling map for building a culture of open communication, accountability and employee development,” says DeLude.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="understanding-the-cybersecurity-industry"&gt;Understanding the cybersecurity industry&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/joseph-menn/cult-of-the-dead-cow/9781541762374/?lens=publicaffairs"&gt;Cult of the Dead Cow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;by Joseph Mennwas put forward by Helen Patton, Cisco CISO and co-founder of the Cyber Canon Project, as an important history of the people in the cybersecurity industry. “It covers one of the most famous hacking groups and describes the impact of cybersecurity on businesses, personal and political lives. It’s also a well-written, engaging read that will inform and entertain security and non-security people alike,” says Patton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/cybersecurity-myths-and/9780137929214/"&gt;Cybersecurity Myths and Misconceptions&lt;/a&gt; by Eugene H. Spafford, Leigh Metcalf and Josiah Dykstra was also recommended by Patton because it explains why “conventional wisdom” of the industry doesn’t really seem to work. “The authors have done a masterful job in explaining why things that might seem logical don’t, in practical terms, make sense. They dissect how the security industry has impacted how we talk about cybersecurity processes, and how that can sometimes be more harmful than helpful,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The book explores long-held industry practices that are now just “understood” and why those same practices no longer make sense. “They reveal how humans bring faulty assumptions and biases to the way we do cybersecurity. This book is one that every security practitioner should keep close, for them and for the people they work with.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ventureinsecurity.net/p/cyber-for-builders"&gt;Cyber for Builders: The Essential Guide to Building a Cybersecurity Startup&lt;/a&gt; by Ross Haleliuk comes highly recommended by Lavy Stokhamer, global head of cybersecurity operations, Standard Chartered. “As CISOs, we’ve moved far beyond being technical guardians. Today, we are business leaders. Our role demands not only securing the enterprise, but also making strategic bets on which technologies, vendors, and innovations will shape the future of our organisations,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That’s why Ross Haleliuk’s book is such a valuable read. It peels back the curtain on the start-up world – how cybersecurity companies are built, what drives their success, and why so many fail. It’s not about code or exploits, but about the market forces, investor pressures, and go-to-market strategies that ultimately determine whether a solution becomes a lasting partner or a short-lived experiment,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For technology leaders, this perspective is a strategic advantage. It sharpens the ability to separate enduring innovation from hype, anticipate which startups will thrive, and make decisions that align security with business resilience and growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="books-are-a-reminder-that-theres-more-to-life-than-work"&gt;Books are a reminder that there’s more to life than work&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a profession that rarely switches off, books offer CISOs a chance to reflect, recharge, and reconnect with meaning beyond the day job. As a CISO, it’s easy to get drawn into the never-ending work day and Thornton Wilder’s &lt;a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/our-town-a-play-in-three-acts-thornton-wilder?variant=32154020544546"&gt;Our Town&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is a reminder to put work into perspective. “When I read — and reread — the book, I’m reminded to nurture and be present in my whole life,” says DeLude.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;DeLude recommended this book because it’s a reminder that paying better attention to balance unlocks creativity and leads to greater impact in professional life. “By reflecting, I’ve solved more of the hardest work problems after a weekend of family fun or while out on a walk than stationed in my office.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/the-alchemist-paulo-coelho?variant=41227794874402"&gt;The Alchemist &lt;/a&gt;by Paulo Coelho, a book with a simple story but a powerful message, was recommended by Nicole Dove, head of security engineering, Games, at Riot Games. “The main character is on a journey to follow a dream — he’s unsure and knows he’s deviating from what tradition says he should do — but he follows his heart. That’s something I truly relate to. I’ve read the book numerous times, and each time I walk away with a new gem. No matter the phase of life I’m in, I can always relate to the character and a stop along his journey. In the end, what he discovers is even greater than he imagined. And that is a story that I too hope to tell,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The final recommendation is a book that challenges professionals to rethink their purpose and value in IT, according to Fortitude Re’s Elliott Franklin. &lt;a href="https://www.iuniverse.com/en/bookstore/bookdetails/134070-GET-OUT-OF-I-T-WHILE-YOU-CAN"&gt;Get Out of I.T. While You Can: A Guide to Excellence for People in I.T.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;by Craig Schiefelbein. “For CISOs and cybersecurity leaders, it’s a bold reminder that excellence isn’t just technical — it’s about strategic impact and personal fulfillment. If your role no longer aligns with your values, it might be time to reimagine your path, not abandon it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4027000/the-books-shaping-todays-cybersecurity-leaders.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV25-737)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-737</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-737</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-738)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-738</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-738</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-739)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-739</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-739</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-740)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-740</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-740</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-741)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-741</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-741</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-742)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-742</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-742</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-743)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-743</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-743</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel security advisory (AV25-744)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av25-744</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av25-744</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-745)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-745</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-745</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-746)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-746</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-746</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-747)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-747</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-747</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV25-748)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av25-748</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av25-748</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-749)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-749</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-749</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-750)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-750</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-750</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-751)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-751</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-751</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-752)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-752</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-752</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Rockwell Automation security advisory (AV25-753)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-rockwell-automation-security-advisory-av25-753</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-rockwell-automation-security-advisory-av25-753</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 21:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Dark Reading Virtual Event] Cybersecurity Outlook 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/dark-reading-virtual-event-cybersecurity-outlook-2026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/dark-reading-virtual-event-cybersecurity-outlook-2026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 486.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
