<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:29:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>CISA updates cybersecurity benchmarks for critical infrastructure organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/cisa-cybersecurity-performance-goals-update/807766/</link>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgproxy.divecdn.com/p1t777lvRYTMuNm-9ZruuRPB3bo1Gk03gNobbnqCDZc/g:ce/rs:fill:1600:900:1/Z3M6Ly9kaXZlc2l0ZS1zdG9yYWdlL2RpdmVpbWFnZS9DSVNBX2hlYWRlci5qcGc=.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agency streamlines and supplements goals it first issued in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/cisa-cybersecurity-performance-goals-update/807766/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:11:45 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-802)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV25-803)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-805)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and Spanish National Police disrupt activities of far-right terrorist group 'The Base'</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</link>
      <description>Europol supported the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional) in disrupting activities of the far-right terrorist group 'The Base'. The operation took place over three days in Madrid and Valencia, resulting in significant seizures and the arrest of three suspected far-right extremists on 25 November 2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New report explores use of robotics and unmanned systems in the fight against crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</link>
      <description>Europol has today published The Unmanned Future(s): The Impact of Robotics and Unmanned Systems on Law Enforcement. The report, produced by the Europol Innovation Lab, provides an in-depth analysis of how unmanned systems could change society, crime and law enforcement, and discusses the challenges and opportunities they present.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-806)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-807)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-018 - Vulnerability affecting React Server Components - CVE-2025-55182</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV25-808)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity isn’t underfunded — It’s undermanaged</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104251/cybersecurity-isnt-underfunded-its-undermanaged.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Much of the narrative I come across online around cybersecurity budgets revolves around convincing the Board and justifying investments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some approaches are built around &lt;a href="https://www.secureworld.io/industry-news/economists-guide-defending-cybersecurity-budget" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;financial models&lt;/a&gt; and aim at justifying return on investment. Some others focus on quantifying &lt;a href="https://hackernoon.com/the-roi-of-cybersecurity-investments-how-businesses-can-quantify-and-justify-security-spending" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;risk&lt;/a&gt; and showing risk reduction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All are data-driven and designed around some form of rational argument.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But is this really the way decisions are made at the top of large organizations?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, those approaches are all part of the bottom-up narrative CISOs, cybersecurity consultants and cybersecurity vendors have been building toward top executives over the past two decades.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my experience, they clash with three aspects of real-life enterprise dynamics:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First of all, decision-making at the enterprise level may have the appearance of a rational endeavour, but is in fact heavily influenced by cognitive biases, as evidenced by Daniel Kahneman and his school of thought.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is perfectly obvious with cybersecurity, and it brings me to &lt;strong&gt;my second point&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anybody who has spent enough time in the security industry would have come across various situations where money that was previously denied appears in vast quantities at the first sight of a regulatory investigation, a bad audit report, an incident, a near miss or a similar event affecting a competitor (that’s the “can it happen to us?” question many CISOs will be familiar with).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No concerns around ROI or risk reduction are raised in those scenarios: Top executives want to see boxes checked and evidence that they have done their job, should a bad breach occur. If execution does not follow, someone else will be blamed (often the CISO, which has sometimes been nicknamed &lt;a href="https://www.scworld.com/perspective/foster-a-cybersecurity-culture-to-avoid-becoming-the-chief-incident-scapegoat-officer" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chief Incident Scapegoat Officer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More seriously, the penny has in fact dropped in many boardrooms around the “when-not-if” paradigm with cyberattacks: Following almost two decades of non-stop breaches, you would probably struggle to find one board member not aware of the business impact they can have. That’s taking me to &lt;strong&gt;my third point&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have had many discussions, in particular with CIOs, openly admitting that they could put “anything they like” in their budgets for cybersecurity, but that their main problem was delivering on cyber projects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Where does that disconnect come from, between many CISOs and their vendors pretending to struggle with resources, and top executives increasingly cyber-aware and wanting to invest to protect the firm?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-budget-myth-why-cybersecurity-isnt-actually-underfunded"&gt;The budget myth: Why cybersecurity isn’t actually underfunded&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, cybersecurity projects are often complex because they need to reach across corporate silos and geographies to deliver effective protection to the business. This is not natural in large firms, which are, almost by essence, territorial and political.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But beyond that, the profile of CISOs is also a key dimension:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most are technologists by trade and background, and have spent the last decade firefighting incidents, incapable of building or delivering any kind of long-term narrative.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They have not developed the type of management experience, political finesse or personal gravitas that they would require to be truly successful, now that the spotlight is firmly on them from the top of the firm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many genuinely think that chronic under-investment in cybersecurity is the root cause of insufficient maturity levels, while it is in fact chronic execution failure linked to endemic business short-termism that is at the heart of the matter: Projects deprioritised as soon as “quick wins” are delivered or boxes checked on compliance reports, changes in direction as soon as a new executive joins or leaves, initiatives put on hold at the first sight of market turbulences: All point to governance and cultural aspects that are the real root causes of the long-term stagnation of cybersecurity maturity levels in large firms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the CISOs who have not integrated those cultural aspects and are almost always left out of those decisions, it breeds frustration; frustration breeds short tenures (in the region to two to three years for many); short tenures aggravate the management and leadership mismatch: You cannot deliver much of genuine transformative impact in large firms on those timeframes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For top executives, the CISO “merry-go-round” also builds frustration: They have seen too many coming in with grandiose plans asking for millions before resigning after a few years, leaving everything half done.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-first-100-days-where-trust-is-won-or-lost"&gt;The first 100 days: Where trust is won or lost&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Quite a lot of that disconnect is effectively built up in the first 100 days of the CISO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many CISOs come into a new job with pre-conceived views, sometimes created at interview time: Things that have worked elsewhere, pet subjects, vendors or consultants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many also feel that they have to prove themselves as specialists in their first 100 days. That’s a mistake. Competence is assumed in the first 100 days (you’ve just been hired). The challenges lie elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first 100 days are about proving your ability to fit in the organisational structure of the firm and act as a leader.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That starts by listening, in my view: Listening to stakeholders and sponsors, understanding their expectations, their pain points, what has worked in the past, what hasn’t and why, what happened with your predecessor… Sometimes “what can I do to help you?” is simply the best question to ask…&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This process should initiate a journey of co-construction of the cybersecurity narrative, and beyond that, of the firm’s cybersecurity strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If objectives are shared with stakeholders and sponsors, friction is reduced; over time, business champions emerge who relay the cybersecurity narrative, not because it’s the CISO’s but because it’s theirs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The process should also embed the CISO in the governance and leadership dynamics of the firm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By listening truly, identifying and following the cultural currents across the firm, the allegiances, the informal networks of trust where real decision-making happens, the CISO becomes a trusted player for business leaders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At that point, budgetary discussions become two-way discussions between trusted partners, not adversarial situations where one party has to win over the other.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Conversely, CISOs who approach their first 100 days looking to prove themselves tactically run the risk of ending up trapped in operational firefighting: This is a situation from which very few escape. They may be seen as a safe pair of hands in the end, but that’s unlikely to get them accepted at the strategy table.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the type of situation where a CSO role becomes a necessity, as I advocated in “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4052270/is-the-ciso-role-broken.html"&gt;Is the CISO role broken&lt;/a&gt;,” to orchestrate business protection at the corporate level and ensure all regulatory obligations are met.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But it is not a fatality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the future of cybersecurity leadership will belong to those CISOs who recognize that building influence and trust has to precede action and investment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boards no longer need to be convinced that cyber risk matters — they need confident, culturally attuned leaders who can navigate complex corporate dynamics, build trust with all stakeholders and orchestrate delivery across silos.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first 100 days set the tone: Not through technical demonstrations or budgetary battles, but through listening, aligning and co-creating a narrative that business leaders feel ownership over.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In doing so, CISOs move from pleading for resources to shaping strategy as true executives — not firefighters on the sidelines, but architects of resilience at the heart of the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104251/cybersecurity-isnt-underfunded-its-undermanaged.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-809)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-810)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-804) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battering RAM hardware hack breaks secure CPU enclaves</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105022/battering-ram-hardware-hack-breaks-secure-cpu-enclaves.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Confidential computing, powered by hardware technologies such as Intel SGX (Software Guard Extensions) and AMD SEV (Secure Encrypted Virtualization), promises strong isolation and transparent memory encryption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Designed to protect against privileged attackers and physical threats such as bus snooping and cold boot attacks, these secure CPU enclaves are used predominantly in cloud computing environments to create protected memory regions that are encrypted and inaccessible to the rest of the system. However, security researchers from Begium’s KU Leuven University have developed a custom, low-cost DDR4 interposer that re-opens the door to supply chain attacks against even fully patched systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During a &lt;a href="https://blackhat.com/eu-25/briefings/schedule/?#fifty-dollars-to-root-the-cloud-low-cost-memory-interposer-attacks-on-confidential-computing-48941"&gt;presentation at the Black Hat Europe conference&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday, Jesse De Meulemeester and Jo Van Bulck demonstrated how this $50 piece of hardware made it possible to manipulate memory address mapping, effectively tricking the processor into granting unauthorized access to portions of encrypted memory.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the hack operates at runtime it circumvents recent boot-time firmware mitigations deployed by Intel and AMD in response to earlier &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com/badram-attack-uses-10-equipment-to-break-amd-processor-protections/"&gt;software-based “BadRAM” memory aliasing attacks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest hack — &lt;a href="https://batteringram.eu/batteringram.pdf"&gt;dubbed Battering RAM&lt;/a&gt; — enables arbitrary plaintext read/write access and extraction of SGX’s platform provisioning key. This, in turn, allowed the researchers to forge attestation reports and implant persistent backdoors on AMD SEV-protected virtual machines. Cloud infrastructures that rely on Intel’s Scalable SGX technology are also potentially vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers reported their findings to both AMD and Intel prior to unveiling their research. Both chip giants said the attack was out of scope because it involved hardware manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;De Meulemeester told CSO that software and firmware modules are currently unable to detect this attack. As a result, if attackers were able to introduce a compromised memory module into the supply chain they would then be able to carry out follow-up malware-based attacks on vulnerable virtual infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The research undercuts fundamental assumptions about encrypted memory security guarantees while raising questions about the performance and security trade-offs built into the architecture of confidential cloud computing systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Comprehensively resolving the problem would involve reintroducing cryptographic freshness protections integrity into the next generation of server chips, says De Meulemeester, a PhD candidate in electrical engineering who specializes in securing high-performance computing systems against emerging threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105022/battering-ram-hardware-hack-breaks-secure-cpu-enclaves.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet ConsentFix, a new twist on the ClickFix phishing attack</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105230/meet-consentfix-a-new-twist-on-the-clickfix-phishing-attack.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new variation of the ClickFix scam tries to get around phishing defenses by capturing an employee’s OAuth authentication token for Microsoft logins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pushsecurity.com/blog/consentfix/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Researchers at Push Security this week outlined the tactic&lt;/a&gt;, which they call ConsentFix, in a blog, calling it “a dangerous evolution of ClickFix and consent phishing that is incredibly hard for traditional security tools to detect and block.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Generally &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096241/new-clickfix-attacks-use-fake-windows-update-screens-to-fool-employees.html" target="_blank"&gt;ClickFix&lt;/a&gt; attacks display a fake error or counterfeit CAPTCHA verification to a user to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4016208/sixfold-surge-of-clickfix-attacks-threatens-corporate-defenses.html" target="_blank"&gt;get them to copy, paste and execute malicious commands&lt;/a&gt; on their devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What’s new in a ConsentFix attack is that the attack happens entirely inside a browser, say the researchers, which removes one of the key detection opportunities because the attack doesn’t touch an endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack starts with a victim coming across a legitimate but compromised website they are looking for in a Google search, which completely circumvents email-based anti-phishing controls. Going to the site triggers a fake Cloudflare CAPTCHA-like verification page asking the victim to enter their business email address to prove they’re human. Doing so makes a Microsoft login page pop up which includes a legitimate URL, based on the victim’s email address, that would contain an OAuth token. The victim is asked to copy and paste that URL into a field, again, to verify they are human. The URL is captured by the threat actor, at which point the victim has granted the attacker access to their Microsoft account via Azure’s command line interface, say the researchers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“At this point, the attacker has effective control of the victim’s Microsoft account, but without ever needing to phish a password, or pass an MFA (multifactor authentication) check,” says Push Security. “In fact, if the user was already logged in to their Microsoft account (i.e. they had an active session) no login is required at all.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cybercrimeanalytics.com/about/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Christopher Kayser&lt;/a&gt;, social engineering expert and president of Canadian-based firm Cybercrime Analytics, says the attack plays on two tactics favored by threat actors: obedience (cut and paste this URL) and trust (this looks like a Microsoft login page). “People think because they are on a trusted [Microsoft] platform that this is OK,” he said in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But this attack also shows the failures of security awareness training that many organizations perform. If training is effective, employees should suspect there’s something wrong when an app asks for a business email address to confirm they are human, he said, and know that it’s suspicious when they’re asked to cut and paste anything online as a way of proving they are human.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is an incredibly new, innovative attack method,” commented Roger Grimes, data-driven defense CISO advisor at KnowBe4. “It’s almost unfair to classify it as a Clickfix subvariant, even though it is.” However, the odds an employee will copy a long URL string as a test of their humanity has to be very, very low, he added. “It screams different and scammy even to the most unknowledgeable user. Can you see your grandparents doing this? Not me. But I’m sure some people do do it, or else the scammers would not try it,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“My guess is that its rate of success is so, so low that it doesn’t become a popular scam method that most of us need to worry about,” he said. “What we do need to communicate to users is how often Cloudflare’s brand is being used in social engineering scams, and what the correct Cloudflare authentication/validation looks like. The Cloudflare CAPTCHA check has become the fake antivirus screen of today’s world.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations must recognize that the ConsentFix attack highlights the dangers of implicit trust in first-party applications, and in the continued use of legacy OAuth scopes, said &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/analyst/b9cb00be7b" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Avivah Litan&lt;/a&gt;, lead analyst for AI trust, risk and security management at Gartner. These include older permission sets within Microsoft Entra ID that grant broad access and are not subject to modern security controls or monitoring. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attackers exploit these legacy scopes to enumerate directory data, meaning they can systematically retrieve and map out user accounts, groups, and other directory objects within the organization,” she said. “This reconnaissance enables attackers to identify high-value targets and plan further attacks, all without triggering alerts that would be associated with newer, more tightly controlled permissions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; The most effective mitigation strategy to this kind of attack is a combination of robust monitoring, strengthened consent governance and real-time user protection, Litan noted. “By addressing these foundational issues — specifically, by limiting the use of legacy OAuth scopes, tightening consent processes for all applications, and deploying browser-based security — enterprises can substantially reduce the risk of unauthorized access resulting from OAuth consent abuse and enhance their overall identity security posture.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Push Security notes that the attack could be successful because targeting a first-party app like Azure CLI means that many of the mitigating controls available for third-party app integrations don’t apply. Because there’s no login required, phishing-resistant authentication controls like passkeys have no impact on this attack, the researchers add. And the use of advanced detection evasion techniques makes this attack difficult to investigate, meaning these attacks are going undetected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the problems is that most security awareness training isn’t doing enough to lower the odds of employees falling for phishing scams, said Kayser.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He cited a study of phishing messages sent to employees at a California hospital over a period of eight months. Those who had taken a cybersecurity awareness course were just as likely to have fallen for a phishing message as those who didn’t, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Training often fails because instructors talk too much in technical terms, he said. Instead they should explain attacks, how they work and how to recognize them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If you can explain to people what’s going on, that sticks,” he maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105230/meet-consentfix-a-new-twist-on-the-clickfix-phishing-attack.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI expands ‘defense in depth’ security to stop hackers using its AI models to launch cyberattacks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105279/openai-expands-defense-in-depth-security-to-stop-hackers-using-its-ai-models-to-launch-cyberattacks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI is preparing for the possibility that threat groups will try to abuse its increasingly powerful AI frontier models to carry out sophisticated cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a blog, the &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/strengthening-cyber-resilience/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;company describes&lt;/a&gt; how the evolving capabilities of its models could be used to “develop working zero-day remote exploits against well-defended systems, or meaningfully assist with complex, stealthy enterprise or industrial intrusion operations aimed at real-world effects.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to OpenAI, the underlying problem is that offensive and defensive uses of AI rely on the same knowledge and techniques. This makes it challenging to enable one without making possible the other. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are investing in safeguards to help ensure these powerful capabilities primarily benefit defensive uses and limit uplift for malicious purposes,” the company said, adding, “we see this work not as a one-time effort, but as a sustained, long-term investment in giving defenders an advantage and continually strengthening the security posture of the critical infrastructure across the broader ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One new initiative is the Frontier Risk Council. The company offered few details of how this will operate, but said it was part of an expanding “defense in depth” strategy designed to contain the widely-speculated potential of AI as an adversarial tool.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Members will advise on the boundary between useful, responsible capability and potential misuse, and these learnings will directly inform our evaluations and safeguards. We will share more on the council soon” OpenAI said.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other initiatives mentioned in the blog include expanding guardrails against misuse, external Red Team testing to assess model security, and a trusted access program designed to give qualifying customers access to enhanced models to explore defensive use cases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI also plans to expand its use of its recently announced &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-aardvark/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Aardvark Agentic Security Researcher scanning tool&lt;/a&gt; beta to identify vulnerabilities in its codebase and suggest patches or mitigations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-teaming-ai"&gt;Red Teaming AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI companies find themselves under increasing pressure to explain how they will block model misuse. The anxiety is not hypothetical; last month, OpenAI rival &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4092571/ai-controlled-cyber-attack-causes-a-stir.html" target="_blank"&gt;Anthropic admitted&lt;/a&gt; that its AI programming tool, Claude Code, had been used as part of a cyberattack targeting 30 organizations, the first time malicious AI exploitation has been discovered on this scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, university researchers in the US reported this week that the &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2512.09882" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Artemis AI research platform outperformed nine out of ten penetration testers&lt;/a&gt; at finding security vulnerabilities. As the team pointed out, it did this at a fraction of the cost of a human researcher, potentially expanding access to such capabilities beyond well-resourced criminals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Balancing this is the possibility that defenders could use AI to find the same vulnerabilities. OpenAI’s blog alludes to this capability when it mentions testing its models against the &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/red-teaming-network/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Red Teaming Network&lt;/a&gt; it announced two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The reaction of industry experts to OpenAI’s latest announcement has been mixed. A recurring worry is the inherent difficulty of stopping malicious use of leading models.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“OpenAI is asking models to constrain their own capabilities through refusal training, which can be compared to asking a lock to decide when it should open,” commented &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jessewilliams1/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jesse Williams&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder and COO of AI agent DevOps company, Jozu. In effect, the model, not its human authors, defines what is harmful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The distinction is intent and authorization, which models cannot infer from prompts. Jailbreaks consistently defeat refusal training, and sophisticated adversaries will probe detection boundaries and route around them. Safeguards reduce casual misuse, but won’t stop determined threats,” said Williams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“OpenAI’s ‘trusted access program’ sounds reasonable until you examine implementation. Who qualifies as trusted? University researchers? Defense contractors? Foreign SOC analysts?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even with guardrails, AI safety can’t be guaranteed, &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/rob-lee" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Lee&lt;/a&gt;, chief AI officer at the SANS Institute, observed. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Last month, Anthropic disclosed that attackers used Claude Code, a public model with guardrails, to execute 80-90% of a state-sponsored cyberattack autonomously. They bypassed the safety controls by breaking tasks into innocent-looking requests and claiming to be a legitimate security firm. The AI wrote exploit code, harvested credentials, and exfiltrated data while humans basically supervised from the couch,” he pointed out. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That’s the model with guardrails. But if you’re [a villain] and you want your AI Minions to be as evil as possible, you just spin up your own unguardrailed model,” he said. “[There are] plenty of open-weight options out there with no ethics training, no safety controls, and nobody watching. Evil will use evil. … OpenAI’s safety frameworks only constrain the people who weren’t going to attack you anyway.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not all experts are this pessimistic. According to &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/allan-liska" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Allan Liska&lt;/a&gt;, threat intelligence analyst at Recorded Future, it is important not to exaggerate the threat posed by AI. “While we have reported an uptick in interest and capabilities of both nation-state and cybercriminal threat actors when it comes to AI usage, these threats do not exceed the ability of organizations following best security practices,” said Liska.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That may change in the future, however, at this moment it is more important than ever to understand the difference between hype and reality when it comes to AI and other threats.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A previous version of this story contained comments incorrectly attributed to Rob Lee, which have been replaced with the correct remarks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105279/openai-expands-defense-in-depth-security-to-stop-hackers-using-its-ai-models-to-launch-cyberattacks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to simplify enterprise cybersecurity through effective identity management</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104438/how-to-simplify-enterprise-cybersecurity-through-effective-identity-management.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identifying and securing ownership of assets can be a challenging task. In addition to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563753/two-factor-authentication-2fa-explained.html"&gt;multifactor authentication&lt;/a&gt;, conditional and privileged access can help organizations to batten down the hatches. But introducing AI technologies often adds a nightmare of complexity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It [using AI technologies] has been a huge challenge for organizations because policy management, compliance management and security touch on every single application and every single system,” Naresh Persaud, US cyber digital identity and cyber AI blueprint leader for Deloitte says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="deloittes-industrial-and-financial-customers-save-time-with-the-consultancys-identity-product"&gt;Deloitte’s industrial and financial customers save time with the consultancy’s identity product&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recently, Deloitte worked with a large industrial customer after identifying that account ownership was sometimes unclear in their existing system. When an endpoint event was identified, it was difficult to trace who owned the targeted account and whether it existed under multiple names.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With identity management systems, we can link the named user of that account and at the same time we can identify whether the account was vaulted in an identity in the privileged access management system,” Persaud explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The system also identifies any other accounts associated with a user so they too can be examined for any evidence of intrusion. Persaud refers to this as the blast radius.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If I compromise a privileged account, I might be able to use that account to reset the password for other accounts,” he says. “Immediately identifying the blast radius, determining an appropriate response and putting that information into the alert — that gives the analyst in the security operation center much better telemetry than they had before.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The system helped connect pieces of the puzzle that might otherwise have to be done manually. The security analyst who flagged the issue would have needed to contact an identity system administrator — an inefficient process in even the most well-oiled operation. Identifying those points of contact and automating the communication process made for a much more efficient response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Time is often consumed by attempting to map the data related to an incident to the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK framework, for example. Industry analysis suggests this can take up to 30 minutes. “With AI enablement an analyst can drastically reduce this time up to 70-80%,” Persaud says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Persaud claims that the Deloitte solution was able to simplify the documentation. It created a dashboard that identified related accounts that were not vaulted and allowed for closer review of privileged accounts. Unvaulted accounts could be vaulted in short order and any vulnerabilities in privileged accounts could be pinpointed and addressed. This provided a higher level of precision to the way the customer does security now compared to before.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Deloitte also worked with a financial services client that had a similar visibility issue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is challenging for a lot of organizations to get a complete picture of what their assets are and what controls apply to those assets,” Persaud says. He explains that Deloitte’s identity solution assisted the customer in connecting users with the assets they utilized. As they discovered these assets, they were able to fine-tune the security controls that were applied to each in a more refined fashion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If the system is going to [process] financial data and other private information, we need to put the right controls in place on the identity side,” he says. “We’ve been able to bring those two pieces together by correlating discovery of assets with discovery of identity and lining that up with controls from the IT asset management system.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, the users were able to more quickly integrate applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-apexanalytix-uses-microsoft-azure-to-manage-identity-security"&gt;How apexanalytix uses Microsoft Azure to manage identity security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Identity protection is one of the critical controls for any organization in terms of protecting digital assets,” Vishal Grover, CIO of supply chain management platform provider apexanalytix says. “But it is important to maintain the balance between restriction and business requirements.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Apexanalytics has used Microsoft products, such as Defender, for more than a decade. “Initially, we were primarily using it for antivirus. Then advanced threat protection came into the picture. Then identity protection. We kept adding more controls and more validations to strengthen the entire security posture,” he tells.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company has been particularly concerned about the increased &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518296/what-is-iam-identity-and-access-management-explained.html"&gt;identity risk&lt;/a&gt; as it expands its international footprint — notably opening offices in Hong Kong in 2016 and Saudi Arabia in 2024. As the offices interact and employees travel to other locations, it is crucial that any access to its systems is verified as legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Their security team has deployed Azure Active Directory (AAD) to verify geographical boundaries — the locations from which employees might reasonably be expected to access their systems from. For example, if an employee based in the US who rarely travels attempts to log in from a remote location where they are unlikely to be, a red flag is immediately raised. Unless the user’s physical presence in that location can be verified, their credentials have likely been compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“From a user perspective, anytime someone is traveling outside of their base location, they need to reach out to the IT and security teams to list their specific location,” Grover notes. The adoption of these policies requires reasonable adjustments to user behavior and company policy. But the rewards are substantial.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If you think from a broader risk management perspective, this has been fundamental to our security model,” he says. The ability to simply track the locations of employees and assign risk accordingly is a significant advancement in risk monitoring for a company growing its international presence. The company looks out for instances of impossible travel, such as if an employee has entered the system in one location and then in another at a distant location that they could not have possibly reached during a specified period, an alert is raised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security analysts also use the software to scan for risky sign-ins. If a user logs in from an IP that has been blacklisted, an alert is raised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They have increasingly relied on conditional access policies that rely on monitoring user behavior. If a user typically spends an average amount of time on certain applications and then radically changes their behavior the activity is flagged and investigated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company continues to evaluate its policies at least quarterly in order to ensure that they accord with its evolving business strategies. Grover feels confident that Azure’s capabilities are up to the task but remains vigilant to new potential vulnerabilities that will need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104438/how-to-simplify-enterprise-cybersecurity-through-effective-identity-management.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-811)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-811</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-811</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-812)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-812</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-812</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-813)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-813</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-813</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-814)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-814</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-814</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–815)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-815</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-815</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-816)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-816</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-816</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft flips security script: ‘In scope by default’ makes all vulnerabilities fair game for bug bounties</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105950/microsoft-flips-security-script-in-scope-by-default-makes-all-vulnerabilities-fair-game-for-bug-bounties.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today’s AI-enabled attackers are agnostic: They’re not limiting themselves to specific companies, products, or services — they’re going where the vulnerabilities are. To meet them on this ground, Microsoft is pivoting its cybersecurity strategy to what it calls ‘In Scope by Default.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now, any “critical vulnerability” with a “demonstrable impact” on Microsoft’s online services is eligible for a bounty award. This applies to code owned and managed by Microsoft, as well as to anything delivered by a third party or via open-source.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors “don’t care who owns the code they try to exploit,” Tom Gallagher, VP of engineering at the Microsoft Security Response Center, wrote in a &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/blog/2025/12/in-scope-by-default" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; announcing the new security policy. “The same approach should apply to the security community who continue to partner with us to provide critical insights that help protect our customers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="goal-to-incentivize-research"&gt;Goal to ‘incentivize research’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘In Scope by Default’ was announced at Black Hat Europe on Friday, with Gallagher saying that Microsoft “will do whatever it takes” to remediate surfaced issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This strategic shift comes as attackers continuously up their game, aided by AI tools. Microsoft was recently impacted by a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4025691/microsoft-sharepoint-zero-day-breach-hits-on-prem-servers.html" target="_blank"&gt;zero-day vulnerability in SharePoint&lt;/a&gt; that trickled down to businesses and government agencies alike, and in October, the company’s own security update triggered &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076016/security-patch-or-self-inflicted-ddos-microsoft-update-knocks-out-key-enterprise-functions-2.html" target="_blank"&gt;a range of failures&lt;/a&gt;. And just today, to plug the gap until Microsoft can develop its own fix, &lt;a href="https://blog.0patch.com/2025/12/free-micropatches-for-windows-remote.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;free unofficial patches&lt;/a&gt; were made available by a third party for a newly-discovered Windows zero-day vulnerability that gives attackers the ability to crash the Remote Access Connection Manager (RasMan) service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has employed a range of tactics to combat these threats. Gallagher pointed out that, in 2024, the company awarded more than $17 million through its bug bounty program and live hacking events, and its strategy pivot will expand award eligibility. Rather than only being offered for bugs in defined scopes, issues with all online services will be included by default, and as soon as the services are released.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Our goal is to incentivize research on the highest risk areas, especially the areas that threat actors are most likely to exploit,” said Gallagher.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eligibility will now include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft-owned domains and cloud services. Security researchers without Microsoft insider perspective will be encouraged to target its infrastructures via agreed upon rules of engagement.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Third-party code, including open source. In cases where no bug bounty exists in this area, Microsoft will now offer one. Identifying vulnerabilities in third-party code can help raise the bar for “everyone who relies on this code,” Gallagher noted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This shift is “quite significant,” particularly for a company of Microsoft’s size, noted &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/erik-avakian/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Erik Avakian&lt;/a&gt;, technical counselor at Info-Tech Research Group. The new default inclusion policy is backed by process and governance, and is being applied across the tech giant’s “massive, heterogeneous ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Microsoft is explicitly pulling third-party and open-source dependencies into scope when they impact Microsoft services, which reflects how real attacks actually traverse shared infrastructure rather than clean product boundaries,” said Avakian.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers are welcome to &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/report/vulnerability" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;submit their findings&lt;/a&gt; for assessment and for coordinated disclosure, the practice of privately reporting vulnerabilities to vendors so that they can diagnose and fix issues before they are announced publicly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and its partners follow the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/pentest-rules-of-engagement" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rules of Engagement for Responsible Security Research&lt;/a&gt;, Gallagher noted, which encourages a variety of red teaming activities, such as performing vulnerability assessments on Azure virtual machines (VMs), testing surge capacity, attempting to break out of system boundaries and shared service containers, testing security monitoring and detection systems, and evaluating conditional access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, these rules of engagement prohibit red teamers from using or accessing credentials that aren’t their own, launching phishing attacks against Microsoft employees, performing denial-of-service testing or other testing that generates excessive traffic, or interacting with storage accounts not included in a user’s own subscription.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pros-and-cons-to-the-approach"&gt;Pros and cons to the approach&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This widening of scope isn’t necessarily new, noted Info-Tech’s Avakian, though cloud service providers (CSPs), financial institutions, and SaaS companies publish narrower scope language and handle many cases through back-channel negotiation. But much of this still relies heavily on researcher goodwill and internal judgment calls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s wider scope is a bit different, and could result in fewer gray-area arguments and the “is this in scope?” back-and-forth questioning that can expend time and create friction with researchers, said Avakian. It also provides better signaling: If people don’t fear disqualification, they’re more likely to submit early-stage findings. This is great for defenders and can foster stronger trust in the research community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It helps send a clear message: ‘We want to hear about problems,’ and internally, it forces ownership,” said Avakian. “Once something’s in scope by default, it helps to force maturity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, this could get difficult when it comes to volume, potentially leading to more low-quality reports and speculative or “nebulous” findings, he said. Engineering teams can burn out quickly if everything is treated as urgent, or if severity isn’t well-communicated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“But this model can work if severity discipline is rock solid,” said Avakian.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, attackers could benefit indirectly if defender teams become overloaded, where potential noise could drown out real signals, and fix velocity could slow due to triage backlogs. “In other words, operational drag could very well become the attacker’s friend,” said Avakian.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers, for their part, might go down unconventional attack path rabbit holes, and less ethical hackers may spray “low-effort findings” at scale and use ambiguity to pressure for bounty money or even publicly frame rejections as Microsoft ignoring security, he noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, “scope is really a governance decision,” said Avakian, pointing out that enterprises fall behind when vulnerability programs are still written primarily to reduce payouts, minimize exposure, and protect brand optics.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Microsoft is signaling that operational clarity beats defensive ambiguity,” said Avakian. However, “in scope by default” only works with maturity behind it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If you don’t already have strong governance, triage processes, consistent severity models, and engineering accountability, it becomes problematic,” he said. “Automation, enrichment, and experienced human judgment matter more than ever here, and Microsoft appears to be clearly investing in that long game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105950/microsoft-flips-security-script-in-scope-by-default-makes-all-vulnerabilities-fair-game-for-bug-bounties.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 01:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-817)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-817</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-817</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-818)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-818</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-818</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-819)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-820)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-821)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-822)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-823)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-824)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-825)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-826)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-827)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-828)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-829)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-830)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreePBX security advisory (AV25–831)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GISEC GLOBAL 2026 – The Middle East &amp;amp; Africa’s Largest Cybersecurity Event</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 13086037818466944.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
