<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-066)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-067)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.5 million AI agents are at risk of going rogue</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127733/1-5-million-ai-agents-are-at-risk-of-going-rogue.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study released Wednesday by API management platform vendor Gravitee indicates that upwards of half of the three million agents currently in use by organizations in the US and UK “are ungoverned and at the risk of going rogue.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on a December 2025 &lt;a href="https://www.einpresswire.com/article/889263114/gravitee-warns-of-invisible-risk-nearly-half-of-ai-agents-run-without-oversight" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;survey of 750 IT executives and practitioners&lt;/a&gt; conducted by Opinion Matters, the results revealed that AI agents are being deployed faster than security teams can keep up. There are, said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rory-blundell-a7545832/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rory Blundell&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Gravitee, now over three million AI agents operating within corporations, which he described as a workforce larger than the entire global employee count at Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The three million number is based on an extrapolation of survey results, based on government estimates of 8,250 UK businesses and 77,000 US businesses that employ 250 employees or more. The mean number of AI agents deployed per business is 36.9, and when respondents were asked if their organization “experienced or suspected an AI agent-related security or data privacy incident in the past 12 months,” 88% said that they had.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The mean percentage of agents that are not actively monitored and secured, according to the findings, was 53%&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked what prompted the study, Blundell wrote in an email, “we’re all familiar with stories of AI agents going rogue: deleting codebases, leaking confidential information, inventing fake data. The working hypothesis that prompted this research was that, while agentic deployment is reaching an exciting stage, businesses have not yet caught up with agent governance. The research validates that.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-global-problem"&gt;A global problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agents, he said, “can offer businesses a huge productivity gain, but we have to be realistic about the risks: without governance and oversight, they can easily start becoming liabilities, and a danger to consumers and businesses alike.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, said Blundell, despite respondents being only from the UK and US, “this is absolutely a global problem. Companies around the world are using AI agents, and across the board there is a gap between the level of deployment and the level of governance. We have a strong customer base in the EU, where we see the same problems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian-based security awareness training firm Beauceron Security, said, “the only thing that shocks me is that people think it’s only 53% of agents that aren’t monitored. It’s higher.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He likened the results from the Gravitee study to a “lesson about the Titanic that everyone in technology keeps ignoring. The Titanic disaster didn’t happen because they didn’t know there would be icebergs on the trip. They knew it was peak iceberg season, they knew they were going too fast.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley said that the ship’s captain and his crew “thought they’d detect [an iceberg]; if they didn’t, and hit one, that their technology controls would protect them to help them recover.” They put their faith in the so-called watertight compartments that, it turned out, weren’t watertight at the top, but, most importantly, they trusted the new wireless communications technology that they could use to call for help if they got in trouble. The equivalent today: “Well, IT and security can fix it if we get in trouble with our agents.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Wrong then, super wrong now,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He said, “we know AI agents are inherently dangerous and unreliable. There’s literally math proofs out there that show it. So, we know there are icebergs. Let me repeat this for those at the back of the room: 100% of AI agents have the potential to go rogue. If a vendor assures you it isn’t possible and their core technology is an LLM, they’re lying. We know we’re going too fast in adoption for the risks we know exist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley added, “now, the funny part: imagine if the Titanic still made the choices it did, knowing the watertight compartments didn’t work (aka monitoring is missing for 53% of AI agents), we know by the time IT and security roll on an AI agent risk, the damage is done (the ship’s sinking too fast and radio isn’t going to help because help will be too late). And we still made the choices we’re making.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-real-issue-is-invisible-ai-not-rogue-ai"&gt;The real issue is invisible AI, not rogue AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/manish-jain" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Manish Jain&lt;/a&gt;, principal research director at Info-Tech Research Group, said that as the “exponential” speed of AI development continues, his firm, based on experiences with CIOs and CDOs, predicts that there will be more AI agents globally by the year 2028 than the number of human employees. “It would be one of the biggest challenges for business and IT executives to govern them without curtailing the innovation that these AI agents bring with them,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even today, he noted, “we see that most enterprise AI agents are running without oversight. Many organizations don’t even know how many agents they have, where they’re running, or what they can touch. If you don’t know how many mules are in the barn, don’t act surprised when one kicks the door down.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jain pointed out that AI agents are no different. “Unaccounted agents often emerge through sanctioned, low-code tools and informal experimentation, bypassing traditional IT scrutiny until something breaks. You cannot govern what you can’t see. So, we need to understand that the real issue isn’t ‘rogue AI’, it’s invisible AI.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; Info-Tech, he added, “strongly believes that governing AI models or pre-approving agents is no longer enough, because invisible, rogue agents will do &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tandava" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;tandava&lt;/a&gt; (the dance of destruction) at runtime. This is because, when it comes to governing these AI agents, the number is so huge that approval gates will not be sustainable without halting the innovation. Continuous oversight should be the priority for AI governance after setting initial guardrails as part of the AI strategy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perspective, he said, also needs to change: “AI agents are no longer helpful bots. They often operate with delegated yet broad credentials, persistent access, and undefined accountability. This can become a costly mistake as overprivileged agents are the new insider threat. We need to define tiered access for AI agents. While we can’t avoid giving a few people keys to our house to speed up things, if you trust every stranger with your house keys, we wouldn’t be able to blame the locksmith when things go missing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127733/1-5-million-ai-agents-are-at-risk-of-going-rogue.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-068) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV26-069)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-070)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-071)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software supply chain risks join the OWASP top 10 list, access control still on top</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126865/software-supply-chain-risks-join-the-owasp-top-10-list-access-control-still-on-top.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Software supply chain failures and mishandling of exceptional conditions are some of the additions to the updated &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/Top10/2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt;, a list of top web application vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most of the list has remained unchanged since 2021. In fact, the top item, broken access control, has been on the Open Worldwide Application Security Project’s list since it was first released in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Everyone tries to craft their own authentication and access control mechanisms,” says Jeff Williams, CTO and cofounder at Contrast Security. Williams created the list and served as the chair of the OWASP board for eight years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are standard mechanisms out there, but most applications have specialized needs, he says. “I’ve seen some really god-awful horrific machines that people have built to do access control checks, and they don’t build them elegantly. They build them piece by piece. ‘Oh, we’re building this function, we need to do an access check’ &lt;strong&gt;— &lt;/strong&gt;and they build their own access check. And almost nobody tests access control.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A typical web application may have a hundred endpoints, Williams says, each one of which can be accessed by a number of different roles. “Now you have to make sure that each of those routes work in each of those roles. Most people do a scan of their application with one role in mind, like that of a normal user. And maybe with an admin user. But there could be twenty different roles, so it’s very difficult to verify.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI didn’t make the top ten list, but it was included in a “next steps” section of issues on the cusp of inclusion, in addition to a lack of application resilience and memory management failures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This AI category is titled: &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/Top10/2025/X01_2025-Next_Steps/#x032025-inappropriate-trust-in-ai-generated-code-vibe-coding" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;X03:2025&lt;/a&gt; Inappropriate Trust in AI Generated Code (‘Vibe Coding’).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Although we didn’t have data to support the fact that AI-generated code is causing significantly more risk than human-written code available, thanks to community feedback, professional experience, and constant online sharing of such data, we felt it prudent to add a section,” says Tanya Janca, lead author of the OWASP Top 10.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers should read and fully understand AI-generated code before committing it, she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The OWASP Top 10 list is based on a combination of security data from a dozen different organizations, covering nearly 3 million applications, as well as a survey of 221 security experts, says security metrics expert Aram Hovsepyan, CEO at Codific and an OWASP contributing member.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 10:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-broken-access-control"&gt;1 – Broken access control&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When applications fail to properly enforce restrictions on what authenticated users are allowed to do, allowing attackers to access unauthorized functionality or data. For example, an attacker might manipulate an URL parameter to access another user’s account information or escalate their privileges from a regular user to an administrator. This item now includes server-side request forgery, which was its own list item in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-security-misconfiguration"&gt;2 – Security misconfiguration&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security settings are not properly defined, implemented, or maintained, leaving systems exposed to attack. Common examples include default credentials that are never changed, unnecessary features left enabled, verbose error messages that reveal sensitive information, or cloud storage buckets left publicly accessible. This vulnerability jumped from fifth place in 2021 to second place in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-software-supply-chain-failures"&gt;3 – Software supply chain failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers compromise software during the build, distribution or updates to inject malicious code that gets distributed to multiple organizations. For example, attackers might &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2119450/the-threats-of-third-party-software-supply-chains-continue-to-plague-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;compromise a popular open-source library&lt;/a&gt; and inject malicious code that then gets incorporated into thousands of applications that depend on it or breach a vendor’s system to insert backdoors into legitimate software updates. This is a new list item, though there was a narrower related item in 2021 &lt;strong&gt;— &lt;/strong&gt;vulnerable and outdated components.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Developers have become a primary target for many online attacks now,” says Janca. “It is no longer a problem of including a library that has a questionable dependency.” Instead, she says, there are now active attacks against the IDE, against the CI/CD pipeline, against plugins and repositories, against developer workstations, and more. “The entire software supply chain is currently a focus for attackers,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-cryptographic-failures"&gt;4 – Cryptographic failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to properly protect sensitive data through encryption or use weak or broken cryptographic algorithms. Examples include transmitting sensitive data in clear text, using weak encryption algorithms, not properly validating SSL/TLS certificates, or storing passwords without proper hashing. These failures often lead to sensitive data exposure or system compromise. This item moved down from second place on 2021’s list.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-injection"&gt;5 – Injection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Untrusted data is submitted as part of a command or query, tricking the application into executing unintended commands or accessing unauthorized data. Examples range from cross-site scripting, where attackers inject malicious scripts into web pages viewed by other users, to SQL injection, where they use database queries to access or modify sensitive data. This item has also moved a couple of spots down on this year’s list.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-insecure-design"&gt;6 – Insecure design&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security wasn’t properly considered during the design phase of the application, resulting in missing or ineffective controls. Examples include failing to implement proper threat modeling, not establishing security requirements before development begins, or designing systems that lack defense in depth. This category was introduced in 2021 to focus on design and architectural flaws rather than implementation bugs, but it’s moved down a couple of places because the industry has made noticeable improvements in threat modeling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-authentication-failures"&gt;7 – Authentication failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to properly verify the identity of users or fail to protect authentication credentials and session tokens. Examples include allowing brute force attacks, permitting weak passwords, exposing session IDs in URLs, not properly invalidating sessions after logout, or failing to implement &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570795/how-to-hack-2fa.html" target="_blank"&gt;multi-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; for sensitive functions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="8-software-or-data-integrity-failures"&gt;8 – Software or data integrity failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to maintain trust boundaries and verify the integrity of software, code, and data artifacts. Examples include applications that rely on plugins, libraries, or modules from untrusted sources without integrity checks, insecure CI/CD pipelines that allow code to be modified before deployment, or applications that auto-update without verifying digital signatures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="9-security-logging-and-alerting-failures"&gt;9 – Security logging and alerting failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to log security-relevant events or fail to alert security teams when suspicious activities occur. Examples include not logging failed login attempts, storing logs locally without backup, logging insufficient detail to reconstruct attacks or generating logs that don’t integrate with security information and event management (SIEM) systems. Great logging with no alerting is of minimal value in identifying security incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="10-mishandling-of-exceptional-conditions"&gt;10 – Mishandling of exceptional conditions&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to properly handle errors, edge cases, and abnormal conditions, leading to security vulnerabilities. Examples include displaying detailed error messages that reveal sensitive information about system architecture, security checks that fail and allow unauthorized access when errors occur, or applications that crash and expose sensitive data in memory dumps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a category that has been just outside the top 10 for several years, says Brian Glas, department chair of computer science at Union University and an OWASP project leader. What took this item over the top was not the data about existing vulnerabilities, he says, but the survey of experts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If it was purely data-driven, we would not have an accurate list as it would only be looking into the past.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related stories:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575497/owasp-lists-10-most-critical-large-language-model-vulnerabilities.html" target="_blank"&gt;10 most critical LLM vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html" target="_blank"&gt;Managing agentic AI risk: Lessons from the OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3828216/understanding-owasps-top-10-list-of-non-human-identity-critical-risks.html" target="_blank"&gt;Understanding OWASP’s Top 10 list of non-human identity critical risks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1313475/keeping-up-with-ai-the-owasp-llm-ai-cybersecurity-and-governance-checklist.html" target="_blank"&gt;Keeping up with AI: OWASP LLM AI Cybersecurity and Governance Checklist&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3828216/understanding-owasps-top-10-list-of-non-human-identity-critical-risks.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126865/software-supply-chain-risks-join-the-owasp-top-10-list-access-control-still-on-top.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building trust with the board through evidence-based proof</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127327/building-trust-with-the-board-through-evidence-based-proof.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is a boardroom issue, but meaningful dialogue often breaks down at the table. Boards ask about cybersecurity investments and cyber resilience; they need answers rooted in reality, not prognostication. When cybersecurity leaders respond with a list of technologies deployed and potential risks that require additional investment, board members may get frustrated by a lack of clear answers and lose trust. This is a great opportunity for CISOs to take a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Part of the challenge is that most boards don’t have cybersecurity practitioners and expertise, making it challenging to understand the linkage between technical risks and business impact. It’s the responsibility of the CISO to translate technical cybersecurity outcomes into business terms that enable board members to make well-informed decisions on future investments and financial protection for the business. Additionally, senior leadership teams need to be prepared to discuss concepts like risk appetite and potential degrees of business interruption. That’s because no amount of cybersecurity investment can guarantee zero disruptions; a certain amount of risk must be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this unintentional communication gap comes with the nature of cyber threats. The board wants to know how well-positioned the company is to avoid costly business interruptions, regulatory penalties or class action lawsuits from cyber incidents. It’s tempting to rely on internal audits and regulatory compliance (such as &lt;a href="https://www.aicpa-cima.com/topic/audit-assurance/audit-and-assurance-greater-than-soc-2"&gt;SOC2&lt;/a&gt; attestations), but these don’t provide a robust answer to cyber resilience: many companies have failed to stop cyberattacks despite extensive investments in cybersecurity tools and compliance. (In fact, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-07-29-gartner-forecasts-worldwide-end-user-spending-on-information-security-to-total-213-billion-us-dollars-in-2025"&gt;Gartner predicts&lt;/a&gt; worldwide end-user spending on information security will reach $240 billion in 2026)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity leaders desperately need to prove the performance of cybersecurity investments and demonstrate confidently and with evidence that safeguards are working as intended all the time. There’s an obvious opportunity to change the conversation with boards and senior leadership teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-trust-fails-the-limits-of-compliance-and-communication"&gt;Why trust fails: The limits of compliance and communication&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity frameworks like &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework"&gt;CSF&lt;/a&gt; — and complying with these frameworks — are key. However, while they were designed to standardize and validate an acceptable level of controls, they don’t guarantee positive cybersecurity outcomes. Passing an audit once a year doesn’t mean your controls work every day. For instance, a misconfigured control can create direct breach exposure. A backup gap might break your recovery time objective (RTO) promise. A missing insurance requirement at the time of an attack could void coverage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting for CISOs to present heatmaps and dashboards that are too technical for board members. When executives ask why something is red, the conversation may wander into what seems to the board like subjectivity. The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3609804/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-the-secs-breach-disclosure-rules.html"&gt;cybersecurity disclosure requirements&lt;/a&gt; have forced boards to engage. New rules have increased visibility and consequences for both boards and CISOs without necessarily improving fluency. CISOs are accountable but still lack the means to prove the outcome of their team’s work. Bridging the language gap between cybersecurity leaders and business requires translation, but it’s also an opportunity to redefine the role of cybersecurity and focus on the desired outcome sought after by business leaders: cyber resilience. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-a-common-language-to-get-to-heres-the-proof-of-cyber-resilience"&gt;Building a common language to get to “Here’s the proof of cyber resilience”&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;CISOs can reframe the discussion using data and evidence. Modern cybersecurity tools produce a large volume of data and information on how they operate at any point in time, the status of controls deployed, the validation of configuration and more. There’s an opportunity to collect such data, sanitize it and derive continuous insights that validate, at any point in time, not just compliance with cybersecurity regulations but also overall cybersecurity posture. Because these insights are proof of actual state, the CISO can illuminate gaps in protection on an ongoing basis and either address these gaps or help the business determine mitigation priorities. And in some cases, a perfectly appropriate business decision is to accept a risk. It’s important to capture that acceptance formally, document why it was accepted and ensure that the acceptance is reviewed on an appropriate cadence so the level of risk over time doesn’t outpace a company’s appetite.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This will remove subjectivity and confusion from board reports. CISOs can show proof of readiness and effectiveness, and boards can interpret results in familiar business terms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="practical-steps-for-cisos-to-prove-resilience"&gt;Practical steps for CISOs to prove resilience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity deployment is critical, but insufficient. Every day, even organizations with robust cybersecurity investments fall victim to cyber attacks. Board and business leaders put the burden on cybersecurity leaders, but actually demand more: they want cyber resilience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cyber resilience is the ability to continue critical operations under degraded circumstances, like a cyber incident, and the agility to return to normal operations quickly and with minimal financial impact. It’s more than the deployment of cybersecurity tools. Backups must be recoverable, and cyber insurance policies need to pay claims. Ideally, the organization knows how long it takes to restart systems from backup and has all information at hand for claims to be paid fully and quickly. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, no single role owns cyber resilience, but different aspects are the purview of the CISO (safeguards), the CIO (backups) and the CFO (insurance). Collaboration between all three is required to assess that all safeguards are in place. It’s also time to upgrade manual tracking of safeguards to evidence-based, automated tracking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The next step is to shift from activity reporting to evidence sharing and decision support. This includes providing a clear view of the state of cybersecurity, which then surfaces risks that the business needs to make decisions on in terms of whether to mitigate or accept. To use evidence to demonstrate whether the business is meeting its goals for cyber resilience, data must replace prediction. Next, automate low-value work. Free teams from repetitive audit preparation by using tools to aggregate and provide tamper-proof evidence. Focus human expertise on strategy and decision-making for cyber resilience instead of administrative tasks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, educate and contextualize for the board. Deliver short, outcome-focused updates that tie cybersecurity performance to cyber resilience goals. Reinforce the point that business risk and continuity ultimately reside with the board, not the CISO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="better-language-stronger-trust"&gt;Better language, stronger trust&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber resilience is a business problem, not an IT and cybersecurity problem. The board will understand it when evidence-driven communication fosters transparency, trust and clarity of action. As they hear information relayed in language they can understand, boards gain confidence in investments and governance decisions. This results in fewer redlines on board reports, more meaningful conversations and longer CISO tenures. It moves cybersecurity from a reactive cost center to a proactive value driver. When CISOs can show proof tailored to the company’s own risk tolerance, the conversation changes from uncertainty to clarity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127327/building-trust-with-the-board-through-evidence-based-proof.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft develops a new scanner to detect hidden backdoors in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127897/microsoft-develops-a-new-scanner-to-detect-hidden-backdoors-in-llms.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has developed a scanner designed to detect backdoors in open-weight AI models, addressing a critical blind spot for enterprises increasingly dependent on third-party LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a blog &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2026/02/04/detecting-backdoored-language-models-at-scale/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, the company said its research focused on identifying hidden triggers and malicious behaviors embedded during the training or fine-tuning of language models, which can remain dormant until activated by specific inputs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such backdoors can allow attackers to alter model behavior in subtle ways that enable data exposure or allow malicious activity to slip past traditional security controls unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As enterprises &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4123740/how-two-companies-are-moving-ai-prototypes-to-production.html"&gt;increasingly rely&lt;/a&gt; on third-party and open-source models for applications ranging from customer support to security operations, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4022073/ai-poisoning-and-the-cisos-crisis-of-trust.html"&gt;the integrity of those models&lt;/a&gt; is under scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Unlike traditional software, where scanners look for coding mistakes or known vulnerabilities, AI risks can include hidden behavior planted inside a model,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunilvarkey1/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sunil Varkey&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity analyst. “A model may work normally but respond in harmful ways when it sees a secret trigger.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That risk is more concerning because LLMs can be deployed without deep inspection, leaving security teams with limited visibility into their training or vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="signatures-that-suggest-backdoors"&gt;Signatures that suggest backdoors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s researchers identified three observable indicators, or “signatures,” that suggest the presence of backdoors in language models.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the strongest indicators is a shift in how a model pays attention to a prompt when a hidden trigger is present. In backdoored models, trigger tokens tend to dominate the model’s attention, effectively overriding the rest of the input.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We find that trigger tokens tend to ‘hijack’ the attention of backdoored models, creating a distinctive double triangle pattern,” Microsoft said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers also found that backdoored models may leak information about how they were poisoned. In some cases, specific prompts caused models to regurgitate fragments of the very training data used to insert the backdoor, including parts of the trigger itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another key finding is that language model backdoors behave differently from traditional software backdoors. Rather than responding only to an exact trigger string, many backdoored models react to partial or approximate versions of the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="effectiveness-of-the-scanner"&gt;Effectiveness of the scanner&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said the scanner does not require retraining models or prior knowledge of backdoor behavior and operates using forward passes only, avoiding gradient calculations or backpropagation to keep computing costs low.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company also said it works with most causal, GPT-style language models and can be used across a wide range of deployments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts say that while the approach improves visibility into language model poisoning, it is an incremental advance rather than a breakthrough, noting that several leading EDR platforms already claim the ability to detect backdoors in open-weight LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bigger question is how long such detection advantages will last.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While this new scanner will help counter real-world attacker techniques currently, adversaries will adapt quickly to outflank this scanner,” said &lt;a href="https://confidis.co/about/our-leadership-team/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keith Prabhu&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CEO of Confidis. “We are seeing a repeat of the ‘virus’ wars, where hackers kept evolving viruses to evade detection by using innovative techniques like polymorphic viruses.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That said, the scanner is essential for companies that download open-source models to use or customize in their own systems, according to Varkey.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For them, AI models become part of the supply chain, just like software libraries,” Varkey said. “The scanner is not a complete solution, but it is an important new layer of protection as AI adoption grows.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127897/microsoft-develops-a-new-scanner-to-detect-hidden-backdoors-in-llms.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The silent security gap in enterprise AI adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127334/the-silent-security-gap-in-enterprise-ai-adoption.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most security leaders believe they know where their sensitive data lives and how it is protected. That confidence is increasingly misplaced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As enterprises deploy AI across customer support, software development, legal analysis and internal operations, a new data exposure surface has quietly emerged. It does not sit in databases, file systems or network links. It lives inside AI inference traffic an area that falls outside most traditional security models and visibility frameworks, as &lt;em&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/em&gt; explains in its analysis of why&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4087007/ai-is-all-about-inference-now.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4087007/ai-is-all-about-inference-now.html"&gt;AI is all about inference now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This shift has happened quickly. In many organizations, AI systems have moved from pilot projects to core infrastructure in less than two years. Yet security architectures have not evolved at the same pace. The result is a widening gap between where sensitive data actually flows and where security teams are looking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This gap is rapidly becoming one of the most overlooked security risks in modern enterprise environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AI prompts are high-value targets&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI prompts are often dismissed as transient inputs temporary strings of text that exist only for the duration of a request. In reality, they frequently contain some of the most sensitive data an organization possesses:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proprietary source code and internal tooling&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Confidential documents and legal contracts&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Customer PII and financial records&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Strategic workflows and decision logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent industry analysis shows that enterprises are increasingly feeding sensitive proprietary data into generative AI systems to improve relevance and accuracy, particularly as organizations work to unlock internal data layers for AI-driven applications. &lt;em&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/em&gt; has documented this trend in its discussion of&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4094124/getting-the-enterprise-data-layer-unstuck-for-ai.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4094124/getting-the-enterprise-data-layer-unstuck-for-ai.html"&gt;getting the enterprise data layer unstuck for AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From a business perspective, this makes sense. AI systems perform best when they are grounded in real organizational knowledge. From a security perspective, however, it represents a fundamental change in how sensitive data is handled. Information that was once confined to controlled repositories is now being copied, transformed and transmitted as part of inference requests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional data flows, prompts are rarely classified, sanitized or monitored. They pass through application layers, middleware, logging systems, observability pipelines and third-party services with minimal scrutiny. In many cases, they are treated as operational exhaust rather than as high-value data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This creates a dangerous mismatch: some of the most sensitive data in the organization is flowing through one of the least protected pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why existing controls fall short&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional security architectures were not designed for AI workloads, and the limitations become clear at the inference layer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Encryption protects data only until it is decrypted for processing. At that point, prompts may be exposed to application memory, runtime environments, debugging tools, observability platforms and administrative access. While transport encryption remains essential, it does little to reduce exposure once data reaches the systems that actually perform inference.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data loss prevention tools also struggle in this context. Legacy DLP solutions were built around structured data, well-defined patterns and predictable storage locations. AI prompts are dynamic, unstructured and context dependent. As a result, DLP tools often lack the semantic understanding needed to determine whether a prompt contains sensitive material or whether its use is appropriate. These limitations are well documented in discussions around why&lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/k/dlp-to-modern-data-security.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/k/dlp-to-modern-data-security.html"&gt;legacy DLP approaches fall short in modern data security environments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Logging and observability introduce another layer of risk. To troubleshoot AI systems, teams often log prompts, responses and intermediate states. These logs are then shipped to centralized platforms, retained for long periods and accessed by broad groups of engineers. What begins as a debugging convenience can quickly become a repository of sensitive data stored far outside its original security perimeter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In many environments, trust effectively stops at the API gateway. Beyond that boundary, AI inference traffic is implicitly trusted, even though it frequently crosses internal and external trust zones. This implicit trust model may have worked for traditional application architectures, but it is poorly suited to AI systems that blur the line between user input, internal data and external services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Internal risk is the bigger threat&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While external attackers remain a concern, internal exposure is often the more likely and less visible risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over-permissioned service accounts, misconfigured logging pipelines, compromised credentials or legitimate insider access can all result in silent prompt leakage. Unlike traditional breaches, these exposures do not require exploitation of vulnerabilities. They occur as a byproduct of normal operations in complex environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI systems exacerbate this risk because of their scale and frequency of use. A single application may generate thousands or millions of inference requests per day, each potentially containing sensitive data. Within that volume, misuse or accidental exposure can easily blend into normal traffic patterns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Research into insider risk consistently shows that accidental exposure is far more common than malicious breach, particularly in cloud environments where ownership and responsibility are distributed across teams. AI systems add yet another layer of complexity, making it harder to answer basic questions about who can access inference data, where it is stored and how long it is retained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because AI usage is frequent and expected, abnormal access patterns may not trigger alarms. This makes AI inference an ideal low noise channel for data exposure one that does not resemble traditional indicators of compromise and is therefore difficult to detect with existing tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The quantum time bomb&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond immediate exposure, there is a longer term risk that security leaders can no longer afford to treat as theoretical: cryptographic durability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI prompts and responses often contain data that must remain confidential for many years source code that underpins competitive advantage, customer records subject to regulatory protection, proprietary processes and strategic decisions. Yet much of today’s AI inference traffic is protected using cryptographic methods designed primarily for short-term transport security, not long term confidentiality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This distinction matters. Advances in quantum computing threaten to weaken many of the cryptographic algorithms currently used to protect data in transit and at rest. While large-scale, fault-tolerant quantum computers are not yet widely available, the associated risk is already present. Adversaries can capture encrypted data today and decrypt it later, once cryptographic assumptions fail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security agencies and standards bodies have explicitly warned about these &lt;em&gt;“harvest now, decrypt later”&lt;/em&gt; threats. The National Institute of Standards and Technology has highlighted the need to assess which data assets require long-term protection in its&lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/pqcrypto"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/pqcrypto"&gt;post-quantum cryptography guidance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI significantly expands the volume of data that may fall into this category. Inference traffic often includes rich contextual information that would be highly valuable if decrypted in the future. Unlike traditional records, this data is frequently generated at scale and retained in logs, analytics systems or backups without clear lifecycle controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For regulated industries with long data-retention requirements such as finance, healthcare and critical infrastructure this creates a silent exposure window that extends far beyond current compliance cycles. Organizations may be meeting today’s regulatory requirements while unintentionally accumulating long-term cryptographic risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI has unintentionally expanded not just the amount of sensitive data in motion, but the amount of data that must remain secure well into a post-quantum future often without organizations realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The bottom line for security leaders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This gap exists not because teams are careless, but because AI inference does not fit cleanly into existing security models. It crosses trust boundaries that were never designed with AI in mind and introduces data flows that traditional controls were never built to govern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As AI becomes embedded in core enterprise workflows, the security implications of inference traffic can no longer be treated as an edge case. They represent a fundamental shift in how sensitive data is created, processed and exposed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is not a call for a specific solution, but a problem the industry can no longer afford to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127334/the-silent-security-gap-in-enterprise-ai-adoption.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attackers exploit decade‑old Windows driver flaw to shut down modern EDR defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127968/attackers-exploit-decade%e2%80%91old-windows-driver-flaw-to-shut-down-modern-edr-defenses.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a recent incident, attackers abused a legitimate but vulnerable Windows kernel driver to shut down endpoint security tools during an ongoing incident response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a Huntress report, the activity was observed during a customer investigation in early 2026 and involved the use of an old EnCase forensic driver (by Guidance Software) as part of the Bring Your Own Vulnerable Driver (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3600750/infostealers-are-using-byovd-to-steal-critical-system-data.html" target="_blank"&gt;BYOVD&lt;/a&gt;) technique to terminate Endpoint Detection and Response (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/568045/what-is-edr-endpoint-detection-and-response.html" target="_blank"&gt;EDR&lt;/a&gt;) processes from kernel mode.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The intrusion began with compromised SonicWall SSL VPN credentials, after which the attacker conducted internal reconnaissance and deployed a custom “EDR killer” binary.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The attack was disrupted before ransomware deployment, but the case highlights a growing trend: threat actors weaponizing signed, legitimate drivers to blind endpoint security,” Huntress researchers said in a blog post. “The EnCase driver’s certificate expired in 2010 and was subsequently revoked, yet Windows still loads it, a gap in Driver Signature Enforcement that attackers continue to exploit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft did not immediately respond to CSO’s request for comments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The BYOVD abuse&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the researchers, the attack used a common technique of abusing a legitimate signed driver that already has kernel-level privileges. This gave the attackers direct, high-privilege access to the kernel, effectively allowing them to terminate almost any process they want, including security tooling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Windows’ Driver Signature Enforcement, the policy requiring all kernel-mode drivers to be digitally signed by a trusted Certificate Authority (CA), doesn’t check certificate revocation lists at kernel load time. Researchers noted this to be a legacy behavior that remains exploitable because of backward compatibility features introduced years ago that allow an exception for drivers signed with certificates issued before July 29, 2015, that chain to a supported cross-signed CA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The EnCase driver contains a timestamp from a VeriSign service, which the authentication check still considers valid. “When code is signed with a timestamp, Windows validates the signature against the time the signature was created, not the current date,” the researchers noted. “Because the driver was timestamped while the certificate was still valid (&lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/install/deprecation-of-software-publisher-certificates-and-commercial-release-certificates" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;before January 31, 2010&lt;/a&gt;), the signature remains valid indefinitely, even though the certificate has since expired.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once in the kernel, the driver exposes an IOCTL interface that lets the malware terminate arbitrary processes with full system privileges. Among the functionality exposed are process termination commands that bypass user-mode safeguards for Protected Process Light (PPL) processes, the defenses EDR systems depend on to avoid tampering.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-kill-list-excluded-huntress"&gt;The kill list excluded Huntress&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The EDR killer binary used in the Huntress-observed attack packed a 64-bit Windows executable and a custom encoded kernel driver payload, which it decoded into OemHwUpd.sys and installed as a kernel-mode service. Because Windows still honors its cryptographic signature, the attackers were able to load the driver.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once the vulnerable driver was in place, the EDR killer compiled an internal list of 59 well-known security tool processes, hashing their names and continuously checking for their presence on the system. “The kill loop runs continuously with a 1-second sleep interval, ensuring any security process that restarts is immediately terminated again,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, Huntress said it wasn’t on the kill list. “While the EDR killer targets nearly every major EDR and AV vendor on the market, the Huntress agent was not among the 59 processes targeted for termination,” it added. Once the driver was written to disk, the binary established persistence by registering it as a Windows kernel service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress recommended enabling Microsoft’s Vulnerable Driver Blocklist on all supported Windows systems to prevent known abused drivers from loading. The researchers also advised enforcing strong access controls on remote access services, including MFA for VPNs such as SonicWall, and closely monitoring for suspicious driver installation activity. Where possible, organizations are also encouraged to enable virtualization-based security features like Hypervisor-protected Code Integrity (HVCI) to further restrict kernel-mode abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127968/attackers-exploit-decade%e2%80%91old-windows-driver-flaw-to-shut-down-modern-edr-defenses.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian State-Backed Group TGR-STA-1030 Breaches 70 Government, Infrastructure Entities</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/02/asian-state-backed-group-tgr-sta-1030.html</link>
      <description>A previously undocumented cyber espionage group operating from Asia broke into the networks of at least 70 government and critical infrastructure organizations across 37 countries over the past year, according to new findings from Palo Alto Networks Unit 42.
In addition, the hacking crew has been observed conducting active reconnaissance against government infrastructure associated with 155</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2026/02/asian-state-backed-group-tgr-sta-1030.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:37:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four new vulnerabilities found in Ingress NGINX</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128439/four-new-vulnerabilities-found-in-ingress-nginx.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Four security vulnerabilities have been found in the open source Ingress NGINX traffic controller that is extensively used by organizations in Kubernetes deployments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They can only be fixed by upgrading to the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of the four holes, two are more serious, because they carry CVSS scores of 8.8:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/issues/136677" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-1580&lt;/a&gt; is an improper input validation issue. If the Ingress NGINX controller is configured with a default &lt;em&gt;custom-errors&lt;/em&gt; configuration that includes HTTP errors 401 or 403, and if the configured default &lt;em&gt;custom-errors&lt;/em&gt; backend is defective and fails to respect the X-Code HTTP header, then an Ingress with the &lt;em&gt;auth-url&lt;/em&gt; annotation may be accessed even when authentication fails.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/issues/136678" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-24512 &lt;/a&gt;is a configuration injection vulnerability where the &lt;em&gt;rules.http.paths.path&lt;/em&gt; Ingress field can be used to inject configuration into nginx. This can lead to arbitrary code execution in the context of the ingress-nginx controller, and disclosure of secrets accessible to the controller. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is a serious vulnerability,” commented Kellman Meghu, CTO of Canada’s DeepCove Cybersecurity, who has experience with Ingress NGINX.  “If I could exploit it, I could get the Ingress gateway to create a path directly to internal resources. It’s like opening the insides that should never be exposed. Will that lead to further exposure or hacks? Probably, but in terms of impact, it’s a first step to gain access into the environment, and from there it could go further, the least of which would be disruption of services.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NGINX is a reverse proxy/load balancer that generally acts as the front-end web traffic receiver and directs it to the application service for data transformation. Ingress NGINX is a version used in Kubernetes as the controller for traffic coming into the infrastructure. It takes care of mapping traffic to pods of containers running jobs without exposing the pods themselves.  Meghu says Ingress NGINX is the primary traffic entry point, and is effective due to its ability to reload its configuration on the fly, allowing it to adjust to changes inside a Kubernetes cluster.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These vulnerabilities only affect Ingress NGINX versions 1.13.7 and below, and 1.14.3 and below, if they are installed on a Kubernetes cluster.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The warning comes just weeks before, as announced at KubeCon in November, &lt;a href="https://www.kubernetes.dev/blog/2025/11/12/ingress-nginx-retirement/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;support for Ingress NGINX ends&lt;/a&gt;. Starting in March, the project will no longer receive active maintenance, security patches, or bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts have been urging Kubernetes administrators to shift to a new controller ever since. They recommend &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/services-networking/gateway/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kubernetes Gateway API&lt;/a&gt; as the standard for traffic management. Meghu notes it is vendor neutral and widely used. Other options are controllers such as Cilium Ingress, Traefik, or HAProxy Ingress.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to CVE-2026-24512, the other new vulnerabilities are &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2026-24513" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-24513&lt;/a&gt;, considered by Meghu a low risk since an attacker needs to have a config containing specific errors to exploit, and &lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2026-24514" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-24514&lt;/a&gt;, which Meghu considers a medium risk. The controller could be subject to a denial of service if an attacker overwhelms it with requests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These are just the most recent issues with Ingress NGINX. Just over a year ago, researchers at Wiz discovered a group of holes&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3854089/critical-rce-flaws-put-kubernetes-clusters-at-risk-of-takeover.html" target="_blank"&gt; dubbed IngressNightmar&lt;/a&gt;e. They can allow unauthenticated users to inject malicious NGINX configurations and execute malicious code into the Ingress NGINX pod, potentially exposing all cluster secrets and leading to cluster takeover.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Satnam Narang, senior staff research engineer at Tenable, told &lt;em&gt;CSO &lt;/em&gt;that he considers the new holes less concerning than IngressNightmare, which he called a “toxic combination” that could result in cluster takeover.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While there’s nothing novel about [the new vulnerabilities], they serve as a stark reminder to all admins that if they haven’t started migrating, they need to start immediately, before Ingres NGINX is retired next month. Given its upcoming retirement, migration is the best strategy to mitigate these vulnerabilities.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128439/four-new-vulnerabilities-found-in-ingress-nginx.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 02:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersicherheitsvorschriften: So erfüllen Sie Ihre Compliance-Anforderungen</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494023/cybersicherheitsvorschriften-so-erfullen-sie-ihre-compliance-anforderungen.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mit der Zunahme von Cyberbedrohungen steigt auch die Zahl der Compliance-Rahmenwerke. So können CISOs diese Herausforderung bewältigen." src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3376750/1200x.jpg" title="Mit der Zunahme von Cyberbedrohungen steigt auch die Zahl der Compliance-Rahmenwerke. So können CISOs diese Herausforderung bewältigen." width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Mit der Zunahme von Cyberbedrohungen steigt auch die Zahl der Compliance-Rahmenwerke. So können CISOs diese Herausforderung bewältigen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Dapitart – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Anforderungen von Cybersicherheitsvorschriften können je nach Unternehmensgröße, Region, Branche, Datensensibilität und Programmreifegrad sehr unterschiedlich sein. Ein börsennotiertes Unternehmen hat beispielsweise keine andere Wahl, als mehrere Vorschriften einzuhalten sowie Risikobewertungen und Pläne für Abhilfemaßnahmen zu erstellen. Regierungsbehörden oder Unternehmen, die an Regierungsbehörden verkaufen, müssen bestimmte Compliance-Anforderungen des öffentlichen Sektors erfüllen. Banken, Organisationen des Gesundheitswesens, Infrastrukturunternehmen, E-Commerce-Firmen und andere Unternehmen haben jeweils eigene branchenspezifische Compliance-Regeln zu befolgen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesetipp:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492518/pci-dss-4-0-sind-sie-bereit-furs-neue-kreditkarten-regelwerk.html" target="_blank" title="Sind Sie bereit fürs neue Kreditkarten-Regelwerk?"&gt;Sind Sie bereit fürs neue Kreditkarten-Regelwerk?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sicherheit-ist-nicht-gleich-compliance"&gt;Sicherheit ist nicht gleich Compliance&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch für Unternehmen, die nicht in eine dieser Kategorien fallen, kann es Gründe geben, warum sie bewährte Sicherheitspraktiken nachweisen müssen, zum Beispiel, wenn sie eine &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492356/security-standard-wie-sie-sich-auf-ein-soc-2-audit-vorbereiten.html" target="_blank" title="SOC-Zertifizierung"&gt;SOC-Zertifizierung&lt;/a&gt; anstreben oder eine Cyberversicherung beantragen. Umfassende Rahmenwerke für die Einhaltung von Cybersicherheitsvorschriften wie &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103179/nis2-umsetzen-ohne-im-papierkrieg-zu-enden.html" target="_blank"&gt;NIS-2&lt;/a&gt; und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495826/iso-und-isms-darum-gehen-security-zertifizierungen-schief.html" target="_blank" title="ISO"&gt;ISO&lt;/a&gt; bieten allen Unternehmen Leitlinien, die sie befolgen können, sowie Strukturen für die Kommunikation der Ergebnisse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aber: Nur, weil man die Vorschriften einhält, heißt das noch lange nicht, dass man auch sicher ist. Erfahrene Sicherheitsexperten betrachten die Einhaltung von Vorschriften als das absolute Minimum und gehen in ihren Empfehlungen weit über die erforderlichen Komponenten zum Schutz ihrer Unternehmen hinaus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="einhaltung-der-vorschriften-als-voraussetzung-fr-geschftsttigkeit"&gt;Einhaltung der Vorschriften als Voraussetzung für Geschäftstätigkeit&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Sicherheitsmanager kann zwar Investitionen und Praktiken für die Cybersicherheit empfehlen, um die Compliance-Anforderungen zu erfüllen, aber er ist nicht der letzte Entscheidungsträger. Eine wichtige Aufgabe des CISO besteht daher darin, das Risiko der Nichteinhaltung von Vorschriften zu kommunizieren und gemeinsam mit anderen Unternehmensleitern zu entscheiden, welche Initiativen Vorrang haben sollen. Das Risiko umfasst in diesem Zusammenhang nicht nur das technische, sondern auch das Geschäftsrisiko. Um Reibungsverluste zu vermeiden, ist es daher sinnvoll, den Mitarbeitern auch den geschäftlichen Nutzen einer konformen Cybersicherheit aufzuzeigen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="kosten-nutzen-abwgung"&gt;Kosten-Nutzen-Abwägung&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Unternehmensführung muss dabei die Kosten und den Nutzen der Einhaltung von Vorschriften gegen die potenziellen Kosten der Nichteinhaltung abwägen. Angenommen ein Unternehmen erfüllt eine Best Practice für die Verwaltung von Berechtigungen nicht vollständig: Bei Nichteinhaltung der Vorschriften können die zugrunde liegenden Schwachstellen neben möglichen Klagen von Anteilseignern noch größere Auswirkungen auf das Unternehmen haben, einschließlich Ausfallzeiten, Ransomware-Zahlungen und Umsatzeinbußen. Die Erfüllung der Compliance-Anforderungen könnte hingegen einen geschäftlichen Nutzen bringen, beispielsweise durch schnellere Verkäufe, stärkere Partnerschaften oder niedrigere Cyberversicherungsraten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="wie-cisos-compliance-rahmenwerke-nutzen-knnen"&gt;Wie CISOs Compliance-Rahmenwerke nutzen können&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs können vorhandene Compliance-Frameworks als Methodik für Techniken und Prozesse verwenden, um sie in ihr Cybersicherheitsprogramm einzubauen. Zu ihren Aufgaben gehört es im Wesentlichen, über die Programmprioritäten zu informieren und eine “Einkaufsliste” für Lösungen zu erstellen, die sie unbedingt benötigen und die mit dem Programm, das sie aufbauen wollen, übereinstimmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aber es gibt auch einen Unterschied zwischen der Verwendung eines Compliance-Rahmenwerkes zur Steuerung eines fundierten &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492182/cybersicherheit-und-risikomanagement-hand-in-hand-zur-resilienz.html" target="_blank" title="Risikomanagements"&gt;Risikomanagements&lt;/a&gt; und der exakten Einhaltung von Vorschriften. Hier gilt es einen Balanceakt zu meistern und fallweise auch risikobasierte Entscheidungen zu treffen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cisos-brauchen-partner-bei-der-einhaltung-von-vorschriften"&gt;CISOs brauchen Partner bei der Einhaltung von Vorschriften&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs sitzen bei der Einhaltung von Vorschriften nicht allein im Boot. Sie müssen Partnerschaften mit Rechtsteams, Datenschutzbeauftragten und Prüfungs- oder Risikoausschüssen aufbauen, um die sich ändernden Compliance-Anforderungen zu verstehen und zu entscheiden, wie sie zu erfüllen sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Manchmal verlangen diese internen Partner von den Sicherheitsteams, dass sie stärkere Kontrollen einführen, aber sie können auch auf die Bremse treten. So würden manche CISOs gerne das Verhalten ihrer Mitarbeiter detailliert überwachen, aber die Datenschutzgesetze verbieten dies und die Rechtsabteilung sorgt dafür, dass diese Gesetze eingehalten werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compliance-Teams erledigen viele Dinge für die Sicherheitsingenieure und -analysten, die weder die Zeit noch die Ressourcen dafür haben. Sie nehmen die Sicherheit in die Pflicht und überprüfen, ob die Kontrollen wie erwartet funktionieren. Sie fungieren quasi als Vermittler zwischen Sicherheitsteams, Aufsichtsbehörden und Prüfern, um die Einhaltung der Vorschriften nachzuweisen, sei es durch das Sammeln von Beweisen mittels manueller Sicherheitsfragebögen oder durch Technologieintegrationen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für eine Zertifizierung im öffentlichen Sektor müssen beispielsweise die Sicherheitskontrollen überwacht, protokolliert und die Daten mindestens sechs Monate lang aufbewahrt werden, um nachzuweisen, dass alle Vorgaben erfüllt wurden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesetipp:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492583/cybersicherheitsabkommen-wie-internationale-security-frameworks-cisos-unterstutzen.html" target="_blank" title="Wie internationale Security Frameworks CISOs unterstützen"&gt;Wie internationale Security Frameworks CISOs unterstützen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="tools-und-ressourcen-zur-untersttzung-der-einhaltung-von-vorschriften"&gt;Tools und Ressourcen zur Unterstützung der Einhaltung von Vorschriften&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risikoregister sind hilfreich, um alle Beteiligten an einen Tisch zu bringen, indem sie alle Risiken dokumentieren und nach Prioritäten ordnen. Wenn alle Beteiligten die gleichen Informationen einsehen, können sie sich auf geeignete Maßnahmen einigen. Im Rahmen eines Risikomanagementprogramms werden Richtlinien, Standards und Verfahren regelmäßig überprüft und alle Änderungen vor ihrer Umsetzung genehmigt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mithilfe von Tools wie &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492710/governance-risk-compliance-grc-adaptiver-ansatz-fur-das-risk-management.html" target="_blank" title="Governance, Risk, and Compliance"&gt;Governance, Risk, and Compliance&lt;/a&gt; (GRC)-Systemen und kontinuierlicher Überwachung der Einhaltung von Vorschriften wie &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493537/neue-eu-it-security-richtline-nis-2-das-sollten-sie-beachten.html" target="_blank" title="NIS-2"&gt;NIS-2&lt;/a&gt; und ISO können Unternehmen laufende Sicherheitsaktivitäten verfolgen und die Ergebnisse melden. GRC-Systeme lassen sich mit &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492608/was-ist-siem.html" target="_blank" title="SIEM"&gt;SIEM&lt;/a&gt;-Lösungen verknüpfen, um Protokolle zu sammeln, durch die Kombination mit Schwachstellen-Scannern kann man nachzuweisen, dass Prüfungen durchgeführt wurden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zusätzlich zu solchen Instrumenten verlassen sich viele Unternehmen auf Dritte, um die Einhaltung der Vorschriften zu bewerten. Diese können vor einer externen Prüfung ein internes Compliance-Audit durchführen, um sicherzustellen, dass es keine Überraschungen gibt, wenn die Aufsichtsbehörden vorbeikommen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="einmal-erfllen-auf-viele-anwenden"&gt;Einmal erfüllen, auf viele anwenden&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die meisten Unternehmen haben zahlreiche Compliance-Stellen, denen sie Rechenschaft ablegen müssen, sowie Cyberversicherungsanbieter, Kunden und Partner. Die Einhaltung von Vorschriften kann zwar eine Belastung sein, aber es gibt Techniken, um den Bewertungsprozess zu rationalisieren. Immerhin ist ein Großteil der gesetzlichen Anforderungen beinahe identisch. Orientieren sich CISOs beispielsweise an einem Rahmenwerk wie NIST, können sie überall die gleichen Verfahren anwenden. So sind zum Beispiel Anforderungen an das &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493543/was-ist-privileged-access-management.html" target="_blank" title="Privileged Access Management"&gt;Privileged Access Management&lt;/a&gt; (PAM) wie Passwortmanagement, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493978/multi-faktor-authentifizierung-etablieren-die-10-haufigsten-mfa-ausreden.html" target="_blank" title="Multi-Faktor-Authentifizierung"&gt;Multi-Faktor-Authentifizierung&lt;/a&gt; (MFA) und rollenbasierte Zugriffskontrollen in allen Compliance-Frameworks zu finden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ausblick"&gt;Ausblick&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Letztlich ist die Einhaltung von Vorschriften ein fließender Bereich mit Anforderungen, die sich weiterentwickeln, um den sich ändernden Risikomustern und Geschäftsbedingungen Rechnung zu tragen. Es ist zu erwarten, dass die Sicherstellung der Compliance in Zukunft einen noch größeren Teil der Arbeit von CISOs ausmachen wird. Da die Branche mit immer größeren Bedrohungen konfrontiert ist, ist die Einhaltung von Vorschriften ein wichtiger Bestandteil eines strategischen und umfassenden Ansatzes für das Management von Cybersicherheitsrisiken. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesetipp:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494025/digitaler-und-analoger-infrastrukturschutzdas-fordert-das-neue-kritis-dachgesetz.html" target="_blank" title="Das fordert das neue KRITIS-Dachgesetz"&gt;Das fordert das neue KRITIS-Dachgesetz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494023/cybersicherheitsvorschriften-so-erfullen-sie-ihre-compliance-anforderungen.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-072)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-073)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–074)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-075)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-076)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-077)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The blind spot every CISO must see: Loyalty</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127687/the-blind-spot-every-ciso-must-see-loyalty.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The longstanding assumption that tenure, performance metrics, or expressed commitment serve as reliable indicators of the trustworthiness of an employee persists across many sectors. Indeed, the great majority of personnel are loyal. But, while small, the percentage of those who aren’t is still well above zero.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, this conflation of loyalty and security overlooks a fundamental reality: Loyalty is not a static trait, but a dynamic human response shaped by perceived fairness, personal circumstances, and organizational alignment. When grievances go unaddressed or external pressures mount, what appears as steadfast allegiance can quietly shift toward disaffection, resentment, or deliberate breaking of trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-half-century-of-observed-patterns"&gt;A half-century of observed patterns&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my more than 50 years of government, private sector, and journalistic endeavors, I have seen this pattern play out repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What begins as genuine commitment can erode under the weight of unmet expectations, financial strain, ideological differences, outside influences, or simply the passage of time in roles that demand constant vigilance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The insider who once seemed beyond reproach becomes the very vector through which sensitive data, intellectual property, or operational integrity is compromised. These are not isolated failures of vetting or technology; they are failures to recognize that loyalty is relational and conditional, not absolute.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-the-misread-appears-in-practice"&gt;How the misread appears in practice&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent examples illustrate the point. In the US federal sphere, abrupt terminations under workforce reduction initiatives have left former employees with lingering access to sensitive systems, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3831772/the-purging-of-us-workers-who-deal-with-secrets-has-created-a-spike-in-insider-risk.html"&gt;amplifying the potential for data exposure or retaliation&lt;/a&gt;. Corporate cases show a similar dynamic: engineers or executives who have spent years building institutional knowledge suddenly depart with proprietary information, motivated not by espionage but by opportunity or resentment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These incidents are not anomalies. They reflect a broader pattern in which subjective judgments of loyalty, what I have come to call “personal barometers,” exist. For example, colleague to colleague, “Janet loves this company, she’s been here 20 years” may be a consensus view, yet it is not accompanied by objective, consistent, and transparent measures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="personnel-history-blind-spots"&gt;Personnel history blind spots&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations have long operated under the belief that loyalty, once demonstrated, becomes a durable shield against insider risk. Extended tenure is rewarded with escalating access privileges, high performers are granted broader system rights without commensurate behavioral review, and verbal affirmations of commitment are taken at face value. Yet time and again patterns repeat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What begins as mutual confidence weakens not through dramatic betrayal but through subtle realignments in personal commitment. An employee who once identified strongly with the mission may begin to feel undervalued, overlooked for advancement, or weighed down by outside pressures. The organization, relying on its subjective gauge of past performance, fails to notice the change until the cow has bolted from the barn.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These patterns are neither new nor rare. They reflect a systemic reluctance to treat loyalty as a living relationship that requires active maintenance and verification.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-blind-spot-becomes-visible"&gt;The blind spot becomes visible&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today we have a confluence of forces that will expose the limitations of assumptive loyalty models. Economic volatility, including persistent inflation, ongoing AI-driven job displacements, and workforce reductions, will &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116983/insider-risk-in-an-age-of-workforce-volatility.html"&gt;heighten personal and professional stressors for employees at every level&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compounding the human element is the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109999/agentic-ai-already-hinting-at-cybersecuritys-pending-identity-crisis.html"&gt;rapid emergence of AI agents as autonomous insiders&lt;/a&gt;. These systems, granted privileged access to sensitive data and decision-making workflows, introduce risks at machine speed: prompt misdirection, goal misalignment, or unintended exfiltration without human intent or oversight. We know AI agents are among the fastest-growing insider vectors, with autonomous capabilities outpacing traditional controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geopolitical tensions further amplify the threat. Nation-state actors and proxies increasingly exploit economic pressures and ideological divides to groom or coerce individuals, blurring the lines between personal discontent and hostile external influence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In critical sectors (transportation, finance, medical, energy) where elevated roles already receive greater scrutiny, the model proves resilient. Yet in less regulated environments, the absence of universal, consensual standards leaves organizations exposed. What was once a subtle misalignment becomes systemic exposure when human volatility meets machine autonomy and geopolitical opportunism.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="parallels-to-ai-poisoning-and-the-dual-crisis-of-trust"&gt;Parallels to AI poisoning and the dual crisis of trust&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These themes extend directly from an earlier column of mine, “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4022073/ai-poisoning-and-the-cisos-crisis-of-trust.html"&gt;AI poisoning and the CISO’s crisis of trust&lt;/a&gt;.” That discussion examined how poisoned training data undermines the foundational integrity of artificial intelligence systems, creating a crisis of confidence in the tools organizations increasingly depend upon. The parallel to human loyalty is clear: Just as corrupted inputs erode the reliability of AI outputs, unexamined or misread human loyalties erode the reliability of the individuals who design, operate, protect, and rely on those systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In both domains, reactive remediation is insufficient. Trust must be rebuilt through deliberate, continuous verification rather than periodic assumptions. The CISO’s crisis of trust is therefore dual: architectural in the machine domain and relational in the human domain. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064326/coherence-insider-risk-strategys-new-core-principle.html"&gt;Coherence across these domains&lt;/a&gt;, ensuring that human and machine behaviors remain aligned with organizational intent, then emerges as the essential principle for long-term resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-path-forward"&gt;The path forward&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The path forward lies in embracing consensual, tiered verification, where elevated responsibility demands greater scrutiny. Positions with access to crown jewels — sensitive data, financial systems, or personnel records — or executive ranks inherently require proportionately more oversight, as regulated sectors have shown. Professionals in these roles accept this as part of the terrain, with history demonstrating minimal talent loss when frameworks are transparent and supportive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.opm.gov/suitability/suitability-executive-agent/suitability-training#url=Overview"&gt;Federal Trusted Workforce 2.0&lt;/a&gt; provides a vital blueprint for the private sector. By 2026, with full implementation across government agencies, this program enrolls millions in continuous vetting, using automated record checks to review a plethora of risks in real-time and reducing reliance on periodic reviews. Private adaptations are feasible and essential: secure releases from key personnel for ongoing monitoring, mirroring TW 2.0’s supportive ethos without federal mandates. These measures are far less expensive than the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567697/what-is-the-cost-of-a-data-breach-3.html"&gt;multimillion-dollar costs of a single malicious insider event&lt;/a&gt; ($4.9M to $13.9M per incident per IBM/Mimecast 2025 analyses).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Broader practices include pulse surveys and engagement tools to surface misalignment early, integrated HR reviews, and wellness interventions. &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-03-03-gartner-identifiesthe-top-cybersecurity-trends-for-2025"&gt;Gartner indicates AI-integrated behavioral programs&lt;/a&gt; reduce employee-driven incidents by 40%. These investments are economical, scalable, and consensual, fostering mutual trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The folly of equating loyalty with security must end. Through verifiable, human-centric vigilance, including consensual scrutiny scaled to responsibility, organizations can earn trust, not assume it, transforming vulnerabilities into resilience. In the era of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;zero trust&lt;/a&gt;, there should be no pushback in the adoption of “trust but verify” personnel policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116983/insider-risk-in-an-age-of-workforce-volatility.html"&gt;Insider risk in an age of workforce volatility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064326/coherence-insider-risk-strategys-new-core-principle.html"&gt;Coherence: Insider risk strategy’s new core principle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127687/the-blind-spot-every-ciso-must-see-loyalty.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zscaler extends zero-trust security to browsers with SquareX acquisition</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128745/zscaler-extends-zero-trust-security-to-browsers-with-squarex-acquisition.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud security company Zscaler has announced the acquisition of SquareX, a Singapore-based browser detection and response (BDR) technology startup. The deal will enable Zscaler to extend its Zero Trust Exchange capabilities directly into standard web browsers, across both managed and unmanaged devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With Zscaler Private Access (ZPA), the company has been assisting enterprises adopt zero trust architecture using a lightweight agent. The SquareX &lt;a href="https://www.zscaler.com/press/zscaler-acquires-squarex#about-zscaler" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;acquisition&lt;/a&gt; is expected to further strengthen Zscaler’s ability to deliver security directly within commonly used browsers through lightweight extensions, eliminating the need for a separate &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573875/secure-web-browsers-for-the-enterprise-compared-how-to-pick-the-right-one.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;enterprise browser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acquisition will assist in enabling posture-like security and protection against advanced spear-phishing and identity-based attacks right into the user’s existing workflow, stated Jay Chaudhry, CEO, chairman, and founder of Zscaler, in his LinkedIn post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="browsers-the-new-frontier-for-attacks"&gt;Browsers, the new frontier for attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditionally treated as a mere gateway to the internet, web &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101173/hardening-browser-security-with-zero-trust-controls.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;browsers&lt;/a&gt; are now at the center of enterprise activity, being widely used for SaaS applications, cloud services, and increasingly for generative AI tools. As employees upload, copy, and share sensitive data through browser sessions, this growing reliance has also opened new avenues for security risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most security stacks protect either the application, the endpoint, or the network. The browser is, unfortunately, the blind spot in between. There are traditional ways of dealing with the issue, but often at too great a risk, or as a result of too limiting an approach,” said Devroop Dhar, co-founder and MD at Primus Partners.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SquareX assists by allowing any browser on any device to function more like a secure enterprise browser using a lightweight, extension-based approach. “This extension becomes a kind of runtime enforcement agent, offering session-specific controls such as browser-based DLP, dynamic content isolation, real-time monitoring of user behaviour, and targeted security enforcement depending on risk levels and session context,” said Sanchit Vir Gogia, CEO and chief analyst at Greyhound Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SquareX’s approach also blocks sensitive data from being pasted into public AI tools, flags suspicious prompts, or limits interactions based on user role and data sensitivity, Dhar said. This is so important because AI misuse is rarely malicious, it is accidental. Browser-native security is better suited to prevent mistakes before they turn into incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SquareX extension-based security can be integrated with most commonly used web browsers, including Chrome, Edge, Firefox and Safari, allowing employees to continue using their preferred browser without requiring enterprises to deploy or manage yet another dedicated security tool.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-win-win-for-customers"&gt;A win-win for customers?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zscaler has acknowledged that browser runtime behaviour was a missing piece in its zero-trust security, and having SquareX solution in its portfolio can help fill the gap, noted Gogia.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Zscaler customers, this acquisition would mean browser security is no longer an afterthought or a separate tool to evaluate but a native part of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It reduces reliance on legacy access methods like VPN and VDI, especially for external users. It also gives Zscaler the ability to unify policy enforcement across network access, app usage, and now browser behaviour. Zscaler customers will be able to apply in-session controls to activities that were previously invisible, such as clipboard actions, extension behaviour, or AI prompt submission. They also gain options for session isolation, file download inspection, and least-privilege app access via browser,” added Gogia.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, for SquareX customers, this means scale and integration. Vivek Ramachandran, founder and CEO of SquareX, confirmed in a &lt;a href="https://sqrx.com/zscaler-acquires-squarex" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that customer deployments and investments will be protected, and over time, they will benefit from tighter integration with Zscaler services, expanded analytics, and more robust, risk-based controls across managed and unmanaged devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In both instances, the customer benefits from improved alignment between access, behaviour, and enforcement approaches, stated Dhar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="different-roads-to-browser-security"&gt;Different roads to browser security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of late, leading cybersecurity companies have been strengthening their product portfolios by investing in and acquiring specialized browser security firms. This is an indication that they now see browser-native security as strategic rather than optional. For instance, in January this year, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116703/crowdstrike-to-add-browser-security-to-falcon-with-seraphic-acquisition.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;CrowdStrike&lt;/a&gt; acquired Israel-based Seraphic Security, a browser runtime security company, which it plans to integrate into the Falcon platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, the concern has shifted from the security of the browser to where the security of the browser should be located. Dhar explained in the case of Zscaler’s move with SquareX, the strategy is to integrate browser controls with its access component of Zscaler zero trust. That’s security beyond granting access. However, in the case of the acquisition by CrowdStrike involving Seraphic, the strategy falls under endpoint security as they extend the visibility of EDR solutions to include the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128745/zscaler-extends-zero-trust-security-to-browsers-with-squarex-acquisition.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA gives federal agencies 18 months to purge unsupported edge devices</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128748/cisa-gives-federal-agencies-18-months-to-purge-unsupported-edge-devices.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency has given federal agencies 18 months to remove all end-of-support edge devices from their networks, escalating its response to what security researchers describe as a fundamental shift in nation-state attack tactics, where attackers exploit network infrastructure rather than endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/directives/bod-26-02-mitigating-risk-end-support-edge-devices" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;binding operational directive&lt;/a&gt;, BOD 26-02, requires Federal Civilian Executive Branch (FCEB) agencies to inventory, update where possible, and ultimately replace firewalls, routers, VPN gateways, load balancers, and network security appliances that no longer receive vendor security patches. CISA warned that the threat from these unsupported devices is “substantial and constant.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Unsupported devices pose a serious risk to federal systems and should never remain on enterprise networks,” CISA Acting Director Madhu Gottumukkala said in the directive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The directive requires FCEB agencies to immediately update any edge device running outdated software to vendor-supported versions where possible.  Within three months, agencies must inventory all end-of-support devices using CISA’s EOS Edge Device List and report findings. Within 12 months, agencies must begin removing devices that have reached end-of-support dates. The 18-month deadline requires all unsupported edge devices to be permanently removed and replaced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-edge-devices-became-prime-targets"&gt;Why edge devices became prime targets&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Edge devices differ fundamentally from traditional IT assets, as they are often end of support, custom, OEM and process dependent,” Avinash Dev Nagumanthri, director analyst at Gartner, told CSO. “This makes discovery, patching, and replacement difficult under tight budgets while maintaining uptime.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="Nation-state%20actors%20exploiting%20outdated%20firewalls%20and%20routers%20prompted%20the%20directive%20requiring%20agencies%20to%20inventory%20and%20replace%20unsupported%20network%20perimeter%20devices"&gt;Network edge devices&lt;/a&gt; have become one of the top initial access vectors for state-affiliated cyberespionage groups and ransomware gangs. Research shows a dramatic increase in edge device exploitation, with &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4031603/32-of-exploited-vulnerabilities-are-now-zero-days-or-1-days.html"&gt;network edge vulnerabilities seeing an 8x increase&lt;/a&gt; in exploitation activity. The &lt;a href="https://www.mandiant.com/m-trends"&gt;2025 Mandiant M-Trends report&lt;/a&gt; found that 21% of ransomware attacks featured vulnerability exploitation as the initial access vector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA has &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa25-239a"&gt;documented nation-state campaigns&lt;/a&gt; targeting devices from Cisco, Fortinet, Palo Alto Networks, Ivanti, Juniper, and other vendors. The agency noted that these devices have become attractive targets because of their position at the network boundary, integration with identity management systems, and privileged access for lateral movement. Once compromised, they enable threat actors to intercept network traffic, harvest credentials, and exfiltrate sensitive data while evading traditional endpoint detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nagumanthri noted that edge devices protecting critical infrastructure can have physical impacts when compromised, putting high-value systems in sectors like water and transportation at risk. “Nation-state actors are increasingly exploiting edge devices as entry points into infrastructure, threatening critical private sector operations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The directive follows two recent emergency directives. In September, CISA issued &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/news/cisa-issues-emergency-directive-requiring-federal-agencies-identify-and-mitigate-cisco-zero-day" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Emergency Directive 25-03&lt;/a&gt; after threat actors exploited zero-day vulnerabilities in Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances, deploying persistent malware that survived reboots. In October, &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/directives/ed-26-01-mitigate-vulnerabilities-f5-devices" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;another emergency directive&lt;/a&gt; followed the compromise of F5 Networks’ development environment, where attackers exfiltrated BIG-IP source code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="implementation-hurdles"&gt;Implementation hurdles&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sunil Varkey, advisor at Beagle Security, warns of implementation complexities. “The operational reality of removing legacy systems is not straightforward,” Varkey said. “Legacy devices continue to exist not by design, but by necessity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He pointed to orphaned systems that remain live and embedded in workflows but lack clear ownership, and operational technology environments where newer hardware or software versions are not available, compatible, or certified. The process requires asset discovery, risk assessment, procurement, configuration redesign, data migration, testing, and managed cutovers to avoid service disruption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A common challenge will be the presence of ‘orphaned’ or ‘ghost’ systems — devices that are live, embedded in workflows, but no longer clearly owned,” Varkey said. “These systems often persist because ‘they’ve always worked,’ even when no one fully understands their function.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="private-sector-implications"&gt;Private sector implications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the directive applies only to federal civilian agencies, CISA strongly encourages private sector organizations to adopt similar measures. The exploitation campaigns targeting federal networks pose equivalent risks to critical infrastructure and commercial enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nagumanthri recommended that organizations treat edge and cyber-physical systems as Tier-0 assets, enforce strong authentication, implement network segmentation, require vendor-supported firmware updates, and centralize logging to limit blast radius. For the private sector, he advocated structured lifecycle management with secure-by-design hardware, continuous monitoring, and controlled updates with rollback capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Varkey saw the directive as a catalyst for modernization beyond compliance. “While the short-term impact will be challenging, the outcome is a more secure, accountable, and defensible infrastructure — one better aligned with today’s threat realities and tomorrow’s operational needs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128748/cisa-gives-federal-agencies-18-months-to-purge-unsupported-edge-devices.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten career-ending mistakes CISOs make and how to avoid them</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128090/ten-career-ending-mistakes-cisos-make-and-how-to-avoid-them.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Chief Information Security Officer role has become one of the most precarious positions in the C-suite. According to a Hitch Partners study, the average CISO tenure is &lt;a href="https://www.hitchpartners.com/ciso-security-leadership-survey-results-25" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;39 months&lt;/a&gt; — a timeframe that reflects the intense pressure and high stakes of the position. With &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3587236/77-of-cisos-fear-next-big-breach-will-get-them-fired.html" target="_blank"&gt;77% of CISOs&lt;/a&gt; fearing dismissal after a major breach, the margin for error continues to shrink.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The IANS/Artico Search CISO Compensation Report reveals that turnover rates hit &lt;a href="https://www.asisonline.org/security-management-magazine/latest-news/today-in-security/2025/november/ciso-compensation/?locale=en" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;15% in 2025&lt;/a&gt;, up from 11% in 2024. Even a 6.7% compensation increase hasn’t slowed the exodus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO role has evolved from technical expert to strategic business executive — a shift many security leaders struggle to navigate. Rising personal liability under regulatory frameworks, persistent budget constraints, and an increasingly sophisticated threat landscape have converged to create an environment where even experienced CISOs find their positions at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This article examines the ten most common reasons CISOs lost their jobs in 2025 and provides mitigation strategies to help security leaders protect their positions. The data comes from recent industry research, including surveys of 550+ CISOs, analysis of security budget trends, and interviews with executive recruiters who’ve witnessed countless CISO departures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-failure-to-prevent-or-manage-major-breaches"&gt;1. Failure to prevent or manage major breaches&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The most direct path to dismissal remains the inability to prevent or effectively respond to significant cybersecurity incidents. Organizations operate under a “one-throat-to-choke” mentality, and when a breach occurs, the CISO becomes the obvious target for accountability. According to &lt;a href="https://www.portnox.com/blog/security-trends/ciso-survey-c-suite-isnt-easy-street-for-security-leaders/#:~:text=data%20and%20systems.-,77%25%20of%20CISOs%20Worry%20a%20Data%20Breach%20Could%20Cost%20Them,to%20a%20more%20collective%20effort." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recent data&lt;/a&gt; , 77% of CISOs believe a major breach will cost them their position.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;High-profile incidents consistently result in leadership changes, regardless of whether the CISO had adequate resources or executive support before the incident.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy: &lt;/strong&gt;A comprehensive incident response plan with clear communication protocols and regular tabletop exercises forms the foundation of effective breach management. Documented risk assessments shared with the board create a paper trail that demonstrates due diligence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When leadership understands the risks flagged by the security team and the resources requested, they’re less likely to assign blame to the CISO when incidents occur.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;2. Poor communication with the board and C-suite&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Technical expertise alone no longer suffices in the modern CISO role. Security leaders who fail to translate cyber risks into business impact quickly lose credibility with decision-makers who control budgets and strategic direction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When security leaders present endless technical details without connecting them to revenue loss, regulatory fines, or competitive disadvantage, boards tune out. This communication gap creates a dangerous disconnect where executives underestimate risks and underinvest in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lavonne Burke, VP of Legal, Global Security, IT &amp;amp; AI at Dell, succinctly framed the solution during the &lt;a href="https://www.diligent.com/resources/blog/top-20-quotes-cyber-risk-virtual-summit" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Risk Virtual Summit 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: “CISOs must translate risk into a language the board understands. Instead of talking about encryption, explain how it prevents financial and reputational loss.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy: &lt;/strong&gt;Effective CISOs frame every security discussion in business terms. Rather than reporting “critical vulnerabilities,” they explain potential financial impact, customer trust erosion, and regulatory consequences. Dashboards that show risk trends and tie security metrics to business objectives the board already tracks prove far more effective than technical reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;3. Inadequate compliance and governance management&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on research by &lt;a href="https://www.globalscape.com/resources/whitepapers/data-protection-regulations-study" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ponemon Institute and GlobalSCAPE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, regulatory frameworks have evolved from guidelines to legal requirements with teeth. Non-compliance costs organizations 2.7 times more than maintaining compliance, and CISOs increasingly face personal liability under frameworks like GDPR, HIPAA, and emerging AI regulations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regulatory frameworks have evolved from guidelines to legal requirements with teeth. Non-compliance costs organizations 2.7 times more than maintaining compliance, and CISOs increasingly face personal liability under frameworks like GDPR, HIPAA, and emerging AI regulations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Meta (Facebook) &lt;a href="https://www.edpb.europa.eu/news/news/2023/12-billion-euro-fine-facebook-result-edpb-binding-decision_en" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€1.2 billion GDPR&lt;/a&gt; fine serves as a sobering reminder that regulators impose penalties that materially impact business operations — and no company, regardless of size or market position, is exempt from enforcement. CISOs who treat compliance as a checkbox exercise put both their organizations and careers at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; A robust governance framework maps security controls to specific regulatory requirements. Detailed audit trails demonstrating due diligence, regular compliance assessments, and quarterly reports to the board on compliance posture create the documentation necessary to demonstrate organizational commitment to regulatory adherence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern password management solutions like &lt;a href="https://passwork.pro/?utm_source=foundry&amp;amp;utm_medium=article&amp;amp;utm_campaign=freemigration" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Passwork&lt;/a&gt; provide the audit trails and access logs that compliance frameworks demand, giving CISOs concrete evidence of credential governance during audits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;4. Lack of business acumen and strategic alignment&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security leaders who position themselves as cost centers rather than business enablers struggle to maintain executive support. In 2026, boards expect CISOs to understand how security decisions impact market share, customer acquisition, and competitive positioning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Adam Fletcher, CISO, Blackstone: “Cybersecurity isn’t about avoiding risk — it’s about managing it intelligently. The future belongs to leaders who make cyber resilience a competitive advantage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When security becomes a barrier to business initiatives rather than a framework for safe innovation, executives start questioning the CISO’s value.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Leaders who can’t articulate how cybersecurity investments protect and enable revenue growth find themselves sidelined during strategic discussions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Successful CISOs develop a deep understanding of their organization’s business model, revenue streams, and competitive landscape. Early participation in product development discussions allows security leaders to offer guidance that accelerates rather than blocks initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Positioning security as a shared responsibility that enables business objectives transforms the function from cost center to strategic partner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;5. Weak password policies and credential management&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Credential-based attacks remain one of the most common breach vectors, yet many organizations still rely on outdated password policies and inadequate credential management. When breaches trace back to compromised passwords, CISOs face difficult questions about why basic security hygiene wasn’t enforced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Human error in password management creates cascading vulnerabilities. Employees reuse passwords across systems, share credentials through insecure channels, and store sensitive access information in plaintext documents. These practices create entry points that attackers exploit with alarming efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where modern enterprise password managers like Passwork become essential. By enforcing strong, unique passwords and providing a centralized vault, they directly address the root cause of many credential-based breaches. These solutions eliminate the friction that leads employees to adopt risky workarounds while giving security teams visibility into credential usage across the organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://passwork.pro/?utm_source=foundry&amp;amp;utm_medium=article&amp;amp;utm_campaign=freemigration" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Enterprise password management solutions&lt;/a&gt; that combine strong password generation, secure sharing capabilities, and comprehensive audit trails address the root cause of credential-based breaches. Pairing this technology with clear policies and regular training builds a culture where credential security becomes second nature.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;6. High stress, burnout, and leadership fatigue&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 39-month average CISO tenure reflects more than just dismissals. Many security leaders resign under the weight of impossible expectations and relentless pressure. Research shows 84% of CISOs experience high stress levels, with &lt;a href="https://nominet.uk/news/nominet-ciso-stress-report-one-year-on/"&gt;48% reporting&lt;/a&gt; significant mental health impacts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Burnout degrades decision-making quality, reduces strategic thinking capacity, and damages relationships with colleagues. When exhausted leaders become reactive rather than proactive, their performance suffers in ways that eventually lead to dismissal or resignation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy: &lt;/strong&gt;Establishing boundaries and delegating effectively protects against burnout. A strong security team capable of handling day-to-day operations allows the CISO to focus on strategic initiatives. Sustainable performance requires protecting mental health as vigilantly as protecting organizational systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;7. Budget mismanagement and failure to demonstrate ROI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security budgets face constant scrutiny, and CISOs who can’t build compelling business cases for investments struggle to secure necessary resources. When security spending appears disconnected from measurable outcomes, CFOs and boards question whether they’re getting value for their investment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The challenge intensifies when CISOs request budget increases after incidents occur. Executives reasonably ask why previous investments didn’t prevent the breach, creating a credibility gap that’s difficult to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy: &lt;/strong&gt;A risk-based budgeting approach quantifies potential losses from different threat scenarios, creating compelling business cases for security investments. Tracking and reporting metrics that demonstrate how security investments reduce risk exposure, prevent incidents, and enable business growth establishes clear ROI that resonates with financial decision-makers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When presenting budget requests, CISOs can point to concrete improvements like reduced credential-related incidents after implementing &lt;a href="https://passwork.pro/?utm_source=foundry&amp;amp;utm_medium=article&amp;amp;utm_campaign=freemigration"&gt;enterprise password management&lt;/a&gt; — measurable outcomes that CFOs understand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;8. Insufficient staff training and cybersecurity culture&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Technology alone can’t secure an organization. When employees don’t understand their role in security or view it as someone else’s problem, even sophisticated defenses fail. CISOs who neglect culture-building create environments where security policies are circumvented rather than embraced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A divided security culture where different departments operate under inconsistent standards creates gaps that attackers exploit. When security feels like an impediment rather than a shared responsibility, employees find workarounds that introduce vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Effective security awareness programs go beyond annual compliance training. Engaging, role-specific education helps employees understand threats relevant to their work. Security champions in each department who advocate for best practices within their teams create a distributed defense model that scales across the organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;9. Overlooking insider threats&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While external attacks dominate headlines, insider threats represent a significant and often underestimated risk. Whether malicious or accidental, employees with legitimate access can cause devastating damage that’s difficult to detect and prevent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Robust &lt;a href="https://passwork.pro/?utm_source=foundry&amp;amp;utm_medium=article&amp;amp;utm_campaign=freemigration" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;password management solutions&lt;/a&gt; provide detailed audit trails that help identify unusual access patterns without invasive monitoring. When you can track who accessed what information and when, investigating potential insider incidents becomes significantly more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Least-privilege access controls limit employee access based on role requirements, reducing the potential impact of both malicious and accidental insider actions. Behavioral analytics identify anomalous activity patterns that warrant investigation. Comprehensive logs of sensitive data access, coupled with transparency about monitoring practices, balance security needs with employee trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;10. Resistance to change and lack of innovation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The threat landscape evolves constantly, and CISOs who cling to outdated methodologies quickly become ineffective. In 2025, AI-driven attacks, quantum computing threats, and sophisticated social engineering require security leaders who embrace innovation rather than resist it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations implementing Zero Trust architectures, AI-powered threat detection, and cloud-native security models need CISOs who understand these technologies and can guide their adoption. Leaders who view new approaches with skepticism or who lack curiosity about emerging threats lose relevance rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Continuous learning about emerging threats and security technologies keeps security leaders relevant in a rapidly evolving landscape. Industry conferences, peer networks, and relationships with vendors provide insight into coming innovations. A culture of experimentation within the security team encourages adaptation and prevents organizational stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Building a sustainable security leadership career&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO role continues to evolve from a technical position into a strategic business function that requires equal parts security expertise, business acumen, and leadership capability. Success in 2026 requires thinking beyond traditional security operations to become a business leader who specializes in security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The future belongs to security leaders who embrace proactive strategies, leverage modern tools like enterprise password managers to address foundational vulnerabilities, and position security as a business enabler.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Start with the basics: credential management remains one of the most exploited attack vectors, yet it’s also one of the most solvable problems. &lt;a href="https://passwork.pro/?utm_source=foundry&amp;amp;utm_medium=article&amp;amp;utm_campaign=freemigration" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Passwork&lt;/a&gt; eliminates password-related risks while providing the audit trails and governance controls that compliance frameworks demand — giving CISOs both improved security posture and the documentation to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By addressing these ten common failure points systematically, you can build a sustainable career that survives the intense pressures of the modern CISO role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to address credential vulnerabilities in your organization?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://passwork.pro/?utm_source=foundry&amp;amp;utm_medium=article&amp;amp;utm_campaign=freemigration" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Passwork offers a zero-risk transition:&lt;/a&gt; free migration assistance and implementation, pay nothing while your current subscription runs — then get 20% off Passwork when you’re ready to switch. See how centralized password management, detailed audit logs, and secure credential sharing can strengthen your security posture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128090/ten-career-ending-mistakes-cisos-make-and-how-to-avoid-them.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes security advisory (AV26-078)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-079)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-080)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substack data breach leaks users’ email addresses and phone numbers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128287/substack-data-breach-leaks-users-email-addresses-and-phone-numbers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Substack, a high-profile publishing platform widely used by academics, journalists, subject matter experts, and controversialists, has suffered a data breach affecting an unknown number of its creators and subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to emails sent out this week to some users, on February 3 the company “identified evidence” that a third party had exploited an unspecified weakness in the company’s systems to gain access to user email addresses, phone numbers and, more vaguely, “other internal metadata.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The breach happened in October 2025, which means that data, which the company said did not include credit card numbers, passwords, or financial information, has been exposed for up to four months.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We have fixed the problem with our system that allowed this to happen. We are conducting a full investigation, and are taking steps to improve our systems and processes to prevent this type of issue from happening in the future,” &lt;a href="https://lorichristian.substack.com/p/notice-of-data-breach" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said the email&lt;/a&gt; from Substack CEO Chris Best.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We do not have evidence that this information is being misused, but we encourage you to take extra caution with any emails you receive that may be suspicious.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="no-passwords-to-lose"&gt;No passwords to lose&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the time of publication, Substack had not yet made a web announcement about the breach, limiting itself to sending emails to users. This implies that the breach only affects a subset of its estimated 35 million active users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the language of the email alert downplays the incident, describing the exposed data as merely being “shared without your permission.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the fact that the breach was only discovered this week, after a four-month delay, raises the possibility that its scope could yet grow as Substack conducts deeper forensics. A &lt;a href="https://dailydarkweb.net/substack-data-breach-leads-to-leak-of-nearly-700000-records/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;dark web source claimed&lt;/a&gt; the breach compromised 697,313 records, although this remains unconfirmed. It also reported that IDs from payment system Stripe, used by creators to receive payment from their subscribers, were compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on the wording of the email alert sent by the company, the breach only affects users who have Substack accounts; anyone who subscribes to a Substack creator’s newsletter directly using an email address shouldn’t be affected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The full extent of what was exposed is less clear. In addition to email addresses and phone numbers, the company mentioned “metadata,” a catch-all term. In its &lt;a href="https://substack.com/privacy#:~:text=What%20Information%20does%20Substack%20collect" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, Substack describes a wide range of data this might include, depending on how the site is used, including user IDs, profile pictures, biographies, and IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How should Substack users react? Normally, the advice after any data breach is to change the account password. However, Substack’s default access method is &lt;a href="https://faq.substack.com/p/logging-in-to-substack" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;via email address&lt;/a&gt;, with authentication confirmed by sending a “magic link” to the user’s email address. This removes the problem of password compromise and phishing attacks by not having a password to phish. If optional multi-factor authentication is turned on, the user must additionally enter a onetime code from an app.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Passwords are still possible — users who signed up before 2023 might have one — but in 2026, the user must actively choose to create one. The company doesn’t mention whether this subset of users should consider changing their passwords as a precaution, but did offer the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We cannot share specifics about our security systems and processes, but we can confirm that the issue has been resolved and safeguards have been put in place to help prevent this issue from happening again.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Substack’s only other known security incident happened in 2020 when it &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Substack#:~:text=On%20July%2028%2C%202020%2C" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;accidentally exposed&lt;/a&gt; user email addresses by adding them to the “cc” (carbon copy) field instead of the “bcc” (blind carbon copy) of an email when sending out a policy update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128287/substack-data-breach-leaks-users-email-addresses-and-phone-numbers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New APT group breached gov and critical infrastructure orgs in 37 countries</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128378/new-apt-group-breached-gov-and-critical-infrastructure-orgs-in-37-countries.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new cyberespionage group that operates out of Asia has compromised 70 government and critical infrastructure organizations across 37 countries over the past year using a sophisticated toolset that combines phishing, exploitation kits, custom malware, Linux rootkits, web shells, and a variety of other tunneling and proxy tools. Researchers believe the group is expanding its activities and is conducting active reconnaissance on even more targets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Between November and December 2025, we observed the group conducting active reconnaissance against government infrastructure associated with 155 countries,” researchers from security firm Palo Alto Networks said in &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/shadow-campaigns-uncovering-global-espionage/"&gt;a new report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto tracks the group as TGR-STA-1030 (aka UNC6619) and believes it is based in Asia based on language settings, its preference for regional tooling, GMT+8 operating hours, and targeting that aligns with events in the region. The researchers, who have been tracking the group since February 2025, believe it has ties to a nation state.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group’s confirmed victims include national-level law enforcement and border control entities; ministries and departments of interior, foreign affairs, finance, trade, economy, immigration, mining, justice, and energy; elected officials and even a parliament’s infrastructure. The group has also targeted national telecommunications companies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While this group might be pursuing espionage objectives, its methods, targets, and scale of operations are alarming, with potential long-term consequences for national security and key services,” Palo Alto’s researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-phishing-to-exploits"&gt;From phishing to exploits&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto started tracking the group a year ago following a series of phishing campaigns directed at European governments that the company dubbed the Shadow Campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The phishing emails posed as announcements about organizational changes in official institutions and were written in the language of their intended targets. The messages contained links that led to the download of a ZIP archive with a custom malware loader the researchers now call Diaoyu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This loader performs various checks to detect the presence of certain antivirus programs and to ascertain whether it is running in a sandbox. It then proceeds to download the Cobalt Strike implant from a GitHub repository. Cobalt Strike is a commercial penetration testing tool that has grown popular among attackers over the years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although the group hasn’t been observed exploiting previously unknown vulnerabilities to gain access to networks, it has used exploits for known vulnerabilities (N-days) in a large number of software products, operating systems, and libraries, including: SAP Solution Manager, Microsoft Open Management Infrastructure, Microsoft Exchange Server, Pivotal Spring Data Commons, Struts2, Eyou Email System, Beijing Grandview Century eHR Software, Weaver Ecology-OA, Commvault CommCell CVSearchService, Zhiyuan OA, Microsoft Windows, networking products from Ruijieyi Networks and D-Link, and more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“On one occasion, we observed the actor connecting to e-passport and e-visa services associated with a ministry of foreign affairs,” the researchers said. “Because the server for these services was configured with Atlassian Crowd software, the actor attempted to exploit CVE-2019-11580, uploading a payload named rce.jar.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-complex-toolset-of-implants"&gt;A complex toolset of implants&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to Cobalt Strike, the group uses various other malware payloads and command-and-control (C2) frameworks, including VShell, Havoc, SparkRat, and Sliver. On compromised web servers, the attackers deploy a variety of web shells, including Behinder, Neo-reGeorg, and Godzilla.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On Linux servers the group has been seen deploying a rootkit dubbed ShadowGuard, which leverages the Extended Berkeley Packet Filter (eBPF), a powerful feature for running sandboxed code inside the Linux kernel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“eBPF backdoors are notoriously difficult to detect because they operate entirely within the highly trusted kernel space,” the researchers said. “eBPF programs do not appear as separate modules. Instead, they execute inside the kernel’s BPF virtual machine, making them inherently stealthy. This allows them to manipulate core system functions and audit logs before security tools or system monitoring applications can see the true data.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ShadowGuard appears to be a tool that’s unique to this group and allows them to hide processes, files, and directories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To conceal outgoing network traffic from victim networks, the attackers use a variety of relay and proxy servers running tunneling software like the GO Simple Tunnel (GOST), Fast Reverse Proxy Server (FRPS), and IOX, but their C2 servers are typically hosted on virtual private servers (VPS) from the US, UK, and Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="increase-in-targeting"&gt;Increase in targeting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto believes the group is expanding its operations because it has scanned networks of organizations from 155 countries for known vulnerabilities since October. The scans appear to be targeted on IP addresses belonging to government infrastructure and specific targets of interest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, during the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066008/government-shutdown-deepens-us-cyber-risk-exposing-networks-to-threat-actors.html"&gt;US government shutdown that began in October&lt;/a&gt;, the group started scanning the infrastructure of governments in the Americas, including in Brazil, Canada, Dominican Republic, Guatemala, Honduras, Jamaica, Mexico, Panama, and Trinidad and Tobago. The researchers believe the group has already compromised entities in Bolivia, Brazil, Mexico, Panama, and Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group seems to time its targeting to certain events. For example, when the president of Czechia met with the Dalai Lama in August, the group immediately started scanning the computer infrastructure belonging to the Czech Army, police, parliament, and presidency, as well as its ministries of interior, finance, and foreign affairs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“TGR-STA-1030 remains an active threat to government and critical infrastructure worldwide,” Palo Alto said. “The group primarily targets government ministries and departments for espionage purposes. We assess that it prioritizes efforts against countries that have established or are exploring certain economic partnerships.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company’s report includes indicators of compromise, including IP addresses, domain names, and file hashes for the implants used by the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128378/new-apt-group-breached-gov-and-critical-infrastructure-orgs-in-37-countries.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-081)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-082)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-083)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django security advisory (AV26-084)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-085)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV26-086)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-087)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-088)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-089)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV26-090)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV26-091)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV26-092)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-093)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-094)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-095)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
