<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:24:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-689)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-690)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ericsson security advisory (AV25-691)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-692)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-694)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-583) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-695)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for CISOs switching between industries</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079956/tips-for-cisos-switching-between-industries.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From the outside, when someone reaches CISO level, the move to the next role should be easy. After all, they’ve already made it to the top. But many security leaders find the opposite is true. Once they’re in a certain industry, it’s harder to get out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Executives and recruiters often assume a CISO’s experience only translates within their current sector. First Bank CISO Marc Ashworth, whose career has spanned aerospace, healthcare and finance, has seen it happen repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You see people staying within the same industry … it seems like those in the startup world stay in the startup world, those in software development stay there. Once you get to larger enterprises, you tend to stay in those larger enterprises. Whereas, if you’re in a small or medium business, it’s harder to break into a larger enterprise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The perception isn’t arbitrary, rather it’s rooted in how executive hiring works, according to Sal DiFranco, global advanced technology managing partner at talent advisory firm DHR Global. “Back in the day, you stayed in your vertical. You were an industrial person, you were a retail person, you were a telecom person, you were a software person. You stayed in your lane and that’s what it was.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;DiFranco highlights the convergence of technology in the last 15 years has started to shift this perception. He says enterprise technologies has become more standardized across industries, allowing CISOs to move more freely between sectors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Technology has become pervasive across all industries,” he says. But DiFranco warns that opportunity alone isn’t enough, CISOs still need to actively reframe why they’re suitable for a role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So how can CISOs move across sectors successfully, and prove their skills are transferable?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-consulting-to-finding-similarities-between-different-industries"&gt;From consulting to finding similarities between different industries&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building a transferable skill set is essential for those looking to switch industries. For Dell’s first-ever CISO, Tim Youngblood, adaptability was never a luxury but a requirement. His early years as a consultant at KPMG gave him a front-row seat to the challenges of multiple industries before he ever moved into cybersecurity. Those early years also taught Youngblood that while every industry has its own nuances, the core security principles remain constant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I’ve always believed that variety is the spice of life,” he says. “I worked for KPMG for several years, servicing 30 different clients a year in multiple industries, oil and gas, healthcare, financial services, you name it. As my career progressed, I took a lot of those key learnings from my consulting days. I felt comfortable I could go work for any company in any industry and be successful with what I knew.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Like Youngblood, Ashworth’s consulting business became his superpower. He says it gave him the ability to switch from working between different verticals without losing sight of his key objectives of identifying risk and finding solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Youngblood also points to engaging with industry-specific information-sharing and analysis centers (ISACs) whether it be healthcare, financial, retail, or even maritime. “These groups were initiated by the government to enable public-private sector sharing, and it’s a great avenue to take to understand how other industries solve the same problem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From a recruitment perspective, the best shot anyone can have if they’re moving from a consulting background is moving across to a CISO role that’s with one of their clients, which DiFranco says is common. “Because you’re a known commodity and they’ve seen how you work. They’ll be able to say you’re consultative, you’re strategic, and knows how to deliver on a strategy. I’ve seen them in action, and I’m willing to give them a shot to come into the enterprise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs without consulting experience, but who still want to switch verticals, DiFranco recommends identifying sectors with structural similarities or adjacent industries because they’re the easiest transition. He describes this kind of moves as “baby steps” toward a bigger vertical shift.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Take someone from pharmaceutical and put them into a healthcare organization. They’re not the same models, and a lot of things are different, but the infrastructure of those companies, from a technology perspective, are similar. You’re still dealing with the regulated environment and all of the things that go into regulation when it comes to technology.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="understand-and-demonstrate-achieved-results"&gt;Understand and demonstrate achieved results&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making the jump into a new industry isn’t about matching past job titles but about proving you can create impact in a new context. DiFranco says the key is to demonstrate relevance early.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When I pitch a candidate, I explain what they did, how they did it, and what their impact was to their organization in their specific industry,” he says. “If what they did and how they did it, and what their impact was on the organization resonates where that company wants to go, they’re a lot more likely to say, ‘I don’t really care where this person comes from because they did exactly what I want done in this organization’. It’s about the results, but it’s about articulating the results of how you’re going to do it if you come into a different industry.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Youngblood took this approach when he moved from being the CISO at Kimberly-Clark to McDonald’s. “On the outside, everybody sees the golden arches, and they all have the same look and feel,” he says. “But on the back end there are joint ventures, conventional licenses, and country licensees. When you’re the CISO, you have to try and bring everybody together, even though they operate slightly differently.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond operational structures, Youngblood also had to adapt quickly to industry-specific threats. “At T-Mobile, SIM swapping is a huge issue in the telecom industry. Most people don’t realize how frequent it’s happening. It’s a billion-dollar industry, sometimes nation-state funded. Some of them are in the back office and directly taking over the identity of a person, which can cause a lot of damage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Cyber Self-Defense CEO Michael Meline, whose career originally started in law enforcement before he stepped into cybersecurity in financial services and then healthcare, the fastest way to build credibility in a new sector is to deeply understand the risk landscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You’ve got a lot of the same risks, so it really is risk management. I don’t care what field you’re in, my intent in dealing with cybersecurity is to go in, identify the risks, and then build a plan to mitigate them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Demonstrating you understand the risk landscape can give candidates a significant edge. “Outline where you think your skills are transferable from the industry you’re in to what you know about the other industries you might be interested in, and then let’s start talking through examples of what you’ve done in your industry and how we think it can relate to the industries you’re talking about targeting and we would build from there,” says DiFranco.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="avoid-getting-pigeonholed"&gt;Avoid getting pigeonholed&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The biggest career risk for many CISOs isn’t burnout or data breach, it’s being seen as a one-industry operator. Ashworth’s advice is to focus on demonstrating transferable skills. “It’s a matter of getting whatever job you’re applying for, to realise that those principles are the same, no matter what industry you’re in. Whether it’s aerospace, healthcare, or finance, the principles are the same. Show that, and you’ll avoid being pigeonholed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Meline, avoiding being pigeonholed starts before moving into a new industry, by focusing on risk first and then learning about the business. “As I’ve progressed throughout my career, what I’ve discovered is cybersecurity is nothing more than risk management. As a cop, I would identify risk and take the appropriate steps to mitigate it,” he says. “It’s the same thing when I deal with risk in the corporate world. I’m working with stakeholders all the way from the bottom of the organization to the top and collaborating on how we deal with this risk, and then build the right plan to address the risk in a way that meets the needs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, DiFranco says the key is showing relevance and being able to draw parallels across industries. “It boils down to the uniqueness of the candidate and drawing your analogies of how close you are to those other industries.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079956/tips-for-cisos-switching-between-industries.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global experts advance the joint fight against crypto-enabled crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</link>
      <description>The criminal use of cryptocurrency is becoming increasingly professionalised, but so too is the global response. Participants at the 9th Global Conference on Criminal Finances and Cryptoassets emphasised three priorities: developing common standards, deepening cooperation and investing in capacity. These are essential if authorities and industry are to keep pace with evolving threats and recover illicit cryptoassets at scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden hosts naval exercise with 200 special tactics operators</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</link>
      <description>Preparing to fight terrorism on land and seaThe exercise scenario focused on the deployment of special intervention units and naval assets during day- and night-time, simulating terrorist and hostage incidents on board of cruise liners and ferries. Day after day, the participants faced new challenges on the water and on some of the archipelago’s many islands, slowly preparing them for...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake number, real damage: Europol urges action against caller ID spoofing</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</link>
      <description>Europol is calling for a coordinated European response to tackle caller ID spoofing, an in increasingly common tool, used for online fraud and social engineering scams. Caller ID spoofing occurs when criminals falsify the information displayed on phones, making numbers appear legitimate to deceive victims. This practice is driving substantial financial and societal harm, with an estimated EUR 850 million lost worldwide each year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity management for boards: Metrics that matter</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081319/cybersecurity-management-for-boards-metrics-that-matter.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ransomware doesn’t schedule a meeting with your CISO. It hits your core systems, deletes your backups and leaks your data. And while the security team races to contain the breach, your board is left with a more pressing question: How bad is it?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most boards don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Patch counts, firewall logs and threat feeds bury them. None of which says anything about business impact or recovery time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This gap between technical noise and executive insight is dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We expect boards to govern cybersecurity the same way they oversee finance: with clarity, accountability and foresight. But you can’t govern what you can’t measure. And most cyber metrics today are built for engineers, not executives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.informationweek.com/cyber-resilience/measure-success-key-cybersecurity-resilience-metrics#:~:text=%E2%80%9CThese%20include%20mean%20time%20to,preventing%20threats.%E2%80%9D%20Kellerman%20adds." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cyber resilience metrics&lt;/a&gt; translate cyber risk into something boards can act on: financial exposure, operational resilience and readiness for tomorrow’s threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are the only metrics that matter to rewire your boardroom dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cyber-resilience-%e2%89%a0-cybersecurity"&gt;Cyber resilience ≠ cybersecurity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boards love clarity. Traditional security metrics throw vulnerabilities, incidents and patch SLAs at you; numbers that scream “busy” but whisper “value.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.businesstechweekly.com/legal-and-compliance/iso27001-certification/cyber-resilience-vs-cyber-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cyber resilience shifts the conversation&lt;/a&gt;. It asks: How fast can we bounce back? What’s the cost of downtime? Who owns recovery?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security focuses on threats. Resilience measures response and survival is the ultimate goal. That’s the mindset shift boards need.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reporting 1,200 blocked phishing attempts says nothing. But telling the board that your business can recover operations within four hours of a ransomware attack, now that’s a metric.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-does-this-matter"&gt;Why does this matter?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Resilience aligns with your actual business goals: continuity, trust and long-term value. It reflects your appetite for risk and your ability to adapt. And with regulations like DORA and NIS2 pushing accountability higher up the ladder, your board is on the hook.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="financial-impact-and-continuity-metrics"&gt;Financial impact and continuity metrics&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can’t fight cyber chaos with &lt;a href="https://securityscorecard.com/blog/9-cybersecurity-metrics-kpis-to-track/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;technical metrics&lt;/a&gt; alone. Boards speak in &lt;a href="https://peris.ai/post/tracking-the-financial-impact-of-cyber-attacks-on-business-operations#:~:text=Cybersecurity%20is%20no%20longer%20just,track%20and%20mitigate%20risks%20effectively." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;financial impact&lt;/a&gt;, not firewall rules. Here’s what gets attention:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average cost per incident.&lt;/strong&gt; Know your burn rate. A ransomware attack that costs $2M in downtime, recovery and lost customers speaks louder than 400 blocked IPs.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downtime costs&lt;/strong&gt;. How long can you survive offline? Calculate cost per minute for critical systems and quantify risk exposure.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer churn post-incident.&lt;/strong&gt; A breach doesn’t just hit the wallet; it hits reputation. Measure the churn rate 90 days post-breach and tie it to customer trust.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MTTR (mean time to recovery).&lt;/strong&gt; Speed is your insurance policy. Can your team recover operations within SLAs or does every incident spiral into a crisis?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security spend ROI.&lt;/strong&gt; For every dollar spent on controls, what’s the risk reduction achieved? This helps your board back investments with confidence and challenge waste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These metrics turn cyber resilience into business resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="governance-and-compliance-performance-indicators"&gt;Governance and compliance performance indicators&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/training/cyber-governance/Assurance_and_Oversight/NCSC-CyberGovernanceforBoards-AssuranceandOversight-v5.1-Web/index.html#/page/67b88ffde4cc15e24fc12bb0" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cyber governance&lt;/a&gt; isn’t a policy PDF buried in SharePoint. It’s how well your people, processes and partners follow through. And yes, it’s measurable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory violations.&lt;/strong&gt; Fines are the easy part; the real cost is shareholder trust. Track violations, root causes and days to remediation.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training completion rates.&lt;/strong&gt; If only 40% of staff complete phishing training, your most significant risk isn’t external. It’s cultural.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy exceptions.&lt;/strong&gt; Measure how often teams bypass controls. Every exception is a governance blind spot.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party assessments.&lt;/strong&gt; If your vendor can’t spell “MFA,” you’re outsourcing liability, not risk. Track security ratings, SLAs and contract clauses tied to resilience.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maturity assessments.&lt;/strong&gt; Align with NIST, ISO or DORA frameworks. Show year-on-year growth in maturity; don’t just say “we’re improving.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boards don’t need to run the cyber program. They need evidence that it’s working.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="operational-resilience-and-response-effectiveness"&gt;Operational resilience and response effectiveness&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can’t prevent every breach. But how your systems respond when under fire is the actual test of cyber health.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean time to detection (MTTD).&lt;/strong&gt; How long does it take to spot trouble? Faster detection = smaller blast radius.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;False-positive rates.&lt;/strong&gt; If your SOC is drowning in noise, real threats will slip through. Measure alert fidelity.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident escalation time.&lt;/strong&gt; Track how long it takes between detection and decision-making. Lag kills.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critical system uptime.&lt;/strong&gt; Boards care less about alerts and more about outcomes. If core systems stayed online during a breach, that’s the story they need to hear.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response plan testing.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait for a real breach to test your playbook. Run tabletop exercises. Report readiness scores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These are the metrics that move you from panic to poise in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="strategic-risk-and-future-readiness-metrics"&gt;Strategic risk and future readiness metrics&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can’t build resilience looking in the rearview mirror. The smartest boards ask: &lt;a href="https://www.kovrr.com/blog-post/what-cybersecurity-metrics-should-i-report-to-my-board" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Are we ready for what’s next&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Residual risk levels.&lt;/strong&gt; After implementing all controls and mitigations, what remains? Track it. Own it.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat landscape mapping.&lt;/strong&gt; Know your enemies. What trends are shaping your sector? Where are attackers investing? How exposed are you?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security talent retention.&lt;/strong&gt; If your best analysts leave every 12 months, you’re bleeding resilience.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skill gap analysis.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you have the capabilities to handle AI threats? Quantum risks? Deepfake scams? If not, when will you?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovation readiness.&lt;/strong&gt; Every digital transformation brings shadow risk. Boards must monitor security integration across cloud, AI and automation initiatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These metrics future-proof your decisions. They don’t just report risk; they predict it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="if-you-cant-measure-it-you-cant-govern-it"&gt;If you can’t measure it, you can’t govern it&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber resilience is a boardroom imperative, not a side project. But if your metrics still read like a SOC dashboard, you’re measuring the wrong things.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You need metrics that speak your language:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial metrics tell you what risk costs&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Governance metrics show if the culture holds&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Operational metrics reveal real-time resilience&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Strategic metrics test your readiness for tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;And resilience metrics connect it all back to the business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Your job isn’t to become a CISO. It’s to ask sharper questions. Demand clearer answers. Push for metrics that expose blind spots, not bury them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start here:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audit your current board metrics. What do they tell you?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Define 1–2 metrics per category that align with your risk appetite.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Set expectations for reporting cadence and accountability.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Iterate. Improve. Adapt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Metrics don’t just reflect resilience. Done right, they drive it. Ask yourself: If ransomware hit tomorrow, would your board know how strong your cyber posture is?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081319/cybersecurity-management-for-boards-metrics-that-matter.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-666) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Typo hackers sneak cross-platform credential stealer into 10 npm packages</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081790/typo-hackers-sneak-cross-platform-credential-stealer-into-10-npm-packages.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a newly disclosed multi-stage supply-chain campaign, a threat actor published ten typosquatted npm packages that mimicked popular libraries to deploy a cross-platform credential stealer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a Socket analysis, the packages were published on July 4 and had collectively amassed nearly 10000 downloads in four months before being flagged for removal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Each package leverages npm’s postinstall hook to execute immediately upon installation, launching in a new terminal window to avoid detection during the install process,” Socket researchers noted in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once installed, these packages automatically launch a fake CAPTCHA prompt, tricking developers into believing it is part of a legitimate installation process. In parallel, the attack chain fingerprints the victim’s IP address and retrieves a PyInstaller-packed binary designed to harvest credentials from keyrings, browsers, SSH keys, API tokens, and cloud configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="npm-postinstall-script-with-obfuscation"&gt;npm postinstall script with obfuscation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malicious packages exploit a built-in npm lifecycle, the postinstall script, to kick off the attack without any additional user steps. Socket found these packages were designed to detect which operating system they were running on and then automatically open a new terminal window to launch the hidden malware script.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By running the payload in a separate window, the actor masks the activity from install logs, researchers &lt;a href="https://socket.dev/blog/10-npm-typosquatted-packages-deploy-credential-harvester" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the JavaScript payload opens a fake CAPTCHA using Node’s readline and prints convincing messages such as “installing discord.js package..” with realistic version numbers and contributor counts. This social engineering step both delays obvious connections to npm install and can confuse developers and automated defenders into thinking the package is performing benign setup work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Socket’s analysis also showed the JavaScript itself is deeply obfuscated across four distinct layers–an IIFE self-decoder, an XOR cipher keyed from the decoder source, URI encoded payload text, and control-flow obfuscation using mixed numeral bases–making static detection and casual code review substantially harder.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This malware demonstrates multiple advanced techniques rarely seen together in npm supply chain attacks,” the researchers said. “The campaign combines four layers of obfuscation, social engineering via fake CAPTCHA and fake legitimate package installations, and automated execution with no additional user interaction after the fake CAPTCHA prompt.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Payload for IP fingerprinting and credential theft&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once the fake CAPTCHA interaction occurs, the installer sends the victim’s IP address to the attacker’s server, a step that allows tracking, geofencing, and exclusion of unwanted targets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It then downloads the payload from the same host, which is a 24 MB Pyinstaller-packed application that contains hundreds of thousands of strings and multiple binaries, indicating a feature-rich stealer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Socket further analyzed the binaries to perform aggressive filesystem and credential harvest, targeting browser password stores and cookies, SSH keys, OS keyrings (Windows Credential Manager, macOS keychain, Linux SecretService), cloud config files, SDK tokens, and other artifacts that can lead to “long-terms access” to code repositories, cloud consoles, and corporate resources. Exfiltration transfers the data to the threat actor’s host, providing a central collection point for harvested secrets. Socket has published a full list of the ten malicious package names, their hashes, and the attacker’s associated email address to help developers and defenders identify potential compromises.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Popular libraries typosquatted in the campaign include TypeScript, discord.js, ethers.js, nodemon, react-router-dom, and zustand. npm’s popularity has made it a growing target for imposter packages, with abusers conducting massive &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3995813/hackers-drop-60-npm-bombs-in-less-than-two-weeks-to-recon-dev-machines.html"&gt;espionage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053725/massive-npm-supply-chain-attack-hits-18-popular-packages-with-2b-weekly-downloads.html"&gt;supply-chain&lt;/a&gt; attacks in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081790/typo-hackers-sneak-cross-platform-credential-stealer-into-10-npm-packages.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-015 - Vulnerability impacting Microsoft Windows Server Update Services - CVE-2025-59287</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium flaw crashes Chrome, Edge, Atlas: Researcher publishes exploit after Google’s silence</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081831/chromium-flaw-crashes-chrome-edge-atlas-researcher-publishes-exploit-after-googles-silence.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A vulnerability in Chromium’s rendering engine can crash Chrome, Microsoft Edge, and seven other browsers within seconds if exploited by attackers, a security researcher warned after Google ignored his vulnerability report for two months.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jose Pino published proof-of-concept code for the flaw on October 29, potentially exposing more than three billion users to browser crashes and system instability. The vulnerability exploits a fundamental design weakness in Blink, the rendering engine that powers all Chromium-based browsers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The timing raises uncomfortable questions about Google’s vulnerability response process. Pino reported the flaw on August 28 and followed up on August 30. He received no response before deciding to publish his research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I decided to publish this PoC to draw attention to a severe issue affecting broad internet users after my initial report two months ago went unanswered,” Pino said in &lt;a href="https://github.com/jofpin/brash" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;technical documentation published on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. “I believe public awareness is necessary when responsible disclosure does not produce timely mitigation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google, Microsoft, and seven other affected browser vendors, including Opera and Vivaldi, did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-the-attack-works"&gt;How the attack works&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability, which Pino called Brash, exploits the complete absence of rate limiting on document.title API updates in Blink. By flooding the browser with millions of title changes per second, an attacker can saturate the main thread and force a crash.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The attack vector originates from the complete absence of rate limiting on document.title API updates,” Pino wrote in the technical document. “This allows injecting millions of DOM mutations per second, and during this injection attempt, it saturates the main thread, disrupting the event loop and causing the interface to collapse.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The exploit affects Chromium versions 143.0.7483.0 and earlier. Pino tested 11 browsers across macOS, Windows, Linux, and Android. Nine proved vulnerable: Chrome, Edge, Vivaldi, Arc, Dia, Opera, Perplexity Comet, ChatGPT Atlas, and Brave.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Firefox and Safari emerged unscathed. Both use different rendering engines — Gecko and WebKit, respectively — that don’t share Blink’s architectural flaw. All iOS browsers also escaped because Apple requires them to use WebKit, Pino added in the document.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Pino’s testing, the exploit produced a predictable collapse timeline. Zero to five seconds triggered extreme CPU consumption. Five to 10 seconds froze tabs completely. Ten to 15 seconds produced browser collapse or “Page Unresponsive” dialogs. Fifteen to 60 seconds required forced termination.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="beyond-desktop-crashes-enterprise-automation-at-risk"&gt;Beyond desktop crashes: enterprise automation at risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While crashed browsers disrupt individual users, the vulnerability poses greater risks to enterprise automation. Organizations running headless Chromium browsers for AI agents, trading systems, or operational monitoring face potential workflow paralysis, the document stated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pino’s documentation outlined several enterprise attack scenarios. AI agents querying compromised websites could crash mid-analysis, halting automated trading decisions. Fraud detection dashboards could collapse during peak transaction periods.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Web-based surgical navigation systems could fail during critical procedures. “The browser process collapses, stopping the entire analysis pipeline,” according to the research documentation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pino’s proof-of-concept code included scheduling parameters that let attackers trigger crashes at specific times. An attacker could inject the code with a time delay, letting it lie dormant until a critical moment—market opening, shift change, peak operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A critical feature that amplifies Brash’s danger is its ability to be programmed to execute at specific moments,” Pino’s documentation stated. “An attacker can inject the code with a temporal trigger, remaining dormant until a predetermined exact time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-disclosure-breaks-down"&gt;When disclosure breaks down&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google’s silence on Pino’s report highlights persistent tensions in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/550736/responsible-disclosure-cyber-security-ethics.html"&gt;vulnerability disclosure&lt;/a&gt;. Google’s own Project Zero team enforces a strict 90-day disclosure deadline, the industry standard, for vulnerabilities it discovers in third-party software.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company’s &lt;a href="https://chromium.googlesource.com/chromium/src/+/main/docs/security/vrp-faq.md" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chrome Vulnerability Reward Program documentation&lt;/a&gt; pledges to “respond promptly and fix bugs in a sensible timeframe.” It states that most security bugs are automatically opened for public access 14 weeks after fixes are committed to Chromium.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But that timeline assumes vendors respond. Pino received no acknowledgment of his August 28 report. His two-month wait fell well short of the 90-day standard, yet exceeded what many researchers consider reasonable when facing vendor silence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The disclosure debate has raged for years. Microsoft once &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/550236/microsoft-blasts-google-for-vulnerability-disclosure-policy.html"&gt;criticized Google&lt;/a&gt; for publishing Windows vulnerabilities before patches were ready, calling it a “gotcha” that left customers exposed. Yet vendors that don’t respond leave researchers with few options.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pino noted another complication. “The problem is more serious than it seems, since each company that uses Chromium has customized functionalities, which leads me to believe that the fix must be independent for each one,” he said in the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google addressed at least six Chrome zero-day vulnerabilities in 2024, according to the company&lt;em&gt;’&lt;/em&gt;s security advisories. But this architectural flaw in Blink has received no public acknowledgment. The Chromium project’s public issue tracker contained no entries matching the vulnerability as of October 30.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, Brave, and other affected vendors had issued no security advisories by press time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="limited-options-for-enterprise-security-teams"&gt;Limited options for enterprise security teams&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CIOs face difficult choices. The vulnerability affects Blink’s core, so standard browser hardening measures — content security policies, site isolation, extension restrictions — provide no protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pino’s proof-of-concept code remained publicly accessible on GitHub under Creative Commons and MIT licenses. The documentation included disclaimers limiting use to educational and security research in controlled environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He also published a live demonstration at brash.run that executed the exploit against visitors’ browsers. The code included configurable intensity settings ranging from “moderate” observation modes to “extreme” instant collapse configurations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The documentation specified that the exploit would cease working once vendors patched the vulnerability. But without response timelines from Google or other browser makers, enterprise security teams have no way to plan their defenses or communicate risks to business units that depend on browser-based workflows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The silence leaves a critical question unanswered: When vendors don’t respond to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570573/6-tips-for-receiving-and-responding-to-third-party-security-disclosures.html"&gt;properly disclosed vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;, how long should researchers wait before warning the public?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081831/chromium-flaw-crashes-chrome-edge-atlas-researcher-publishes-exploit-after-googles-silence.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening security with a converged security and networking platform</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079505/strengthening-security-with-a-converged-security-and-networking-platform-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today’s IT environment of multiple clouds, hybrid work, and the exploding popularity of AI has given cybercriminals unprecedented opportunities for launching attacks — and the traditional arsenal of tools organizations use to stop them isn’t working.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The network perimeter has disappeared, and every new device, app, cloud connection, and AI tool expands the threat surface. Not surprisingly, the &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/T10b/reports/2025-dbir-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf"&gt;2025 Verizon Data Breach Investigations Report&lt;/a&gt; found a 34% increase in the number of attackers exploiting vulnerabilities to gain network access and cause security breaches. Cybercriminals are also extending their reach by selling ransomware kits on the dark web and blasting out targeted, AI-generated phishing messages and malware at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In response, organizations are doing what they’ve done for years, adding to the dozens of separate point products they use to manage various aspects of security. These range from network security tools like next-gen firewalls, secure web gateways, and intrusion prevention systems to identity and access management systems, endpoint protection platforms, and cloud access security brokers to encryption servers, data loss prevention tools, threat detection and response systems, and more…the list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The irony is, while many of these point systems work well on their own, deploying and managing them separately has &lt;em&gt;created &lt;/em&gt;new security risks. Products are designed with different fundamental security assumptions. Each has a separate security policy and requires a specially trained administrator, making it difficult to coordinate security policies and use products together.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The result is a fragmented security infrastructure with inconsistent rules and poor visibility. Conflicting policies and uneven enforcement create the gaps cybercriminals love to exploit. Teams struggle to identify incoming threats, and critical minutes, hours, or even days elapse as they correlate datasets and develop a response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This system is no match for today’s fast-moving, multifaceted threat environment. To deliver effective protection, organizations need to move from scattered tools to a unified platform. Uniting networking and security on a single platform reduces blind spots and provides full, real-time threat visibility across traffic, users, applications, and devices. When a platform is built right — with security and networking natively integrated — it can react to threats faster and apply inline and consistent policy enforcement in real time — everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, not every “unified platform” lives up to its name, and CISOs must be aware of the differences. Building a fully integrated platform is tough, and many vendors simply bolt together different products that operate separately. Others offer “platformized” solutions, refactoring and integrating acquired products that may work today, but can’t adapt to tomorrow’s innovations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VersaONE, a universal secure access service edge (SASE) platform, takes a different approach with a natively integrated platform that allows security teams to move beyond the limits of fragmented, static tools. Built-in AI continuously correlates massive volumes of network and security data, identifies anomalies and threats across the environment, and responds to incidents at machine speed. A single software stack enforces a unified policy framework for all users, devices, applications, and threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust network access at the heart of the platform ensures that no user, device, or application is implicitly trusted — ever. Instead, access is granted and modified based on real-time factors, such as identity, device posture, and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Additionally, users, devices, and applications are isolated into controlled microsegments, significantly reducing the risk of lateral movement and privilege escalation if an attacker breaches the network.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VersaONE is the future of security — an adaptive, easy-to-use, fully integrated platform. Versa’s Universal SASE approach represents a major leap forward from disjointed point solutions, just as cloud-based software supplanted the old castle-and-moat approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving world of security, can you afford to be left behind with fragmented tools? To learn how VersaONE can dynamically strengthen security while simplifying operations, visit us &lt;a href="https://versa-networks.com/platform/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079505/strengthening-security-with-a-converged-security-and-networking-platform-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malicious packages in npm evade dependency detection through invisible URL links: Report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082195/malicious-packages-in-npm-evade-dependency-detection-through-invisible-url-links-report.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors are finding new ways to insert invisible code or links into open source code to evade detection of software supply chain attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest example was found by researchers at Israel-based Koi Security, who this week said they have &lt;a href="https://www.koi.ai/blog/phantomraven-npm-malware-hidden-in-invisible-dependencies" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;discovered a threat actor’s campaign&lt;/a&gt; that has been running since August, contaminating 126 packages in Microsoft’s npm open source code repository. There have been more than a combined 86,000 installs of these infected packages, and the campaign is continuing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What’s the trick? The bad packages don’t contain malicious code that could be detected by a scanner. Instead, there’s an invisible link to a URL that, when the package is installed by a developer, fetches malicious code from the attacker’s server.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The invisible dependency could be hidden behind a line that simply says ‘Hello.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When you install a package with this kind of dependency, npm fetches it from that external URL,” the researchers note. “Not from npmjs.com, from wherever the attacker wants. And npmjs.com doesn’t follow those URLs. Security scanners don’t fetch them. Dependency analysis tools ignore them. To every automated security system, these packages show “0 Dependencies.” So, to the developer who downloaded an infected package from npm, the package looks safe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-does-it-work"&gt;Why does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This works, say the researchers, because npm supports HTTP URLs as dependency specifiers, so when the malicious package is installed, npm automatically fetches it from the external URL.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The goal: To steal developer GitHub, GitLab, Jenkins and other credentials, and to obtain an outline of the developer’s environment – including public IP addresses, server hostnames, usernames, current directories and node.js version – for further exploitation. The data is then carefully exfiltrated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="campaign-also-exploits-ai"&gt;Campaign also exploits AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The names of packages uploaded to npm aren’t typosquats of common packages, a popular tactic of threat actors. Instead the hackers exploit AI hallucinations. When developers ask AI assistants for package recommendations, the chatbots sometimes suggest plausible-sounding names that are close to those of legitimate packages, but that don’t actually exist. These are the names the threat actor uses. So if a developer asks an AI assistant about a package called ‘eslint-plugin-unused-imports’ the chatbot might suggest the (unknowingly malicious) ‘unusued-imports’ package, and the developer might trust the recommendation and install that package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Koi Security calls the tactic slopsquatting. They call the overall campaign PhantomRaven.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At some point, npm leadership either discovered this campaign on its own or was alerted by other researchers, because in August, 21 packages were removed from the repository. However, after September, 80 additional packages were uploaded. All, Koi Security believes, were clearly controlled by the same person.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="disastrous-flaw-in-npm"&gt;‘Disastrous’ flaw in npm&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a “disastrous” systemic design flaw in npm’s dependency management functionality, &lt;a href="https://shehackspurple.ca/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Tanya Janca&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian secure coding training firm She Hacks Purple Consulting, told &lt;em&gt;CSO. &lt;/em&gt;The lack of validation for dependency URLs bypasses the trust boundary for the Node.js software supply chain, she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Few programming languages allow dependencies to be specified via URLs, and even most of those that do have package managers that block this feature due to security concerns, she said. For instance, she pointed out, it’s allowed in Python, but the open source Python Package Index repository of packages (PyPI) blocks this functionality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The danger of the PhantomRaven attacks is that an threat actor can compromise developer and build systems, rather than end users directly, Janca said. “Because Node.js and npm are used by millions of projects, even a single compromised package can have cascading effects across that entire software ecosystem,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack is called an ‘unvalidated redirect’ [accepting an untrusted URL as data] and was on the &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-project-top-ten/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Open Web Application Security Project’s (OWASP) Top Ten &lt;/a&gt;attacks as far back as in 2013, Janca said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Input validation is the number one most important step in all secure coding practices, and this feature of npm circumventing the developer’s ability to even be aware that this is happening is terrifying. This attack vector is likely to be use by many attackers in the near future until this is removed by npm.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft was asked to comment on the Koi report and asked how it will better secure npm. A spokesperson said they were working on a reply but none had been received by publication deadline.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="invisible-attacks"&gt;‘Invisible’ attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors have been using invisible code to fool defenders in many ways. For example, in August, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4043693/hackers-can-slip-ghost-commands-into-the-amazon-q-developer-vs-code-extension.html" target="_blank"&gt;a security blogger reported&lt;/a&gt; that Amazon’s Q Developer service could be fooled by invisible Unicode Tag characters. In another case, Unicode &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4076668/self-propagating-worm-found-in-marketplaces-for-visual-studio-code-extensions.html" target="_blank"&gt;was used to hide malware&lt;/a&gt; in Visual Studio code extensions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/orenyomtov/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oren Yomtov&lt;/a&gt;, author of the Koi Security report, said that Microsoft should enhance npm’s scanning tools to follow and analyze remote dependency URLs rather than ignoring them. Currently, security scanners don’t fetch HTTP URL dependencies, and dependency analysis tools ignore them, he said, making packages with remote dynamic dependencies appear to have “0 Dependencies.” Microsoft should also require security validation for any externally fetched dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers shouldn’t blindly trust AI tools for package recommendations, he added. As the report points out, when developers ask AI assistants like GitHub Copilot or IDEs like Cursor for package recommendations, the models sometimes suggest plausible-sounding package names that don’t actually exist. PhantomRaven took advantage of this, and created malicious versions of those non-existent packages. “Always verify packages exist on the official npm registry before installation,” he advised, “and audit package.json files for suspicious HTTP URL dependencies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, CSOs should have endpoint visibility into all software types, not just traditional binaries. “PhantomRaven demonstrates how sophisticated attackers exploit blind spots in traditional security tooling, as remote dynamic dependencies aren’t visible to static analysis,” he said. “Implement governance controls across the entire software intake surface, including code packages, extensions, and AI models that traditional MDMs and EDRs miss.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082195/malicious-packages-in-npm-evade-dependency-detection-through-invisible-url-links-report.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered bug hunting shakes up bounty industry — for better or worse</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082265/ai-powered-bug-hunting-shakes-up-bounty-industry-for-better-or-worse.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-powered bug hunting has changed the calculus of what makes for an effective bounty program by accelerating vulnerability discovery — and subjecting code maintainers to ballooning volumes of AI flaw-hunting slop.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security researchers are using large language models (LLMs) to automate reconnaissance, reverse engineer APIs, and scan codebases faster than ever. By applying AI tools to techniques ranging from fuzzing and exploit automation to pattern recognition across codebases and websites, researchers are discovering flaws at accelerated rates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Over the past year, we’ve entered what we call the era of the ‘bionic hacker,’ which is human researchers using agentic AI systems to collect data, triage, and advance discovery,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/crystal-hazen-0x01/"&gt;Crystal Hazen&lt;/a&gt;, senior bug bounty program manager at HackerOne, which has added AI tools to its platform to help streamline submissions and triage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Research by HackerOne found a 210% increase in valid AI-related vulnerability reports this year compared to 2024. It also saw a 339% jump in total bounties paid for AI vulnerabilities this year, as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657751/top-bug-bounty-programs.html"&gt;bug bounty programs&lt;/a&gt; evolve to address vulnerabilities in AI-enabled applications, with prompt-injection flaws, model manipulation, and insecure plug-in design accounting for the majority of findings.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-slop-taxes-defenders"&gt;AI slop taxes defenders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Industry experts advise that AI should only be used as a ‘research assistant’ or guide rather than the principle mechanism of vulnerability discovery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/intidc/?originalSubdomain=be"&gt;Inti De Ceukelaire&lt;/a&gt;, chief hacker officer at bug bounty platform Intigriti, says AI has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3632268/gen-ai-is-transforming-the-cyber-threat-landscape-by-democratizing-vulnerability-hunting.html"&gt;leveled the playing field for hackers&lt;/a&gt; because it can help less skilled researchers to identify potentially vulnerable systems or analyze code for flaws. But the results of AI-based analysis are not always reliable — and this has created practical problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We have seen AI acting as an echo chamber and amplifier for individuals that believe they might be onto something, luring them into a downwards spiral of confirmation bias,” De Ceukelaire tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams dealing with external vulnerability reports will need to be increasingly skeptical of inbound reports that show signs of relying heavily on AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Bug bounty platforms offering triage services could help with this, as they are able to measure the track record of researchers over time, and use in-depth technologies to detect and recognize AI slop before it gets to the company,” De Ceukelaire says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other security experts agree that outcomes of applying AI tools to bug hunting have thus far been mixed, while arguing that problems can be mitigated by careful triage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI tools, when properly applied and validated, do provide high impact findings, but we’re also seeing programs being overwhelmed by huge numbers of reports, most of which are slop, to put it delicately,” says &lt;a href="https://www.procircular.com/people/bobby-kuzma/"&gt;Bobby Kuzma&lt;/a&gt;, director of offensive cyber operations at cybersecurity and compliance consulting firm ProCircular.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Triaging the increasing volume of variable-quality reports generated by some AI tools is putting a strain on under-resourced programs, including those associated with critical open-source software projects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, the curl project — a command-line tool commonly used for downloading files — has put out public entreaties to stop submitting AI-detected bugs. Maintainers of the project complained that they were spending &lt;a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2025/07/14/death-by-a-thousand-slops/"&gt;too much time on low-quality bug reports generated using AI tools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Project lead Daniel Stenberg compared the barrage of unsubstantiated and false reports to a denial-of-service attack. More recently, Stenberg softened his criticism following the submission of some genuine bug reports partly generated by AI tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="firehose-of-false-positives"&gt;Firehose of ‘false positives’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gunterollmann/"&gt;Gunter Ollmann&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at Cobalt.io, warns that AI is exacerbating the existing problem that comes from vendors getting swamped with often low-quality bug submissions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security researchers turning to AI is creating a “firehose of noise, false positives, and duplicates,” according to Ollmann.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The future of security testing isn’t about managing a crowd of bug hunters finding duplicate and low-quality bugs; it’s about accessing on demand the best experts to find and fix exploitable vulnerabilities — as part of a continuous, programmatic, offensive security program,” Ollmann says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/trevorhorwitz/"&gt;Trevor Horwitz&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at UK-based investment research platform TrustNet, adds: “The best results still come from people who know how to guide the tools. AI brings speed and scale, but human judgment is what turns output into impact.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/authors/gal-nagli"&gt;Gal Nagli&lt;/a&gt;, head of threat exposure at cloud security vendor Wiz and a bug bounty hunter, tells CSO that AI tools are yet to make a dramatic difference in bug bounty hunting, at least when it comes to more skilled practitioners. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, researchers who automate infrastructure-based vulnerabilities at scale — like default credentials or subdomain takeovers — already have reliable tooling and detections in place. “AI isn’t needed in those cases,” Nagli says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The real value of AI is in augmenting expert researchers, especially when testing authenticated portals or analyzing sprawling codebases and JavaScript files,” Nagli explains. “It helps uncover vulnerabilities that were previously too complex or subtle to detect without AI.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest generation of models can provide real assistance to skilled bug bounty hunters, not by replacing them, but by enhancing what they’re able to find.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Fully autonomous agents still struggle, especially with authentication and scenarios where human context is critical,” Nagli adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprise-risk-management"&gt;Enterprise risk management&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3619983/bug-bounty-programs-why-companies-need-them-now-more-than-ever.html"&gt;Bug bounty programs&lt;/a&gt; have matured into extensions of enterprise risk management strategies by constantly surfacing real threats before attackers exploit them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security leaders are moving toward continuous, data-driven exposure management, combining human intelligence with automation to maintain real-time visibility across assets, supply chains, and APIs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HackerOne reports 83% of organizations surveyed now use bug bounties, and payouts grew 13% year-over-year, reaching $81 million across all programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As common vulnerability types like cross-site scripting (XSS) and SQL injection become easier to mitigate, organizations are shifting their focus and rewards toward findings that expose deeper systemic risk, including identity, access, and business logic flaws, according to HackerOne.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HackerOne’s latest annual benchmark report shows that improper access control and insecure direct object reference (IDOR) vulnerabilities increased between 18% and 29% year over year, highlighting where both attackers and defenders are now concentrating their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The challenge for organizations in 2025 will be balancing speed, transparency, and trust: measuring crowdsourced offensive testing while maintaining responsible disclosure, fair payouts, and AI-augmented vulnerability report validation,” HackerOne’s Hazen concludes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082265/ai-powered-bug-hunting-shakes-up-bounty-industry-for-better-or-worse.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aembit Introduces Identity and Access Management for Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082320/aembit-introduces-identity-and-access-management-for-agentic-ai.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aembit.io" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Aembit&lt;/a&gt; today announced the launch of Aembit Identity and Access Management (IAM) for Agentic AI, a set of capabilities that help organizations safely provide and enforce access policies for AI agents as they move into production. The release introduces Blended Identity, which defines how AI agents act on behalf of verified users, and the MCP Identity Gateway, which ensures secure access to enterprise resources based on identity, access policy, and runtime attributes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new offering extends the Aembit Workload IAM Platform to address one of the most pressing operational questions in artificial intelligence and modern IT: how to control what autonomous and user-driven AI agents can access, under what conditions, and with what accountability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI agents are rapidly becoming a key part of enterprise operations. Nearly half of technology executives say they are already adopting or fully deploying agentic AI, and about the same share expect most of their AI deployments to be autonomous within two years, according to an &lt;a href="https://www.ey.com/en_us/newsroom/2025/05/ey-survey-reveals-that-technology-companies-are-setting-the-pace-of-agentic-ai-will-others-follow-suit" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;EY survey&lt;/a&gt;. These agents retrieve sensitive data, open tickets, and execute code across cloud, on-premises, and SaaS environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yet most access models were built for people, not self-directed software. Many still rely on static secrets and shared credentials, creating risk and obscuring accountability. Worse yet, agents’ actions are often hidden behind the identity of a human, making it almost impossible to audit the actions each actor has taken. The result is a widening gap between the pace of AI adoption and the ability of organizations to secure it with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aembit.io/product-overview/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Aembit IAM for Agentic AI&lt;/a&gt; assigns each agent a cryptographically verified identity, issues ephemeral credentials, and enforces policy at runtime. The system records every access decision and maintains attribution across both human-driven and autonomous agent activity. By bringing agent activity under the same centralized policy control plane that governs other workloads, Aembit enables enterprises to deploy AI at scale while maintaining control, auditability, and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises want to say yes to agentic AI, and they’re asking Aembit for ways to securely grant agents access to data and applications,” said David Goldschlag, co-founder and CEO of Aembit. “Aembit IAM for Agentic AI gives enterprises the same level of control and audit over agent access that IAM systems have long provided for employees. Our approach enables organizations to advance their AI initiatives without expanding their threat and risk surface.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The release introduces two core capabilities to the Aembit Workload IAM Platform:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blended Identity&lt;/strong&gt;, which gives every AI agent its own verified identity and, when needed, binds it to the human it represents. This establishes a single, traceable identity for each agent action and allows Aembit to issue a secure credential that reflects that combined context.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCP Identity Gateway&lt;/strong&gt;, which receives that identity credential and controls how agents connect to tools through the Model Context Protocol (MCP). The gateway authenticates the agent, enforces policy, and performs token exchange to securely retrieve the necessary access permissions for each connected resource – without ever exposing them to the agent runtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Together, this functionality allows enterprises to apply least-privilege access, revoke permissions immediately when needed, and ensure that every AI action is attributable and auditable. They operate on Aembit’s established Workload IAM foundation, which enforces policy dynamically at runtime, issues ephemeral credentials just in time, and records structured events for full traceability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aembit developed IAM for Agentic AI through collaboration with large businesses, government organizations, and innovative agentic AI startups deploying AI for operational and security workloads. Those efforts helped shape an approach that combines enterprise enforcement with the adaptability AI projects demand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI agents don’t live inside one stack or trust domain,” said Kevin Sapp, co-founder and CTO of Aembit. “They move between hybrid environments in seconds. With Aembit, every agent carries a verified identity that our gateway can authenticate and control in real time. It’s how enterprises can give agents the access they need to work, while never losing sight of who they are or what they touch.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aembit IAM for Agentic AI is now available to customers using its Workload IAM Platform. Organizations can learn more, request a demo, or get started today at &lt;a href="http://aembit.io" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;aembit.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Aembit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aembit.io" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Aembit&lt;/a&gt; is the identity and access management platform for agentic AI and workloads. It enforces access based on identity, context, and centrally managed policies, giving organizations a singular place to control access risk from AI agents, automate credential management, and accelerate AI adoption. With Aembit, enterprises can confidently control access to sensitive resources across all the workloads that power their business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apurva Dave&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aembit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;info@aembit.io&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082320/aembit-introduces-identity-and-access-management-for-agentic-ai.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-696)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-696</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-696</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-697)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-697</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-697</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-698)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-698</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-698</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bug-Bounty-Programm trifft KI – ein zweischneidiges Schwert</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082459/bug-bounty-programm-trifft-ki-ein-zweischneidiges-schwert.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dev AI 16z9" class="wp-image-4082461" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/DC-Studio_shutterstock_2659208607_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;KI-gestütztes Bug Hunting verspricht viele Vorteile. Ob sich diese auch in der Praxis verwirklichen, ist eine andere Sache.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;DC Studio | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Künstliche Intelligenz (KI) wird zunehmend auch zum Treiber von &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/3501141/russlands-problematische-bug-bounty-offensive.html" target="_blank"&gt;Bug-Bounty-Programmen&lt;/a&gt;. Sicherheitsexperten greifen auf Large Language Models (LLMs) zurück, um:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;die Suche nach Schwachstellen zu automatisieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Reverse Engineering von APIs zu bewerkstelligen, und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Code-Basen schneller denn je zu durchleuchten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Allerdings gehen diese Effizienz- und Geschwindigkeitsgewinne in der Praxis mit neuen Problemen einher.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-bug-bounty-filterblase"&gt;Die Bug-Bounty-Filterblase&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Wir haben beobachtet, dass KI als Echokammer und Verstärker für Personen fungiert, die glauben, etwas entdeckt zu haben. Das führt in eine Abwärtsspirale der Bestätigungsverzerrung”, erklärt etwa &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/intidc/?originalSubdomain=be" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Inti De Ceukelaire&lt;/a&gt;, Chief Hacker Officer bei der Bug-Bounty-Plattform Intigriti. Sicherheitsteams, die sich mit externen Schwachstellenmeldungen befassen, sollten KI-generierte Reports deshalb skeptisch betrachten, rät der Sicherheitsexperte. Um fehlerhafte, KI-generierte Bug-Reports zu erkennen, helfen nach Meinung von De Ceukelaire Bug-Bounty-Plattformen mit integrierten Triage-Services: “Solche Plattformen können die Erfolgsbilanz von Research-Experten über einen längeren Zeitraum messen und auch KI-Fehler identifizieren.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Doch selbst wenn Triage an dieser Stelle helfen kann: Besonders Bug-Bounty-Programme, die nicht mit Ressourcen im Übermaß gesegnet sind (Stichwort: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493759/die-10-grosten-open-source-risiken.html" target="_blank"&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt;), werden auch dadurch zusätzlich belastet. Ein Beispiel liefert etwa das quelloffene Projekt Curl (ein Befehlszeilen-Tool, das etwa dazu genutzt wird, Dateien herunterzuladen). Projektleiter Daniel Stenberg beklagt &lt;a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2025/07/14/death-by-a-thousand-slops/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in einem Blogbeitrag&lt;/a&gt;, dass er und sein Team inzwischen viel zu viel Zeit damit verbringen, sich mit minderwertigen, von KI-Tools erstellten Bug Reports zu befassen: “Das Curl-Sicherheitsteam besteht aus sieben Personen. Jeder Report beschäftigt drei bis vier Personen für den Zeitraum von 30 Minuten bis hin zu drei oder vier Stunden.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dass die Ergebnisse, die KI-Tools beim Bug Hunting liefern, bislang eher gemischt ausfallen, bestätigen auch andere Security-Praktiker. Etwa &lt;a href="https://www.procircular.com/people/bobby-kuzma/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bobby Kuzma&lt;/a&gt;, Manager bei der Security- und Compliance-Beratung ProCircular: “Wenn sie richtig angewendet und validiert werden, können KI-Tools aussagekräftige Ergebnisse liefern. Aber es gibt auch Bug-Bounty-Programme, die dadurch von einem Übermaß an Meldungen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493521/false-positives-reduzieren-5-tipps-fur-weniger-security-alerts.html" target="_blank"&gt;überflutet werden&lt;/a&gt;, die – um es vorsichtig auszudrücken – Schrott sind.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dass die Menschen, die diese KI-Tools bedienen, wissen, was sie tun, sieht auch &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/trevorhorwitz/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Trevor Horwitz&lt;/a&gt;, CISO bei der britischen Investment-Research-Plattform TrustNet, als Voraussetzung für erfolreiches Bug Hunting an: “Die besten Ergebnisse erzielen nach wie vor Menschen, die wissen, wie man die Tools einsetzt. KI kann für Geschwindigkeit und Skalierbarkeit sorgen, aber erst menschliches Urteilsvermögen sorgt für nachhaltige Ergebnisse.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/authors/gal-nagli" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gal Nagli&lt;/a&gt;, Head of Threat Exposure beim Cloud-Sicherheitsanbieter Wiz, sieht das ähnlich: “Der wahre Wert der KI liegt darin, erfahrene Forscher zu unterstützen. Besonders, wenn es darum geht, authentifizierte Portale zu testen oder umfangreiche Code-Basen und JavaScript-Dateien zu analysieren. Das hilft, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495294/schwachstellen-managen-die-6-besten-vulnerability-management-tools.html" target="_blank"&gt;Schwachstellen&lt;/a&gt; aufzudecken, die ohne KI bisher zu komplex oder zu subtil waren, um sie erkennen zu können.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vollautonome Agenten hätten in diesem Bereich noch immer Schwierigkeiten, so der Wiz-Manager – besonders in Szenarien, in denen es auf den menschlichen Kontext ankomme. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082459/bug-bounty-programm-trifft-ki-ein-zweischneidiges-schwert.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The unified linkage model: A new lens for understanding cyber risk</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082062/the-unified-linkage-model-a-new-lens-for-understanding-cyber-risk.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/10/hackers-stole-access-tokens-from-oktas-support-unit/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Okta’s support credentials were stolen&lt;/a&gt; in 2023, the breach didn’t stop at the identity provider. It rippled outward — through SaaS integrations, internal legacy applications and downstream development pipelines. Okta’s systems were not directly exploited. Instead, the attack propagated through the quiet linkages that bound those systems together.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most security programs don’t model those linkages. The &lt;a href="https://www.uscybersecurity.net/csmag/unified-linkage-models-recontextualizing-cybersecurity/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;unified linkage model (ULM)&lt;/a&gt; shows why that is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity teams are faced with a considerable volume of data, including asset inventories, vulnerability scans, threat intelligence feeds, SBOMs, configuration alerts and risk dashboards. However, major incidents continue to take organizations by surprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue at hand is not one of visibility, but of structure. Traditional tools concentrate on three main areas: hosts, vulnerabilities and adversaries. Often, the linkages that determine how quickly a vulnerability spreads, how far an attack can extend or how deeply trust can be compromised are not examined.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ULM shifts the analytical lens from individual components to the relationships that bind digital systems together. The modeling of adjacency, inheritance and trustworthiness provides a structural framework that integrates threat modeling, vulnerability analysis and governance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-current-models-fall-short"&gt;Why current models fall short&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most cybersecurity frameworks, including the &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/207/final" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://attack.mitre.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MITRE&lt;/a&gt; frameworks, implicitly treat systems as collections of assets and controls. Risk registers list vulnerabilities and their severities. Threat reports describe attacker TTPs. Architecture diagrams show components and networks. But &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Linked-Everything-Connected-Business-Everyday/dp/0465085733" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;linkages&lt;/a&gt; — how these elements actually interact — are often undocumented, unmodeled and unanalyzed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This blind spot leads to three major problems:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missed systemic risk:&lt;/strong&gt; Organizations secure individual components but miss how vulnerabilities propagate through dependencies (e.g., Log4j embedded in third-party apps).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ineffective prioritization:&lt;/strong&gt; Without a linkage structure, teams patch high-severity CVEs on isolated systems while leaving lower-scored flaws on critical trust pathways.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slow incident response:&lt;/strong&gt; When a zero-day emerges, teams scramble to locate vulnerable components. Without pre-existing linkage models, impact analysis becomes a matter of guesswork.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-unified-linkage-model"&gt;The unified linkage model&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the NIST Zero Trust Architecture and MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK frameworks have a great deal of utility, ULM provides a structural modeling layer. Traditional network diagrams focus on topology; attack graphs, on the other hand, model exploitation steps. ULM focuses on the linkages, the connective tissue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s not a simple topology map or an attack graph; instead, ULM serves as a conceptual backbone to determine both how vulnerabilities propagate and how adversaries move.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="adjacency"&gt;Adjacency&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Adjacency describes what is connected or reachable:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network adjacency (e.g., VLANs, VPNs, cloud peering)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;API connections between services&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Federated identity relationships (e.g., Okta to SaaS)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Inter-organizational data sharing or third-party integrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Adjacency determines how attackers or vulnerabilities can traverse systems. For example, a misconfigured identity provider can act as a high-trust adjacency between external and internal domains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="inheritance"&gt;Inheritance&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Inheritance describes what properties, vulnerabilities or behaviors are passed along chains of dependency or control. For example:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software dependencies: a vulnerable library that affects every application that depends on it.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Identity systems: a compromised credential grants downstream access.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;CI/CD pipelines: a malicious build step is inherited by all artifacts produced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Inheritance explains how a single flaw can cascade through layers — even into domains that didn’t create or deploy the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="trustworthiness"&gt;Trustworthiness&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trustworthiness represents the quality, confidence and resilience of a linkage:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-trust internal SSO connections differ from loosely monitored vendor VPNs.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Implicit trust relationships can be exploited more easily than explicitly verified ones.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Over-trusted adjacencies amplify the impact of both vulnerabilities and adversaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trustworthiness determines the extent of damage that can be caused when a linkage is exploited. A vulnerability in a low-trust, segmented environment may be contained; the same flaw in a high-trust linkage can trigger systemic failure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional network models that rely on static topology or IP-based reachability, ULM abstracts the network as a system of heterogeneous linkages — logical, organizational and functional — not just physical. This allows defenders to model paths that adversaries actually use, such as identity trust chains, software dependencies or implicit API adjacencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ulm-vs-existing-models"&gt;ULM vs. existing models&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are many common cybersecurity modeling approaches between ULM and existing security models. Each contributes to a better understanding of the threat environment while generally addressing a specific aspect — software components, attacker goals, network reachability or vulnerability spread. However, no other model offers a unified structural view. The ULM integrates adjacency, inheritance and trustworthiness, bridging threat intelligence and vulnerability analysis to reveal systemic risk pathways.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-table"&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-table-wrapper"&gt;&lt;table class="has-fixed-layout"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SBOM Dependency Graphs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Static component structure&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Software inventory, license compliance, vulnerability scanning&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack Trees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Logical attacker goals and sub-goals&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Threat modeling&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack Graphs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;State transitions and network reachability&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Penetration testing, lateral movement analysis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerability Propagation Models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;How flaws spread through dependencies&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Blast radius analysis, patch prioritization&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ULM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Structural linkages: adjacency, inheritance, trustworthiness&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Integrating threat and vulnerability views; systemic risk analysis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ULM is not dependent upon a single phenomenon. It can describe software supply chains, network topologies, identity infrastructures and organizational relationships using a common vocabulary of linkages. This flexibility makes it a robust foundation for integrating threat assessments, vulnerability analyses and architectural models.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The novelty of ULM is not in listing vulnerabilities or threats — those are known concepts. The novelty is in modeling the enterprise through linkages that integrate functional, inherited and trust relationships. This sits between network topology (routers, VLANs, IPs) and attack graphs (threat paths) — and that’s exactly what most organizations lack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-simple-example-okta-and-beyond"&gt;A simple example: Okta and beyond&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most enterprises are hybrid, with numerous internal and external dependencies. The Okta breach began with stolen support credentials, allowing attackers to access the identity provider’s high-trust connections. In that instance, the hybrid enterprise environment included the following key elements:   &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An external identity provider (IdP), in this instance, Okta, for authentication.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Several SaaS applications integrated via SSO.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Internal legacy applications that trust assertions from the IdP without extra validation.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A development pipeline pulling open-source libraries into both internal and SaaS extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An attacker compromised the IdP through stolen credentials. Through those adjacencies, they reached SaaS and internal applications. Inheritance extended the compromise downstream, amplifying impact without exploiting individual vulnerabilities — illustrating how structural linkages, not isolated flaws, can drive widespread organizational exposure. Because the IdP operated in a high-trust zone, its compromise had a multiplying effect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analyzed from a vulnerability perspective, none of the internal apps may have had critical CVEs. From a threat intel perspective, the attacker profile was known. A linkage perspective could have been useful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="strategic-benefits-of-ulm"&gt;Strategic benefits of ULM&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A linkage perspective exposes how attackers move along trusted connections, chaining adjacencies and inherited dependencies to bypass hardened perimeters. By mapping structural relationships — identity trust, software supply chains and implicit integrations — defenders can see hidden pathways that static vulnerability lists or isolated threat intelligence miss, revealing true systemic exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ULM provides a structural foundation for:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better prioritization:&lt;/strong&gt; Focus defenses where vulnerabilities and attacker pathways intersect.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faster impact analysis:&lt;/strong&gt; Overlay new vulnerabilities on existing linkage maps to find exposures quickly.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat–vulnerability integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Link threat TTPs to adjacency and trust pathways; map vulnerabilities onto inherited components.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-domain insight:&lt;/strong&gt; Describe IT, OT, identity and supply chains in one framework.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A new lens on network structure:&lt;/strong&gt; Reframe networks as linkage graphs, not just nodes and edges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="getting-started"&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Getting started with the ULM involves shifting perspective from isolated assets to the relationships that bind systems together. Before mapping, organizations should understand that linkages — adjacency, inheritance and trustworthiness — form the backbone of systemic risk analysis, enabling more strategic, integrated and anticipatory cybersecurity decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inventory linkages, not just assets&lt;/strong&gt;. Map adjacencies (network connections, API integrations) and inheritance paths (identity, software dependencies).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assess trustworthiness explicitly.&lt;/strong&gt; Identify which linkages are implicitly trusted versus explicitly verified.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overlay vulnerability and threat data.&lt;/strong&gt; Use scans, SBOMs and intel to find intersections.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize and scenario-plan.&lt;/strong&gt; Ask: Which inherited vulnerabilities sit on high-trust adjacencies? Which adversaries can exploit them?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iterate and integrate.&lt;/strong&gt; Over time, fold ULM maps into dashboards, incident response and tabletop exercises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-more-thorough-systemic-approach"&gt;A more thorough systemic approach&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers exploit the spaces between — not just the endpoints. The unified linkage model offers a systematic approach to analyzing the structural spaces where threats intersect vulnerabilities. By modeling networks through linkages rather than infrastructure, ULM offers CISOs a fundamentally new way to understand how digital systems behave under stress — whether from vulnerabilities, adversaries or both.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story was adapted from my longer article in the fall 2025 edition of “United States Cybersecurity Magazine,” &lt;a href="https://www.uscybersecurity.net/csmag/unified-linkage-models-recontextualizing-cybersecurity/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Unified Linkage Models: Recontextualizing Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;. Additional details are available in the original article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082062/the-unified-linkage-model-a-new-lens-for-understanding-cyber-risk.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–699)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-700)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI launches Aardvark to detect and patch hidden bugs in code</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082497/openai-launches-aardvark-to-detect-and-patch-hidden-bugs-in-code.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI has unveiled Aardvark, a GPT-5-powered autonomous agent designed to act like a human security researcher capable of scanning, understanding, and patching code with the reasoning skills of a professional vulnerability analyst.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Announced on Thursday and currently available in private beta, Aardvark is being positioned as a major leap toward AI-driven software security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike conventional scanners that mechanically flag suspicious code, Aardvark attempts to analyze how and why code behaves the way it does. “OpenAI Aardvark is different as it mimics a human security researcher,” said Pareekh Jain, CEO at EIIRTrend. “It uses LLM-powered reasoning to understand code semantics and behavior, reading and analyzing code the way a human security researcher would.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By embedding itself directly into the development pipeline, Aardvark aims to turn security from a post-development concern into a continuous safeguard that will evolve with the software itself,  Jain added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;From code semantics to validated patches&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What makes Aardvark unique, OpenAI noted, is its combination of reasoning, automation, and verification. Rather than simply highlighting potential vulnerabilities, the agent promises multi-stage analysis–starting by mapping an entire repository and building a contextual threat model around it. From there, it continuously monitors new commits, checking whether each change introduces risk or violates existing security patterns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Additionally, upon identifying a potential issue, Aardvark attempts to validate the exploitability of the finding in a sandboxed environment before flagging it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This validation step could prove transformative. Traditional static analysis tools often overwhelm developers with false alarms–issues that may look risky but aren’t truly exploitable. “The biggest advantage is that it will &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571649/5-tips-for-reducing-false-positive-security-alerts.html"&gt;reduce false positives&lt;/a&gt; significantly,” noted Jain. “It’s helpful in open source codes and as part of the development pipeline.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once a vulnerability is confirmed, Aardvark integrates with &lt;a href="https://chatgpt.com/en-IN/features/codex/?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=paidsearch_brand&amp;amp;utm_campaign=GOOG_B_SEM_GBR_Codex_TEM_BAU_ACQ_PER_MIX_ALL_APAC_IN_EN_102925&amp;amp;utm_term=codex%20openai&amp;amp;utm_content=188506859260&amp;amp;utm_ad=781429313176&amp;amp;utm_match=e&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gad_campaignid=23197178085&amp;amp;gbraid=0AAAAA-I0E5f6LHgIjPh9AuJjJqrUD7iQ5&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwvJHIBhCgARIsAEQnWlDdfysb3h7kcd3blAwQm9Y8es0zvHVo-7H347u7-PBC1UrC3_m6DQQaAsy9EALw_wcB"&gt;Codex&lt;/a&gt; to propose a patch, then re-analyzes the fix to ensure it doesn’t introduce new problems. OpenAI claims that in benchmark tests, the system identified 92 percent of known and synthetically introduced vulnerabilities across test repositories–a promising indication that AI may soon shoulder part of the burden of modern code auditing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Securing open source and shifting security left&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aardvark’s role extends beyond enterprise environments. OpenAI has already deployed it across open-source repositories, where it claims to have discovered multiple real-world vulnerabilities, ten of which have received official CVE identifiers. The LLM giant said it plans to provide pro-bono scanning for selected non-commercial open-source projects, under a coordinated disclosure framework that gives maintainers time to address the flaws before public reporting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This approach aligns with a growing recognition that software security isn’t just a private-sector problem, but a&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570779/the-shared-responsibility-model-explained-and-what-it-means-for-cloud-security.html"&gt; shared ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; responsibility. “As security is becoming increasingly important and sophisticated, these autonomous security agents will be helpful to both big and small enterprises,” Jain added. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI’s announcement also reflects a broader industry concept known as “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/997815/secure-from-the-get-go-top-challenges-in-implementing-shift-left-cybersecurity-approaches.html"&gt;shifting security left&lt;/a&gt;,” embedding security checks directly into development, rather than treating them as end-of-cycle testing. With over 40,000 CVE-listed vulnerabilities reported annually and the global software supply chain under constant attack, integrating AI into the developer workflow could help balance velocity with vigilance, the company added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082497/openai-launches-aardvark-to-detect-and-patch-hidden-bugs-in-code.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-701)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Tomcat security advisory (AV25-702)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV25-703)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese hackers target Western diplomats using hard-to-patch Windows shortcut flaw</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082701/chinese-hackers-target-western-diplomats-using-hard-to-patch-windows-shortcut-flaw.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chinese hackers have been spotted targeting European diplomats using a longstanding Windows shortcut vulnerability that’s been popular with threat groups as far back as 2017.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to security company &lt;a href="https://arcticwolf.com/resources/blog/unc6384-weaponizes-zdi-can-25373-vulnerability-to-deploy-plugx/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Arctic Wolf&lt;/a&gt;, whose researchers uncovered the latest campaign, the latest attacks saw spear phishing emails sent to officials working for the governments of Hungary, Belgium, Serbia, Italy, and The Netherlands during September and October.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Chinese government-operated group suspected of being behind the campaign is named UNC6384 by the Google Threat Intelligence Group (GTIG). The same group is believed to have targeted diplomats of several Asian countries earlier in 2025, which might give the impression that UNC6384 is a recently discovered threat actor, hence its UNC (“uncategorized”) status.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, Arctic Wolf said it believed the group’s tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) strongly resemble those of a known Chinese threat group, “Mustang Panda,” which has been around since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the face of it, this looks like just another Chinese cyber-espionage campaign against foreign governments. But there is a deeper story: the Windows vulnerability used in the campaign, which Microsoft has so far been unwilling – or unable – to patch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ghost-flaw"&gt;Ghost flaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Arctic Wolf, the latest campaign used spear phishing emails with diplomatic themes to lure targets into executing malicious Windows .LNK shortcut files. The vulnerability stems from a flaw in Windows UI parsing that allows command-line instructions to be hidden in &lt;a href="https://detection.fyi/sigmahq/sigma/windows/process_creation/proc_creation_win_susp_lnk_exec_hidden_cmd/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;.LNK format whitespace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This allows the attackers to launch a sequence of malicious actions while displaying a decoy PDF showing the agenda for a genuine European Commission meeting scheduled to have been held in Brussels on September 26. The result is the deployment of the PlugX remote access Trojan, which has been popular since 2008 as a tool for opening backdoors into Windows systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trend Micro told Microsoft about the weakness in September 2024, after which it was given a &lt;a href="https://cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-9491" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-9491&lt;/a&gt; identifier. However, it turns out that the company’s Zero Day Initiative (ZDI) had noticed the same issue in 2017, when it was given a separate internal ‘candidate’ identifier, &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/c/windows-shortcut-zero-day-exploit.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ZDI-CAN-25373&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The vulnerability has been exploited by state-sponsored APT groups from North Korea, Iran, Russia, and China,” said Trend Micro in a &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en/research/25/c/windows-shortcut-zero-day-exploit.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;March 2018 blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite there being a formal CVE, Microsoft appears reluctant to address the issue. As Trend Micro noted in a more recent blog from 2025, “We submitted a proof-of-concept exploit through Trend ZDI’s bug bounty program to Microsoft, who declined to address this vulnerability with a security patch.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That reluctance probably stems from the fact that CVE-2025-9491/ZDI-CAN-25373 would be difficult to patch without breaking legacy applications that depend on its current design.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mitigation"&gt;Mitigation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the absence of a patch, organizations worried about .LNK attacks should consider blocking .LNK files or disabling their execution in Windows Explorer, Arctic Wolf advised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This should be put in place across all Windows systems, prioritizing endpoints used by personnel with access to sensitive diplomatic or policy information. While this vulnerability was disclosed in March 2025, adoption by threat actors within months of disclosure necessitates urgent monitoring and countermeasures,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations could also block the command and control (C2) domains used by attackers, although these will change over time. In addition, Arctic Wolf recommends that IT teams search for the presence of Canon printer assistant utilities such as &lt;em&gt;cnmpaui.exe&lt;/em&gt;, which are part of the campaign’s exploit chain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; “The breadth of targeting across multiple European nations within a condensed timeframe suggests either a large-scale coordinated intelligence collection operation or deployment of multiple parallel operational teams with shared tooling but independent targeting,” Arctic Wolf noted, adding that the fact that UNC6384 had jumped on the flaw so quickly since it was made public earlier in 2025 suggested that the group had access to advanced capabilities and resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s not as if attacks exploiting Windows shortcut files in different ways are terribly new or innovative. During 2025, they’ve been abused in different ways by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3987073/after-helping-russia-on-the-ground-north-korea-targets-ukraine-with-cyberespionage.html" target="_blank"&gt;Russian cyber-campaigns&lt;/a&gt; against Ukraine, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3986671/stealth-rat-uses-a-powershell-loader-for-fileless-attacks.html" target="_blank"&gt;Chinese attacks&lt;/a&gt; using the Remcos RAT, and to target companies in the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3837964/polyglot-files-used-to-spread-new-backdoor.html" target="_blank"&gt;United Arab Emirates (UAE)&lt;/a&gt;. In June the technique was used to hide payloads in attacks abusing the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4009636/phishing-campaign-abuses-cloudflare-tunnels-to-sneak-malware-past-firewalls.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cloudflare Tunnel service&lt;/a&gt;. The issue is really that this type of flaw, which exploits an otherwise useful feature, is simply difficult to patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082701/chinese-hackers-target-western-diplomats-using-hard-to-patch-windows-shortcut-flaw.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-704)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-705)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-705</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-705</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-706)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-016 Internet-accessible industrial control systems (ICS) abused by hacktivists</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-707)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker security advisory (AV25–708)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV25-693) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-709)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-710)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-629) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-711)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress security advisory (AV25-712)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-713)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
