<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:27:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-006)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-007)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV26-008)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity at the state and local level: Washington has the framework, it’s time to act</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116303/cybersecurity-at-the-state-and-local-level-washington-has-the-framework-its-time-to-act.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The White House’s March 2025 Executive Order (EO) on “&lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/achieving-efficiency-through-state-and-local-preparedness/"&gt;Achieving Efficiency Through State and Local Preparedness&lt;/a&gt;” raised an issue of utmost importance for national security and our critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As noted in the order, “federal policy must rightly recognize that preparedness is most effectively owned and managed at the state, local and even individual levels, supported by a competent, accessible and efficient federal government.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite claims from various cybersecurity leaders that the March EO is a federal retreat on information technology security, has funding gaps and lacks implementation clarity and expertise at the local level, the president is correct: Local jurisdictions are best positioned to anticipate their electronic security needs, understand their unique weaknesses, vulnerabilities and risks, and are best suited to develop and implement an incident response, mitigation and recovery plan based on their unique circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Congress is right, too. In 2021, it established the State and Local Cybersecurity Grant Program (SLCGP) to “award grants to eligible entities to address cybersecurity risks and cybersecurity threats to information systems owned or operated by, or on behalf of, state, local or tribal governments.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SLCGP authorizes $1 billion over four years to help state, local, tribal and territorial governments reduce systemic cyber risks and requires a pass-through of at least 80 percent of those funds to local governments, while reserving 25 percent of those funds for rural jurisdictions. A key component of the SLCGP ties any disbursement of funds to the Cybersecurity Infrastructure and Security Agency’s (CISA) approval of a state’s cybersecurity plan. That proposal must meet the requirements set forth in the SLCGP, such as implementation of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) cybersecurity framework.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This September, the Homeland Security Committee — with bipartisan support — introduced the Protecting Information by Local Leaders for Agency Resilience Act(PILLAR Act, H.R. 5078), which seeks to not only extend SLCGP for 10 years, but also provide long‑term stability and funding, strengthen milestone‑based accountability, expand its scope to AI and operational technology, and clarify cost‑sharing between federal and state governments. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Combined, the March 2025 EO and the SLCGP create a framework that will succeed if implemented in tandem. Unfortunately, that’s not what happened. In January 2025, the Office of Management and Budget directed all federal agencies to “temporarily pause all activities related to obligations or disbursement of all federal financial assistance.” This effectively ended all SLCGP disbursements and left it and the EO as unfunded mandates. But that’s not quite where this story ends. As part of the re-opening of the government in November, the SLCGP was potentially resurrected when its authorization was extended to January 30. This is a crucially important development. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to act and bring SLCGP fully back to life through the PILLAR Act. With our adversaries already embedded in our critical infrastructure (see Salt and Volt Typhoon, advanced persistent threat actors tied to China’s government), and the recent deployment of AI as a cyber-super-weapon — as demonstrated by Anthropic’s recent announcement of how its Claude AI was manipulated by Chinese state-sponsored hackers to conduct a large-scale attack executed almost entirely by AI agents — states and local jurisdictions are even more vulnerable. This is not simply a matter of funding; it’s a matter of national security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There should not be much debate as to whether states will utilize SLCGP effectively; they already have the data. As of August 1, 2024, according to the Government Accountability Office, “the Department of Homeland Security provided approximately $172 million in grants to 33 states and territories” and “[t]he grants are funding 839 state and local cybersecurity projects that align with core cybersecurity functions as defined by [NIST],” including developing cybersecurity plans and policies, employing cybersecurity contractors, upgrading equipment and implementing multi-factor authentication. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The passage of the PILLAR Act will also enhance CISA’s reach, even with its reduced workforce and limited resources, by making it a force multiplier because it can now focus on oversight — approving state cybersecurity tactics, setting standards and guiding and monitoring priorities — while state, local and tribal governments execute the day-to-day implementation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not mentioned in the PILLAR Act, but something practical and easily executed as part of the SLCGP, is local governments partnering with private and public universities to tap into a pipeline of students trained in cybersecurity strategy (e.g., law, policy, risk management, governance) and emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, resulting in lower costs for the local governments, hands-on experience for students and community building and outreach between local governments and universities. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The PILLAR Act has bipartisan support, and the president’s March 2025 EO reinforces everything contained within it. We now have the framework for securing our state, local and tribal governments. Let’s get this done immediately, as the stakes have never been higher and our national security depends on it. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116303/cybersecurity-at-the-state-and-local-level-washington-has-the-framework-its-time-to-act.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical flaw in AWS Console risked compromise of build environment</title>
      <link>https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/critical-flaw-in-aws-console-risked-compromise-of-build-environment/809745/</link>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgproxy.divecdn.com/fBBVrlGndvm29LNxlcSCPW7oy7U5n8taGo5PnGz9qZc/g:ce/rs:fill:1600:900:1/Z3M6Ly9kaXZlc2l0ZS1zdG9yYWdlL2RpdmVpbWFnZS9HZXR0eUltYWdlcy0xMjI0NTAwNDU3LmpwZw==.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CodeBreach&amp;nbsp;vulnerability could have enabled a massive supply chain attack, researchers warn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/critical-flaw-in-aws-console-risked-compromise-of-build-environment/809745/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:54:51 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike to add browser security to Falcon with Seraphic acquisition</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116703/crowdstrike-to-add-browser-security-to-falcon-with-seraphic-acquisition.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CrowdStrike has agreed to acquire Israel-based Seraphic Security, a browser runtime security company, to extend its Falcon platform to browser-native enterprise security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Expected to close by April, the acquisition will allow CrowdStrike to integrate Seraphic’s browser-native protection with its Falcon endpoint telemetry and threat intelligence capabilities. The move comes just days after CrowdStrike announced plans to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114957/crowdstrike-to-acquire-sgnl-for-740m-expanding-real-time-identity-security.html" target="_blank"&gt;acquire&lt;/a&gt; SGNL, a continuous identity authorization company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="browser-as-attack-surface"&gt;Browser as attack surface&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With web browsers increasingly serving as the primary interface for enterprise work, communication, SaaS applications, and AI tools, they are emerging as one of the most exposed layers in corporate IT environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Traditional endpoint controls like EDR focus on the OS level and miss in-session browser activity, while network tools like firewalls can’t inspect HTTPS-encrypted sessions or user actions within apps. They lack visibility into browser telemetry, shadow IT, malicious extensions, and data flows, leaving gaps that attackers exploit via phishing, session hijacking, and zero-days,” said &lt;a href="https://ankura.com/experts-and-advisors/amit-jaju" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amit Jaju&lt;/a&gt;, global partner/senior managing director – India at Ankura Consulting. He added that web browsers pose risks even in controlled environments because they inherently process untrusted internet code, enabling zero-day exploits, malicious extensions acting as supply chain attacks, and credential theft that bypasses perimeter defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CrowdStrike &lt;a href="https://ir.crowdstrike.com/news-releases/news-release-details/crowdstrike-acquire-seraphic-turning-any-browser-secure" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the Seraphic acquisition will allow it to extend the Falcon platform deeper into in-browser activity.  With Seraphic, the company aims to transform the SOC by correlating trillions of endpoint signals with deep, in-session browser telemetry. This will allow the Falcon platform to understand user intent, application context, and data flow in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Seraphic’s true USP lies in its ability to make the browser session itself a governable security surface, rather than treating the browser as a passive extension of the endpoint,” said &lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research. “Most enterprise security stacks stop at device health and identity validation. They confirm who logged in and from what device, but they lose visibility once the user begins interacting inside SaaS applications. Seraphic addresses this by enforcing policy inside the live browser session, covering user actions, session behaviour, and data movement that never touches disk and never triggers network anomalies. When integrated into CrowdStrike Falcon, it moves from detecting threats around user activity to governing behaviour during it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="gen-ai-altering-browser-risk"&gt;Gen AI altering browser risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Generative AI has fundamentally altered the browser risk profile. Gogia noted that the browser is now a bidirectional data exchange, where employees routinely feed sensitive context into AI systems. Most of this activity happens outside formal enterprise governance. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Copying internal data into AI prompts, uploading files for summarisation, or using AI-enhanced browser features has become one of the fastest-growing data leakage paths in organisations. As a result, browser-level enforcement is one of the few practical ways to address this without resorting to unrealistic bans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CrowdStrike will also integrate SGNL’s continuous authorization technology, enabling permissions to be dynamically granted or revoked on a per-session and risk-level basis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The two solutions combined will create what the company described as a unified security fabric.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The integration will be designed to secure how generative AI applications and agents are accessed, to prevent shadow AI tools from scraping or exfiltrating sensitive enterprise data. It will also aim to prevent the copying, uploading, or screen-grabbing of sensitive data using AI-based content filtering and granular execution-layer controls, stop session hijacking, sophisticated phishing, and man-in-the-browser attacks at the point of execution by randomizing the browser’s JavaScript engine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, CrowdStrike will extend protection to unmanaged and BYOD devices by securing the browser session without requiring a full endpoint agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116703/crowdstrike-to-add-browser-security-to-falcon-with-seraphic-acquisition.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpyCloud Launches Supply Chain Solution to Combat Rising Third-Party Identity Threats</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116536/spycloud-launches-supply-chain-solution-to-combat-rising-third-party-identity-threats.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpyCloud&lt;/a&gt;, the leader in identity threat protection, today announced the launch of its &lt;strong&gt;Supply Chain Threat Protection&lt;/strong&gt; solution, an advanced layer of defense that expands identity threat protection across the extended workforce, including organizations’ entire vendor ecosystems. Unlike traditional third-party risk management platforms that rely on external surface indicators and static scoring, &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/products/supply-chain-threat-protection/?utm_medium=pr&amp;amp;utm_source=cybernewswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=supply-chain-launch-2026" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpyCloud Supply Chain Threat Protection&lt;/a&gt; provides timely access to identity threats derived from billions of recaptured breach, malware, phished, and combolist data assets, empowering organizations – from enterprise security teams to public sector agencies – to act on credible threats rather than simply observe and accept risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Supply Chain Threat Protection addresses a critical gap in enterprise security: the inability to maintain real-time awareness of identity exposures affecting third-party partners and vendors. According to the 2025 Verizon Data Breach Investigations Report, &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/blog/verizon-2025-data-breach-report-insights/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;third-party involvement in breaches&lt;/a&gt; doubled year-over-year, jumping from 15% to 30% primarily due to software vulnerabilities and weak security practices. As supply chain compromises continue to escalate, security teams need intelligence that goes beyond questionnaires and external scans to reveal active threats like phishing campaigns targeting their trusted partners, confirmed credential theft, and malware-infected devices exposing critical business applications to criminals. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/wo7MqWbUCZ4?utm_medium=pr&amp;amp;utm_source=cybernewswire&amp;amp;utm_content=video&amp;amp;utm_campaign=supply-chain-launch-2026"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video"&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For government agencies and critical infrastructure operators, supply chain threats present national security risks that demand heightened vigilance. Public sector organizations managing sensitive data and critical services increasingly rely on contractors and technology vendors whose compromised credentials could provide adversaries with pathways into classified systems or essential infrastructure. Last year alone, the top 98 &lt;a href="https://engage.spycloud.com/rs/713-WIP-737/images/spycloud-2025-infographic-DIB.pdf?_gl=1*29lkhl*_gcl_au*MzgxMTg0NjkyLjE3NjE5MjE3NTg." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Defense Industrial Base suppliers&lt;/a&gt; had over 11,000 dark web exposed credentials – an 81% increase from the previous year. SpyCloud Supply Chain Threat Protection enables federal, state, and local agencies to identify when suppliers or contractors have been compromised – allowing them to take proactive measures before an identity exposure escalates into a matter of national security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Third-party threats have evolved far beyond what traditional vendor assessment tools can detect,” said Damon Fleury, Chief Product Officer at SpyCloud. “Public and private sector organizations need to know when their vendors’ employees are actively compromised by malware or phishes, when authentication data is circulating on the dark web, and which partners pose the greatest real downstream threat to their business. Our new solution delivers those signals by transforming raw underground data into clear, prioritized actions that security teams use to protect their organization.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Supply Chain Threat Protection enables organizations and agencies to continuously monitor thousands of suppliers, with each company’s threats enumerated in detail, and also represented in an at-a-glance Identity Threat Index. The Index is a comprehensive and continuously updated analysis that quantifies vendor security posture through the lens of identity exposure, from both active and historical phishing, breach, and malware sources, and surfaces which partners pose the most significant risk based on verified dark web intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Capabilities Include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real Evidence of Compromise:&lt;/strong&gt; Timely recaptured identity data from breaches, malware, and successful phishes collected continuously from the criminal underground, with context that gives security teams enhanced visibility into the identity threats facing suppliers today.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Threat Index:&lt;/strong&gt; Aggregates multiple verified data sources weighted by the recency, volume, credibility, and severity of compromise, emphasizing verified identity data over static breach records for more robust and real-time visibility into vendor risk.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compromised Applications&lt;/strong&gt;: Identifies the internal and third-party business applications exposed on malware-infected supplier devices to support deeper investigation and risk assessment.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Vendor Management and Communications:&lt;/strong&gt; Facilitates sharing of actionable evidence and detailed executive-level reports directly with vendors to collaboratively improve security posture, transforming vendor relationships from adversarial scoring to collaborative protection.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated Response: &lt;/strong&gt;Leveraging SpyCloud’s console, teams now have access to identity threat protection beyond the traditional employee perimeter with this extension to suppliers, allowing analysts to respond to workforce identity threats within a single tool. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpyCloud Supply Chain Threat Protection is designed to support multiple use cases across Security Operations, Infosec, Vendor Risk Management, and GRC teams. Organizations can leverage the solution for vendor due diligence during procurement and onboarding, continuous risk reviews to strengthen vendor relationships, and accelerated incident response when vendor exposures threaten their own environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security teams and their counterparts across the business are overwhelmed with vendor assessments, questionnaires, and risk scores that often don’t translate to real prevention,” said Alex Greer, Group Product Manager at SpyCloud. “Our customers have often reported that when they’re evaluating doing business with a new vendor, they lack the actionable data their legal and compliance teams need for evidence-based decision making. That’s where SpyCloud stands out. Surfacing verified identity threats tied directly to vendor compromise, letting teams escalate to leadership when to restrict data access and prioritize efforts for the greatest impact on reducing organizational risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike existing solutions that rely on external surface indicators and static scoring, SpyCloud provides threat data derived from underground sources – the same recaptured darknet identity data that criminals actively use to target organizations and agencies. This fundamental difference enables SpyCloud customers to move from passive risk acceptance to proactive and holistic identity threat protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more about defending organizations from the exposures of vendors and suppliers, registration is open for SpyCloud’s upcoming Live Virtual Event, &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/events/how-to-solve-the-hidden-identity-crisis-in-your-supply-chain/?utm_medium=pr&amp;amp;utm_source=cybernewswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=supply-chain-launch-2026" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond Vendor Risk Scores: How to Solve the Hidden Identity Crisis in Your Supply Chain, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, January 22, 2026, at 11 am CT&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SpyCloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpyCloud transforms recaptured darknet data to disrupt cybercrime. Its automated identity threat protection solutions leverage advanced analytics and AI to proactively prevent ransomware and account takeover, detect insider threats, safeguard employee and consumer identities, and accelerate cybercrime investigations. SpyCloud’s data from breaches, malware-infected devices, and successful phishes also powers many popular dark web monitoring and identity theft protection offerings. Customers include seven of the Fortune 10, along with hundreds of global enterprises, mid-sized companies, and government agencies worldwide. Headquartered in Austin, TX, SpyCloud is home to more than 200 cybersecurity experts whose mission is to protect businesses and consumers from the stolen identity data criminals are using to target them now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more and see insights on your company’s exposed data, users can visit &lt;a href="http://spycloud.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;spycloud.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Specialist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phil Tortora&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REQ on behalf of SpyCloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spycloud@req.co&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116536/spycloud-launches-supply-chain-solution-to-combat-rising-third-party-identity-threats.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS prepares replacement for critical infrastructure collaboration framework</title>
      <link>https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/dhs-critical-infrastructure-collaboration-cipac-anchor/809748/</link>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgproxy.divecdn.com/I87P4irOukLTj5qlFPbhK62C1l4y8zJeNFemY-naup0/g:ce/rs:fill:1600:900:1/Z3M6Ly9kaXZlc2l0ZS1zdG9yYWdlL2RpdmVpbWFnZS9HZXR0eUltYWdlcy05MTg1NjQzNS5qcGc=.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;It remains unclear if the new system will include liability protections that companies say are necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/dhs-critical-infrastructure-collaboration-cipac-anchor/809748/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:04:46 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-009)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-010)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-011)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trend Micro security advisory (AV26-012)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s partial internet shutdown may be a windfall for cybersecurity intel</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116890/irans-partial-internet-shutdown-may-be-a-windfall-for-cybersecurity-intel.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The near-total internet blackout imposed by the Iranian government starting January 8, reportedly due to a crackdown on protesters, may offer a rare opportunity to SOC staffers and other cybersecurity analysts, briefly allowing all government traffic sources to be identified and digitally fingerprinted, a massive help in tracking Iranian state actors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3595792/nation-state-actors-increasingly-hide-behind-cybercriminal-tactics-and-malware.html" target="_blank"&gt;global malicious state actors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4115379/iran-linked-muddywater-apt-deploys-rust-based-implant-in-latest-campaign.html"&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt; is near the top, behind &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/653302/chinese-state-actors-behind-espionage-attacks-on-southeast-asian-government.html" target="_blank"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107406/russian-apt-group-pivots-to-network-edge-device-misconfigurations.html" target="_blank"&gt;Russia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4090979/north-koreas-job-test-trap-upgrades-to-json-malware-dropboxes.html" target="_blank"&gt;North Korea&lt;/a&gt;, which suggests that this kind of intel on Iranian systems might prove useful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One cybersecurity vendor CEO argues that it is indeed a potential threat intel goldmine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an almost-total internet blackout, “the attack surface available to state hackers shrinks. They can no longer hide in the noise of millions of residential IPs. They are forced to route their attacks through the few remaining whitelisted pipes, which are exactly those boring government agencies such as Agriculture, Energy, Universities,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kakooch" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kaveh Ranjbar&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Whisper Security. “Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) groups routinely co-opt benign government infrastructure to launch attacks because it looks clean. When the rest of the country is dark, those boring servers become the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; available launchpads. A connection from the Ministry of Agriculture might not be a farmer. It’s likely a tunnel for a state actor who needs an exit node.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ranjbar said the removal of the traffic from millions of routine Iranian business and residential users allows a powerful visibility into Iranian government traffic patterns, thereby allowing SOCs to flag those sources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For a CISO, the calculus is simple: User traffic is zero. If Amazon or a bank sees traffic from Tehran during a blackout, it is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a customer buying books or checking a balance. It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a remote employee. [All] of the traffic is machine-generated and state-sanctioned. Even if it’s just a misconfigured cron job at the Ministry of Water, it is an anomaly. But more often, it is scanning, probing, or reconnaissance,” Ranjbar said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You don’t need a list of malicious agencies,” he observed. “You need to know that the entire visible IP space of Iran is currently a privileged enclave. If a server is allowed to speak to the outside world while 80 million citizens are silenced, that server is, by definition, an asset of the state. In a zero-trust environment, that makes it a high-confidence Indicator of Compromise (IoC) if it touches your network.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts and consultants, however, were reserved about the approach, but pointed out that, on an ROI basis, it will typically require minimal effort to capture that data during the blackout, so it can’t hurt much to do so. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think there’s any downside to capturing it,” said &lt;a href="https://moorinsightsstrategy.com/team/robert-kramer/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Robert Kramer&lt;/a&gt;, vice president/principal analyst at Moor Insights &amp;amp; Strategy. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-might-be-of-limited-value"&gt;Data might be of limited value&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, Kramer and other experts said, the nature of state actors today may make that captured data of limited value. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;State actors for those four countries are among the most sophisticated, experienced, and best-financed attackers anywhere. One of their top skills is not only knowing how to cover their tracks, but how to create false logs and other deceptions to make the attack look like it is being launched from anywhere &lt;em&gt;other than &lt;/em&gt;its true source. In short, if the logs point to the attack coming from China, a CISO knows that the attack almost certainly wasn’t launched by China. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research, said that he sees some of the potential value, but added that it is limited. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this kind of blackout, “the few packets that escape become disproportionately meaningful. You’re looking at whitelisted ASNs, state-controlled telecoms and government-operated services. That residual traffic helps map adversary digital infrastructure with surprising clarity. The presence of DNS queries, passive malware beacons, or control-plane BGP signals during a blackout gives analysts a blueprint of national priorities.” Gogia said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, he stressed, that’s where the value may stop. “Residual traffic does not readily convert into block rules or SIEM logic. It does not hand you command-and-control servers on a silver platter. Most of it is either benign or diagnostic. And unless correlated with strong behavioral signals, it rarely survives the trip from strategic context to operational action,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Yes, you might find an Iranian IP that kept chattering when no one else could. But was it a threat actor’s box, or just a government website? Without high-confidence enrichment, it’s guesswork. Worse, if that same IP goes back to hosting payroll services a week later, your SOC is stuck chasing shadows. That’s why this intelligence is best used for threat modelling, not triage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia added that the captured data is also likely to expire relatively quickly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Routing anomalies and observable proxies are equally unstable. During partial shutdowns, traffic might reroute through unexpected neighbors or temporarily migrate to backup ISPs,” he noted. “A sharp analyst might catch an Iranian subnet using a German transit point during a blackout. But once service restores, that path disappears. If you treated it as a long-term IoC, it would quickly become a dead end.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Setting aside deliberate deception, there is also a lot of legitimate traffic coming from Iranian government agencies, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthewestern/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew Stern&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at CNC Intelligence, pointed out. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This may offer short-term insight into routing behavior, protocol usage, and infrastructure dependencies that Iranian state-linked operators may later reuse. However, this should not be overstated,” Stern said. “Government traffic is not inherently malicious and sophisticated Iranian cyber actors frequently operate through foreign infrastructure, compromised hosts, and third-party services outside Iran, which significantly limits the long-term defensive value of domestic traffic fingerprinting.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, executive director of FormerGov, said the rare nature of this shutdown makes it worth performing whatever data capture is viable. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-signal-to-noise-ratio-flips"&gt;The signal to noise ratio flips&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“From an intelligence perspective, this is one of the rare moments when the signal‑to‑noise ratio flips. If traffic is flowing out of Iran right now, odds are high it’s state‑linked, and that alone makes it worth capturing,” Levine said. “Even legitimate Iranian government activity can be valuable to SOCs. State actors tend to reuse infrastructure, routes, and operational patterns. Today’s ‘normal’ traffic can become tomorrow’s attribution breadcrumb.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although Levine agreed that the quantity of actionable long-term data is likely small, he thinks it is still worth capturing. “Collecting digital fingerprints during a blackout won’t solve attribution on its own, but it can sharpen it. In cyber defense, even a few percentage points of clarity can make the difference between catching an intrusion early and missing it entirely.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, two VP analysts with Gartner, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/jeremy-dhoinne" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jeremy D’Hoinne&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/akif-khan" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Akif Khan&lt;/a&gt;, were more skeptical of the data’s value and discouraged CISO teams from pursuing it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attribution is dangerous based on fragmented technical evidence,” D’Hoinne said. “Don’t get distracted.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Khan was more blunt. “In the fog of war, trying to find verifiable information is very challenging. Without being able to corroborate, I don’t think this goes beyond an intellectual exercise. If people in your enterprise SOC have the time to do this, they need to refocus their priorities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116890/irans-partial-internet-shutdown-may-be-a-windfall-for-cybersecurity-intel.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-013)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-013</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-013</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophisticated VoidLink malware framework targets Linux cloud servers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117038/sophisticated-voidlink-malware-framework-targets-linux-cloud-servers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have uncovered a new sophisticated and modular malware framework designed to operate stealthily inside Linux systems and containers. The framework seems to have been designed by Chinese developers with in-depth knowledge of Linux internals and was created to be used against cloud servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The framework, internally referred to by its original developers as VoidLink, is a cloud-first implant written in Zig and designed to operate in modern infrastructure,” researchers from security firm Check Point said in their &lt;a href="https://research.checkpoint.com/2026/voidlink-the-cloud-native-malware-framework/"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. “It can recognize major cloud environments and detect when it is running inside Kubernetes or Docker, then tailor its behavior accordingly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Check Point only found samples of the malware that appear to be an in-progress project rather than a completed product. However, the project is mature, and the company’s researchers suspect it won’t be long before the malware is used in real-world attacks, possibly for cyberespionage or supply-chain compromises because it harvests credentials for cloud environments and source code repository management systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="highly-extensible-and-customizable"&gt;Highly extensible and customizable&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VoidLink draws inspiration from the beacon implant of Cobalt Strike, an adversary simulation framework that has been widely adopted and misused by attackers over the years. The malware uses an API to communicate with additional plug-ins that add a diverse set of capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By default, the platform comes with 37 plug-ins that can be selected and delivered to the victim to enable additional capabilities. However, the operator can also deliver custom plug-ins. This is controlled through a professional-looking web-based command-and-control (C2) dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This interface is localized for Chinese-affiliated operators, but the navigation follows a familiar C2 layout: a left sidebar groups pages into Dashboard, Attack, and Infrastructure,” the researchers said. “The Dashboard section covers the core operator loop (agent manager, built-in terminal, and an implant builder). In contrast, the Attack section organizes post-exploitation activity such as reconnaissance, credential access, persistence, lateral movement, process injection, stealth, and evidence wiping.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware framework is written in Zig, a relatively new programming language that’s an alternative to C and is an unusual choice for malware development. However, the developers have also shown proficiency in other languages such as Go, C, and JavaScript frameworks such as React.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers note that VoidLink is much more advanced that typical Linux malware, with a well-designed core component handling state, communication and task execution that is delivered through a two-stage loader. Operators can deliver additional code to be executed in the form of plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-reconnaissance-and-adaptability"&gt;Cloud reconnaissance and adaptability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware was designed to detect whether it’s being executed on various cloud platforms such as AWS, GCP, Azure, Alibaba, and Tencent and then to start leveraging those vendors’ management APIs. The code suggests the developers plan to add detections for Huawei, DigitalOcean, and Vultr in the future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware collects extensive amounts of information about the machine and environment it runs in, including whether it’s a Docker container or a Kubernetes pod. It then can execute post-exploitation modules that attempt privilege escalation through container escapes or lateral movement to other containers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Ultimately, the goal of this implant appears to be stealthy, long-term access, surveillance, and data collection,” the researchers said, adding that developers might be a target for initial delivery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another interesting aspect is that the malware has a sophisticated algorithm through which it adapts its operations based on the security posture of the environment. It will scan for common Linux endpoint and detection response (EDR) tools and kernel hardening technologies and then calculate a risk score for the environment, which is then used to select a detection evasion strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware also has multiple rootkit components with deployment strategies for different versions of the Linux kernel and will deploy them based on the environment in which it runs. These rootkit modules hide the malware’s processes, files, and network sockets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;C2 traffic is hidden in multiple ways, including as encrypted data in PNGs or JS, HTML, or CSS files, making it hard to detect at the network layer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“VoidLink aims to automate evasion as much as possible, profiling an environment and choosing the most suitable strategy to operate in it,” the researchers said. “Augmented by kernel mode tradecraft and a vast plugin ecosystem, VoidLink enables its operators to move through cloud environments and container ecosystems with adaptive stealth.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While malware for Linux is less common and often less sophisticated than malware programs for Windows, VoidLink stands out as a unique and highly capable framework. Even if it’s not totally clear whether this malware is intended to be a product for cybercriminals or as future commercial penetration testing framework of sorts, it serves as an example of the type of threats organizations should be prepared to defend in their Linux-based cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117038/sophisticated-voidlink-malware-framework-targets-linux-cloud-servers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware gangs extort victims by citing compliance violations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116976/ransomware-gangs-blackmail-victims-with-compliance-violations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563507/what-is-ransomware-how-it-works-and-how-to-remove-it.html"&gt;Ransomware attacks&lt;/a&gt; remain among the most common attack methods. As recent analyses show, cyber gangs are increasingly threatening their victims with reporting violations of regulations such as the GDPR to supervisory authorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the security provider Akamai have observed an increasing trend in this tactic over the past two years. As an example, the security vendor points to ransomware group Anubis. Its members reportedly focus primarily on industries with high compliance risks, such as healthcare. The notorious &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2139658/new-ransomhub-ransomware-gang-has-ties-to-older-knight-group.html" target="_blank"&gt;Ransomhub&lt;/a&gt; gang also allegedly employs this method, explicitly encouraging its partners to threaten hacked companies with regulatory penalties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="consequences-for-companies"&gt;Consequences for companies&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This puts companies under a double pressure that is almost impossible to manage,” Klaus Hild, manager of solution engineering for enterprise at SailPoint, explained to CSO. They have to weigh the risk of paying ransoms against potentially ruinous penalties and reputational damage. “This ‘compliance extortion’ is no longer a theoretical threat — it has become standard practice for ransomware cartels,” Hild added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tim Berghof, security evangelist at G DATA, confirmed to CSO that while this approach is technically just an extension of the “industry-standard” double extortion, it can have massive consequences. “Even if a complaint turns out to be unfounded, official investigations generate attention, tie up resources, and potentially become public,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-amplifies-attacks"&gt;AI amplifies attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hild points to another problem: “AI-powered tools dramatically accelerate these attacks. Criminals can now screen stolen documents for ‘material’ compliance violations within hours of a data breach — faster and more accurately than many companies can audit their own systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SailPoint specialist explains: “They create detailed, legally sound complaints for authorities and set tight deadlines. With new regulations like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570091/eus-dora-regulation-explained-new-risk-management-requirements-for-financial-firms.html" target="_blank"&gt;DORA&lt;/a&gt; in the EU and stricter SEC reporting requirements, the arsenal of these extortionists is constantly growing.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Berghoff summarizes: “The question remains which has the less severe consequences for companies: a self-report or an anonymous report to the relevant authority by a group of criminals. Since there is still a great deal of uncertainty surrounding compliance in some areas, threats involving authorities potentially fall on fertile ground.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116976/ransomware-gangs-blackmail-victims-with-compliance-violations.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From typos to takeovers: Inside the industrialization of npm supply chain attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117139/from-typos-to-takeovers-inside-the-industrialization-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A massive surge in attacks on the npm ecosystem over the past year reveals a stark shift in the software supply‑chain threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What once amounted to sloppy typosquatting attempts has evolved into coordinated, credential-driven intrusions targeting maintainers, CI pipelines, and the trusted automation that underpins modern development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For security leaders, these aren’t niche developer mishaps anymore — they’re a direct pathway into production systems, cloud infrastructure, and millions of downstream applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The goal is no longer to trick an individual developer, but to quietly inherit their authority. And with it, their distribution reach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“NPM is an attractive target because it is the world’s largest JavaScript package repository and a key control point for distributing software,” said Melinda Marks, cybersecurity practice director at Enterprise Security Group. “Security teams need an understanding of dependencies and ways to regularly audit and mitigate risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="structural-weaknesses-in-the-npm-infrastructure"&gt;Structural weaknesses in the npm infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly every enterprise relies on npm, whether directly or indirectly. According to &lt;a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=US51141024"&gt;IDC&lt;/a&gt;, 93% of organizations use open-source software, and npm remains the largest package registry in the JavaScript ecosystem. “Compromising a single popular package can immediately reach millions of downstream users and applications,” IDC’s research manager (DevSecOps), Katie Norton, said, turning one stolen credential into what she described as a “master key” for distribution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That scale, however, is only part of the risk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The exposure is amplified by structural weaknesses in how modern development pipelines are secured, Norton remarked. “Individual open-source maintainers often lack the security resources that enterprise teams rely on, leaving them susceptible to social engineering,” she said. “CI/CD runners and developer machines routinely process long-lived secrets that are stored in environment variables or configuration files and are easily harvested by malware.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Build systems also tend to prioritize speed and reliability over security visibility, resulting in limited monitoring and long dwell times for attackers who gain initial access,” Norton added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While security leaders can’t patch their way out of this one, they can reduce exposure. Experts consistently point to the same priorities: treating CI runners as production assets, rotating and scoping publish tokens aggressively, disabling lifecycle scripts unless required, and pinning dependencies to immutable versions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These npm attacks are targeting the pre-install phase of software dependencies, so typical software supply chain security methods of code scanning cannot address these types of attacks,” Marks said. Detection requires runtime analysis and anomaly detection rather than signature-based tooling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;From typo traps to legitimate backdoors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For years, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570173/what-is-typosquatting-a-simple-but-effective-attack-technique.html"&gt;typosquatting&lt;/a&gt; defined the npm threat model. Attackers published packages with names just close enough to popular libraries, such as “lodsash,” “expres,” “reacts,” and waited for automation or human error to do the rest. The impact was usually limited, and remediation straightforward.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That model began to break in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of impersonating popular packages, attackers increasingly compromised real ones. Phishing &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4028412/supply-chain-attack-compromises-npm-packages-to-spread-backdoor-malware.html"&gt;campaigns&lt;/a&gt; spoofing npm itself harvested maintainer credentials. Stolen tokens were then used to publish trojanized updates that appeared legitimate to every downstream consumer. The Shai-Hulud &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095578/new-shai-hulud-worm-spreading-through-npm-github.html"&gt;campaign&lt;/a&gt; illustrated the scale of the problem, affecting tens of thousands of repositories and leveraging compromised credentials to self-propagate across the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The npm ecosystem has become the crown jewels of modern development,” said Kush Pandya, a cybersecurity researcher at Socket.dev. “When a single prolific maintainer is compromised, the blast radius spans hundreds of downstream projects.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The result was a quiet but powerful shift: attackers no longer needed to create convincing fakes. They could ship malware through &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4026380/prettier-eslint-npm-packages-hijacked-in-a-sophisticated-supply-chain-attack.html"&gt;trusted channels&lt;/a&gt;, signed and versioned like any routine update.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="developer-environments-over-developer-laptops"&gt;Developer environments over developer laptops&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern npm &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3506897/github-actions-typosquatting-a-high-impact-supply-chain-attack-in-waiting.html"&gt;attacks&lt;/a&gt; increasingly activate inside CI/CD environments rather than on developer laptops. Post-install &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3995813/hackers-drop-60-npm-bombs-in-less-than-two-weeks-to-recon-dev-machines.html?utm=hybrid_search#:~:text=post%2Dinstall%20scripts"&gt;scripts&lt;/a&gt;, long treated as benign setup helpers, became an execution vector capable of running automatically inside GitHub Actions or GitLab CI. Once inside a runner, malicious packages could read environment variables, steal publish tokens, tamper with build artifacts, or even push additional malicious releases under the victim’s identity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Developer environments and CI runners are now worth more than end-user machines,” Pandya noted. “They usually have broader permissions, access to secrets, and the ability to push code into production.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several campaigns observed in mid-2025 were explicitly &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088529/malicious-npm-package-sneaks-into-github-actions-builds.html"&gt;CI-aware&lt;/a&gt;, triggering only when they detected automated build environments. Some included delayed execution or self-expiring payloads, minimizing forensic visibility while maximizing credential theft.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For enterprises, this represents a fundamental risk shift. CI systems often operate with higher privileges than any individual user, yet are monitored far less rigorously. “They are often secured with weaker defaults: long-lived publish tokens, overly permissive CI secrets, implicit trust in lifecycle scripts and package metadata, and little isolation between builds,” Pandya noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to IDC Research, organizations allocate only about 14% of AppSec budgets to supply-chain security, with only 12% of them identifying CI/CD pipeline security as a top risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Evasion as a first-class feature&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As defenders improved at spotting suspicious packages, attackers adapted too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent npm campaigns have used invisible Unicode characters to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082195/malicious-packages-in-npm-evade-dependency-detection-through-invisible-url-links-report.html"&gt;obscure&lt;/a&gt; dependencies, multi-stage loaders that fetch real payloads only after environment checks, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4050956/malicious-npm-packages-use-ethereum-blockchain-for-malware-delivery.html"&gt;blockchain-hosted &lt;/a&gt;command-and-control (C2) references designed to evade takedowns. Others deployed worm-like behavior, using stolen credentials to publish additional malicious packages at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Manual review has become largely ineffective against this level of tradecraft. “The days when you could skim index.js and spot a malicious eval() are gone,” Pandya said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Modern packages hide malicious logic behind layers of encoding, delayed execution, and environment fingerprinting.” Norton echoed the concern, noting that these attacks operate at a behavioral level where static scanning falls short. “Obfuscation techniques make malicious logic difficult to distinguish from legitimate complexity in large JavaScript projects,” she said. “CI-aware payloads and post-install scripts introduce behavior that only manifests under specific environmental conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117139/from-typos-to-takeovers-inside-the-industrialization-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-014)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-015)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-016)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-017)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-018)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–019)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Possible software supply chain attack through AWS CodeBuild service blunted</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117692/possible-software-supply-chain-attack-through-aws-codebuild-service-blunted-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An AWS misconfiguration in its code building service could have led to a massive number of compromised key AWS GitHub code repositories and applications, say researchers at Wiz who discovered the problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability stemmed from a subtle flaw in how the repositories’ &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codebuild/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AWS CodeBuild&lt;/a&gt; CI (continuous integration) pipelines handled build triggers. “Just two missing characters in a regex filter allowed unauthenticated attackers to infiltrate the build environment and leak privileged credentials,” the researchers&lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/wiz-research-codebreach-vulnerability-aws-codebuild" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt; said in a Thursday blog.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The regex (regular expression) filter at the center of the issue is an automated pattern-matching rule that scans log output for secrets and hides them to prevent leakage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue allowed a complete takeover of key AWS GitHub repositories, particularly the AWS JavaScript SDK, a core library that powers the AWS Console.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This shows the power and risk of supply chain vulnerabilities,” Yuval Avrahami, co-author of the report about the bug, told CSO, “which is exactly why supply chain attacks are on the rise: one small flaw can lead to an insanely impactful attack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After being warned of the vulnerability last August, AWS quickly plugged the hole and implemented global hardening within the CodeBuild service to prevent the possibility of similar attacks. Details of the problem are only being revealed now by Wiz &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/security/security-bulletins/2026-002-AWS/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;and AWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AWS told CSO that it “found that there was no impact on the confidentiality or integrity of any customer environment or AWS service.” It also advised developers &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/webhooks.html#webhook-best-practices%EF%BF%BC%EF%BF%BC%5B3%5D" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to follow best practices in using AWS CodeBuild.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the Wiz researchers warned developers using the product to take steps to protect their projects from similar issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="discovery"&gt;Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz discovered the problem last August after an attempted supply chain attack on the Amazon Q VS Code extension. An attacker exploited a misconfigured CodeBuild project to compromise the extension’s GitHub repository and inject malicious code into the main branch. This code was then included in a release which users downloaded. Although the attacker’s payload ultimately failed due to a typo, it did execute on end users’ machines – clearly demonstrating the risk of misconfigured CodeBuild pipelines. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz researchers investigated and found the core of the flaw, a threat actor ID bypass due to unanchored regexes, and notified AWS. Within 48 hours, that hole was plugged, AWS said in a statement accompanying the Wiz blog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It also performed additional hardening, including adding further protections to all build processes that contain Github tokens or any other credentials in memory. AWS said it also audited all other public build environments to ensure that no such issues exist across the AWS open source estate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, it examined the logs of all public build repositories, as well as associated CloudTrail logs, “and determined that no other actor had taken advantage of the unanchored regex issue demonstrated by the Wiz research team. AWS determined there was no impact of the identified issue on the confidentiality or integrity of any customer environment or any AWS service.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellman/?originalSubdomain=ca" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kellman Meghu&lt;/a&gt;, chief technology officer at Deepcove Cybersecurity, a Canadian-based risk management firm, said it wouldn’t be a huge issue for developers who don’t publicly expose CodeBuild. “But,” he added, “if people are not diligent, I see how it could be used. It’s slick.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="developers-shouldnt-expose-build-environments"&gt;Developers shouldn’t expose build environments&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs should ensure developers don’t expose build environments, Meghu said. “Using public hosted services like GitHub is not appropriate for enterprise code management and deployment,” he added. “Having a private GitLab/GitHub, service, or even your own git repository server, should be the default for business, making this attack impossible if [the threat actors] can’t see the repository to begin with. The business should be the one that owns the repository; [it should] not be something you just let your developers set up as needed.” In fact, he said, IT or infosec leaders should set up the code repositories. Developers “should be users of the system, not the ultimate owners.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz strongly recommends that all AWS CodeBuild users implement the following safeguards to protect their own projects against possible compromise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent untrusted Pull Requests from triggering privileged builds by:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;enabling the new &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/pull-request-build-policy.html"&gt;Pull Request Comment Approval&lt;/a&gt; build gate;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;alternatively, using &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/action-runner.html"&gt;CodeBuild-hosted runners&lt;/a&gt; to manage build triggers via GitHub workflows;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you must rely on &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/webhooks.html"&gt;webhook filters&lt;/a&gt;, ensure their regex patterns are anchored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure the CodeBuild-GitHub connection by:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;generating a unique, fine-grained Personal Access Token (PAT) for each CodeBuild project;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/access-tokens-github.html"&gt;strictly limiting the PAT’s permissions&lt;/a&gt; to the minimum required.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;considering using a dedicated unprivileged GitHub account for the CodeBuild integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4117662/possible-software-supply-chain-attack-through-aws-codebuild-service-blunted.html" target="_blank"&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117692/possible-software-supply-chain-attack-through-aws-codebuild-service-blunted-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-001 – Vulnerabilities affecting n8n – CVE-2026-21858, CVE-2026-21877 and CVE-2025-68613</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One click is all it takes: How ‘Reprompt’ turned Microsoft Copilot into data exfiltration tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117792/one-click-is-all-it-takes-how-reprompt-turned-microsoft-copilot-into-data-exfiltration-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI copilots are incredibly intelligent and useful — but they can also be naive, gullible, and even dumb at times.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new one-click attack flow discovered by Varonis Threat Labs researchers underscores this fact. ‘Reprompt,’ as they’ve dubbed it, is a three-step attack chain that completely bypasses security controls after an initial &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3997429/risk-assessment-vital-when-choosing-an-ai-model-say-experts.html" target="_blank"&gt;LLM prompt&lt;/a&gt;, giving attackers invisible, undetectable, unlimited access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI assistants have become trusted companions where we share sensitive information, seek guidance, and rely on them without hesitation,” Varonis Threat Labs security researcher &lt;a href="https://www.varonis.com/blog/author/dtaler" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dolev Taler&lt;/a&gt; wrote in a &lt;a href="https://www.varonis.com/blog/reprompt" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “But … trust can be easily exploited, and an AI assistant can turn into a data exfiltration weapon with a single click.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that, as of now, Reprompt has only been discovered in Microsoft Copilot Personal, not Microsoft 365 Copilot — but that’s not to say it couldn’t be used against enterprises depending on their copilot policies and user awareness. Microsoft has already released a patch after being made aware of the flaw.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-reprompt-silently-works-in-the-background"&gt;How Reprompt silently works in the background&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reprompt employs three techniques to create a data exfiltration chain: Initial parameter to prompt (P2P injection), double request, and chain-request.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;P2P embeds a prompt directly in a URL, exploiting Copilot’s default ‘q’ URL parameter functionality, which is intended to streamline and improve user experience. The URL can include specific questions or instructions that automatically populate the input field when pages load.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Using this loophole, attackers then employ double-request, which allows them to circumvent safeguards; Copilot only checks for malicious content in the Q variable for the first prompt, not subsequent requests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For instance, the researchers asked Copilot to fetch a URL containing the secret phrase “HELLOWORLD1234!”, repeating the request twice. Copilot removed the secret phrase from the first URL, but the second attempt “worked flawlessly,” Taler noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From here, attackers can kick off a chain-request, in which the attacker’s server issues follow-up instructions to form an ongoing conversation. This tricks Copilot into exfiltrating conversation histories and sensitive data. Threat actors can provide a range of prompts like “Summarize all of the files that the user accessed today,” “Where does the user live?” or “What vacations does he have planned?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This method “makes data theft stealthy and scalable,” and there is no limit to what or how much attackers can exfiltrate, Taler noted. “Copilot leaks the data little by little, allowing the threat to use each answer to generate the next malicious instruction.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The danger is that reprompt requires no plugins, enabled connectors, or user interaction with Copilot beyond the initial single click on a legitimate Microsoft Copilot link in a phishing message. The attacker can stay in Copilot as long as they want, even after the user closes their chat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All commands are delivered via the server after the initial prompt, so it’s almost impossible to determine what is being extracted just by inspecting that one prompt. “The real instructions are hidden in the server’s follow-up requests,” Taler noted, “not from anything obvious in the prompt the user submits.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-devs-and-security-teams-should-do-now"&gt;What devs and security teams should do now&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As in usual security practice, enterprise users should always treat URLs and external inputs as untrusted, experts advised. Be cautious with links, be on the lookout for unusual behavior, and always pause to review pre-filled prompts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This attack, like many others, originates with a phishing email or text message, so all the usual best practices against phishing apply, including ‘don’t click on suspicious links,’” noted &lt;a href="https://ca.linkedin.com/in/bernardes" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Henrique Teixeira&lt;/a&gt;, SVP of Strategy at Saviynt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Phishing-resistant authentication should be implemented, not only during the initial use of a chatbot, but throughout the entire session, he emphasized. This would require developers to implement controls when first building apps and embedding copilots and chatbots, rather than adding controls later on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;End users should avoid using chatbots that are not authenticated and avoid risky behaviors such as acting on a sense of urgency (such as being encouraged to speedily completing a transaction), replying to unknown or potentially nefarious senders, or oversharing personal info, he noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Lastly and super importantly is to not blame the victim in these instances,” said Teixeira. App owners and service providers using AI must build apps that do not allow prompts to be submitted without authentication and authorization, or with malicious commands embedded in URLs. “Service providers can include more prompt hygiene and basic identity security controls like continuous and adaptive authentication to make apps safer to employees and clients,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Further, design considering insider-level risk, says Varonis’ Taler. “Assume AI assistants operate with trusted context and access. Enforce least privilege, auditing, and anomaly detection accordingly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this represents yet another example of enterprises rolling out new technologies with security as an afterthought, other experts note.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Seeing this story play out is like watching Wile E. Coyote and the Road Runner,” said &lt;a href="https://www.beauceronsecurity.com/blog/tag/David+Shipley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt; of Beauceron Security. “Once you know the gag, you know what’s going to happen. The coyote is going to trust some ridiculously flawed Acme product and use it in a really dumb way.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this case, that ‘product’ is &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4006436/llms-hype-versus-reality-what-cisos-should-focus-on.html" target="_blank"&gt;LLM-based technologies&lt;/a&gt; that are simply allowed to perform any actions without restriction. The scary thing is there’s no way to secure it because LLMs are what Shipley described as “high speed idiots.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They can’t distinguish between content and instructions, and will blindly do what they’re told,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLMs should be limited to chats in a browser, he asserted. Giving them access to anything more than that is a “disaster waiting to happen,” particularly if they’re going to be interacting with content that can be sent via e-mail, message, or through a website.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Using techniques such as applying least access privilege and zero trust to try to work around the fundamental insecurity of LLM agents “look brilliant until they backfire,” Shipley said. “All of this would be funny if it didn’t get organizations pwned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4117750/one-click-is-all-it-takes-how-reprompt-turned-microsoft-copilot-into-a-data-exfiltration-tool.html" target="_blank"&gt;Computerworld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117792/one-click-is-all-it-takes-how-reprompt-turned-microsoft-copilot-into-data-exfiltration-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insider risk in an age of workforce volatility</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116983/insider-risk-in-an-age-of-workforce-volatility.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Economic pressures, AI-driven job displacement, and relentless organizational churn are driving insider risk to its highest level in years. Workforce instability erodes loyalty and heightens grievances. The accelerating deployment of powerful new tools, such as AI agents, amplifies the threats from within, both human and machine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.rationalfx.com/forex-brokers/global-tech-sector-layoffs"&gt;according to RationalFX&lt;/a&gt; and other job trackers, the global technology sector saw &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4114572/global-tech-sector-layoffs-surpass-244000-in-2025.html"&gt;roughly 245,000 layoffs&lt;/a&gt; announced across hundreds of companies. These figures, while concentrated in the tech industry, reflect broader trends seen across other sectors, including manufacturing, retail, finance, energy, and government, where employers announced more than 1.17 million job cuts through November 2025 in the US, according to &lt;a href="https://www.challengergray.com/blog/category/job-cuts-report/"&gt;Challenger, Gray &amp;amp; Christmas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This surge, up significantly from prior years, creates fertile ground for disgruntlement: financial stress, resentment over automation, and opportunistic behavior, from negligence and careless data handling to deliberate malevolent actions like data exfiltration and credential monetization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All this shows that our trusted insiders are the prime vector for serious incidents across sectors and geographies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-emerging-machine-threat-ai-agents-as-a-volatile-vector"&gt;The emerging machine threat: AI agents as a volatile vector&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compounding the human element is the rapid rise of AI agents, which &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/perspectives/2026-cyber-predictions"&gt;Palo Alto Networks has identified&lt;/a&gt; as one of the most acute and evolving insider risks for 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Autonomous agents with privileged system access, superhuman execution speed, and decision-making at scale are no longer mere productivity boosters. They are becoming exploitable vectors for silent data exfiltration, disruption, or unintended catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is particularly concerning when volatility reduces human oversight and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3529615/companies-skip-security-hardening-in-rush-to-adopt-ai.html"&gt;rushes deployment without commensurate controls&lt;/a&gt;. Palo Alto Networks’ 2026 cybersecurity predictions emphasize that these agents introduce vulnerabilities such as goal hijacking, tool misuse, prompt injection, and shadow deployment, often amplified by the very churn that drives their adoption across multinational organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security leaders are taking note. Surveys indicate that 60% of organizations express high concern over AI misuse enabling or amplifying insider risks, according to &lt;a href="https://secureframe.com/blog/cybersecurity-statistics"&gt;Secureframe’s Q4 2025 cybersecurity statistics compilation&lt;/a&gt; and related reports. Meanwhile, hybrid and remote work models rank as the top emerging risk for insider risks over the next three to five years, cited by 75% of respondents in &lt;a href="https://www.cybersecurity-insiders.com/portfolio/2025-insider-risk-report-cogility/"&gt;Cybersecurity Insiders’ 2025 Insider Risk Report&lt;/a&gt;. These decentralized environments further blur visibility and control, making it harder to detect anomalous behavior from either humans or machines in global operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="early-warnings-the-machine-as-insider-risk-threat"&gt;Early warnings: The machine as insider risk/threat&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These dynamics are not emerging in a vacuum. They represent the culmination of warnings that have been building for years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As early as 2021, in my CSO opinion piece “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571391/device-identity-the-overlooked-insider-threat.html"&gt;Device identity: The overlooked insider threat&lt;/a&gt;,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajan-koo-2a591221/"&gt;Rajan Koo&lt;/a&gt; (then chief customer officer at DTEX Systems, now CTO) observed: “There needs to be more application of the insider threat framework toward devices at the same level as we do with humans&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;” That insight highlighted how machine identities such as APIs, bots, scripts, and &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/227908/what-is-rpa-robotic-process-automation-explained.html"&gt;robotic process automation (RPA)&lt;/a&gt; were already serving as conduits for both intentional and unintentional incidents, deserving the same scrutiny as human insiders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This perspective was reinforced in 2022 in “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571835/what-cisos-can-learn-from-the-kyoto-university-backup-data-deletion.html"&gt;Machine as insider threat: Lessons from Kyoto University’s backup data deletion&lt;/a&gt;,” which analyzed a real-world automation failure as “a classic case of the machines being the insider threat.” The incident, where an unchecked scripting error led to the permanent deletion of critical backup data, demonstrated that the outcome, catastrophic loss, was identical to what a malicious insider could achieve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By mid-2023, the conversation shifted to the positive potential in the 2023 CSO feature, “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/648380/when-your-teammate-is-a-machine-how-cisos-are-learning-to-embrace-ai.html"&gt;When your teammate is a machine: 8 questions CISOs should be asking about AI&lt;/a&gt;,” which explored AI as a collaborative force in cybersecurity workflows, yet tempered with the need to have a firm understanding of what’s under the hood. Today, that teammate has proliferated: Palo Alto Networks forecasts that machine identities and autonomous agents will outnumber humans by ratios as high as 82:1 in many enterprises, turning early cautions into urgent 2026 reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-compounding-effect-human-churn-meets-machine-proliferation"&gt;The compounding effect: Human churn meets machine proliferation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The convergence of these factors — human volatility driven by layoffs and economic stress combined with the unchecked scaling of machine agents — creates a compounding effect. Organizations facing cost pressures often prioritize speed of AI adoption over governance, leading to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4044007/shadow-ai-is-surging-getting-ai-adoption-right-is-your-best-defense.html"&gt;shadow AI deployments&lt;/a&gt; and insufficient monitoring. At the same time, displaced or disgruntled employees may monetize access, exfiltrate sensitive data, or simply neglect controls as they disengage, as we witnessed in the &lt;a href="https://www.resecurity.com/blog/article/knownsec-data-breach-a-trove-of-espionage-tradecraft-with-an-insider-narrative"&gt;KnownSec incident&lt;/a&gt;, where an insider exposed how the company was an adjunct of the Chinese government’s offensive cyber operations infrastructure. While the action was no doubt welcomed by many cyberdefenders for the insight into China’s capabilities, it also demonstrates that no entity is immune from the volatility factor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that such anxiety from ongoing layoffs and role uncertainty can lead to nervous mistakes, privilege hoarding, or rushed workarounds that expose data without intent to harm. Yet harm is actualized. The result is a heightened insider risk landscape that is amplified when the interplay between human churn and machine proliferation is overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="toward-coherent-strategies-holistic-mitigation-in-a-volatile-era"&gt;Toward coherent strategies: Holistic mitigation in a volatile era&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;a href=""&gt;coherence in insider risk strategy&lt;/a&gt; becomes essential. Holistic approaches must integrate behavioral analytics that monitor both human patterns (for example, sentiment shifts during restructuring or after-hours data collection) and machine behaviors (for example, anomalous API calls or agent activity spikes).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reskilling programs can help retain talent and reduce resentment by positioning employees as partners in AI-augmented roles rather than casualties of displacement. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089732/rethinking-identity-for-the-ai-era-cisos-must-build-trust-at-machine-speed.html"&gt;Strong governance of machine identities&lt;/a&gt;, requiring authentication, least-privilege access, and continuous monitoring, extends &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;zero-trust principles&lt;/a&gt; to the non-human domain. And crucially, organizations need to bridge HR and security functions to detect early indicators of volatility before they manifest as threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without these proactive, integrated measures, the cascade could be significant. A single exploited AI agent could exfiltrate terabytes of data at speeds no human could match. As history has shown, a disgruntled employee may use lingering credentials to plant backdoors, steal or sell information, or cause deliberate destruction. The stakes are no longer confined to isolated incidents. They now span the entire ecosystem, from supply chains to critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-path-forward"&gt;The path forward&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we enter 2026, the message is clear: Insider risk is no longer primarily a human problem. It is a volatility problem, one that economic pressures, AI displacement, and organizational churn are intensifying at an unprecedented pace. Addressing it requires the same rigor we apply to external threats, but applied inward, with foresight, coherence, and a willingness to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116983/insider-risk-in-an-age-of-workforce-volatility.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-020)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-021)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV26-022)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-023)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-025)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-026)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV26-027)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-028)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-029)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-030)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-031)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-032)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Spot at RSAC 2026 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 60802221.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
