<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:23:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-825)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-826)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New report explores use of robotics and unmanned systems in the fight against crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</link>
      <description>Europol has today published The Unmanned Future(s): The Impact of Robotics and Unmanned Systems on Law Enforcement. The report, produced by the Europol Innovation Lab, provides an in-depth analysis of how unmanned systems could change society, crime and law enforcement, and discusses the challenges and opportunities they present.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-827)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D&amp;O liability protection rising for security leaders — unless you’re a midtier CISO</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107332/do-liability-protection-rising-for-security-leaders-unless-youre-a-midtier-ciso.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Smaller firms are far less likely than multinationals to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2505459/how-cisos-can-protect-their-personal-liability.html"&gt;protect their CISOs from personal liability&lt;/a&gt; for security breaches, according to a study by RSAC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts quizzed by CSO said the finding was concerning because without protection &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3631759/personal-liability-sours-70-of-cisos-on-their-role.html"&gt;CISOs face legal and financial risk&lt;/a&gt; tied to decisions made in their role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vast majority (88%) of CISOs from Fortune 1000 firms are legally indemnified by their companies, but this figure drops to just 53% for CISOs from organizations with 500 or more employees, &lt;a href="https://www.rsaconference.com/library/research/rsac-cybersecurity-insights-futures-volume-3"&gt;according to the survey by RSAC&lt;/a&gt; (formerly RSA Conference).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2512968/if-youre-a-ciso-without-do-insurance-you-may-need-to-fight-for-it.html"&gt;Directors’ and officers’ (D&amp;amp;O) insurance&lt;/a&gt; is the most common indemnification vehicle for both groups, and 70% of the Fortune 1000 CISOs surveyed report being covered by it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cm.law/people/kelly-culhane/"&gt;Kelly Rittenberry Culhane&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of CM Law, told CSO the finding is a concern for security leaders and midsize employers alike, given that, midsize or multinational, organizations face similar risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While the complexity and scale of operations may differ in a midsize company, the cybersecurity risks — ransomware, data breaches, regulatory compliance failures — are equally severe,” Rittenberry Culhane says. “Without indemnification, CISOs risk personal liability, which can deter highly qualified professionals from accepting these roles.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, midsize organizations put themselves at greater risk by not offering to protect from personal liability the top security leader they employ.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="do-for-cisos-on-the-rise"&gt;D&amp;amp;O for CISOs on the rise&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs have the potential for more than one safety net, the first of which is a company’s indemnification provisions — rules typically embedded in the company’s articles of incorporation and bylaws.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The language of a company’s indemnification provisions must be properly worded — typically achieved by the general counsel and a board vote — to provide indemnification for a CISO equal to every other director or officer of a company,” explains &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-peterson-15330975/"&gt;John Peterson&lt;/a&gt; of World Insurance Associates, a provider of employment practice liability insurance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second safety net for a CISO is the D&amp;amp;O liability insurance policy procured by the CISO’s company through an insurance broker. Even when a company has D&amp;amp;O insurance in place, Peterson advises CISOs to review those policies to make sure they are covered as an “insured person.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://www.iansresearch.com/resources/press-releases/detail/new-report-from-ians-and-artico-search-shows-6.7--rise-in-ciso-compensation-in-2025-amid-economic-uncertainty-and-evolving-digital-risk"&gt;latest IANS Research + Artico Search’s CISO Compensation Report&lt;/a&gt;, inclusion of CISOs in D&amp;amp;O insurance policies is increasing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More than 50% of CISOs in the US and Canada received this insurance benefit as part of their compensation package, according to the 2025 edition of the study. This figure is up from the 40% who said they received this protection in last year’s edition of the CISO Compensation Report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One in 5 CISOs also reported to IANS Research that they have access to external counsel — typically for investigations or audits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-question-of-indemnity"&gt;A question of indemnity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href="https://mcgillpartners.com/team?member=1864"&gt;Ryan Griffin&lt;/a&gt;, US cyber leader at insurance broker McGill and Partners, points out that the difference between D&amp;amp;O insurance and a direct indemnification agreement is often misunderstood.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The most crucial tool for a CISO’s protection is the indemnification agreement with their employer,” Griffin explains. “The D&amp;amp;O policy is how the company pays to protect its officer, but the indemnification agreement is what actually legally guarantees that protection.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without a formal indemnification agreement, CISOs are at great risk, Griffin warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They would be responsible for covering their own legal defense costs, forcing them to rely on personal savings or a personal umbrella insurance policy,” Griffin tells CSO. “Beyond the financial hit, their career could be severely damaged.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Griffin adds: “An enforcement action, even if it’s ultimately dismissed, could result in penalties that bar them from serving as an officer for a public company for years, which seriously limits future job prospects.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="blame-game"&gt;Blame game&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Central to the issue as well is accountability, which almost always lands on the shoulders of the person perceived to be “in charge of security,” according to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenrickbagnall/?originalSubdomain=ca"&gt;Kenrick Bagnall&lt;/a&gt;, president and co-founder of RB-Cyber Assurance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Whether that’s the CISO of a Fortune 500 company or the sole IT director of a 100-person manufacturing firm, when things go wrong, someone has to answer for it,” says Bagnall, a former detective constable with the Toronto Police Service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The difference between a multinational and a midsize company isn’t the exposure, Bagnall says; it’s the resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While enterprise CISOs often have access to legal teams and crisis PR advisors to help shield them, a midrange firm often has one or two people — possibly more — wearing multiple hats, like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4050232/pressure-on-cisos-to-stay-silent-about-security-incidents-growing.html"&gt;compliance&lt;/a&gt;, IT, and security all rolled into one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This can become an issue because “regulators, customers, and even the courts won’t lower the expectations just because the company is smaller,” Bagnall says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Without legal protection, CISOs face significant personal and professional risk,” Bagnall said. “They can be blamed for systemic failures outside of their control — things like legacy systems that were never budgeted for replacement, or business units that refuse to adopt security controls because they’re ‘too disruptive.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="solarwinds-case-continues-to-cast-lingering-shadow"&gt;SolarWinds case continues to cast lingering shadow&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1302388/solarwinds-calls-sec-charges-unfounded-and-inexplicable-files-for-dismissal.html"&gt;SEC’s 2023 lawsuit against SolarWinds’ CISO Timothy Brown&lt;/a&gt; over allegations that he misled investors and failed to accurately report the vendor’s cybersecurity measures is far from an isolated case. Even though the ultimate dismissal of this high-profile lawsuit eased immediate fears that many &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/569923/uber-breach-case-a-watershed-moment-for-cisos-liability-risk.html"&gt;CISOs might be held personally liable for security incidents&lt;/a&gt; the issue has far from gone way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cybersecurity leaders are increasingly held accountable for breaches and their handling of incidents,” CM Law’s Rittenberry Culhane says. “Regulatory bodies, shareholders, and courts are naming CISOs in lawsuits — even when they acted in good faith.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Midsize companies tend to have more limited legal and compliance resources, making indemnity insurance even more important as a potential safety net for security professionals employed by midrange firms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“D&amp;amp;O insurance should always be obtained but that doesn’t always cover all the risk,” Rittenberry Culhane says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rittenberry Culhane, a former general counsel turned attorney whose practice specializes in advising corporations on risk management and insurance, offered CISOs a best practice checklist:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm CISO coverage under your D&amp;amp;O policy&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Review policy limits and exclusions for cyber-related claims&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Consider supplemental indemnification agreements for CISOs and security leaders&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Align indemnity provisions with incident response and disclosure policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more, see “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2092069/navigating-personal-liability-post-data-breach-recommendations-for-cisos.html"&gt;Navigating personal liability: post data-breach recommendations for CISOs&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="governance-structures-need-revamping"&gt;Governance structures need revamping&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO role has evolved faster than the governance structures that protect it, according to RB-Cyber Assurance’s Bagnall.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We now ask security leaders to be part strategist, part technologist, part crisis responder, and part scapegoat,” Bagnall says. “Until organizations, especially midsized ones, recognize that and build legal and contractual protections accordingly, we’ll continue to see talented leaders hesitate to take on these roles, resulting in organizations of all sizes not getting the proper tech and information security guidance they need.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The CISO isn’t just defending the network — they’re defending the business’s reputation, its trust, and its future,” Bagnall adds. “That responsibility deserves protection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107332/do-liability-protection-rising-for-security-leaders-unless-youre-a-midtier-ciso.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-828)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-829)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russlands Einfluss – Kritik an Lücken bei Cybersicherheit</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108430/russlands-einfluss-kritik-an-lucken-bei-cybersicherheit.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 8786w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Die Bundesregierung wirft Russland eine massive Cyberattacke sowie die Verbreitung von Falschinformationen im jüngsten Bundestagswahlkampf vor.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;PHOTOCREO Michal Bednarek – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Grünen sehen sich durch die jüngsten Erkenntnisse über russische Einflussoperationen im Bundestagswahlkampf in ihrer Einschätzung bestärkt, dass die aktuellen Maßnahmen zum Schutz der parlamentarischen Demokratie nicht ausreichen. “Dass unsere Demokratie und ihre Institutionen zunehmend hybriden Angriffen autoritärer Regime ausgesetzt sind, kann spätestens seit den jüngsten und deutlichen Warnungen der Spitzen unserer Nachrichtendienste und der Einbestellung des russischen Botschafters niemand mehr bestreiten”, sagt der stellvertretende Vorsitzende der Grünen-Bundestagsfraktion, Konstantin von Notz.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieser bedrohlichen Kombination aus “anhaltend großer Verwundbarkeit und zunehmender Gefahren” müsse die schwarz-rote Koalition endlich entschlossen entgegentreten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="vorgaben-nur-fur-bundestagsverwaltung-nicht-das-parlament-selbst"&gt;Vorgaben nur für Bundestagsverwaltung – nicht das Parlament selbst&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zwar hätten die Regierungsfraktionen den schlechten Entwurf der Bundesregierung zur &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4090107/bundestag-beschliest-nis2-umsetzung.html" target="_blank"&gt;Umsetzung der europäischen NIS-2-Richtlinie&lt;/a&gt; zum Schutz der kritischen Infrastruktur vor Cyberangriffen so überarbeitet, dass hiervon nun auch die Bundesverwaltung und die Verwaltung des Bundestages umfasst seien. Der Bundestag selbst, inklusive der Fraktionen und Abgeordneten mit ihren Wahlkreisbüros, gehöre aber nicht zum Geltungsbereich.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es sei “geradezu absurd”, dass der Bundestag als “Herzstück der Demokratie” bisher nicht als kritische Infrastruktur eingestuft sei, obwohl er seit Jahren immer wieder angegriffen werde, sagt der Grünen-Politiker, der dem Bundestagsgremium zur Kontrolle der Geheimdienste angehört.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nis-2-richtlinie-der-eu-umgesetzt"&gt;NIS-2-Richtlinie der EU umgesetzt&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Am 6. Dezember ist das Gesetz in Kraft getreten, mit dem die NIS-2-Richtlinie in deutsches Recht umgesetzt wird. Das Gesetz erhöht die Anforderungen an die Cybersicherheit der Bundesverwaltung sowie bestimmter Unternehmen, die als wichtig für das Gemeinwesen gelten. Dazu zählen etwa Telekommunikationsanbieter und Energieversorger.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für sie gelten jetzt strengere Vorgaben in puncto IT-Sicherheit sowie die Pflicht, erhebliche Sicherheitsvorfälle dem Bundesamt für Sicherheit in der Informationstechnik zu melden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cyberattacke-und-desinformation"&gt;Cyberattacke und Desinformation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Bundesregierung wirft Russland eine massive Cyberattacke sowie Falschinformationen im jüngsten Bundestagswahlkampf vor und hatte deshalb vergangene Woche Konsequenzen angedroht. Die “gezielte Informationsmanipulation” reihe sich in eine Serie von Aktivitäten ein, die das Ziel hätten, das Vertrauen in demokratische Institutionen und Prozesse in Deutschland zu untergraben, teilte das Auswärtige Amt mit. Der russische Botschafter wurde daher ins Ministerium einbestellt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Konkret gehen nach Überzeugung der Bundesregierung zwei hybride Angriffe auf das Konto des russischen Militärgeheimdienstes GRU.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="it-der-flugsicherung-betroffen"&gt;IT der Flugsicherung betroffen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zum einen könne ein Cyberangriff gegen die Deutsche Flugsicherung (DFS) im August 2024 klar der russischen Hackergruppe “Fancy Bear” und dem GRU zugeordnet werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zum anderen könne man nun verbindlich sagen, dass Russland mit der Kampagne “Storm 1516” versucht habe, “sowohl die letzte Bundestagswahl als auch fortlaufend die inneren Angelegenheiten der Bundesrepublik Deutschland zu beeinflussen und zu destabilisieren”. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Fokus standen vor der Bundestagswahl unter anderem der Grünen-Spitzenkandidat Robert Habeck und der damalige Unions-Kanzlerkandidat Friedrich Merz (CDU). Um sie in Misskredit zu bringen, wurden unter anderem falsche Zeugenaussagen produziert und ins Netz gestellt sowie Websites mit erfundenen Inhalten aufgesetzt. (dpa/jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id=""&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108430/russlands-einfluss-kritik-an-lucken-bei-cybersicherheit.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-830)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreePBX security advisory (AV25–831)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The innovative CISO’s bucket list: Human-led transformation at the core</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108133/the-innovative-cisos-bucket-list-human-led-transformation-at-the-core.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ask any chief information security officer (CISO) what keeps them up at night and you’ll likely get a familiar list of persistent threats: ransomware, AI-enabled nation-state actors and in-the-wild exploitation of vulnerabilities hiding in an ever-expanding digital footprint. For years, the role has been defined by a state of constant vigilance, a reactive posture against an unending siege.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In nearly every conversation I now have with CISOs, I ask them what they would do if they could reclaim 25% of their time. What I hear aren’t wishes for more tropical vacations. Instead, the responses form a new bucket list focused on innovation and transformation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Energized by AI’s power and potential, CISOs are creating lists that paint a picture of a new-normal state for security that is proactive, deeply human-centric and autonomous. This isn’t about adding another blinking box to the security stack; it’s a practical — and at times profound — roadmap for re-engineering the very function of security. It’s about fundamentally shifting the paradigm of how security creates value, moving from a cost center to an innovation center that truly enables the business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on my conversations, here are the top three themes that characterize the innovative CISO’s new collective bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-tactical-debt-to-strategic-foresight"&gt;From tactical debt to strategic foresight&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before a CISO can focus on the horizon, they must first solidify the ground beneath their feet. The first theme on every CISO’s list is the desire to build a foundation of excellence that enables truly proactive strategy. This starts with clearing out the tactical debt that consumes so much time. Leaders are eager to finally tackle housekeeping — tying up the 10% of projects left at 90% completion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In security, that last 10% is far from insignificant. It comprises &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4056080/ransomware-gang-going-after-improperly-patched-sonicwall-firewalls.html"&gt;unpatched systems&lt;/a&gt;, misconfigured or &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4003365/cloud-assets-have-115-vulnerabilities-on-average-some-several-years-old.html"&gt;neglected cloud assets,&lt;/a&gt; and other open doors that attackers could walk right through. These incomplete projects represent not only a persistent security gap but also a significant waste of budget and resources that CISOs are desperate to reclaim.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This foundational work extends to the entire ecosystem. Leaders want the time to analyze all vendor assessments methodically. In an age of interconnected APIs and third-party dependencies, a CISO’s defense is only as strong as its weakest vendor. They are constantly thinking about the next Log4j scenario and know that without a proper handle on supply-chain risk, their entire strategy rests on a house of cards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, clearing the decks means nailing every last plan of action and milestone (POAM) from their audits. This goes beyond simple box-checking to demonstrating institutional integrity. It proves to the board and to regulators that security is a mature, accountable and continuous process, not just a perpetual game of whack-a-mole played in the wake of a bad report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By clearing the decks and closing existing gaps, they can shift their focus to the bigger picture: preventative security that stops attacks before they happen. This foundational excellence gives them the credibility and mental space to devote crucial time to the calculus of risk; for example, analyzing whether faster detection capabilities allow them to adjust or dial back specific preventive controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It also enables more effective strategic communication with the board, framed in the language of business acceptance and risk tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-a-unified-integrated-defense"&gt;Building a unified, integrated defense&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second major bucket list theme is &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066733/cisos-rethink-the-security-organization-for-the-ai-era.html"&gt;breaking down the silos&lt;/a&gt; that perpetually plague security organizations. Application security (AppSec), cloud security (CloudSec) and governance, risk and compliance (GRC) groups all work from different spreadsheets and tools and often with different objectives. This model is inefficient, expensive and leaves massive gaps for attackers to exploit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs aim to develop innovative processes and solutions that integrate disparate teams. As one leader eloquently described it to me, the ultimate goal is a “beautiful web of automations.” For example, this means automating control evidence across all security tools so that when an auditor requests proof of compliance, it’s generated in seconds — not through a three-week fire drill that diverts 10 analysts from their primary responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s a vision that allows all security functions to work together seamlessly, with AI correlating data from all sources to provide a single, unified picture of risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This integration extends beyond the security team itself. A key priority is bringing “the harmony of security into legal” from a privacy perspective and deeply embedding compliance into security engineering. In a world of GDPR, CCPA and a patchwork of other regulations, privacy is no longer just a legal concern: it’s a core security and engineering challenge. The CISOs want to partner with their general counsels to embed privacy-by-design into the development life cycle, rather than just react to data breaches or privacy requests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This vision is also pragmatic. CISOs are tired of shelfware — the expensive, complex tools their teams are too busy to deploy correctly. Their list includes time for strategic problem-solving: digging into their existing platforms to find creative ways to up their game, rather than just chasing the next silver-bullet solution. It’s about creative engineering to build an environment that, as one CISO told me, “just works.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-as-a-human-led-business-enabler"&gt;Security as a human-led business enabler&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, the CISO bucket list is profoundly human. This begins with a profound shift in mindset, from being a gatekeeper to being a partner. Their &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4083604/why-cybersecurity-leaders-find-important-to-prove-the-business-value-of-cyber.html"&gt;ultimate objective is business enablement&lt;/a&gt; through effective risk management, freeing leaders from being dragged into operational tasks and allowing them to function as true C-suite peers. This requires investing time in understanding the business by sitting with product managers, joining sales calls and learning what drives revenue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While AI can automate tasks, it cannot build trust. CISOs are adamant about carving out time for human engagement — building relationships with partners, mentoring associates and collaborating with fellow executives. This is the irreplaceable human work that creates the political capital and cross-functional alignment needed to drive real change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This human-centric view is also the key to solving security’s most persistent challenge: the talent gap. The bucket list is filled with a passionate desire to invest in people. Internally, this means doubling down on talent that can grow and innovate. CISOs want to provide their team members with the time and budget to obtain the desired education credits and the space for genuine innovation. This isn’t just a nice-to-have; it’s a critical retention strategy. It’s how they keep their top analysts from burning out due to alert fatigue and empower them to solve the company’s most unique and challenging problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Externally, this passion extends to giving back to the community, engaging with middle and high schools to cultivate the next generation of defenders and solving the talent pipeline problem at its root.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By fostering an environment of learning and innovation, CISOs empower their people to achieve the final — and perhaps most important — item on their bucket list: the time to break and reinvent the inefficient security processes they have all observed and been forced to live with throughout their careers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-future-is-human-led-and-ai-powered"&gt;The future is human-led and AI-powered&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Taken together, these bucket list themes paint a clear picture of the future of security leadership. It’s a future where CISOs are no longer just the chief defenders, but strategic business partners who cultivate resilience and enable innovation. Achieving this vision means shifting from chasing alerts to anticipating threats, empowering security professionals to do their most meaningful work and leveraging AI not to replace human expertise, but to amplify it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The goal is to build a security function that is as intelligent, adaptive and creative as the humans at its core. That is the future we should all strive for.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108133/the-innovative-cisos-bucket-list-human-led-transformation-at-the-core.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE OneView vulnerable to remote code execution attack</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109162/hpe-oneview-vulnerable-to-remote-code-execution-attack.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A maximum severity remote code execution vulnerability in Hewlett Packard Enterprise (HPE) OneView network and systems management suite is “bad” and needs to be patched immediately, says a cybersecurity expert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Vendors typically downplay the severity of a vulnerability,” says &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/curtis-dukes" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Curtis Dukes&lt;/a&gt;, executive VP for security best practices at the Center for Internet Security, “but HPE did not – it’s a 10.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability is remotely executable by an unauthenticated user, he added, and it impacts every recent version of the suite. On top of that, he pointed out, OneView is a central manager of IT infrastructure in organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For these reasons, the patch should be implemented immediately,” Dukes said.  “Adversaries, nation-state, and criminal gangs alike know there is a window of opportunity and are likely working on an exploit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HPE says in &lt;a href="https://support.hpe.com/hpesc/public/docDisplay?docId=hpesbgn04985en_us&amp;amp;docLocale=en_US#hpesbgn04985-rev-1-hewlett-packard-enterprise-onev-0" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its advisory&lt;/a&gt; that the vulnerability, &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-37164" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-37164&lt;/a&gt;, affects all versions between 5.20 and 10.20.  It can be resolved by applying a security hotfix, which must be reapplied after an appliance upgrade from HPE OneView version 6.60.xx to 7.00.00, as well as after any HPE Synergy Composer reimage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HPE offers separate hotfixes for &lt;a href="https://myenterpriselicense.hpe.com/cwp-ui/product-details/HPE_OV_CVE_37164_Z7550-98077/-/sw_free" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HPE OneView virtual appliance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://support.hpe.com/hpesc/public/swd/detail?swCollectionId=MTX-64daeb5ed0df44a0" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HPE Synergy Composer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The advisory adds that any third party security patches that are to be installed on systems running HPE software products should be applied in accordance with the customer’s patch management policy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked for comment, an HPE spokesperson said the company has nothing to say beyond its advisory, other than to urge admins to download and install the patches as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bicer/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jack Bicer&lt;/a&gt;, director of vulnerability research at Action1, said that because this vulnerability can be exploited without authentication or any user interaction, it is “an extremely severe security issue. There are no available workarounds, so the patch should be applied immediately. Until the patch can be applied, restrict network access to the OneView management interface to trusted administrative networks only.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HPE describes OneView as a solution that simplifies infrastructure lifecycle management across compute storage and networking through a unified API. It allows admins to create a catalogue of workload-optimized infrastructure templates so more general IT staff can rapidly and reliably provision resources. These templates can quickly provision physical, virtual, and containerized systems, setting up BIOS settings, local RAID configuration, firmware baseline, shared storage and more. HPE says software-defined intelligence allows IT to run multiple applications simultaneously with repeatable templates that ensure high reliability, consistency, and control. The vendor also says the embedded automation speeds provisioning and lowers operating expenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The most recent major vulnerability in OneView was revealed in June: &lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-37101" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-37101&lt;/a&gt;, a local elevation of privilege issue which relates specifically to OneView for VMware vCenter. If exploited, an attacker with read only privilege could upgrade their access to allow them to perform admin actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109162/hpe-oneview-vulnerable-to-remote-code-execution-attack.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing agentic AI risk: Lessons from the OWASP Top 10</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLM-powered chatbots have risks that we see playing out in the headlines on a nearly daily basis. But chatbots are limited to answering questions. AI agents, however, access data and tools and carry out tasks, making them infinitely more capable – and more dangerous to enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://genai.owasp.org/resource/owasp-top-10-for-agentic-applications-for-2026/"&gt;OWASP Top 10 for Agentic Applications&lt;/a&gt; can help CISOs explain what the issues are to their business counterparts. It can also help CISOs to directly improve agentic AI security, because it comes with &lt;a href="https://genai.owasp.org/resource/agentic-ai-threats-and-mitigations/"&gt;threats taxonomy&lt;/a&gt;, mitigation strategies and playbooks, and example threat models.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s all part of &lt;a href="https://genai.owasp.org/initiatives/agentic-security-initiative/"&gt;OWASP’s&lt;/a&gt; Agentic Security Initiative. Scott Clinton, OWASP GenAI security project board co-chair and co-founder, says he was surprised by how many agentic solutions were already deployed in organizations that the OWASP team uncovered while they were researching the list. And how many of those solutions were deployed without the knowledge of IT and security teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This level of risk is unprecedented, he says. That includes a lot of theoretical, “academic” risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However, we focused on those that were data-driven,” he says. “Where we would provide practical guidance based on real-world conditions today.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-challenge-of-educating-stakeholders"&gt;The challenge of educating stakeholders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If you’re a CSO, chances are you are having quite a time educating your stakeholders about the risks that are being introduced by the use cases that are probably being pushed on you,” says Kayla Underkoffler, director of AI security and policy advocacy at Zenity, an AI security company, and one of the core contributors to the OWASP list.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO might not be able to say no, she adds – but might also be a little hesitant to say that the company can go all in and adopt the technology without thinking of the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The list was deliberately designed to be consumable, she says. “It will help with threat modeling, help with telling the story, help explain what controls need to be in place to reduce the risk and why.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A security leader can get an agentic AI use case from the business and align the top risks to fit that use case. The list also provides a common language around agentic AI and its risks, Underkoffler says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="actionable-guidance"&gt;Actionable guidance&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agentic AI is the main topic of conversation in discussions among his peers, says Keith Hillis, VP of security engineering at Akamai Technologies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most organizations are confronted with the challenge of balancing the promising power of AI while also ensuring the organization is not incurring increased security risk,” he says. So, the biggest value he finds in the new Agentic AI OWASP top 10 is that it’s immediately useful. “It’s directly actionable as a control baseline in both security architecture and governance, risk, and compliance contexts,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One aspect of the list that he found particularly insightful was the evolution of “least privilege” to “least agency.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He recommends that CISOs use the list to assess their programs, identify gaps, and map out a plan of action for improvement. “Most likely already have active programs in place,” he says. But it’s also likely they will need to evolve to accommodate the specific risks of agentic AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="missing-pieces"&gt;Missing pieces&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The only thing that’s lacking in this first release of the list is that some of the mitigation sections aren’t detailed enough, says Zenity’s Underkoffler.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But there are plans to address that. “We have some efforts to really dive into the mitigations for security teams, to help implement these controls,” she says. “Not just descriptions of what you should do but real code examples of how you can implement them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, she says, one of the suggested mitigations is to “apply the principle of least privilege”. “Which is completely accurate,” she says. “Everyone should apply the principle of least privilege. But what does that mean for agents?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rick Holland, data and AI security officer at Cyera, a data security vendor, says he’d like the list to explain the likelihood of each type of attack. “Not all threat actors are created equal,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For organizations targeted by nation-state actors, for example, the attackers might use more sophisticated attack vectors, like memory and context poisoning or &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4015077/ai-supply-chain-threats-are-looming-as-security-practices-lag.html"&gt;agentic supply chain vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;. Rank-and-file cybercriminals might go after more low-hanging fruit, Holland says, using techniques like agent goal hijack or tool misuse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jose Lazu, associate director of product management at CMD+CTRL, a security training company, says that there are some second-tier risks that could have been included, such as model and tuning supply-chain integrity, long-horizon data poisoning, multi-agent coordination exploits, and cost-based resource exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These areas are evolving quickly, so CSOs need to keep them on their radar,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="owasp-top-10-for-agentic-ai"&gt;OWASP Top 10 for Agentic AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Below we list the OWASP Top 10 for Agentic Applications 2026, a framework that identifies the most critical security risks facing autonomous and agentic AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-agent-goal-hijack"&gt;1 – Agent Goal Hijack&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers use prompt injection, poisoned data, and other tactics to manipulate the AI agent’s goals, so that the agent carries out unwanted actions. For example, a malicious prompt can manipulate a financial agent into sending money to an attacker.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-tool-misuse-and-exploitation"&gt;2 – Tool Misuse and Exploitation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agents misuse legitimate, authorized tools for data exfiltration, destructive actions, and other unwanted behaviors. In fact, we’ve already seen examples of &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4081125/whos-the-real-boss-of-your-ai.html"&gt;AI agents deleting databases&lt;/a&gt; and wiping hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-identity-and-privilege-abuse"&gt;3 – Identity and Privilege Abuse&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Flaws in agent identity, delegation, or privilege inheritance allow attackers to escalate access, exploit confused deputy scenarios, or execute unauthorized actions across systems. For example, an attacker can use a low-privilege AI agent to relay instructions to a high-privilege in order to do things they’re not supposed to be able to do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-agentic-supply-chain-vulnerabilities"&gt;4 – Agentic Supply Chain Vulnerabilities&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compromised or malicious third-party agents, tools, models, interfaces, or registries introduce hidden instructions or unsafe behavior into agentic ecosystems. For example, an attacker can embed hidden instructions into a tool’s meta-data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-unexpected-code-execution"&gt;5 – Unexpected Code Execution&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agent-generated or agent-invoked code executes in unintended or adversarial ways, leading to host, container, or environment compromise. AI agents can generate code on the fly, bypassing normal software controls, and attackers can leverage this. For example, a coding agent writing a security patch might include a hidden back door due to poisoned training data or adversarial prompts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-memory-and-context-poisoning"&gt;6 – Memory and Context Poisoning&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers corrupt persistent agent memory, RAG stores, embeddings, or shared context to affect an agent’s future actions. For example, an attacker keeps mentioning a fake price for a product, which gets stored into an agent’s memory, and the agent might later think the price is valid and approves bookings at that price.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Contaminated context and shared memory can spread between agents, compounding corruption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-insecure-inter-agent-communication"&gt;7 – Insecure Inter-Agent Communication&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Weak authentication, integrity, or semantic validation in agent-to-agent messaging enables spoofing, tampering, replay, or manipulation. For example, an attacker can register a fake agent in a discovery service, and intercept privileged coordination traffic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="8-cascading-failures"&gt;8 – Cascading Failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A single fault, such as hallucination, poisoned memory, or compromised tool, propagates across autonomous agents. For example, a regional outage in a hyperscaler can break multiple AI services, leading to a cascade of agent failures across many organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="9-human-agent-trust-exploitation"&gt;9 – Human-Agent Trust Exploitation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agents exploit human trust, authority bias, or automation bias to influence decisions or extract sensitive information. For example, a compromised IT support agent can request credentials from an employee and send them to the attacker.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="10-rogue-agents"&gt;10 – Rogue Agents&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agents can act harmfully and deceptively in such a way that individual actions may appear legitimate. This could be due to prompt injection, or due to conflicting objectives or reward hacking. For example, an agent whose job is to reduce cloud costs might figure out that deleting files is the most efficient way to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-832)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-833)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-834)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-835)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-836)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-837)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–838)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-839)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectWise security advisory (AV25-840)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-841)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-821) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iranian APT Prince of Persia returns with new malware and C2 infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109985/iranian-apt-prince-of-persia-returns-with-new-malware-and-c2-infrastructure.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have discovered new activity from a threat actor dubbed Prince of Persia that’s believed to be tied to the Iranian government. The group appeared to have gone dormant in 2022 after multiple security companies documented its operations and crippled its command-and-control infrastructure, but new evidence shows the attackers retooled and continued to target new victims under the radar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Prince of Persia, also known as Infy based on the name of its original malware, has been operating for almost 20 years. Researchers have noted likely ties to Iran based on the group’s target selection and other factors. Victims were previously identified in 35 countries and included Iranian dissidents and government targets from Europe and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first company to &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/prince-of-persia-infy-malware-active-in-decade-of-targeted-attacks/"&gt;document the group’s attacks and malware toolkit in detail was Palo Alto Networks back in 2016&lt;/a&gt;. That same year the company &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/unit42-prince-of-persia-game-over/"&gt;executed a successful takedown operation&lt;/a&gt; that involved sinkholing the group’s command-and control servers. However, the group was back one year later with new malware variants dubbed Foudre and Tonnerre — lighting and thunder in French.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Despite the appearance of having gone dark in 2022, Prince of Persia threat actors have done quite the opposite,” researchers from security firm SafeBreach said in &lt;a href="https://www.safebreach.com/blog/prince-of-persia-a-decade-of-an-iranian-nation-state-apt-campaign-activity"&gt;a new report&lt;/a&gt;. “Our ongoing research campaign into this prolific and elusive group has highlighted critical details about their activities, C2 servers, and identified malware variants in the last three years. This threat group is still active, relevant, and dangerous.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="changes-in-malware-delivery-and-c2-infrastructure"&gt;Changes in malware delivery and C2 infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When the group fell off the radar in 2022, the latest known version of Foudre was v27 and for Tonnerre it was v15. Today, the most recent versions recovered by researchers are Foudre v34 and Tonnerre v17, both of which include significant changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Foudre is first-stage malware used for reconnaissance and victim identification. If a target is deemed important enough, the Tonnerre Trojan is deployed for data exfiltration and surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Foudre used to be distributed through malicious macros embedded in Microsoft Office documents sent as attachments in phishing emails on topics of interest to their targets. The latest version is delivered as an Excel file with an embedded malicious executable that’s not detected by any antivirus engine on VirusTotal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The embedded executable is a self-extracting archive (SFX) file that contains a malicious DLL and a decoy MP4 video file. Excel files with malicious macros continue to be used and they attempt to execute a file called ccupdate.tmp.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One major difference compared to previous versions is the switch to a new domain generation algorithm (DGA) through which the malware determines on which domain names it will find the command-and-control server. Tonnerre v17 uses the same DGA with a different key prefix, meaning the domains it will generate for C2 will be different.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SafeBreach researchers managed to identify many C2 servers and to extract data from them. Some servers were used for testing while other had data collected from real victims.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most of the victims were located in Iran, but there were some across Europe and countries like Iraq, Turkey, India, and Canada,” the researchers said. “While we have chosen not to publish the data here due to privacy concerns, we are more than willing to share the data with authorized law enforcement agencies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Monitoring the group’s campaigns is difficult because the attackers switch C2 servers quite often and they issue commands to delete the malware from the systems of victims that are no longer of interest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-shift-to-telegram"&gt;A shift to Telegram&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More recently, the researchers identified a new Tonnerre variant that’s advertised as v50, as well as an unknown new Foudre version that goes along with it. These versions use a new C2 server structure and, most importantly, can download a file from the server that enables Telegram communication via its API.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Telegram feature is enabled only for a select number of victims, but the researchers managed to use the API to query the configured Telegram channel. It had two members, one of which was a channel bot and one user named Ehsan written in Farsi, who could be one of the hackers in charge of controlling the malware and who was last active as of Dec. 13.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Ehsan is a common Persian name typical for an Iranian,” the researchers said. “This attribution is pretty strong in combination with the IP location of the attacker’s testing machine. We tracked the IP addresses used over several years, all of which indicated Iran as the location. While different IP location databases provided different cities, all of them were in Iran.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers also uncovered other samples of malware and payloads used in campaigns prior to 2022, including signs of an additional malware family called Rugissement (roar in French), a newer version of MaxPinner, a Telegram-based trojan used by the group in 2021, as well as various trojanized binaries used to distribute the malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report includes details about the new DGA algorithms as well as indicators of compromise and sample hashes in hopes it will help other companies and researchers track the elusive group’s activities going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109985/iranian-apt-prince-of-persia-returns-with-new-malware-and-c2-infrastructure.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 22:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-842)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-843)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-845) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-846)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dismantling Defenses: Trump 2.0 Cyber Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/12/dismantling-defenses-trump-2-0-cyber-year-in-review/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration has pursued a staggering range of policy pivots this past year that threaten to weaken the nation’s ability and willingness to address a broad spectrum of technology challenges, from cybersecurity and privacy to countering disinformation, fraud and corruption. These shifts, along with the president’s efforts to restrict free speech and freedom of the press, have come at such a rapid clip that many readers probably aren’t even aware of them all.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/12/dismantling-defenses-trump-2-0-cyber-year-in-review/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-847)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-848) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard fixes ‘critical’ zero-day allowing firewall takeover</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109884/watchguard-fixes-critical-zero-day-allowing-firewall-takeover.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;WatchGuard has issued an urgent patch alert for its Firebox firewall appliances after discovering a critical-rated vulnerability that is under exploit by threat actors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tracked as &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-14733" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-14733&lt;/a&gt;, with a CVSS score of 9.3, the flaw is an Out-of-bounds Write vulnerability affecting the iked process, a WatchGuard Fireware OS component responsible for the IKEv2 key exchange in IPSec VPNs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://www.watchguard.com/wgrd-psirt/advisory/wgsa-2025-00027" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;WatchGuard advisory&lt;/a&gt;, this weakness could “allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code,” taking control of the appliance through remote code execution (RCE) without having to log in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because it was under attack before a patch was made available by WatchGuard on December 18, this makes CVE-2025-14733 a bona fide zero-day vulnerability. The first job for admins should therefore be to check Firebox appliances for signs of current or recent compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;WatchGuard’s advisory lists four IP addresses associated with exploitation; outbound traffic to them is “a strong indicator of compromise,” while inbound connections from them “could indicate reconnaissance efforts or exploit attempts,” the advisory said. With logging enabled, other strong indicators were an IKE_AUTH request log message with an abnormally large CERT payload greater than 2,000 bytes, or evidence of an iked process hang, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Affected Fireware OS versions are 2025.1 up to and including 2025.1.3, 12.0 up to and including 12.11.5, and legacy 11.10.2 up to and including 11.12.4_Update1. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The resolved versions are 2025.1.4, 12.11.6, 12.5.15 (T15 &amp;amp; T35 models), and 12.3.1_Update4 (B728352) for the FIPS-certified release. There is no fix for 11.x, which is considered &lt;a href="https://www.watchguard.com/wgrd-trust-center/end-of-life-policy" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;end of life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Importantly, WatchGuard warned, patching may not be enough: “If the Firebox was previously configured with the mobile user VPN with IKEv2 or a branch office VPN using IKEv2 to a dynamic gateway peer, and both of those configurations have since been deleted, that Firebox may still be vulnerable if a branch office VPN to a static gateway peer is still configured.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And some admins have even more post-patching tasks to perform, it said, noting, “in addition to installing the latest Fireware OS that contains the fix, administrators that have confirmed threat actor activity on their Firebox appliances must take precautions to rotate all locally stored secrets on vulnerable Firebox appliances.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="deja-vu"&gt;Deja vu&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In September, WatchGuard patched a similar &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4059623/watchguard-patches-critical-vpn-flaw-in-firewalls-that-could-lead-to-compromise.html" target="_blank"&gt;Firebox vulnerability, CVE-2025-9242&lt;/a&gt;, also affecting the iked VPN configuration and given a CVSS score of 9.3. At the time, WatchGuard said there were no reports of active exploitation, but by October, the company had &lt;a href="https://www.watchguard.com/wgrd-psirt/advisory/wgsa-2025-00015" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;revised this assessment&lt;/a&gt; after exploitation attempts were detected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a reminder not to read initial vulnerability assessments for this type of infrastructure too optimistically — exploitation is frequently detected after a flaw has been made public. Firewalls and VPNs are major targets for cybercriminals, and every significant vulnerability in them represents a clear and present cyber security risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the evidence shows that some WatchGuard customers don’t patch vulnerabilities as quickly as they should. In October, &lt;a href="https://x.com/Shadowserver/status/1979902019696509099" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a scan by The Shadowserver Foundation&lt;/a&gt; found that over 71,000 Firebox appliances had not yet been patched for CVE-2025-9242, including 23,000 in the US. Despite its zero-day status, it’s likely to be a similar story for CVE-2025-14733.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Slow or reluctant patching might also explain why Russian-aligned ‘Sandworm’ hackers were recently discovered to be &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107406/russian-apt-group-pivots-to-network-edge-device-misconfigurations.html" target="_blank"&gt;targeting WatchGuard Firebox and XTM appliances&lt;/a&gt; by exploiting CVEs dating back several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109884/watchguard-fixes-critical-zero-day-allowing-firewall-takeover.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-849)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-849</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-849</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 20:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-851)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-851</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-851</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-852)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-852</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-852</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-853)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-853</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-853</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-850) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-850</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-850</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
