<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:57:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Think agentic AI is hard to secure today? Just wait a few months</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123246/think-agentic-ai-is-hard-to-secure-today-just-wait-a-few-months.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Early experimentation with agentic AI has given CISOs a preview of the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109999/agentic-ai-already-hinting-at-cybersecuritys-pending-identity-crisis.html"&gt;possible cybersecurity nightmares ahead&lt;/a&gt;. But with autonomous agent adoption expected to soar throughout 2026, CISOs’ lack of visibility into agentic identities, activities, and decision-making is set to get far worse in quick measure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agentic use will vary by enterprise, but analysts, consultants, and security vendors agree that their numbers will expand far beyond CISOs’ ability to maintain control as they simultaneously navigate the price of decades of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3520884/personhood-cybersecuritys-next-great-authentication-battle-as-ai-improves.html"&gt;identity governance neglect for non-human identities (NHIs)&lt;/a&gt;, including service accounts, OAuth tokens, embedded API keys, and automation credentials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ishraqkhann/"&gt;Ishraq Khan&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of coding productivity tool vendor Kodezi, sees most enterprises today housing 8 to 10 million such identities, a figure he projects will hit 20 to 50 million by year’s end.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.digicert.com/blog/author/jason-sabin"&gt;Jason Sabin&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at DigiCert, predicts an even steeper rise, with enterprises’ identity role calls increasing 10 times by January 2027.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We need to rethink how identity and data provisioning is done and put in place the right processes that can scale with the growth of agentic identities,” says&lt;a href="https://acceligence.com/talent/profiles/justin-greis/"&gt; Justin Greis&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of consulting firm Acceligence and former head of the North American cybersecurity practice at McKinsey. “You simply cannot apply human processes to something that will scale at this rate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="visibility-is-the-bigger-problem"&gt;Visibility is the bigger problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As bad as that massively expanding identity universe is, the bigger problem may be how little visibility CISOs have into NHIs, with AI agents offering not just the fastest growth but the least visibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://moorinsightsstrategy.com/team/jason-andersen/"&gt;Jason Andersen&lt;/a&gt;, principal analyst for Moor Insights &amp;amp; Strategy, estimates 25% NHI visibility for enterprise CISOs today. “The remaining 75% is in the shadows,” he adds. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those shadows include “semi-shadow” activities, such as third parties or lines of business that have been given permission to experiment with agentic AI but have not necessarily alerted IT or security teams about what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, Andersen sees that number getting a lot worse, projecting visibility to drop to about 12% by year-end and then into the single digits by January 2028. “And then they’ll likely fix it,” he says, adding, “It’s a big frickin’ problem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner analysts &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/jeremy-dhoinne"&gt;Jeremy D’Hoinne&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/akif-khan"&gt; Akif Khan&lt;/a&gt; agree CISOs face urgent problems in this area today. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NHIs are going to be “several orders of magnitude larger than human identities and most organizations do not have a strong enough foundation to manage both machine and agentic identities,” Gartner’s Khan says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprise CISOs are “blind to what is happening. The numbers are going to be overwhelming,” D’Hoinne adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forrester expects similar outcomes for CISOs. “There is going to be an explosion of non-human identities,” says Forrester analyst&lt;a href="https://www.forrester.com/analyst-bio/geoff-cairns/BIO20052"&gt; Geoff Cairns&lt;/a&gt;. “The exponential growth is indisputable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kodezi’s Khan notes that the lack of a robust base for NHI governance — now including agentic AI — is a critical problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises never solved non-human authentication so we don’t have the systems in place for a good secure environment. At its core, we never had the right foundation. That means that we will never have that perfect inventory,” he explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cost-effective-fix-do-nothing"&gt;Cost effective fix: Do nothing&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kodezi’s Khan offers an interesting fix for that foundational problem: Don’t even try. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He argues it’s a money pit that will never be fully resolved. Instead, he suggests pouring resources into creating a strict identity strategy for every NHI going forward. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Aim for containment rather than for perfection. You can’t really govern every identity, but if you start now, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; govern future actions,” he says, adding that, over the years, the percentage of uncontrolled identities will slowly drop as millions more identities are added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikkale"&gt;Nik Kale&lt;/a&gt;, principal engineer at Cisco and member of the Coalition for Secure AI (CoSAI) and ACM’s AI Security (AISec) program committee, agrees with that assessment. “If you are drowning, you don’t start by draining the ocean.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The ratios tell you why this is so ungovernable. These identities are growing much faster than the discovery capabilities,” Kale notes. “It becomes a math problem at that point.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As for the path forward, Kale advises not to try to fix the legacy situation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You just have to contain it, segment it, assume it’s compromised and that it’s hostile territory,” he says. “The plan needs to be containment plus a clean slate going forward. Inventory all non-human identities. Identify which have standing versus just-in-time access. Assign ownership to every one of them. No product required — just a terrifying spreadsheet.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kale adds that cleaning IDs from now on will deliver a better benefit to CISOs. “In my opinion, the ratio matters less than the governance gap. Whether it’s 200:1 or 500:1, if IAM [identity access management] only manages 44% of them, the attack surface is already unmanageable,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But he stresses that NHIs — especially when agentic — can be particularly difficult to find, let alone control. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most organizations are undercounting by two to three times because machine identities are scattered across cloud consoles, repos, config files, and secrets managers that nobody’s aggregating,” Kale says. “Agentic AI is a multiplier, not an addition. Agents spawn subagents, create credentials dynamically, and establish agent-to-agent auth chains. One agent deployment can generate dozens of new machine identities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research, sees a reckoning ahead.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The enterprise control plane has quietly shifted from humans to machines, while governance stayed behind,” he says. “Once nonhuman identities outnumber humans by hundreds to one, identity stops being an administrative discipline and becomes the operating system of trust. The failure mode is not that there are too many identities; it is that enterprises cannot assert intent, ownership, and accountability for what those identities are doing at runtime.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the situation is intensifying thanks to today’s business environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is compounded by incentive structures that reward speed and uptime while penalizing breakage, which leads teams to overpermission machines by default,” Gogia says. “Overpermission is invisible until it is catastrophic. At that point, audits, roles, and reviews offer comfort but not control.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="agentic-didnt-start-the-fire"&gt;Agentic didn’t start the fire&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;None of this situation was caused by agentic AI, Gogia underscores. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises did not enter a machine identity crisis because of agentic AI. They entered it years ago through service accounts, embedded API keys, long lived tokens, and automation credentials that were created to keep systems moving and then quietly forgotten,” he says. “What agents change is velocity and reach. They inherit trust and then operationalize it at machine speed. A legacy identity that once represented a contained risk now becomes an execution layer across systems, vendors, and workflows.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia adds: “The most dangerous assumption in enterprise security today is that valid identity implies safe behavior. In machine-driven environments, credentials are often correct and activity is authorized, yet outcomes are harmful. Machines do not follow joiner-mover-lever models. They do not pause for approvals. They operate continuously and propagate actions automatically.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, decision-making agents, layered into operations, achieve a rate of action that “collapses the window for detection,” he says. “The failure shifts from prevention to detection lag. By the time humans understand what happened, the agent already did it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This should — and likely will — cause a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089732/rethinking-identity-for-the-ai-era-cisos-must-build-trust-at-machine-speed.html"&gt;rethinking from both enterprise CISOs and CIOs&lt;/a&gt;, he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This moment tests leadership alignment. CIOs are under pressure to deploy agents for productivity and scale. CISOs are staring at accountability gaps, forensic complexity, and cascading blast radius. If these agendas diverge, the enterprise ends up with autonomy without responsibility. Boards will ask who owns an agent, who sets its boundaries, and who answers when it causes harm,” Gogia explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The next phase of governance will require responsibility mapping for agents, separation of duties for high impact actions, and clear human checkpoints where judgment truly matters,” he adds. “Incident response must also evolve toward reconstructing chains of machine decisions, not just tracing logins.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123246/think-agentic-ai-is-hard-to-secure-today-just-wait-a-few-months.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OTF GRIMM: Swedish organiser of serious violence arrested in Iraq</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</link>
      <description>A High-Value Target under Europol-supported Operational Taskforce GRIMM was arrested in Iraq following long-term cooperation between the Swedish Police Authority and Iraqi law enforcement authorities. The 21-year-old suspect, a Swedish national who was listed on the EU Most Wanted list, is identified as a key organiser of serious violence directed at Sweden from abroad.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNU security advisory (AV26-047) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmarterTools security advisory (AV25-866) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol report: evolving tactics in maritime cocaine trafficking operations</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</link>
      <description>A new Europol report published today provides a comprehensive analysis of the evolving tactics employed by criminal networks to traffic cocaine into Europe via maritime routes. The report, 'Diversification in Maritime Cocaine Trafficking Modi Operandi', provides an in-depth analysis of the shifting tactics employed by organised crime networks, which continue to exploit vulnerabilities and evade detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL security advisory (AV26-058)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol supports French investigation into alleged criminal activity linked to platform X</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</link>
      <description>The investigation is conducted by the Paris Public Prosecutor’s Office with the support of the French Gendarmerie’s cybercrime unit (UNCyber) and Europol.On the action day, French authorities carried out investigative measures in the offices of the platform in France. Europol supported the investigation through its European Cybercrime Centre (EC3), providing specialised cybercrime expertise and deploying an analyst on the ground...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notepad++ infrastructure hijacked by Chinese APT in sophisticated supply chain attack</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126269/notepad-infrastructure-hijacked-by-chinese-apt-in-sophisticated-supply-chain-attack.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The popular open-source text editor Notepad++ was targeted in a sophisticated supply chain attack that allowed Chinese state-sponsored hackers to deliver malware through compromised software updates, the project’s maintainer disclosed in a &lt;a href="https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/hijacked-incident-info-update/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack, which ran from June through December 2025, involved infrastructure-level compromise of Notepad++’s shared hosting provider that enabled threat actors to selectively intercept and redirect update traffic to servers under their control, Notepad++ author Don Ho said in the statement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Multiple independent security researchers have assessed that the threat actor is likely a Chinese state-sponsored group, which would explain the highly selective targeting observed during the campaign,” Ho wrote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident highlights a critical blind spot in enterprise security. Attackers prize distribution points like update servers because one successful insertion delivers access to thousands of environments at once, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.forrester.com/blogs/when-a-hosting-provider-becomes-a-hostile-provider-the-notepad-compromise/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Forrester analysis&lt;/a&gt; also published Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The compromise is particularly concerning because Notepad++ is widely used by developers, analysts, and IT operators, yet “does not require an enterprise contract or license, and does not include usage tracking by default and therefore may not be tracked in an enterprise software inventory,” Forrester analysts Jeff Pollard, Allie Mellen, Jess Burn, Janet Worthington, and Tope Olufon wrote in their blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-the-attack-unfolded"&gt;How the attack unfolded&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The compromise occurred at the hosting provider level rather than through vulnerabilities in Notepad++ code, Ho said in the note. Attackers gained access to the shared hosting server and redirected traffic from the update endpoint to attacker-controlled servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The bad actors specifically searched for the Notepad++ domain to intercept the traffic to your website, as they might know the then-existing Notepad++ vulnerabilities related to insufficient update verification controls,” the hosting provider said in a statement shared by Ho.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The name of the hosting provider, however, is not disclosed in the blog post. A detailed query seeking comments from Ho remains unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The server was initially compromised until September 2, 2025, when scheduled maintenance included kernel and firmware updates. However, attackers maintained stolen credentials to internal services until December 2, 2025, allowing continued traffic interception, according to the provider’s statement. The targeting was highly selective — traffic from certain users was redirected while most legitimate updates proceeded normally, Ho said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="rapid7-identifies-custom-malware"&gt;Rapid7 identifies custom malware&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity firm Rapid7 also published a &lt;a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/tr-chrysalis-backdoor-dive-into-lotus-blossoms-toolkit/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;detailed technical analysis&lt;/a&gt; corroborating Ho’s disclosure and identifying the attack as part of a broader campaign deploying previously undocumented malware. Rapid7’s investigation uncovered a custom backdoor the firm dubbed “Chrysalis,” alongside Cobalt Strike and Metasploit frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Forensic analysis conducted by the MDR team suggests that the initial access vector aligns with publicly disclosed abuse of the Notepad++ distribution infrastructure,” Rapid7 researcher Ivan Feigl wrote. The Chrysalis backdoor supports 16 distinct command capabilities ranging from interactive shell access to complete self-removal. One loader variant exploited Microsoft Warbird, an internal code protection framework, to execute shellcode while masquerading as a legitimate Microsoft-signed binary.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rapid7 attributed the campaign to Lotus Blossom, also known as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3967354/chinese-apt-billbug-deploys-new-malware-toolset-in-attack-on-multiple-sectors.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;Billbug&lt;/a&gt;, a Chinese APT group active since 2009, known for espionage operations targeting government, telecommunications, and critical infrastructure sectors across Southeast Asia and Central America. The attribution is based on strong similarities to previously published Symantec research, particularly the use of a renamed Bitdefender executable to side-load malicious DLLs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-detection-proved-difficult"&gt;Why detection proved difficult&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The sophisticated malware evaded detection for months largely because a compromised utility blends into normal developer behavior, making it challenging to identify. “Most EDR programs are blind by design to ‘expected’ developer behavior,” the Forrester analysts wrote. “A compromised utility does not need exploits, LOLBins, or exotic malware. It just needs to look boring—like something a dev would do.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ho noted that his incident response team was unable to extract concrete indicators of compromise despite analyzing roughly 400 GB of server logs. In an edit posted Sunday, Ho acknowledged Rapid7’s more detailed findings. “Last evening I received an email from Ivan Feigl (Rapid7) to share their excellent investigation story—it seems to be the same story, and obviously, they have more tangible information (including IoCs) than I do,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rapid7 identified network infrastructure, including IP addresses in Malaysia and China, along with command and control URLs, including api.skycloudcenter.com and api.wiresguard.com.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-enhancements-and-broader-implications"&gt;Security enhancements and broader implications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In response, Notepad++ has migrated to a new hosting provider and enhanced WinGup (the updater component) in version 8.8.9 to verify both certificate and signature of downloaded installers, Ho said. Certificate and signature verification will be enforced starting with version 8.9.2, expected within approximately one month.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I deeply apologize to all users affected by this hijacking,” Ho wrote. “I recommend downloading v8.9.1 and running the installer to update your Notepad++ manually.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For enterprise security teams, the incident underscores the need for comprehensive software inventories that include widely used utilities, cryptographic verification of all updates, and what Forrester described as a “shift from implicit trust to continuous verification.” The Forrester analysts also warned that AI agents could amplify similar risks. “The same supply chain blind spots that let a compromised tool blend into developer noise will let a compromised agent establish persistence and elevate privileges at scale,” they wrote. Organizations that cannot strictly define what should execute and communicate are “structurally conceding this class of attack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126269/notepad-infrastructure-hijacked-by-chinese-apt-in-sophisticated-supply-chain-attack.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Critical Flaws in n8n AI Workflow Automation Platform Allow Complete Takeover</title>
      <link>https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/two-critical-flaws-in-n8n-ai/</link>
      <description>Pillar Security discovered two new critical vulnerabilities in n8n that could lead to supply chain compromise, credential harvesting and complete takeover attacks</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/two-critical-flaws-in-n8n-ai/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-059) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-060)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-060</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-060</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719 - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-061)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-062)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-064)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-065)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From credentials to cloud admin in 8 minutes: AI supercharges AWS attack chain</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126336/from-credentials-to-cloud-admin-in-8-minutes-ai-supercharges-aws-attack-chain.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors tore through an Amazon Web Services environment in under eight minutes, chaining together credential theft, privilege escalation, lateral movement, and GPU resource abuse with the help of large language models, an attack so fast that defenders had virtually no time to react. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to new findings from Sysdig’s Threat Research Team, the intruders turned a single exposed credential in a public S3 bucket into full administrative control, demonstrating how AI‑assisted automation has collapsed the cloud attack lifecycle from hours to mere minutes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The operation, observed in November 2025, reportedly combined a cloud misconfiguration with large language models (LLMs) to compress the entire attack lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The cybersecurity world today is brand new,” said Ram Varadarajan, CEO at Acalvio. “In this threat environment, organizations have to accept that the speed of the breach has shifted from days to minutes. Autonomous intruders can now escalate from initial access to full administrative control in minutes.” Defending against this class of attacks, he added, demands “AI-focused technology” that can reason and respond at the same speed as automated attackers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Public Buckets to privilege escalation in minutes&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The compromise began with valid AWS credentials left exposed in public S3 buckets. Those buckets contained AI-related data, and the associated IAM user had permissions to interact with &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572509/new-cryptomining-malware-targets-aws-lambda.html"&gt;Lambda&lt;/a&gt; and limited access to Amazon Bedrock. “This user was likely intentionally created by the victim organization to automate Bedrock tasks with Lambda functions across the environment,” Sysdig researchers said in a blog post shared with CSO ahead of its publication on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With read access across the environment, the attacker rapidly enumerated AWS services, then escalated privileges by modifying an existing Lambda function. By injecting malicious code into a function that already had an overly permissive execution role, the attacker was able to create new access keys for an administrative user and retrieve them directly from the Lambda execution output.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, said the root cause was depressingly familiar. “We must look past the novelty of AI assistance to recognize the mundane error that enabled it,” he said. “The entire compromise began because the victim left valid credentials exposed in public &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094475/ransomware-gangs-find-a-new-hostage-your-aws-s3-buckets.html"&gt;S3 buckets&lt;/a&gt;. This failure represents a stubborn refusal to master security fundamentals.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Lambda code showed signs of LLM generation, including comprehensive exception handling, iterative targeting logic, and even non-English comments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to an AWS spokesperson, AWS services and infrastructure are not affected by this issue, and they operated as designed throughout the incident described. “The report describes an account compromised through misconfigured S3 buckets. We recommend all customers secure their cloud resources by following security, identity, and compliance best practices, including never opening up public access to S3 buckets or any storage service, least-privilege access, secure credential management, and enabling monitoring services like GuardDuty, to reduce risks of unauthorized activity. AWS customers who suspect or become aware of malicious activity within their AWS accounts should follow guidance for remediating potentially compromised AWS credentials or contact AWS Support for assistance.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Lateral movement, LLMjacking, and GPU abuse&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once administrative access was obtained, the attacker moved laterally across 19 distinct &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/mediapackage/latest/userguide/policy-principal.html"&gt;AWS principals&lt;/a&gt;, assuming multiple roles and creating new users to spread activity across identities. This approach enabled persistence and complicated detection, the researchers noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attackers then shifted focus to Amazon Bedrock, enumerating available models and confirming that model invocation logging was disabled. The researchers said multiple foundation models were invoked, a pattern consistent with “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3535433/llmjacking-how-attackers-use-stolen-aws-credentials-to-enable-llms-and-rack-up-costs-for-victims.html"&gt;LLMjacking&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Then, the operation escalated into resource abuse. After preparing keys and security groups, the attackers attempted to initiate high-end GPU instances for machine learning workloads. While most powerful instances failed due to capacity limits, a costly GPU instance was eventually launched, with scripts to install &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/527144/build-ci-sdlc-nvidia-eyes-cuda-in-mobile-devices.html"&gt;CUDA&lt;/a&gt;, deploy training frameworks, and expose a public JupyterLab interface.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some of the code was found referencing nonexistent repositories and resources, which Sysdig researchers attributed to LLM &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3961304/ai-hallucinations-lead-to-new-cyber-threat-slopsquatting.html"&gt;hallucinations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts argue that the most unsettling takeaway isn’t that AI introduced a new attack technique. It is that AI removed hesitation.“When you strip this attack down to its essentials, what stands out isn’t a breakthrough technique,” said Shane Barney, CISO at Keeper Security. “It’s how little resistance the environment offered once the attacker obtained legitimate access.” He warned that AI collapses reconnaissance, privilege testing, and lateral movement into “a single, rapid sequence,” eliminating the buffer time defenders have historically relied on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To reduce exposure, Sysdig researchers advised enforcing least privilege across IAM users, roles, and Lambda execution roles, tightly limiting permissions such as “UpdateFunctionCode” and “PassRole”, and ensuring sensitive S3 buckets are never public. Enabling Lambda versioning, turning on Amazon Bedrock model invocation logging, and monitoring for large-scale enumeration activity are also critical, they added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126336/from-credentials-to-cloud-admin-in-8-minutes-ai-supercharges-aws-attack-chain.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-066)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-067)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-068) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV26-069)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-070)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-071)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay or should I go?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125356/should-i-stay-or-should-i-go-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even the most seasoned CISOs sometimes run into insurmountable roadblocks at their organizations. Despite their best efforts at building relationships, and even with their technical depth and business acumen, they can’t garner the support needed to protect their organizations — and themselves — from pending disaster.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the big picture, CISO roles are hard, and so the majority of CISOs switch jobs every two to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4049347/lack-of-board-access-the-no-1-ciso-dissatisfaction.html#:~:text=" target="_blank"&gt;three years or less&lt;/a&gt;. Lack of support from senior leadership and lack of budget commensurate with the organization’s size and industry are top reasons for this CISO churn, according to The life and times of cybersecurity professionals &lt;a href="https://issa.org/new-research-from-techtargets-enterprise-strategy-group-and-the-issa-reveals-crisis-in-leadership-as-the-cybersecurity-profession-grows-increasingly-difficult/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from the ISSA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More specifically, CISOs leave on account of limited board engagement, high accountability with insufficient authority, executive misalignment, and ongoing barriers to implementing risk management and resilience, according to an ISSA spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many of these roadblocks are common across industries, so how does a CISO know when it’s time to move on?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They look for the flags.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-flag-playing-lip-service"&gt;Red flag: Playing lip service&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A common red flag and reason CISO’s leave their jobs is because leadership is paying “lip service” to auditors, customers and competitors, says FinTech CISO Marius Poskus, a popular blogger on security leadership who posted an essay about resigning from “security‑theater roles.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, even before signing onto a new job, Poskus suggests looking for recent events proceeding the organization hiring its first-ever CISO. “I see this often. Usually after an impactful breach, they negotiate fines down by saying they’ll hire their first CISO. In fact, a friend in New Zealand reached out to me today with just such a story,” he tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other indicators that executives are playing lip service to security include constant resource denials, lack of risk ownership, and failure to sign off on identified risks at the top level, leaving the CISO vulnerable. To this end, Poskus shared a &lt;a href="https://www.mpcybersecurity.co.uk/blog/why-you-need-a-cybersecurity-charter-and-how-to-get-it-approved" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;security executive charter&lt;/a&gt; that outlines responsibilities of senior executives’ accountability around the cybersecurity program.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, since lack of access to the board is a top-cited reason for leaving, Poskus says to look for problematic reporting lines that block access to executives, such as through a boss who refuses to report issues and requests to executives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-flag-cognitive-disconnect"&gt;Red flag: Cognitive disconnect&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lack of access to executives and the board comes up repeatedly in Cybersecurity Ventures &lt;a href="https://cybersecurityventures.com/cybersecurity-almanac-2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; as a top reason CISO’s decide to leave their jobs, according to Steve Morgan, founder of Cybersecurity Ventures. He cites lack of support as another top reason CISO’s leave.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Splunk’s &lt;a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/campaigns/ciso-report.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 CISO report&lt;/a&gt; found 29% of respondents had adequate budget compared to 41% of boards who felt cybersecurity budgets were adequate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This cognitive disconnect was clear in &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nawabkabir/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nawab Kabir’s&lt;/a&gt; case. He declined on the prospect of taking a full-time CISO role to become a fractional CISO after a merger left him reporting to an IT director rather than the CEO as he previously had reported to. “One of the key red flags for CISO’s is if their boss, usually the CIO or CTO, repeatedly blocks attempts to escalate missions to the CEO by downplaying the real risk, asking the CISO to accept that risk, and saying that the CEO simply doesn’t care. So, the risk never gets mentioned in executive leadership meetings,” Kabir says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After the merger, the initiatives and intervention strategies he developed never got past the director of IT (who came from the merger) to executive leadership. So, Kabir knew it was time to leave. “That’s one of the reasons I became a fractional cybersecurity leader, which I love because now I’m being hired to make a difference at my client companies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-flag-pushing-ethical-boundaries"&gt;Red Flag: Pushing ethical boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Above all these, the biggest red flag is when leadership pushes against your professional and personal ethics. For example, when a CEO or board wants to conceal compliance gaps, cover up reportable breaches, and refuse to sign off on responsibility for gaps and reporting failures they’ve been made aware of. “This happens more often than we know because most CISOs won’t make public what happened behind the scenes that made them quit, especially when they’re looking for new jobs,” Poskus explains. “Your integrity is your most important asset, so that’s the biggest red flag when we talk about leaving a role rather than staying and fighting.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In these types of scenarios, the CISO likely lacks critical allies within the organization. Acknowledge this sense of vulnerability, Poskus advises, because it’s a huge red flag. Human resources and legal teams in these situations won’t help because they owe their loyalty to the business, he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such was the case with former Uber CISO &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575375/former-uber-cso-joe-sullivan-and-lessons-learned-from-the-infamous-2016-uber-breach.html" target="_blank"&gt;Joe Sullivan&lt;/a&gt; who was thrown under the bus by Uber’s shady leadership after a 2016 breach. In contrast, SolarWinds CISO Tim Brown felt fully supported after a historic &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570191/solarwinds-supply-chain-attack-explained-why-organizations-were-not-prepared.html" target="_blank"&gt;supply chain hack in 2020&lt;/a&gt; spread to 18,000 business clients &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570191/solarwinds-supply-chain-attack-explained-why-organizations-were-not-prepared.html" target="_blank"&gt;through its Orion&lt;/a&gt; network management product patch update system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Joe was in such a difficult situation. The company was aggressive towards him, which was so different from my experience at SolarWinds,” says Brown, who had responded to the breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="green-flag-they-have-your-back"&gt;Green flag: They have your back&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In contrast to Sullivan’s employer, Brown shares that everyone involved in responding to the SolarWinds breach — from IT responders to communications, legal, and executives — felt the same way he did in terms of making things right for clients and regulators. “My situation was difficult, but manageable in many ways because of that support from my team. From day one, we had no question about doing the right thing. We decided on transparency to our customers all the way through the SEC filings,” Brown explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even as a new CEO came onboard under a planned transition shortly after the breach, and as the SEC charged SolarWinds and Brown with fraud for certifying compliance with SolarWinds security shortly before the sophisticated supply-chain hack occurred, Brown has felt ongoing support.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Given his access to the board and CEO, Brown knew well before the breach that the company had his back. He also points to another green flag: The company’s commitment to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518982/tabletop-exercise-scenarios.html" target="_blank"&gt;tabletop exercises&lt;/a&gt; of impactful breaches. Throughout the practice scenarios, teams worked together under a customer-centric mandate that advocated transparency and education, the same playbook that they followed in the 2020 breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109992/what-cisos-should-know-about-the-solarwinds-lawsuit-dismissal.html" target="_blank"&gt;SEC dropped its charges against Brown&lt;/a&gt;, and in November, he attended a virtual toast in his honor to celebrate the SEC dropping the case against him “without prejudice.” More than 200 CISOs of top companies joined, including co-host Joe Sullivan. Ultimately, as Brown had hoped, the entire experience provided teachable moments to help push the CISO role up the maturity curve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="changing-internal-mindsets"&gt;Changing internal mindsets&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As CISOs burn out or leave under stressful circumstances, many turn to fractional work as Kabir has. And, in his case, working with new clients gives him plenty of opportunities to turn red flags into green flags.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, he points to lack of board access and resources. In many cases he steps into, the former cybersecurity leaders didn’t understand the business and talked technically over their executives’ heads. As a result, he’s had to convert fatigued, resistant executive teams that don’t want to repeat those experiences with a new cybersecurity leader.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For these clients, he likes to call “all hands” to a meeting and conduct what he calls interactive “business continuity stress tests” in table-top scenarios that impact a revenue-generating activity. “Take manufacturing, if this machine is down for six to eight hours what would be our revenue costs associated with this downtime? That gets attention,” Kabir says. “Then finance starts talking within their teams and it goes beyond that to the CEO because now it’s seen as a business issue.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs, then, can change culture to turn a red flag into a green flag. But knowing when and how to do so depends on the indicators mentioned. Even with a fractional role, CISOs should still expect some of their clients to try and compromise ethics by covering up findings for example. Fortunately, that red flag usually reveals itself early in the audit, when the executives and business units appear afraid to answer questions as if trying to hide something.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A lot of red flags have to do with lack of security culture or mismatch in understanding the risk tolerance of the company and what the actual risks are. This red flag goes beyond: If they don’t want to be questioned about what they’ve done so far, that is a huge red flag that they’re covering something up,” Kabir explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To be safe, he carries indemnity insurance and retains his own legal counsel — as should all CISO’s with large enough salaries who are reporting to the board and C-suite. Because, as in the case with Joe Sullivan and many other examples that go unreported, CISO’s can’t count on their organizations to have their backs legally or professionally should the big one hit&lt;a&gt; —&lt;/a&gt; especially if those executives, by virtue of their unresponsiveness and lack of support, are the cause of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125356/should-i-stay-or-should-i-go-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminals set sites on identities</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126064/identities-in-the-crosshairs-of-cybercriminals.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eye Security’s &lt;a href="https://www.eye.security/de/trend-report-der-stand-der-incident-response-2026" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2026 State of Incident Response Report&lt;/a&gt; shows that cyberattacks on companies are increasingly going undetected, and the damage occurs within minutes. According to the report, attackers are now focusing less on hacking systems and more on exploiting existing access points.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity-based attacks dominate the field, with passwords being involved in 97% of incidents tracked by Eye Security. Abuse of legitimate accounts is a primary cause of cloud security incidents and drives the business of initial access brokers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the study’s results show that attackers’ fundamental methods remain unchanged. “Even in 2026, compromise will still begin with phishing, exploiting misconfigured or vulnerable internet-enabled systems, social engineering, or attacks via the software supply chain,” explains Lodi Hensen, VP of security operations at Eye Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="bec-attacks-are-particularly-common"&gt;BEC attacks are particularly common&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570999/business-email-compromise-bec-attacks-take-phishing-to-the-next-level.html" target="_blank"&gt;Business email compromise (BEC)&lt;/a&gt; is the most common form of attack, according to the study: More than 70% of incidents fall into this category. In 40% of these cases, phishing served as the initial point of entry. Analysts say that BEC attacks can remain undetected for weeks without continuous monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the study highlights that ransomware remains one of the biggest threats. “The proliferation of Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS), BuilderLeaks, and access broker marketplaces has lowered the barriers to entry and created a professional ecosystem,” the authors explain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report reveals a dangerous trend: the commercialization of insider knowledge. “Groups like ShinyHunters are actively recruiting employees to buy access credentials. This blurs the line between external attacks and insider threats,” the security researchers explain. “For ransomware actors, this purchased access is often faster and more reliable than technical hacking.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies in the industrial, construction, and transport and logistics sectors are particularly affected. Many ransomware attackers exploit everyday vulnerabilities: unprotected applications, insecure remote access, or phishing emails through which employees unknowingly disclose login credentials. The analysis evaluated a total of 630 security incidents in Europe from 2023 to 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126064/identities-in-the-crosshairs-of-cybercriminals.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero trust in practice: A deep technical dive into going fully passwordless in hybrid enterprise environments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126694/zero-trust-in-practice-a-deep-technical-dive-into-going-fully-passwordless-in-hybrid-enterprise-environments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the past three years, I’ve led passwordless migration initiatives at three Fortune 500 companies, and I can tell you with confidence that eliminating passwords from a hybrid Active Directory and Microsoft Entra ID environment is one of the most rewarding — and most underestimated — technical challenges in modern identity management. The theoretical appeal is obvious: no passwords means no credential compromise, phishing becomes exponentially harder and your security posture fundamentally shifts from “prevent breaches” to “assume breach.” But the reality of implementation in environments spanning on-premises and cloud infrastructure? That’s where the genuine complexity lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most organizations I’ve worked with start this journey with romantic notions of flipping a switch and sailing into a passwordless future. What they discover instead is that achieving true passwordless authentication requires rethinking identity architecture from the ground up. It’s not about swapping one authentication method for another — it’s about fundamentally restructuring how you verify identity across every layer of your infrastructure. The transition demands careful planning, technical rigor and unwavering commitment to security principles over convenience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="prerequisites-building-the-foundation-before-the-migration"&gt;Prerequisites: Building the foundation before the migration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before we can talk about passwordless authentication, we need to address what I call the “prerequisite triangle”: cloud Kerberos trust, device registration and Conditional Access policies. Skip any one of these, and your migration will stall before it gains momentum.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud Kerberos trust is the unsung hero of hybrid passwordless deployments. When I started working on my first full migration, I underestimated how critical this piece was. Traditional Kerberos assumes a managed network with domain controllers you control. Cloud Kerberos allows your cloud-based services to issue Kerberos tickets to hybrid-joined devices without requiring a domain controller on the internet. This is your bridge between on-premises and cloud identity, and it’s non-negotiable for seamless hybrid authentication. The mechanics of Kerberos itself haven’t changed significantly since its introduction in the 1980s, but extending it to cloud environments required a fundamental rethinking of how authentication tickets are issued and validated across trust boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Getting cloud Kerberos working requires Azure AD Connect to run version 2.0 or later with the cloud sync agent configured for password hash synchronization (even if you’re not using it for authentication — this remains a prerequisite). Your hybrid-joined devices need to be running Windows 10 20H2 or later, and they must have reliable network connectivity to both your on-premises domain controllers and Azure. In one deployment, my team spent two weeks troubleshooting authentication failures before discovering that a firewall rule was blocking the necessary communication on port 88. This single finding reinforced why network validation should occur before pilot rollout, not during.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Device registration and management come next. Every device attempting passwordless authentication must be either Azure AD joined, hybrid AD joined or registered with Entra ID. I’ve found that hybrid-joined devices work best in truly hybrid environments because they maintain connection to on-premises infrastructure while gaining cloud identity benefits. Your Intune Mobile Device Management deployment becomes critical here — devices must be compliant with your policies before they’re trusted for passwordless sign-in. This means ensuring that disk encryption is enabled, that antivirus is running and that devices meet your organization’s baseline security posture. The compliance baseline isn’t punitive; it’s the minimum acceptable security threshold.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Conditional Access policies form the final leg of the prerequisite triangle. These aren’t optional — they’re how you enforce the “trust zero, verify always” principle of Zero Trust. The &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/sp/800-207/final"&gt;National Institute of Standards and Technology&lt;/a&gt; defines Zero Trust architecture as requiring continuous verification and explicit access grants based on all available data points. I configure policies that require device compliance, enforce multi-factor authentication for sensitive operations, and block legacy authentication entirely. The policy I typically recommend as a starting point requires hybrid-joined devices, compliant Intune status and MFA for all access to on-premises resources, while allowing seamless sign-in for fully compliant devices. This creates a virtuous cycle where security and user experience reinforce each other.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="architecture-decisions-hybrid-authentication-flows-and-windows-hello-for-business"&gt;Architecture decisions: Hybrid authentication flows and Windows Hello for Business&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once your prerequisites are in place, you face critical architectural decisions that will shape your deployment for years to come. The primary decision point is whether to use Windows Hello for Business, FIDO2 security keys or phone sign-in as your primary authentication mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my experience, Windows Hello for Business is the foundation for hybrid environments. It leverages biometric or PIN authentication on the device itself, preventing credentials from ever being transmitted across the network. When a user signs in with Windows Hello, they’re not sending a password or even a credential — they’re using a private key stored in the device’s Trusted Platform Module (TPM) to prove their identity. For hybrid-joined devices, this works seamlessly because the device can authenticate both to your on-premises domain controller (using cloud Kerberos) and to Entra ID in a single operation. This eliminates the attack surface that traditional password-based authentication creates. Organizations seeking more information on passwordless authentication approaches can review guidance from the &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/"&gt;Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency&lt;/a&gt;, which has published extensive recommendations on moving beyond passwords.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However — and this is crucial — not all devices have TPM 2.0, which is required for the most secure implementations. In one organization where we deployed to 15,000 devices, we discovered that 12% didn’t meet hardware requirements. We ended up implementing a phased approach: Windows Hello for Business on compliant devices, with FIDO2 security keys as the backup for devices that couldn’t support it. FIDO2 keys, which conform to the open &lt;a href="https://fidoalliance.org/fido2/"&gt;FIDO2 standard&lt;/a&gt;, are also your answer for scenarios where you need physical authentication tokens — particularly useful for privileged accounts or high-risk scenarios. They’re resistant to phishing and account takeover because possession of the physical token is required. Research from the &lt;a href="https://www.idsalliance.org/"&gt;Identity Defined Security Alliance&lt;/a&gt; has shown that organizations using FIDO2-compliant authenticators reduce account compromise incidents by over 90% compared to password-dependent systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The architectural decision also includes determining how you handle legacy applications that still require passwords. Your options are limited: implement a passwordless-compatible application gateway, deprecate the application entirely or use Entra ID’s smart lockout and password protection features to reduce risk while you transition. I typically recommend treating legacy application support as a temporary bridge, not a permanent architecture. Organizations that treat this as permanent inevitably find themselves maintaining password infrastructure indefinitely, undermining the entire security posture you’re building.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="migration-workflows-the-step-by-step-reality"&gt;Migration workflows: The step-by-step reality&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The migration itself needs to follow a structured approach that I’ve refined across multiple organizations. Start with a pilot group — I recommend between 50 and 200 users who are willing to accept some friction in exchange for security improvements. This group should include IT staff and security-conscious users who can provide meaningful feedback without becoming frustrated with early-stage issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the pilot phase, configure Windows Hello for Business using Group Policy on your on-premises infrastructure for domain-joined devices, while using Intune policies for cloud-managed devices. Configure Entra ID to require Windows Hello as the preferred authentication method. During this phase, maintain traditional password authentication as a fallback — not because you lack confidence, but because user trust in the system matters. I typically see a three to four week period where you’re supporting both methods while users adapt. This period provides invaluable data about real-world usage patterns and edge cases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second phase involves expanding to department-level groups. At this point, you should have identified and documented all the troubleshooting patterns that emerged in your pilot. Common issues I’ve encountered include PIN complexity policies that conflict with Windows Hello configuration, credential caching issues on hybrid-joined devices and confusion around how to recover access when a device is lost or compromised. A well-designed help desk knowledge base at this stage prevents the third phase from becoming a support crisis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The final phase is organization-wide rollout with password authentication disabled. This is where you must have complete confidence in your fallback mechanisms and your support team’s ability to handle edge cases. I recommend maintaining password authentication for break-glass scenarios (though heavily restricted and logged) for at least 90 days after full rollout. This safety net provides psychological comfort to leadership and creates a genuine escape hatch if something unexpected occurs at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="troubleshooting-patterns-and-lessons-learned"&gt;Troubleshooting patterns and lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After guiding three large-scale deployments, I’ve compiled a list of issues that deserve attention before they become production problems rather than documented solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Device compliance checking often becomes a bottleneck. If your Intune policies are too strict, you’ll have users locked out of passwordless authentication because their devices are non-compliant. The solution isn’t to loosen policies — it’s to automate compliance remediation. Use Intune’s remediation scripts to automatically enable required features and update settings rather than blocking access. When a device becomes non-compliant due to a missing security update, remediation scripts can deploy that update silently, restoring access without support interaction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud Kerberos ticket refresh failures occur when devices lose network connectivity. I’ve found that users appreciate understanding that brief network outages might require them to use an alternative authentication method temporarily. Documenting this expectation and providing clear error messages reduces support burden significantly. One organization I worked with created a simple status dashboard showing cloud connectivity health, which dramatically improved user confidence in the system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Windows Hello PIN reset flow needs careful planning. Users will forget PINs — not because they’re careless, but because they now have one less password to remember and are redirecting that cognitive effort elsewhere. Implement Entra ID’s self-service PIN reset capability, but test it thoroughly in various network conditions. I discovered in one deployment that users couldn’t reset their PIN while offline, which created support tickets even though the feature was technically available online. A simple offline reset option would have eliminated those tickets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recovery mechanisms deserve special attention. What happens when a user’s device is stolen? What if the TPM fails? What if they forget their PIN and can’t reach your self-service portal? Document these scenarios and test them with your help desk before full rollout. I’ve found that help desk confidence in recovery procedures directly correlates with user confidence in passwordless authentication.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-endpoint-a-genuinely-passwordless-enterprise"&gt;The endpoint: A genuinely passwordless enterprise&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reaching true passwordless authentication in a hybrid environment means accepting that you’re building a new security model, not just changing how users authenticate. The effort required is substantial, but the security improvement is profound. I’ve watched organizations move from breach-heavy authentication scenarios to Zero Trust architectures where every access request is evaluated in context, and where the compromise of a single device doesn’t cascade into wholesale account takeover.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The passwordless journey isn’t a destination you reach in months — it’s a direction you move in consistently. The organizations that succeed view passwordless migration not as a project with an end date, but as a fundamental shift in how they think about identity and trust. They maintain that momentum by continuously updating policies, expanding coverage to new applications and use cases, and refining their architecture as technology evolves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The view from the other side is worth the journey. Once you’ve lived in a passwordless environment, going back to password-based authentication feels like removing your seatbelt during a drive. The risk seems obvious in retrospect, and the safety you’ve gained becomes non-negotiable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126694/zero-trust-in-practice-a-deep-technical-dive-into-going-fully-passwordless-in-hybrid-enterprise-environments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.5 million AI agents are at risk of going rogue</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127733/1-5-million-ai-agents-are-at-risk-of-going-rogue.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study released Wednesday by API management platform vendor Gravitee indicates that upwards of half of the three million agents currently in use by organizations in the US and UK “are ungoverned and at the risk of going rogue.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on a December 2025 &lt;a href="https://www.einpresswire.com/article/889263114/gravitee-warns-of-invisible-risk-nearly-half-of-ai-agents-run-without-oversight" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;survey of 750 IT executives and practitioners&lt;/a&gt; conducted by Opinion Matters, the results revealed that AI agents are being deployed faster than security teams can keep up. There are, said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rory-blundell-a7545832/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rory Blundell&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Gravitee, now over three million AI agents operating within corporations, which he described as a workforce larger than the entire global employee count at Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The three million number is based on an extrapolation of survey results, based on government estimates of 8,250 UK businesses and 77,000 US businesses that employ 250 employees or more. The mean number of AI agents deployed per business is 36.9, and when respondents were asked if their organization “experienced or suspected an AI agent-related security or data privacy incident in the past 12 months,” 88% said that they had.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The mean percentage of agents that are not actively monitored and secured, according to the findings, was 53%&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked what prompted the study, Blundell wrote in an email, “we’re all familiar with stories of AI agents going rogue: deleting codebases, leaking confidential information, inventing fake data. The working hypothesis that prompted this research was that, while agentic deployment is reaching an exciting stage, businesses have not yet caught up with agent governance. The research validates that.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-global-problem"&gt;A global problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agents, he said, “can offer businesses a huge productivity gain, but we have to be realistic about the risks: without governance and oversight, they can easily start becoming liabilities, and a danger to consumers and businesses alike.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, said Blundell, despite respondents being only from the UK and US, “this is absolutely a global problem. Companies around the world are using AI agents, and across the board there is a gap between the level of deployment and the level of governance. We have a strong customer base in the EU, where we see the same problems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian-based security awareness training firm Beauceron Security, said, “the only thing that shocks me is that people think it’s only 53% of agents that aren’t monitored. It’s higher.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He likened the results from the Gravitee study to a “lesson about the Titanic that everyone in technology keeps ignoring. The Titanic disaster didn’t happen because they didn’t know there would be icebergs on the trip. They knew it was peak iceberg season, they knew they were going too fast.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley said that the ship’s captain and his crew “thought they’d detect [an iceberg]; if they didn’t, and hit one, that their technology controls would protect them to help them recover.” They put their faith in the so-called watertight compartments that, it turned out, weren’t watertight at the top, but, most importantly, they trusted the new wireless communications technology that they could use to call for help if they got in trouble. The equivalent today: “Well, IT and security can fix it if we get in trouble with our agents.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Wrong then, super wrong now,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He said, “we know AI agents are inherently dangerous and unreliable. There’s literally math proofs out there that show it. So, we know there are icebergs. Let me repeat this for those at the back of the room: 100% of AI agents have the potential to go rogue. If a vendor assures you it isn’t possible and their core technology is an LLM, they’re lying. We know we’re going too fast in adoption for the risks we know exist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley added, “now, the funny part: imagine if the Titanic still made the choices it did, knowing the watertight compartments didn’t work (aka monitoring is missing for 53% of AI agents), we know by the time IT and security roll on an AI agent risk, the damage is done (the ship’s sinking too fast and radio isn’t going to help because help will be too late). And we still made the choices we’re making.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-real-issue-is-invisible-ai-not-rogue-ai"&gt;The real issue is invisible AI, not rogue AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/manish-jain" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Manish Jain&lt;/a&gt;, principal research director at Info-Tech Research Group, said that as the “exponential” speed of AI development continues, his firm, based on experiences with CIOs and CDOs, predicts that there will be more AI agents globally by the year 2028 than the number of human employees. “It would be one of the biggest challenges for business and IT executives to govern them without curtailing the innovation that these AI agents bring with them,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even today, he noted, “we see that most enterprise AI agents are running without oversight. Many organizations don’t even know how many agents they have, where they’re running, or what they can touch. If you don’t know how many mules are in the barn, don’t act surprised when one kicks the door down.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jain pointed out that AI agents are no different. “Unaccounted agents often emerge through sanctioned, low-code tools and informal experimentation, bypassing traditional IT scrutiny until something breaks. You cannot govern what you can’t see. So, we need to understand that the real issue isn’t ‘rogue AI’, it’s invisible AI.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; Info-Tech, he added, “strongly believes that governing AI models or pre-approving agents is no longer enough, because invisible, rogue agents will do &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tandava" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;tandava&lt;/a&gt; (the dance of destruction) at runtime. This is because, when it comes to governing these AI agents, the number is so huge that approval gates will not be sustainable without halting the innovation. Continuous oversight should be the priority for AI governance after setting initial guardrails as part of the AI strategy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perspective, he said, also needs to change: “AI agents are no longer helpful bots. They often operate with delegated yet broad credentials, persistent access, and undefined accountability. This can become a costly mistake as overprivileged agents are the new insider threat. We need to define tiered access for AI agents. While we can’t avoid giving a few people keys to our house to speed up things, if you trust every stranger with your house keys, we wouldn’t be able to blame the locksmith when things go missing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127733/1-5-million-ai-agents-are-at-risk-of-going-rogue.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-072)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-073)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–074)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-075)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-076)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-077)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes security advisory (AV26-078)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-079)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-080)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-081)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-082)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-083)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django security advisory (AV26-084)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-085)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV26-086)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-087)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-088)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
