<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 11:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-783)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe tightens the net on sanctions evasion</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</link>
      <description>Europol is reinforcing its support to EU Member States in enforcing EU sanctions, as criminal networks develop ever more sophisticated methods to bypass restrictive measures linked to Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-785)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-786)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-787)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and partners shut down ‘Cryptomixer’</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partners-shut-down-cryptomixer</link>
      <description>From 24 to 28 November 2025, Europol supported an action week conducted by law enforcement authorities from Switzerland and Germany in Zurich, Switzerland. The operation focused on taking down the illegal cryptocurrency mixing service ‘Cryptomixer’, which is suspected of facilitating cybercrime and money laundering.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partners-shut-down-cryptomixer</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and Spanish National Police disrupt activities of far-right terrorist group 'The Base'</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</link>
      <description>Europol supported the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional) in disrupting activities of the far-right terrorist group 'The Base'. The operation took place over three days in Madrid and Valencia, resulting in significant seizures and the arrest of three suspected far-right extremists on 25 November 2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-788)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice &amp; Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 arrests in Bulgaria in a large art trafficking investigation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</link>
      <description>On 19 November 2025, a coordinated effort led by Bulgarian authorities and supported by Europol, resulted in the dismantling of a criminal network involved in large-scale trafficking of cultural goods across Europe and beyond. This operation was conducted under the framework of a Europol operational taskforce. The action day involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Albania, France, Germany, Greece,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 suspects arrested in two blows against human trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>France and Spain: disrupting a Chinese human trafficking networkConducted jointly by France and Spain, this operation targeted a Chinese organised crime group involved in trafficking human beings for sexual exploitation. The network, active for several years, coordinated sexual exploitation rings across France and multiple EU Member States. Members of the network rented apartments online for short terms, a modus operandi...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From feeds to flows: Using a unified linkage model to operationalize threat intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4100422/from-feeds-to-flows-using-a-unified-linkage-model-to-operationalize-threat-intelligence.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-problem-static-intelligence-in-a-dynamic-world"&gt;The problem: Static intelligence in a dynamic world&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every CISO knows the fatigue that comes with modern threat intelligence. Dozens of vendor feeds pour in daily — STIX packages, IP blocklists, domain indicators, malware hashes — all claiming to help your organization stay one step ahead.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yet most threat feeds still behave like spreadsheets of badness. They tell you &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to watch for, but not &lt;em&gt;why it matters&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;how it moves&lt;/em&gt; through your environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The result is a paradox of abundance: CISOs have more data than ever before, but less operational clarity. Analysts are overwhelmed by indicators disconnected from context or mission relevance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Each feed represents a snapshot of a potential threat, but it does not capture the dynamic pathway through which that threat could exploit relationships within the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional intelligence products describe discrete artifacts; real-world attacks exploit linkages amongst users and cloud services, between supply-chain vendors and data repositories, between identity providers and DevOps pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The shift from threat feeds to threat flows requires a model that can describe those linkages, quantify their trustworthiness and prioritize risk based on how threats actually travel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s where the &lt;a href="https://www.uscybersecurity.net/csmag/unified-linkage-models-recontextualizing-cybersecurity/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Unified Linkage Model (ULM)&lt;/a&gt; comes in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="rhizomatic-networks-and-the-modern-attack-surface"&gt;Rhizomatic networks and the modern attack surface&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Classical network defense models assume hierarchical systems — servers at the core, clients at the edge and clear boundaries in between. But digital enterprises no longer look like trees; they behave more like &lt;em&gt;rhizomes&lt;/em&gt; — living systems of lateral, recursive connections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A rhizomatic network, a term from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Thousand_Plateaus" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Deleuze and Guattari’s &lt;em&gt;A Thousand Plateaus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and explored in this context elsewhere, is one where any node can seemingly connect to almost any other, directly or indirectly, through APIs, shared identity layers or multi-cloud infrastructure. In these environments, roots have become less permanent and topologies have become less predictable. Within this landscape, dependencies emerge dynamically and relationships evolve faster than documentation can keep up. This shift from hierarchy to rhizome changes the way we know how threats propagate. A compromise in one SaaS tenant can ripple laterally through adjacent cloud accounts, CI/CD pipelines or shared identity providers with surprising speed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers no longer exploit static perimeters — they weaponize &lt;em&gt;relationships&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.uscybersecurity.net/csmag/rhizomatic-threats-in-practice-applied-cybersecurity-modeling-for-emergent-threat-landscapes/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The ULM provides a structured way to visualize this chaos.&lt;/a&gt; By mapping three core linkage types — adjacency, inheritance and trustworthiness — the ULM reveals how risk moves rhizomatically through complex ecosystems. It transforms modern network entanglement into something quantifiable, allowing CISOs to reason about propagation rather than static exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-unified-linkage-model-ulm"&gt;The unified linkage model (ULM)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ULM was conceived initially to describe how cyber risk propagates through interdependent systems — not merely by asset or vulnerability, but by &lt;em&gt;relationship&lt;/em&gt;. Instead of seeing networks as linear hierarchies, ULM views them as living ecosystems where risk flows along three primary linkage types:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjacency linkages&lt;/strong&gt;: Proximity or shared interfaces between systems, such as network segments, APIs or shared infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inheritance linkages: &lt;/strong&gt;Dependencies and configuration flows, such as a compromised library in a build pipeline or inherited IAM policies.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.uscybersecurity.net/csmag/establishing-trustworthiness-an-adaptive-governance-approach/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trustworthiness linkages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Human or contractual relationships, such as vendor access, federated identities or service-to-service tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Each linkage represents a potential &lt;em&gt;path of exploitation&lt;/em&gt;. Rather than treating each threat artifact in isolation, ULM maps how those artifacts connect — showing how an attacker could traverse from an initial compromise point to an ultimate target through adjacency, inheritance and trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This concept reframes threat intelligence from &lt;em&gt;collection&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;connection&lt;/em&gt;. In the ULM view, the organization’s environment is not simply a list of assets but a graph of interactions. Threats are not isolated incidents but &lt;em&gt;flow across linkages&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-feeds-to-flows-building-a-living-threat-graph"&gt;From feeds to flows: Building a living threat graph&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Imagine receiving a feed that reports a malicious IP address associated with a phishing campaign. In most SOCs, that indicator enters a SIEM rule or firewall blocklist — a transactional act of defense. The intelligence stops there.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now apply ULM thinking:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The malicious IP is associated with a compromised third-party marketing tool.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;That tool has API keys embedded in your marketing automation system.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The automation platform uses OAuth tokens that connect to your corporate CRM.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The CRM is integrated with your cloud identity provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Each linkage forms part of a &lt;em&gt;threat flow&lt;/em&gt; — a connected chain of potential exploitation that moves laterally through business processes, not just through ports and protocols.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By mapping linkages, the CISO can see that the “malicious IP” is not an isolated data point; it’s the first observable in a multi-stage flow that touches customer data, credentials and identity infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When threat intelligence is structured as linkages, not lists, analysts can:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correlate faster:&lt;/strong&gt; Identify shared infrastructure or behavior patterns across feeds.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize better&lt;/strong&gt;: Focus on threats that intersect with high-value or high-trust linkages.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Predict earlier&lt;/strong&gt; by anticipating propagation through modeling adjacent or inherited dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;em&gt;threat feeds become threat flows&lt;/em&gt; — intelligence with direction, momentum and consequence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="operationalizing-ulm-in-threat-intelligence-pipelines"&gt;Operationalizing ULM in threat intelligence pipelines&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-ingest-and-normalize"&gt;1. Ingest and normalize&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ULM begins by ingesting diverse threat feeds — commercial, open-source, government and internal telemetry. Each artifact (IP, domain, hash, tactic or technique) becomes a &lt;em&gt;node&lt;/em&gt; in the linkage model, enriched with metadata such as MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK techniques, timestamps or confidence scores.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-establish-linkages"&gt;2. Establish linkages&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The system identifies relationships between nodes using multiple criteria:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjacency:&lt;/strong&gt; Shared IP ranges, ASN or cloud hosting; shared libraries or API keys.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inheritance:&lt;/strong&gt; Supply-chain dependencies, build-system components or configuration drift.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trustworthiness:&lt;/strong&gt; Credential sharing, federated SSO connections, vendor contracts or known trust relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Linkages are scored for strength and directionality — similar to weights in a graph — producing a threat-linkage graph showing how a compromise could cascade across systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-integrate-with-mitre-attck-and-tips-and-fair"&gt;3. Integrate with MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK and TIPs and FAIR&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ULM aligns naturally with &lt;a href="https://attack.mitre.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK’s&lt;/a&gt; technique-level data.Each linkage can be annotated with the ATT&amp;amp;CK tactics it enables — from &lt;em&gt;Initial Access&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Impact&lt;/em&gt;. Integration with Threat Intelligence Platforms such as MISP or ThreatConnect allows ULM graphs to update dynamically as new indicators appear.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A previously benign linkage can instantly become high-risk when connected to a newly malicious node, turning static intel into a living, breathing operational map.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the &lt;a href="https://www.fairinstitute.org/blog/extending-fair-unified-linkage-model-strengthens-cyber-risk-quantification-1" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ULM bridges quantitative risk frameworks like FAIR and FAIR-CAM&lt;/a&gt; by embedding linkage dynamics into loss-event modeling, thereby enabling risk assessments not only of the magnitude of loss but of the &lt;strong&gt;pathway through which loss may propagate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-visualize-threat-flows"&gt;4. Visualize threat flows&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Visualization is key. And in the emerging environment of AI/ML models and cloud-based resources, this visualization can occur. Using ULM, CISOs can see attack pathways as flow diagrams rather than spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For instance:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A connection to a compromised supplier’s GitHub repo (inheritance linkage)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;→ injects code into a shared container image (adjacency linkage)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;→ which is deployed into production through an automated pipeline (trust linkage).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such visualizations reveal choke points where a single control — code-signing enforcement or identity segmentation — can break multiple flow paths at once.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ulm-as-a-bridge-between-intelligence-and-authorization"&gt;ULM as a bridge between intelligence and authorization&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the persistent frustrations in enterprise security is the divide between intelligence and governance. Threat feeds inform SOCs; frameworks like NIST SP 800-37 Rev. 2, ISO/IEC 27001:2022 or the CMMC 2.0 Model govern compliance. The two rarely meet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ULM provides the connective tissue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because ULM formalizes relationships between systems, it can feed directly into risk management frameworks:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/system/files/documents/2018/03/28/vickie_nist_risk_management_framework_overview-hpc.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIST RMF Step 1–2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (Categorize/Select controls):&lt;/strong&gt; Use ULM to identify linkage-dense areas where compromise would have the highest propagation potential.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3–4 (Implement/Assess):&lt;/strong&gt; Validate that controls exist along key linkages — authentication boundaries, code-inheritance chains, vendor access.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 6 (Monitor):&lt;/strong&gt; Continuously refresh linkages with new threat intel, transforming continuous monitoring into continuous linkage validation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In compliance contexts, ULM metrics — such as linkage density, trustworthiness scores and adjacency exposures — become measurable inputs for CMMC maturity, ISO 27001 risk registers or &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/207/final" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zero Trust Architecture (SP 800-207)&lt;/a&gt; policy enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A threat flow, therefore, is not only a technical visualization but an auditable artifact of due diligence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="zero-trust-and-the-flow-perspective"&gt;Zero trust and the flow perspective&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust architecture (ZTA) is often summarized as “never trust, always verify,” as formalized in NIST SP 800-207. ULM adds nuance by showing &lt;em&gt;what to verify&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;where trust actually exists.&lt;/em&gt; Every trust boundary in a zero-trust design corresponds to one or more linkages in ULM:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user authenticating through an identity provider — &lt;em&gt;a trustworthiness linkage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A microservice calling another via API — &lt;em&gt;an adjacency linkage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A software update pipeline pulling from a third-party repo — an &lt;em&gt;inheritance linkage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When threat intelligence is mapped onto those linkages, the CISO gains real-time visibility into which trust paths are under active threat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of treating zero trust as a static segmentation map, ULM enables a &lt;em&gt;dynamic trust model&lt;/em&gt; — continuously updated by threat-flow data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This approach converts zero trust from an architectural goal to an operational feedback system. Each linkage is verified not only against access policies but also against active threat flows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ciso-use-case-prioritizing-by-linkage-impact"&gt;CISO use case: Prioritizing by linkage impact&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consider two simultaneous alerts:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A phishing domain targeting the finance department.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A compromised API key in a DevOps integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both seem essential, but which deserves immediate attention?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A traditional feed-based approach might treat them equally. The ULM view quickly shows that the API key sits on a high-trust, high-inheritance linkage — it connects the build system to production containers and those containers share adjacency with customer data stores.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The phishing domain, by contrast, leads to isolated user inboxes with strong controls. By quantifying the linkage weight, the CISO can prioritize the DevOps compromise, knowing that its flow potential — the ability to move from one system to another — is far higher. This is attack-path prioritization, not just vulnerability management. It is the difference between chasing every indicator and focusing on the flows that matter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="toward-a-flow-based-defense"&gt;Toward a flow-based defense&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams often describe their posture in terms of &lt;em&gt;perimeters&lt;/em&gt;, boundaries, &lt;em&gt;endpoints&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;controls&lt;/em&gt;. But adversaries don’t think in boxes — they believe in flows. They exploit the connective tissue: the forgotten trust token, the unmonitored CI/CD handoff, the shared SaaS credential.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ULM provides a way to think and act like an attacker while maintaining the analytical rigor of a defender. By modeling linkages, CISOs can:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualize attack surfaces:&lt;/strong&gt; Understand not just what assets exist, but how they relate to each other.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantify propagation risk:&lt;/strong&gt; Measure how fast and far a compromise could move.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operationalize threat intel: &lt;/strong&gt;Feed dynamic linkage updates into monitoring and response playbooks.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Align intelligence with compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; Demonstrate to auditors and boards that risk is understood &lt;em&gt;in context&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In practice, adopting ULM doesn’t require replacing existing tools. Most organizations already possess the data — network maps, identity graphs, vulnerability scanners and threat feeds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ULM unifies them into a linkage framework, transforming siloed outputs into a coherent risk narrative.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cisos-call-to-action"&gt;The CISO’s call to action&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For decades, we have been trained to collect — logs, indicators, feeds. The next era of cybersecurity requires that we understand connections: how elements interact, inherit and propagate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By adopting a linkage mindset, CISOs can elevate threat intelligence from reactive to predictive. The ULM provides the analytical bridge between static data and dynamic defense — a means to see threats not as isolated alerts but as &lt;em&gt;flows of intent&lt;/em&gt; moving through digital ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The message is simple but powerful:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop simply reading threat feeds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start mapping threat flows.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That is how you operationalize threat intelligence in the age of rhizomatic, interconnected systems — and how CISOs finally gain the visibility to act, not just react.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional details are available in my original research paper:  &lt;a href="https://www.uscybersecurity.net/csmag/unified-linkage-models-recontextualizing-cybersecurity/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Unified Linkage Models: Recontextualizing Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; (United States Cybersecurity magazine).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4100422/from-feeds-to-flows-using-a-unified-linkage-model-to-operationalize-threat-intelligence.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16.6 million packages of fake and harmful toys taken off EU markets</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</link>
      <description>Fake toys are poisoning, deafening and injuring children across Europe, while causing major losses to the EU economy. 26 countries, coordinated by Europol, co-led by France, Spain and Romania, and supported by the EUIPO and OLAF, have once again led initiatives to take down the producers and importers of counterfeit toys. With the global toy market valued at up to EUR 300 billion annually, it also remains the second-most counterfeited industry globally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI creates new security risks for OT networks, warns NSA</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101239/ai-creates-new-security-risks-for-ot-networks-warns-nsa.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The security of operational technology (OT) in critical infrastructure has been a recurring theme for years, but this week the US National Security Agency (NSA) and its global partners added a new concern to the mix: how the increasing use of AI in OT risks making things worse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The scope of these concerns, and guidance for addressing them, is outlined in the &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/Dec/03/2003834257/-1/-1/0/JOINT_GUIDANCE_PRINCIPLES_FOR_THE_SECURE_INTEGRATION_OF_AI_IN_OT.PDF" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Principles for the Secure Integration of Artificial Intelligence in Operational Technology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; authored by the NSA in conjunction with the Australian Signals Directorate’s Australian Cyber Security Centre (ASD’s ACSC) and a global alliance of national security agencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the use of AI in critical infrastructure OT is in its early days, the guidance reads like an attempt by the NSA and its partners to get ahead of the problem before misuse or misapplication becomes entrenched. Although drafted for OT admins, the guidelines mirror concerns that also apply to IT administration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Currently, AI is being put to work in OT networks in the energy, water treatment, healthcare, and manufacturing sectors for the same reason it is being used elsewhere: to optimize and automate processes, thereby improving efficiency and uptime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The worry is that organizations are jumping into a new and far from battle-hardened technology without assessing its limitations, echoing what has been happening in IT. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3485728/why-ot-cybersecurity-should-be-every-cisos-concern.html" target="_blank"&gt;Measuring risk&lt;/a&gt; against the industrial control systems (ICS) &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Purdue_Enterprise_Reference_Architecture" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Purdue Model hierarchy&lt;/a&gt;, the guidelines enumerate worries such as adversarial prompt injection and data poisoning, data collection leading to reduced safety, and “AI drift” in which models become less accurate as new data diverges from training data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also mentioned: AI can lack the explainability necessary to diagnose errors, there are difficulties meeting compliance requirements as AI rapidly evolves, and there’s a human de-skilling effect caused by a creeping over-dependence on AI. Likewise, AI alerts might lead to distraction and cognitive overload among employees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, the tendency of AI technologies such as chatbots and LLMs to hallucinate raises doubts about whether the technology is robust enough to be used in environments where safety is a priority. “AI may not be reliable enough to independently make critical decisions in industrial environments. As such, AI such as LLMs almost certainly should not be used to make safety decisions for OT environments,” said the authors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This underlines an important difference between using AI in an OT setting and an IT one – OT networks are by nature safety-critical. Although many of the issues are the same, the margin for error is much smaller.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="struggling-to-unwind"&gt;Struggling to unwind&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The guidance raises the right questions: what risks are we introducing, what value does AI truly bring, who is accountable for oversight, and how do we respond when the technology misbehaves?” commented &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sammaesschalck/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Maesschalck&lt;/a&gt;, an OT engineer with cyber security training platform Immersive Labs. “We’ve already seen what happens when operational demands outpace secure design. IT/OT convergence brought efficiency, but it also exposed OT networks in ways the industry is still struggling to unwind.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Maesschalck, grafting AI systems onto OT infrastructure would fail if pre-existing issues aren’t addressed first. These include the inability of some OT devices to feed the required volumes of data to AI platforms, and a lack of asset inventories that make problem interactions more difficult to predict.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the guidelines’ recommendations are for organizations to adopt CISA’s &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3803081/cisa-unveils-secure-by-demand-guidelines-to-bolster-ot-security.html" target="_blank"&gt;secure design principles&lt;/a&gt;, and to assess whether developing an AI-OT project inhouse would give organizations more control over AI design and implementation in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This kind of guidance is influential because operators are looking for clarity. Having government-backed principles to reference gives owners and engineers something concrete to point to when they push back on unsafe or rushed adoption. It also reinforces how essential education is,” said Maesschalck.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The guidelines arrive on the heels of last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3545051/make-ot-networks-a-priority-say-nine-national-security-agencies.html" target="_blank"&gt;NSA and ACSC report&lt;/a&gt; listing the steps organizations should take to secure OT in critical infrastructure. But neither document addresses &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3951163/too-little-budget-for-ot-security.html" target="_blank"&gt;continuing concerns that OT security still doesn’t get the budget it warrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101239/ai-creates-new-security-risks-for-ot-networks-warns-nsa.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suspicious traffic could be testing CDN evasion, says expert</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101395/suspicious-traffic-could-be-testing-cdn-evasion-says-expert.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An individual or group is doing new probing of content delivery networks (CDNs), an effort that CSOs, CIOs and network administrators should worry about if they use CDNs instead of web application firewalls to protect websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the conclusion of &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute, &lt;a href="https://isc.sans.edu/diary/32532" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;who this week said&lt;/a&gt;  his organization’s honeypots last month detected a curious amount of traffic with server requests that include CDN-related headers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, he said, someone is testing a tactic to evade CDN defences for launching either a targeted attack or a widespread distributed denial of service (DDoS) attack on a site.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, the honeypots have seen headers on traffic that include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Cf-Warp-Tag-Id,” which is associated with Cloudflare’s Warp VPN service;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“X-Fastly-Request-Id,”, which is associated with the Fastly CDN;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“X-Akamai-Transformed,” a header added by Akamai;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;and a puzzler: “X-T0Ken-Inf0.” Ullrich thinks it might contain a form of authentication token, but isn’t sure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an interview, he said one explanation is that a threat actor is trying to get around a CDN’s filters by creating page requests that include a CDN-related header.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another possible explanation is that these requests are merely going through a CDN, but, Ullrich said, “the requests we’re seeing don’t quite look like that.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Internet requests are messages sent from a client such as a web browser to a web server, requesting a web page. A wave of requests can be a DDoS attack, or mask a different kind of attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These days, many organizations use CDNs or cloud providers for basic DDoS protection and bot filtering in addition to load balancing. In a typical setup, Ullrich said, DNS is used to point clients to the CDN, which then forwards the request to a customer’s web server.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, there’s a problem: If an attacker can identify the IP address of the actual web server, they are often able to bypass the CDN and reach the web server directly. There are a few ways for users to prevent this. For example, depending on the CDN selected, it may be possible to allow access only from the CDN’s IP address space. However, for some of the larger providers, this list of addresses may be large and very dynamic. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another option is to add custom headers. Some CDNs offer special custom headers with randomized values to identify requests that have passed through the CDN. And a less secure option is to look for any header that identifies the CDN. However, Ullrich noted, merely looking for a header should be avoided, as attackers can easily include this header in their traffic. This appears to be the activity the SANS honeypot has been seeing since November.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for CDN Cloudflare’s PR agency said a comment couldn’t be arranged by deadline.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related content:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4092917/how-a-bot-management-file-push-crippled-cloudflares-global-network.html" target="_blank"&gt;How a bot management file push crippled Cloudflare’s global network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellman/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kellman Meghu&lt;/a&gt;, chief security architect at DeepCove Security, says the activity seen by the SANS Institute’s honeypots isn’t new. But, he added, it only becomes an issue when there is improper access control, or the controls fail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Origin web servers should be deployed with access controls, be it security groups or firewall rules, to only ever allow communication with the CDN service,” he said in an email. “Just deploying your web application as accessible to the world, and then overlaying a CDN to act as the front end seems like a terrible waste of money and effort. In today’s world of infrastructure-as-code, this can and should be easy to manage and mitigate as far as risk goes.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.aryaka.com/author/adityaksood/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Aditya Sood&lt;/a&gt;, VP of security engineering and AI strategy at Aryaka, said in an email that a surge in requests that include CDN-related headers “is clear experimentation from threat actors, and the impersonation isn’t just random noise, its reconnaissance. Attacks are probing to uncover the weak origin validation in organizations who are trusting the mere presence of a CDN-specific header instead of enforcing proper controls like IP allowlists, private network peering, or cryptographically validated tokens. When you see multiple CDN fingerprints being spoofed at roughly the same time, it usually means new tooling or automated scanners are being deployed in the wild.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Proper origin hardening that includes strict IP allowlists, validated tokens, or private connectivity is essential to protect websites, he said. “Relying only on the presence of CDN-specific headers is no longer viable, and organizations that have not fully locked down their backend infrastructure may already be exposed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ullrich added that CDNs and other traffic filtering services will issue a unique value to each customer as proof that traffic has gone through its service, so web administrators should configure their web servers or next generation firewalls to only accept requests with that unique value.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The activity SANS has seen is “definitely something that should be seen as a warning that something that could become more than it is now,” he said. “Now it’s only a curiosity, but it could easily become more. You [admins] need to follow your content delivery network’s guidance to protect your web server from attacks like this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101395/suspicious-traffic-could-be-testing-cdn-evasion-says-expert.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Das CISO-Paradoxon: Innovation ermöglichen und Risiken managen</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4099334/das-ciso-paradoxon-innovation-ermoglichen-und-risiken-managen.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Zusammenarbeit" class="wp-image-4099374" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2196524059.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;CISOs sollten eng mit anderen Teams zusammenarbeiten.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;eamesBot – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eine der Hauptaufgaben von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072083/vom-ciso-zum-chief-risk-architect.html" target="_blank"&gt;CISOs&lt;/a&gt; besteht darin, nicht mehr die „Abteilung des Neins“ zu sein. Sie müssen Wege finden, die schnelle Bereitstellung von Produkten und Dienstleistungen für das Unternehmen zu ermöglichen, ohne gleichzeitig neue Risiken einzuführen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das ist, kurz gesagt, das Paradoxon. In einem Umfeld, in dem Produktteams ständig neue Technologien testen und Updates in Rekordgeschwindigkeit bereitstellen müssen, können traditionelle Audits am Ende des Entwicklungszyklus nicht mithalten. Sicherheit muss vorgelagert werden. Sie muss in den täglichen Betrieb integriert werden, mit proaktiven, umsetzbaren Maßnahmen, die Innovationen fördern, anstatt sie zu bremsen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs müssen daher von Anfang an enger mit den Teams zusammenarbeiten, um klare und praktische Risikotoleranzen festzulegen und Sicherheit in die Entwicklungsabläufe zu integrieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="fruhzeitig-partnerschaften-eingehen-um-ergebnisse-zu-gestalten"&gt;Frühzeitig Partnerschaften eingehen, um Ergebnisse zu gestalten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs gewinnen nicht an Einfluss, wenn sie erst am Ende auftauchen. Sie müssen ihre Gatekeeper-Mentalität ablegen und vom ersten Tag an echte Partner sein. In der Vergangenheit, als Sicherheitsmaßnahmen erst in der Endphase eingeführt wurden, standen Entscheidungsträger vor einer schwierigen Wahl: Projektverzögerungen akzeptieren oder unverminderte Risiken in Kauf nehmen. Als Produktzyklen noch quartalsweise waren und Geschwindigkeit nicht über die Wettbewerbsfähigkeit entschied, war dieser Ansatz sinnvoll. In der heutigen Realität mit KI-gesteuerter Produktentwicklung funktioniert ein solcher Prozess in einem Umfeld, das aus Wochensprints, kontinuierlicher Bereitstellung und Abhängigkeiten von Herstellern besteht, nicht mehr.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn die Sicherheitsabteilung die Umsatzziele, Kundenversprechen und regulatorischen Risiken versteht, werden die Leitlinien konkret und hilfreich. Unternehmen sollten daher jedem Produktteam einen Sicherheitsbeauftragten zur Seite stellen. Dadurch gibt es immer eine vertraute Person, die sich mit Entscheidungen zu Identität, Datenflüssen, Protokollierung und Verschlüsselung befasst, sobald diese anstehen. Wir sollten nicht wollen, dass Entwickler für eine einfache Frage zweiwöchige Tickets eröffnen müssen. Es sollte offene „Sprechstunden”, Chat-Kanäle und kurze Telefonate geben, damit sie sofortiges Feedback zu Entscheidungen wie API-Design, Verschlüsselungsanforderungen und regionalen Datenbewegungen erhalten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bürokratie muss im Sicherheitsumfeld abgeschafft werden. Sicherheitsmanager sollten an Sprint-Planungen und frühen Design-Reviews teilnehmen, um wichtige Fragen zu klären – beispielsweise Authentifizierungspfade, Least-Privilege-Zugriffe, Logging-Abdeckungoder wie Änderungen in der Produktion durch SIEM und EDR überwacht werden. Wenn CISOs mit am Tisch sitzen, ändert sich die Frage von „Können wir das machen?“ zu „Wie machen wir das sicher?“ und schon vom ersten Tag an werden bessere Ergebnisse erzielt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risikotoleranzen-und-leitplanken-festlegen"&gt;Risikotoleranzen und Leitplanken festlegen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Teams werden langsamer, wenn sie sich nicht sicher sind, wie sie vorgehen sollen. Deshalb sollten ihnen ein Teil der Entscheidungsfindung abgenommen und die Integration von Authentifizierung, Autorisierung und Abrechnung in den Entwicklungsprozess übernommen werden. Für die Authentifizierung sollten Sie Lösungen für das Identitätsmanagement im Unternehmen einrichten und nutzen, anstatt Accounts zu entwickeln, die fest in Datenbanken geschrieben werden und die leicht kompromittierbar sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sicherheitschefs müssen außerdem standardisierte rollenbasierte Zugriffskontrollstufen definieren, die eine klare Aufgabentrennung im Lösungsdesign gewährleisten. Dazu sollte die Abrechnung nicht nur aus Protokollen bestehen, sondern Daten mit hoher Kardinalität zur Erkennung von Anomalien erfassen. Anschließen müssen diese in ein zentrales &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4043049/warum-das-soc-in-der-krise-steckt-und-wie-sie-das-andern.html" target="_blank"&gt;SOC&lt;/a&gt; (Security Operations Center) zur Erkennung und Reaktion auf Bedrohungen integriert werden. Produktentwicklungsteams sollten nicht mit Sicherheitsaufgaben betraut werden; stattdessen sollten andere Teams die Sichtbarkeit der Bedrohungen für die Lösungen in der Produktion im Auge behalten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495028/chief-information-security-officer-ein-neues-berufsbild-fur-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;CISOs&lt;/a&gt; müssen die Risikobereitschaft des Unternehmens in einer Geschäftssprache definieren, die keine Interpretationsspielräume zulässt. Sie sollten festlegen, welche Profile von Drittanbietern einer eingehenden Bewertung bedürfen und welche als begrenzte Pilotprojekte mit kompensierenden Kontrollen durchgeführt werden können. Entscheiden Sie, welche Schwachstellen einen Merge blockieren müssen und welche mit einem zeitlich begrenzten Behebungsplan fortgesetzt werden können. Klären Sie, welche Datenklassifizierungen regionenübergreifend sein dürfen und welche Schutzmaßnahmen dafür erforderlich sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anschließend müssen diese Entscheidungen in Automatisierung umgesetzt werden. Integrieren Sie Schutzmaßnahmen in CI/CD und Infrastructure-as-Code, damit die Durchsetzung konsistent und sichtbar ist. Scannen Sie jeden Code-Commit auf Schwachstellen, und wenn eine Änderung gegen eine kritische Richtlinie verstößt, schlägt der Build fehl – mit einer klaren Begründung und einem Lösungsweg. Liegt die Änderung innerhalb der Toleranzen, wird er ohne manuelles Eingreifen fortgesetzt. Das Ergebnis ist Governance als Beschleuniger: vorhersehbar, transparent und abgestimmt auf die Arbeitsweise der Entwicklungsteams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-by-design-in-schnelle-entwicklerzyklen-integrieren"&gt;Security-by-Design in schnelle Entwicklerzyklen integrieren&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn Entwickler mehrmals täglich Code bereitstellen, funktioniert eine „abschließende Sicherheitsüberprüfung” vor der Veröffentlichung einfach nicht. Dieses traditionelle Gatekeeping-Modell am Ende des Prozesses blockiert nicht nur Innovationen, sondern versäumt es auch, reale Risiken zu erkennen. Um effektiv zu sein, muss &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491579/secdevops-sicherheit-im-devops-prozess.html" target="_blank"&gt;Sicherheit während der Entwicklung&lt;/a&gt; eingebettet werden und nicht erst nachträglich überprüft werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn der sichere Weg schwieriger ist als der unsichere Weg, werden Entwickler jedes Mal den einfachen Weg wählen. Die Aufgabe des CISO besteht nicht darin, ein 50-seitiges PDF zu verteilen, sondern Sicherheit direkt in die Entwicklerumgebung zu integrieren und ihnen vorab geprüfte, gehärtete Templates mit bereits integrierter Authentifizierung und Autorisierung zur Verfügung zu stellen, die standardmäßig sicher sind. Wenn die sichere Komponente einfacher zu verwenden ist als die unsichere Alternative, können Entwickler sie problemlos und jederzeit einsetzen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Automatisierung ist die Durchsetzungsebene für diese Strategie. Wenn Sicherheitstools direkt in die CI/CD-Pipeline integriert sind, ist Feedback fast in Echtzeit verfügbar. So kann das Team bei kritischen Risiken „schnell scheitern“ und gleichzeitig umsetzbare Korrekturen vornehmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Disziplin muss sich bis in die Produktion hineinziehen. Selbst mit erstklassigen DevSecOps wissen wir, dass Zero-Day-Angriffe oder Konfigurationsabweichungen auftreten können. Deshalb sollten wir uns auf übergreifende Lösungen zum Schutz von Webanwendungen verlassen, die eine robuste Web-Application-Firewall mit Laufzeit-Angriffsabwehr und Selbstschutz integrieren. Diese Lösungen mindern Schwachstellen und Risiken in Echtzeit, während die Anwendung in der Produktion läuft. Sie verschaffen den Entwicklungsteams die entscheidende Zeit, die sie benötigen, um das zugrunde liegende Problem ohne Dienstunterbrechung oder Sicherheitsverletzung zu beheben. Zudem wird so sichergestellt, dass wir selbst dann eingreifen können, wenn alle anderen Kontrollen versagen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laufzeit-Telemetrie und risikobasierte Warnmeldungen sind die letzte Schutzschicht in diesem Konzept. Dies fördert einen kulturellen Wandel, der es Entwicklern ermöglicht, die volle Verantwortung für ihre Anwendungen zu übernehmen, von der ersten Codezeile bis hin zur Produktion. Die Sicherheit wiederum erreicht so eine umfassende und dauerhafte Abdeckung, ohne zum Engpass zu werden. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4098347/vaillant-ciso-starten-statt-warten.html" target="_blank"&gt;Vaillant-CISO im Interview – “Starten statt Warten”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4099334/das-ciso-paradoxon-innovation-ermoglichen-und-risiken-managen.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpyCloud Data Shows Corporate Users 3x More Likely to Be Targeted by Phishing Than by Malware</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101513/spycloud-data-shows-corporate-users-3x-more-likely-to-be-targeted-by-phishing-than-by-malware.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phishing has surged 400% year-over-year, highlighting need for real-time visibility into identity exposures.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpyCloud&lt;/a&gt;, the leader in identity threat protection, today released new data showing a sharp rise in phishing attacks that disproportionately target corporate users. The company tracked a 400% year-over-year increase in successfully phished identities, with nearly 40% of the 28+ million recaptured phished records containing a business email address – compared to just 11.5% in recaptured malware data. The result is a warning to enterprises that their workforce is three times more likely to be targeted with phishing attacks than infostealer malware. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The findings reinforce a growing shift in cybercriminals’ strategy: phishing is now the preferred gateway into enterprise environments, and &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/resource/report/2025-lessons-2026-predictions/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpyCloud sees this trend continuing in 2026&lt;/a&gt;. Threat actors are using this access as a launchpad for follow-on attacks, with SpyCloud reporting in its &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/resource/report/identity-threat-report-2025" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 Identity Threat Report&lt;/a&gt; that phishing is now the leading entry point for ransomware, accounting for 35% of all ransomware infections. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Phishing is now one of the most scalable tools cybercriminals use to breach enterprise environments,” said Trevor Hilligoss, SpyCloud’s Head of Security Research. “Cybercrime enablement services, like phishing-as-a-service kits that automate convincing lures and adversary-in-the-middle tactics that capture MFA tokens and session cookies, put advanced tactics into the hands of low-skilled actors, making it easier than ever to compromise users at scale. SpyCloud’s visibility into these campaigns gives organizations a critical edge, helping them detect who’s been targeted and what data has been exposed, and remediate those credentials before they can be weaponized.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpyCloud is the only provider recapturing and automatically remediating successfully phished identity data and targeting lists at scale before follow-on attacks like ransomware, fraud, and account takeover can occur.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many organizations rely on traditional defenses like email filtering, endpoint protection, and employee education to stop phishing and malware attempts, but those tools only go so far,” said Damon Fleury, SpyCloud’s Chief Product Officer. “Attackers are still getting through – and when they do, it’s the exposed identity data that enables further harm. Security teams need to be vigilant about what’s already been compromised and circulating in the criminal underground. Prevention is important, but without real-time visibility and post-compromise remediation, it’s not enough.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While phishing has become a dominant entry point, malware remains a critical threat vector. In the age of remote work and bring-your-own-device policies, personal exposures are increasingly used to compromise enterprise environments. A recent example is the &lt;a href="https://www.nikkei.co.jp/nikkeiinfo/en/news/announcements/1394.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 Nikkei breach&lt;/a&gt;, where malware on a personal device led to the compromise of sensitive corporate data. Despite only 11.5% of recaptured malware infections exfiltrating business email addresses directly, SpyCloud data shows that &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/newsroom/annual-identity-exposure-report-2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;nearly 1 in 2 corporate users&lt;/a&gt; have been the victim of an infostealer malware infection in their digital history, whether that be on a managed or unmanaged device – a strong indicator that threat actors are moving laterally from personal to corporate accounts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Protecting the enterprise means looking beyond corporate accounts,” Fleury added. “Due to the continuous reuse of passwords and shared identity data across work and personal accounts like mobile numbers, the line between a user’s personal digital history and their professional access effectively no longer exists. That’s why it’s essential to monitor and remediate exposures across the full spectrum of an individual’s digital identity – personal and professional.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpyCloud is the leader in holistic identity protection, detecting and protecting organizations from the phishing, malware, and breach exposures of employees, contractors, and vendors across personal and professional identities. Users can click &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/use-case/phishing-exposure-remediation/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SpyCloud:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpyCloud&lt;/a&gt; transforms recaptured darknet data to disrupt cybercrime. Its automated identity threat protection solutions leverage advanced analytics and AI to proactively prevent ransomware and account takeover, detect insider threats, safeguard employee and consumer identities, and accelerate cybercrime investigations. SpyCloud’s data from breaches, malware-infected devices, and successful phishes also powers many popular dark web monitoring and identity theft protection offerings. Customers include seven of the Fortune 10, along with hundreds of global enterprises, mid-sized companies, and government agencies worldwide. Headquartered in Austin, TX, SpyCloud is home to more than 200 cybersecurity experts whose mission is to protect businesses and consumers from the stolen identity data criminals are using to target them now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more and see insights on their company’s exposed data, users can visit &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;spycloud.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sr. Account Director&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emily Brown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REQ on behalf of SpyCloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spycloud@req.co&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101513/spycloud-data-shows-corporate-users-3x-more-likely-to-be-targeted-by-phishing-than-by-malware.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 years in, zero trust remains elusive — with AI rising to complicate the challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101457/15-years-in-zero-trust-remains-elusive-with-ai-rising-to-complicate-the-challenge.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;zero trust&lt;/a&gt; approach cybersecurity access control is more than 15 years old but organizations continue to struggle with its implementation due in large part to fragmented tooling and legacy infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4048002/88-of-cisos-struggle-to-implement-zero-trust.html"&gt;recent report from Accenture&lt;/a&gt; paints a picture of widespread industry struggles in rolling out zero trust technologies, a perspective in line with the experiences of experts and security practitioners quizzed on the topic by CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/zero-trust/"&gt;Zero trust networking&lt;/a&gt; involves applying a security framework where no user or device is trusted by default. Under zero trust, every access attempt is accompanied by authenticating identity and device compliance regardless of whether or not it originates within an organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The approach contrasts with traditional “castle and moat” models where devices within an enterprise network were trusted by default.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many enterprises have progressed slowly on their &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3965399/security-leaders-shed-light-on-their-zero-trust-journeys.html"&gt;zero trust journeys&lt;/a&gt; largely because implementation requires a fundamental shift in both mindset and infrastructure. Key roadblocks include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legacy systems that weren’t designed for zero trust principles,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Fragmented identity and access tools that make unified enforcement difficult, and&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Cultural and organizational resistance to changing long-standing trust models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kylewickert/?originalSubdomain=ca"&gt;Kyle Wickert&lt;/a&gt;, field CTO at AlgoSec, says zero trust remains one of the most misunderstood transformations in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many organizations still hesitate to pursue it because they associate zero trust with rigid architectures, operational complexity, and high implementation costs,” Wickert says. “That perception is rooted in the legacy days of reassigning IPs, redesigning routing, re-plumbing VLANs, or physically rewiring environments just to enforce segmentation policies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The industry-wide shift to software-defined and cloud-driven data centers has lifted legacy challenges while creating new issues in the shape of growing policy and application complexity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“One of the biggest obstacles to zero trust at scale is no longer the infrastructure — it’s the challenge of defining, governing, and maintaining policies that adapt across hybrid networks, spanning on-prem firewalls, cloud-native controls, SDN, SD-WAN, and SASE technologies,” Wickert says. “The most effective way to overcome these challenges is to shift the focus of segmentation from ‘devices and subnets’ to applications and their connectivity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rickhholland/"&gt;Richard Holland&lt;/a&gt;, field CISO at threat-led cybersecurity firm Quorum Cyber, argues that zero trust represents a method to mature an organization’s security health rather than a set of products and services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I would argue that the technology to achieve zero trust has been in existence for some time and CISOs and CIOs may have already found themselves on a roadmap without realizing it is zero trust,” Holland says. “By treating zero trust as a journey to improve cybersecurity health, and by taking small bite-size chunks, you can iterate through a series of improvements in relatively quick succession.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other cybersecurity experts contend that zero trust migrations offer an opportunity to support more ambitious IT transformation projects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-fridakis-96184b/"&gt;Stephen Fridakis&lt;/a&gt;, CISO in residence at Cyderes, says the shift from network-based rules to identity-based rules inherent in zero trust implementations offers a roadmap to “safer, simpler, and more durable” enterprise architectures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“IP ranges, VLANs, and physical locations are brittle and age badly, especially with M&amp;amp;A churn and cloud adoption,” Fridakis explains. “Identity-based access follows the user and device, not the network.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He adds: “It eliminates firewall sprawl, reduces engineering overhead, and enforces intent instead of infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="wise-up"&gt;Wise up&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;University of Texas CISO &lt;a href="https://www.utsystem.edu/offices/information-security/chief-information-security-officer"&gt;George Finney&lt;/a&gt; has discussed zero trust with hundreds of security leaders. Those conversations have uncovered several common denominators on why zero trust projects fail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Firstly, internal politics has the potential to derail zero trust implementations. “Technology in a company is generally operated and supported in silos,” Finney says. “These different areas may not understand the big picture of how much risk a cybersecurity breach could represent and resist change.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Conversely, in organizations that have successfully shifted to zero trust, “leadership in every area agree that security is a core part of the success of the organization as a whole,” Finney says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Insufficient education can also act as a barrier preventing the successful rollout of zero trust technologies, according to Finney.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Starting a zero trust project requires more than just changing the design of a network or modifying some settings in an application,” he says. “Everyone on the team needs to understand what zero trust is, why the organization is doing it, and what role they’ll play in supporting it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This means that every zero trust project needs to begin with education to help change not just the technology, but the culture of the organization as well,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/garybrickhouse/"&gt;Gary Brickhouse&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at GuidePoint Security, notes that an “overly-complex approach” to zero trust has driven up costs and timelines as organizations pursue overly strict alignment with zero trust principles.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most organizations would benefit from a simplified risk-based approach, identifying critical use cases that are achievable and deliver the desired outcome of risk reduction,” Brickhouse says. “Early wins improving the security of the organization and moving the ZT [zero trust] needle forward builds confidence across the organization.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/"&gt;Rob Forbes&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at Stratascale, advises security leaders to develop a strategic roadmap before embarking on any zero trust project.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“[CISOs should] start with a comprehensive assessment of their current security posture and assets,” Forbes counsels. “Next, develop a roadmap for zero trust implementation, prioritizing critical assets and high-risk areas.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These steps should be followed by investments in training and tools to support the transition to a zero trust model, which ought to be left open to further refinement as requirement evolve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“[Companies should] regularly review and update their zero trust strategy to adapt to new threats and technologies,” Forbes adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-reinforces-zero-trust-paradigm"&gt;AI ‘reinforces’ zero trust paradigm&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4047974/agentic-ai-a-cisos-security-nightmare-in-the-making.html"&gt;agentic AI &lt;/a&gt;becomes increasingly embedded in the business, standard zero trust principles must be extended to keep the enterprise secure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By 2027, growth of AI agents will push 50% of CIOs to restructure and automate identity and data access and authorization management to reduce misuse and leakage as part of a zero trust architecture, according to industry analyst firm IDC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security experts call on organizations to implement a new wave of zero trust, extending beyond people and devices to include AI agents. In practice, this means enforcing strict context boundaries, trusted domain controls, and AI-specific security reviews.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-kindervag-40572b1/"&gt;John Kindervag&lt;/a&gt;, chief evangelist officer at Illumio, tells CSO that “AI doesn’t change the zero trust paradigm — it reinforces it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI operates within the constraints of cybersecurity’s foundational rules, and attacks only work if there’s an open door,” Kindervag argues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bigger risk is from AI models, according to Kindervag.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI models can become a liability if not governed by zero trust,” he says. “If an organization doesn’t treat its AI models as protect surfaces, they risk manipulation, poisoning, or theft.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In most cases, AI supports zero trust implementation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Good AI highlights high-risk communication patterns, surfaces unusual behaviour, and accelerates processes like labeling and policy implementation,” Kindervag explains. “AI can help in every step of the zero trust five-step methodology, but it really helps organizations to push beyond resilience into anti-fragility.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101457/15-years-in-zero-trust-remains-elusive-with-ai-rising-to-complicate-the-challenge.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-790)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-790</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-790</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-791)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-791</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-791</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-792)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-792</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-792</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25-793)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-793</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-793</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-794)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-794</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-794</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding the next technical debt: Building AI governance before it breaks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101145/avoiding-the-next-technical-debt-building-ai-governance-before-it-breaks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The AI rush is repeating a familiar mistake. Early in my career, a risk executive I worked with used to say, “You didn’t invite me to drink the beer; now you want me to pay the bill?” whenever problems came up because a project moved ahead without enough oversight. If someone tried to avoid explaining the details, he’d add, “I don’t know if you’re showing me the monster’s head or just its toe.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, I’ve watched new products, business services and innovations launch without enough security or risk checks. Cloud computing, big data, BYOD, APIs, IoT, social media and low-code are just a few examples. We usually innovate first and worry about governance later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is following the same pattern. Leaders in many industries are excited about AI, just like they were with earlier technologies. But many still don’t have a clear way to track where AI is used, who owns the risks or how automated decisions could affect the business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ten years of fail fast have shown us the risks: more incidents, data breaches and bigger exposure. If organizations don’t build risk and accountability into AI now, they’ll face the same problems we saw with earlier innovations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-real-risk-isnt-ai-itself-its-how-we-use-it"&gt;The real risk isn’t AI itself, it’s how we use it&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even with detailed frameworks like the &lt;a href="https://airisk.mit.edu/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MIT AI Risk Repository&lt;/a&gt;, many organizations still struggle to connect AI risks to real business problems. Everyone wants new use cases, but few are tracking where risks begin — in the data, the models or the quick decisions machines make.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, AI risks aren’t just about the future — they’re already part of daily operations. These risks arise when algorithms affect business results without clear accountability, when tools collect sensitive data and when automated systems make decisions that people no longer check.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These governance gaps aren’t new. We saw the same issues with cloud, APIs, IoT and big data. The solution is also familiar: keep track, assess, control and monitor. The first step is knowing where AI is used, what data it handles and which processes it touches. With this visibility, governance becomes about managing what’s already in the business, not just fearing the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The next step is protection. We don’t need to reinvent the wheel or develop advanced new methods. Instead, we should start with the basics: with simple governance steps and then you can evolve your journey.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="borrow-what-already-works"&gt;Borrow what already works&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The good news is companies don’t have to start from scratch with AI governance. Guidelines for secure and compliant technology already exist in cybersecurity, cloud and privacy programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What’s needed is to apply traditional controls to this new context:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification and ownership.&lt;/strong&gt; Every model should have a clear owner, with limits on who can train, query or deploy it. Its relevance to the business should be clear by different criteria, such as regulatory, operational or revenue.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baseline security and non-negotiables.&lt;/strong&gt; Access control, multifactor authentication, network segmentation and audit logging are just as important for AI environments as they are for servers or clouds.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous monitoring.&lt;/strong&gt; Model behavior should be more than just accurate — it should be observable, traceable and accountable for any changes in purpose.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party due diligence.&lt;/strong&gt; Contracts with AI providers should clearly define rights over training data, generated content and how to respond to incidents.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing and validation.&lt;/strong&gt; Red-teaming, AI-specific penetration testing and scenario simulations should be regular practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These controls aren’t new, nor is the hope of avoiding another form of technical debt. Maybe this time we can apply the secure by design approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The same governance principles will be tested again soon; this time by a new wave of autonomous systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-rise-of-agent-ai-and-the-accountability-vacuum"&gt;The rise of agent AI and the accountability vacuum&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new generation of agent AI systems can act on their own across different platforms, doing tasks, making purchases or retrieving data without direct human input. This move from simple chatbots to self-directed agents creates an accountability gap that most organizations aren’t ready for.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without the right guardrails, an agent can access systems it shouldn’t, expose confidential data, create unreliable information, start unauthorized transactions, skip established workflows or even act against company policy or ethics. These risks are made worse by how fast and independently agent AI works, which can cause big problems before people notice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the rush to try new things, many companies launch these agents without basic access controls or oversight. The answer is to use proven controls like least privilege, segregation of duties, monitoring and accountability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Executives should be able to answer fundamental questions, drawn from frameworks such as NIST AI RMF, about any autonomous AI operating in their environment:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What governance processes are in place (policies, roles and responsibilities, oversight)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Which use cases and business applicability are being leveraged?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Who is accountable when it goes wrong?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Which risks does it represent? And which controls are applied?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-governance-into-the-business-not-around-it"&gt;Building governance into the business, not around it&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effective AI governance isn’t an IT function, any more than cybersecurity is. It’s a business function with shared accountability. Forward-looking organizations are now introducing three mechanisms that embed governance into operations:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI self-assessment frameworks&lt;/strong&gt; — simple checklists that help each business unit map their AI use cases, data sources and risks.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage governance committees&lt;/strong&gt; — cross-functional bodies with representation from risk, compliance, cybersecurity and business leaders.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corporate AI use policies&lt;/strong&gt; — defining approved tools, contractual standards and minimum safeguards for both internal and external AI usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These aren’t bureaucratic layers but foundations of sustainable innovation. When the business owns the inventory, risk teams can focus on assurance rather than discovery. Modern governance should enable adoption, not inhibit or slow it down, but help scale it safely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dont-build-another-debt"&gt;Don’t build another debt&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The similarities to cloud adoption are clear. Ten years ago, not having early controls led to exposed data, unmonitored systems and expensive fixes. AI is showing the same pattern, but it’s happening faster and with bigger consequences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Technical debt isn’t just about code anymore. It’s also about trusting your data, holding models accountable and protecting your brand’s reputation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The organizations that succeed with AI will be the ones that see governance as part of the design process, not as something that causes delays. They’ll move forward with clear plans and measure value and risk together.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They’ll see that real innovation isn’t just about building smarter systems but about making them safe, accountable and trusted from the start. For technology and business leaders, this isn’t just a security imperative. It’s a strategy for sustainable innovation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101145/avoiding-the-next-technical-debt-building-ai-governance-before-it-breaks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-795)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-795</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-795</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-796)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-796</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-796</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-797)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-797</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-797</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 20:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hardening browser security with zero-trust controls</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101173/hardening-browser-security-with-zero-trust-controls.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The shift from perimeter-based security to zero trust is now indispensable for combating modern threats. The obsolete “castle-and-moat” model, granting implicit trust to any device or user inside the network, collapsed with the rise of cloud, remote work and BYOD. Attackers now bypass traditional controls by targeting identity, exploiting AI-driven phishing, supply chain intrusions and advanced session hijacking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The browser is at this frontline, serving as the universal access point for SaaS, developer tools and sensitive AI resources. As data from diverse trust domains converge, each access request demands rigorous, real-time validation of identity, device posture and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIST SP 800-207 provides the model: decouple access from network location by using a policy engine, policy administrator and browser-based policy enforcement point to enforce dynamic, context-aware authorization. &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/207/a/final" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST SP 800-207A&lt;/a&gt; extends this to runtime control across multi-cloud and microservices. Simultaneously, &lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/resources/cisa-zero-trust-maturity-model-v2" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CISA’s Zero Trust Maturity Model v2&lt;/a&gt; maps a clear implementation path spanning five pillars and emphasizing automation, analytics and governance as essential enablers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This journal unites these leading standards with current enterprise practices, delivering a comprehensive browser-first ZTA framework that balances least-privileged access, SSO/MFA, device compliance and session isolation for secure, adaptable operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-imperative-for-browser-centric-zero-trust"&gt;The imperative for browser-centric zero trust&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As remote work and cloud adoption become the default operating model, the inability of implicit network trust and legacy VPNs to address the modern attack surface is undeniable. Adversaries now target the browser directly with attacks like cross-site scripting (XSS), session hijacking via stolen tokens and advanced phishing that bypasses traditional MFA. A browser-centric ZTA framework is the necessary response, built on the following six principles.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-identity-first-access-control"&gt;1. Identity-first access control&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Network proximity is now an inferior trust signal. Only federated, cryptographically verifiable identity tokens issued by centralized enterprise IdPs using OIDC or SAML are permitted as gates to corporate resources. This transition, well-documented by &lt;a href="https://fidoalliance.org/passkeys/"&gt;FIDO Alliance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/security/zero-trust/deploy/identity"&gt;Microsoft research&lt;/a&gt;, transfers the very concept of “inside” the organization from the network to the user’s validated persona. No session proceeds without a signed, short-lived identity claim.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-least-privileged-access-lpa"&gt;2. Least-privileged access (LPA)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Legacy roles that confer standing privileges are antithetical to zero trust. LPA decrees that entitlements are minimized, time-bounded and context-aware. The application of just-in-time access, JWT token scoping and dynamic risk assessment ensures users receive only what is necessary for their current task, never more. Device state, resource value and behavior all adjust privilege in flight: a noncompliant device or anomalous login instantly narrows the access window.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-continuous-verification-and-adaptive-policy"&gt;3. Continuous verification and adaptive policy&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust is not “authenticate once, trust forever.” It is a continuous cycle of verification. Adaptive policy rules, executed by the policy engine, must re-evaluate access in real-time based on new telemetry. This “posture drift” can be triggered by numerous signals:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behavioral:&lt;/strong&gt; If a user typically logs in from Texas at 9 am but suddenly authenticates from Eastern Europe at 3 am (“impossible travel”), adaptive rules flag the anomaly and restrict access.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Device:&lt;/strong&gt; An EDR agent detects a malicious process, changing the device’s health state from “compliant” to “at-risk.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network:&lt;/strong&gt; A user moves from a trusted corporate network to an untrusted public Wi-Fi hotspot. In response, the PE can automatically initiate a session revocation, force a step-up MFA challenge or reduce the session to read-only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-integrated-phishing-resistant-authentication"&gt;4. Integrated phishing-resistant authentication&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To secure the identity-first gate, the authentication method itself must be robust. Traditional MFA (like SMS or one-time passcodes) is phishable. The ZTA browser model mandates the adoption of phishing-resistant MFA, primarily through FIDO2/WebAuthn passkeys. As detailed by the &lt;a href="https://fidoalliance.org/passkeys/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;FIDO Alliance, passkeys are a W3C standard&lt;/a&gt; that replaces passwords with cryptographic key pairs. The private key never leaves the user’s device (e.g., a YubiKey, a phone’s secure enclave or a Windows Hello TPM), making it impossible to phish. The user authenticates with a simple biometric or PIN, providing unparalleled security with a superior user experience. By 2025, passkey adoption will have moved from emerging to mainstream, with deployments showing authentication times under two seconds and proven reductions in phishing-related losses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-device-health-gating"&gt;5. Device health gating&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A trusted user on a compromised device is a critical threat. The ZTA model must validate the &lt;em&gt;endpoint&lt;/em&gt; before issuing an access token. This “device health gating” is a cornerstone of modern IdP solutions. The conditional access policy engine queries the device for posture signals collected by an MDM (mobile device management) or EDR (endpoint detection and response) agent. As documented in &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/entra/identity/conditional-access/overview" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft’s conditional access framework&lt;/a&gt;, policies enforce compliance before token issuance. Key signals include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patch level:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the OS fully patched?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDR status:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the EDR agent (e.g., CrowdStrike, Defender) running and reporting no active threats?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disk encryption:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the primary drive encrypted (e.g., BitLocker, FileVault)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Device state:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the device jailbroken or rooted? Only devices that meet this baseline are considered “compliant” and eligible for access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-remote-browser-isolation-rbi"&gt;6. Remote browser isolation (RBI)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the highest-risk activities, we must assume the endpoint &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; be fully trusted and that web content &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; malicious. Remote browser isolation (RBI) addresses this by executing risky or privileged web sessions in isolated, disposable cloud containers. The user’s endpoint never interacts with active web code; it only receives a stream of pixels (pixel-streaming RBI) or a sanitized, reconstructed version of the page (DOM-reconstruction RBI). As demonstrated by &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/zero-trust/products/browser-isolation/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;zero trust solutions like Cloudflare RBI&lt;/a&gt;, this neutralizes all browser-based exploits, prevents malware from reaching the endpoint and can enforce data loss prevention (DLP) by disabling copy/paste or uploads from the isolated session.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="modern-workflows-and-policy-patterns-a-blueprint"&gt;Modern workflows and policy patterns: A blueprint&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A modern ZTA browser architecture is not a single product but an integrated system that operates on a continuous, per-request verification loop.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the foundational user-facing workflow for all access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request:&lt;/strong&gt; A user on a managed browser (e.g., Chrome Enterprise) attempts to access a protected app (e.g., test.company.com).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intercept &amp;amp; redirect:&lt;/strong&gt; An access proxy (ZTNA/PEP), like Cloudflare Access or Zscaler Private Access, intercepts the request. Seeing no valid session token, it redirects the browser to the enterprise IdP (e.g., Okta, Entra ID) to initiate an OIDC or SAML authentication flow.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP authenticates the user. Based on policy, it requires a phishing-resistant MFA step using a FIDO2/WebAuthn passkey. The user taps their YubiKey or uses Windows Hello.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextual evaluation:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP’s Conditional Access Policy Engine (PE) evaluates the request. It queries the Microsoft Intune or CrowdStrike ZTA integration for device posture. The policy is: ALLOW IF (user_group == ‘Sales’) AND (device_status == ‘Compliant’) AND (auth_method == ‘FIDO2’).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Token issuance:&lt;/strong&gt; Upon success, the IdP mints a signed JSON Web Token (JWT). This token contains critical &lt;em&gt;claims&lt;/em&gt;: the user’s ID (sub), their roles (groups), the authentication method (amr) and a short-lived expiration (exp).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access granted:&lt;/strong&gt; Browser supplies JWT to proxy, proxy grants direct, secure application access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="b-adaptive-session-management-and-least-privilege"&gt;B. Adaptive session management and least privilege&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This workflow demonstrates the “continuous verification” principle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario 1 — Posture drift:&lt;/strong&gt; The user is authenticated and working. Midway through the session, their EDR agent detects a high-priority threat (e.g., malware execution). The EDR agent instantly updates the device’s health state. The IdP’s conditional access, which leverages a continuous access evaluation protocol (CAEP), receives this signal and &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt; revokes all active session tokens for that device, forcing a logout and remediation.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario 2 — Step-up authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; A user with a valid session for a low-risk app (like a wiki) clicks a link to a high-risk app (like the SAP admin console). The ZTNA proxy (PEP) intercepts this new request, recognizes the “Tier 0” sensitivity of the application and re-challenges the user, forcing a new step-up authentication with a hardware passkey before proceeding, even though they already have an active SSO session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="c-privileged-and-sensitive-operations-via-isolation"&gt;C. Privileged and sensitive operations via isolation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This workflow is for protecting “Tier 0” assets like administrator consoles.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request:&lt;/strong&gt; An administrator attempts to access the Okta admin console or an internal Kubernetes dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy enforcement:&lt;/strong&gt; After successful FIDO2 authentication, the ZTNA policy (PEP) for this “Tier 0” application is configured not with an “Allow” action, but with an “Isolate” action.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isolation:&lt;/strong&gt; The user is transparently routed to an RBI service. The entire admin session is executed in a secure, disposable container in the cloud. Only benign pixels are streamed to the end-user’s browser.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DLP &amp;amp; threat neutralization:&lt;/strong&gt; This mitigates two critical risks:
&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endpoint Malware: If the admin’s workstation is compromised, keyloggers or token-stealing malware cannot access the privileged session, as it’s not running locally.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Data Exfiltration: Granular RBI policies are applied: copy/paste, file downloads and printing are disabled for this session, preventing accidental or malicious credential or data leakage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="d-forward-thinking-scim-provisioning"&gt;D. Forward-thinking SCIM provisioning&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This workflow is the automation backbone that makes LPA viable at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System for cross-domain identity management (SCIM) is an open standard (RFC 7643) for automating the exchange of user identity information between systems. &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc7643" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The SCIM protocol (RFC 7643)&lt;/a&gt; defines a REST API and schema for managing user and group resources.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Workflow (Joiner/Mover/Leaver):
&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source event:&lt;/strong&gt; A manager in the HRIS (e.g., Workday) changes an employee’s role from “Sales Rep” to “Sales Manager.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCIM push:&lt;/strong&gt; The HRIS (or an integration layer) automatically triggers a SCIM PATCH request to the IdP (Okta, Entra ID).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IdP update:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP updates the user’s attributes, removing them from the group:sales-rep and adding them to the group:sales-manager.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy propagation:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP’s Policy Engine (PE) immediately uses this new attribute data.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re-evaluation:&lt;/strong&gt; The next time the user authenticates (or their token expires), their access is re-evaluated. Their old access to rep-level tools is gone, and their new access to manager dashboards is automatically granted. This “Just-in-Time” provisioning prevents “privilege creep” and ensures all access decisions are based on accurate, real-time identity data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="maturity-pathways-roadmap-to-optimal-state"&gt;Maturity pathways: Roadmap to optimal state&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This roadmap, aligned with the CISA ZTMM v2, allows organizations to make measurable, incremental progress.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial:&lt;/strong&gt; At this stage, the organization moves beyond the “Traditional” perimeter. All browser-accessed applications are federated with a central IdP and protected by an access proxy (ZTNA). SSO and passkey-based FIDO2/WebAuthn MFA are mandatory for all users. All access logs are centralized in a SIEM. This achieves the &lt;em&gt;Identity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Network&lt;/em&gt; pillar foundations.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced:&lt;/strong&gt; The organization builds on the initial foundation with richer context. Device compliance (via Intune/CrowdStrike integration) is enforced for all sessions. Policy decisions become adaptive, leveraging real-time telemetry from EDR and user behavior analytics (UBA). SCIM is fully implemented for automated provisioning from an identity source of truth (e.g., HRIS). This demonstrates maturity in the &lt;em&gt;Devices&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Automation&lt;/em&gt; capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimal:&lt;/strong&gt; At the highest level of maturity, access is determined on a per-request, least-privilege basis, fully aligning with NIST 800-207A. RBI is automatically and transparently enforced for all privileged, unmanaged or high-risk web sessions. The entire ecosystem is automated, with post-authentication security (like token theft detection and CAEP) fully integrated. This represents an optimal state across all CISA pillars, driven by robust automation and governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="operationalizing-zta-browser-security"&gt;Operationalizing ZTA browser security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implementing this architecture requires a shift in operational thinking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy design:&lt;/strong&gt; Move from network rules to a “who, what, where, when, why” logic model. Policies should be readable statements: GRANT access IF (user_group == ‘Finance’) AND (app == ‘SAP’) AND (device_status == ‘Compliant’) AND (auth_method == ‘FIDO2’). Start with a default “deny” and create explicit “allow” rules, creating a policy matrix that maps user personas to data and applications.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic access:&lt;/strong&gt; Token claims must be context-bound and short-lived. A token issued for a read-only wiki should not be valid for accessing a finance application. True phishing resistance &lt;em&gt;requires&lt;/em&gt; eliminating all phishable recovery methods. This means deprecating SMS, email links and security questions in favor of passkey-based recovery or in-person identity verification.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk automation:&lt;/strong&gt; Session adaptation (step-up, revocation) must be triggered by automated analytics. Integrate the IdP and ZTNA solution with your SIEM/SOAR platform. An EDR alert (e.g., “high-severity malware”) or a UBA alert (e.g., “impossible travel”) should automatically trigger a SOAR playbook that calls the IdP’s API to revoke the user’s session tokens.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governance-as-code:&lt;/strong&gt; Policies must not be managed via manual “click-ops” in a GUI. All ZTNA access rules, IdP Conditional Access policies and RBI configurations should be defined as code (e.g., using Terraform, HCL or JSON). This enables version control, peer review (via pull requests) and automated CI/CD pipelines, aligning with CISA’s cross-cutting controls for governance and automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="configuration-patterns-latest-2025"&gt;Configuration patterns (Latest, 2025)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chrome Enterprise:&lt;/strong&gt; Use Chrome Browser Cloud Management to enforce a secure baseline on all corporate browsers. Enforce policies like BrowserSignin (to force login to a managed profile), PasswordManagerEnabled (set to false to mandate use of an enterprise password manager), SafeBrowsingProtectionLevel (set to Enhanced) and BuiltInDnsClientEnabled (to enforce secure DNS). &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/a/answer/2657289" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google’s Chrome Enterprise policies&lt;/a&gt; provide the full list of controls to manage extensions, data leakage and security settings.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intune/conditional access:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a non-negotiable “baseline” policy: Require compliant device and Require phishing-resistant MFA for &lt;em&gt;all users&lt;/em&gt; accessing &lt;em&gt;all cloud apps&lt;/em&gt;. Then, create more granular policies. For example, block access entirely from high-risk countries or require a “Compliant + Hybrid Joined” device for access to legacy on-prem apps.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIDO2/WebAuthn passkeys:&lt;/strong&gt; Deploy passkeys (platform-based like Windows Hello and hardware-bound like YubiKeys) as the primary authenticator. Start with privileged users (admins) and high-value targets (executives, finance) first, then roll out to the general population.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare RBI/ZTNA:&lt;/strong&gt; Configure clientless ZTNA to secure third-party and BYOD access without requiring an agent. Use Service Auth policies (based on mTLS certificates or service tokens) to secure non-human (RPA bot) access to web applications. Configure a “default-isolate” policy that automatically sends all traffic to unclassified or high-risk domains through the RBI service.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCIM automation:&lt;/strong&gt; Connect your IdP (Okta, Entra ID) to your source of truth (e.g., Workday) via a pre-built SCIM connector. Map HR attributes (e.g., Department, Role, EmploymentStatus) to IdP attributes. Use these attributes to drive dynamic group membership, which in turn drives all application access and ZTNA policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-browser-is-now-both-sword-and-shield"&gt;The browser is now both sword and shield&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Browser security is the linchpin for zero trust and organizational resilience. By converging validated identity, rigorous device posture, adaptive access policies, automated provisioning and session isolation, we not only defend against the sophisticated threats of 2025 but also set a foundation for scalable, measurable governance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In moving from static perimeters to live, session-level policy enforcement, every click and credential is scrutinized, every privilege time-boxed, every access revocable by context and behavior not convenience or legacy. Teams must treat the browser not as an exposed window, but as the policy stronghold of the modern enterprise. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building toward this architecture is a journey: Begin with SSO and robust MFA, enforce device compliance, automate provisioning and integrate RBI where risk justifies isolation. Codify policy, automate telemetry and develop governance as code. Refuse the ‘trusted network’ myth. Zero trust is here, and the browser is now both sword and shield.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101173/hardening-browser-security-with-zero-trust-controls.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Submarine cable cybersecurity: protecting critical infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4099959/submarine-cable-cybersecurity-protecting-critical-infrastructure.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Between 95 and 99% of the world’s data traffic travels through submarine cables. An extensive network of more than 1.3 million kilometers, which travels across the seas and oceans, from shore to shore. According to &lt;a href="https://www2.telegeography.com/transport-networks?hsCtaAttrib=180200503225" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TeleGeography&lt;/a&gt;, there are 650 of these infrastructures in operation or in the pipeline, mainly operated by private companies. Whether we can connect to the internet, back up our computer files, make a bank transaction with our cell phone or communicate with other people depends to a large extent on whether nothing happens to the submarine cables that cross the world from one coast to another.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In recent times, numerous incidents where the breakage of a cable leaves a territory without connectivity are proof that despite their critical nature. They are not always properly protected: in the Baltic Sea alone, between 2022 and July 2025, ten cases of submarine cable breakage were &lt;a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/news/baltic-sea-undersea-cable-security/"&gt;recorded&lt;/a&gt;, seven between November 2024 and January 2025. In most of these incidents, international governments interests were suspected to be behind them, with Chinese or Russian involvement. In a complicated geopolitical context, these types of events, in which there remains some doubt as to whether they are accidental or intentional, put the focus on the need to ensure protection. Both at the physical and cybersecurity levels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US &lt;em&gt;think tank&lt;/em&gt; Atlantic Council &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/cyber-defense-across-the-ocean-floor-the-geopolitics-of-submarine-cable-security/"&gt;identifies&lt;/a&gt; several trends that threaten the security of submarine cables. On the one hand, linked to the geostrategic issue, the presence of authoritarian governments are reshaping the internet’s physical layout through companies that control internet infrastructure, to route data more favorably, interrupting the provision of services or taking advantage of infrastructures for espionage. In addition, network management centers have moved from locations close to cable entry points to remote ones, which adds new levels of risk. Finally, with the rise of technologies such as cloud computing, 5G or IoT, the volume of data transmitted over these cables has increased, but also their sensitivity, as more and more sectors depend on these tools for their performance. Once again, these are added factors for which cybersecurity and security policies for these critical infrastructures need to be reviewed. In fact, the European Union is taking action, with a &lt;a href="https://joint-research-centre.ec.europa.eu/jrc-explains/subsea-cables-how-vulnerable-are-they-and-can-we-protect-them_en"&gt;Cable Security Action Plan&lt;/a&gt; published in February 2025 that alludes not only to the physical challenges, but also to the need for cyber protection. But with the vast majority of cables in the hands of private companies, the approach they take is critical.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dealing-with-the-cybersecurity-of-submarine-cables"&gt;Dealing with the cybersecurity of submarine cables&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this new scenario, big technology companies are becoming major players thanks to their growing presence as a project developer: in a decade, Google, Meta, Amazon and Microsoft have gone from having 10% of international capacity to 71%. Asked how they address issues of infrastructure protection and cybersecurity, Google says they focus on the physical aspect. “Security is a key factor in all our infrastructure investments. Routes are deliberately chosen with many factors in mind, and methods such as shielding and cable burial are used to protect submarine cables.” Google says fishing boats and ship anchors as the greatest physical risk, and notes that “the best protection against these risks and any other physical damage is to build a network infrastructure that achieves resilience, in part, through multiple diverse network routes. Our philosophy is to create sufficient concurrent network paths at metropolitan, regional and global levels, along with a scalable software control plane, to support traffic redistribution and minimize network congestion. When physical damage occurs, redundant network paths can reroute traffic to minimize service disruption for customers and users.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the Spanish companies most involved in this global network is Telxius, a subsidiary of Telefónica. The company stresses that “submarine cables are more than just infrastructure; they are the backbone of the global digital ecosystem. In a hyperconnected world, submarine cables are essential and are part of a broader digital ecosystem that goes beyond the coast to key data centers,” the company says. Regarding the physical protection of this type of critical infrastructure, the company points to a significant improvement in recent times. “Physical accessibility is limited, so redundancy and resilience are still essential to guarantee continuity in the event of accidental damage caused by fishing, anchoring or natural phenomena such as earthquakes or landslides which, in the absence of redundancy, could affect service continuity”. In terms of cybersecurity, there is a twofold perspective. On the one hand, “it guarantees diversity and redundancy in all our terrestrial and submarine routes, which allows us to maintain service continuity with high availability even in the event of outages”. They exemplify this with the case of its transatlantic route, where Telxius offers what they call redundant connectivity through its two state-of-the-art submarine cables: Marea and Dunant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, from the Telefónica subsidiary they talk about protecting the infrastructure through a comprehensive security model. “In terms of cybersecurity, Telxius adopts, for its IT systems, networks and devices, a multi-layered approach and leverages artificial intelligence and machine learning for real-time threat detection.” This comprehensive model would thus combine different elements including physical measures and cybersecurity in the mooring stations, periodic audits and continuous evaluation, continuity and disaster recovery plans, periodic testing and clear protocols for crisis action, training and awareness to reduce social engineering risks and the use of AI and machine learning for proactive detection and risk mitigation. “And all this from regulatory compliance in key areas: business continuity, information security, environmental management and energy efficiency,” they summarize. A necessary framework to ensure the continuity of an infrastructure on which much of modern life depends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4099959/submarine-cable-cybersecurity-protecting-critical-infrastructure.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insecure use of Signal app part of wider Department of Defense problem, suggests Senate report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101859/insecure-use-of-signal-app-part-of-wider-department-of-defense-problem-suggests-senate-report.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Signalgate scandal that enveloped US Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth in March appears to be symptomatic of a wider lax attitude towards the use of non-approved messaging apps by officials and employees, a Senate Committee has concluded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In March, the US Senate Committee on Armed Services set out to examine issues raised by the &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3854632/signalgate-theres-an-it-lesson-here.html" target="_blank"&gt;Signalgate incident&lt;/a&gt;: the need to clarify the existing rules on using “non-controlled” apps, and looking at whether Defense Secretary Hegseth adhered to them in his use of Signal, and whether his actions were evidence of a wider culture of insecure app usage within the Department of Defense (DoD).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This week’s dual reports have come back with a mixed assessment of these points. Broadly, what Hegseth was accused of doing – communicating sensitive information using a third-party messaging app – appears to have been happening at the DoD in less serious contexts since at least 2020.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This mirrors issues familiar to enterprises: unsanctioned or unmanaged messaging apps, including ones touting end-to-end encryption (E2EE) security, quickly become an IT backchannel that can invisibly undermine carefully-assembled security, compliance, and data retention policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="shadow-communications"&gt;Shadow communications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/Dec/04/2003834916/-1/-1/1/DODIG_2026_021.PDF" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;first report&lt;/a&gt;, an assessment of the Defense Secretary’s use of the Signal app to communicate with senior colleagues in advance of a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/March%E2%80%93May_2025_United_States_attacks_in_Yemen" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;military operation against Yemen on March 15&lt;/a&gt;, is used to illustrate the point. It confirms the widely reported fact that two hours before the raid, Hegseth revealed details of the operation to a Signal group of 19 people, including a journalist who had been added to it in error.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In doing so, the report agrees he violated security policies by sending sensitive information from a personal device, and using the non-approved Signal app in a way that revealed important operational details in advance of the strike. The report ducks the issue of whether this information was classified at the time it was sent, noting that Hegseth was senior enough to determine this for himself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/Dec/04/2003834921/-1/-1/1/DODIG_2026_022.PDF" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;second background report&lt;/a&gt; has uncovered evidence of a more general culture of shadow communications in the DoD, including widespread use of video-conferencing apps during the Covid 19 pandemic.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The evidence gathered is sparse and partly redacted, making it difficult to assess the seriousness of any breaches. Because the scope of its remit was limited to the evidence from previous audits, one of the committee’s recommendations is to undertake a more comprehensive assessment of unsanctioned app usage inside the DoD. There’s also a question mark around how old audits analyzed by a Senate committee could accurately measure something that, by its nature, is hidden and only recorded on personal devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the report says it is certain that Hegseth’s actions were not an isolated example, noting that staff had “used non-DoD-controlled electronic messaging systems for a variety of reasons. For example, some personnel used them because of the systems’ perceived appearance of security. As a result, DoD personnel increased the risk of exposing sensitive DoD information to our adversaries and did not comply with the legal obligation to retain and preserve official records.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In short, while there was no evidence that unsanctioned app use is routine or normalized, it is likely that enough staff are using them to make a serious breach possible at some point. The report concludes that one of the reasons staff have taken to these messaging apps was that they lack convenient alternatives. It recommends developing approved apps to remove this need, implementing a training program to ensure existing communication regulations are complied with, and limiting the authority to use messaging apps to senior staff, in specific circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What’s surprising about this is that it has taken a major political row at government level to raise an issue that enterprise CISOs have been grappling with for years: the effects of BYOD, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575457/shadow-it-is-increasing-and-so-are-the-associated-security-risks.html" target="_blank"&gt;shadow IT&lt;/a&gt; (and now &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/646835/is-genai-quietly-ushering-in-shadow-it-on-steroids.html" target="_blank"&gt;shadow AI&lt;/a&gt;), and unsanctioned apps that creep into organizations without anyone realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the last two decades, the rise of mobile devices, the cloud, and apps has radically de-centralized IT in ways that top-down management models struggle to control. Meanwhile, nothing has changed; the Signal app at the center of this scandal remains hugely popular on both sides of the political divide, despite the appearance of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3977385/company-behind-modified-signal-app-used-by-mike-walz-allegedly-hacked.html" target="_blank"&gt;additional issues&lt;/a&gt; with the technology. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101859/insecure-use-of-signal-app-part-of-wider-department-of-defense-problem-suggests-senate-report.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 21:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN security advisory (AV25-798)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openvpn-security-advisory-av25-798</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openvpn-security-advisory-av25-798</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-799)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-799</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-799</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Struts security advisory (AV25-800)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-struts-security-advisory-av25-800</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-struts-security-advisory-av25-800</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-801)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-801</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-801</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupang breach of 33.7 million accounts allegedly involved engineer insider</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101486/coupang-leaks-personal-information-of-33-7-million-accounts-suspected-of-poor-authentication-key-management.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A prolonged lack of management of valid authentication keys for signed access tokens issued to authenticators is believed to be the root cause of over 30 million accounts being exposed externally by ecommerce giant Coupang. Ongoing analysis suggests that these keys could have been exploited even after the responsible employee left the company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 29, Coupang &lt;a href="https://news.coupang.com/archives/58849/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;released a statement&lt;/a&gt; confirming the unauthorized exposure of personal information from approximately 4,500 accounts on Nov. 18. The company also noted that the breach had been reported to the National Police Agency, the Korea Internet &amp;amp; Security Agency, and the Personal Information Protection Commission. Subsequent investigations, however, revealed that the damage involved approximately 33.7 million accounts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Leaked information included names, email addresses, shipping address lists, and some order information. Coupang stated that payment information, credit card numbers, and login information were not included. It is believed that unauthorized access occurred via overseas servers starting on June 24, 2025. The company also stated that it is currently cooperating with relevant authorities to investigate the cause of the breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.msit.go.kr/bbs/view.do?sCode=user&amp;amp;mPid=208&amp;amp;mId=307&amp;amp;bbsSeqNo=94&amp;amp;nttSeqNo=3186554" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Ministry of Science and ICT, the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency, and other relevant agencies conducted&lt;/a&gt; an on-site investigation after receiving a report of a breach on Nov. 19 and a report of a personal information leak on Nov. 20. The investigation confirmed that the attacker exploited an authentication vulnerability in Coupang’s servers, bypassing the normal login process and leaking customer information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The government launched a joint public-private investigation team on Nov. 30, and the Personal Information Protection Commission is investigating whether Coupang violated its personal information protection safety measures — access control, access authority management, encryption, etc. As a service with such a high user base that it’s often called the “Amazon of Korea,” Coupang issued a public security notice on Nov. 29 to prevent secondary damage. Furthermore, a three-month period, starting Nov. 30, will be dedicated to strengthening the monitoring of personal information leaks and illegal distribution online.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Choi Min-hee, Chairwoman of the National Assembly Science, ICT, Broadcasting and Communications Committee, released the results of an analysis of the specific causes of the incident in a press release on Nov. 30. According to information received from Coupang, the company reportedly responded that “the token signing key validity period is often set to 5 to 10 years,” adding that “the rotation period is long and varies greatly depending on the key type.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chairman Choi’s side explained this incident using an analogy to an access control system. If the “token” required for login is a single-use access card, the “signature key” is like the authentication stamp used to issue the access card. While access is impossible without the authentication stamp, even with the access card, if the signature key is left unattended for an extended period, it can be subject to continued exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Rep. Choi Min-hee’s office, Coupang’s login system is designed to immediately discard tokens after they are created, but the signature information required for token creation was deleted or not updated when the employee in charge left the company, and was thus exploited by internal employees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a press release, Chairman Choi Min-hee stated, “Coupang did not follow the most basic internal security procedure of renewing the signing key,” and “Abandoning a long-term valid authentication key was not simply a deviation by an internal employee, but the result of organizational and structural problems at Coupang that neglected the authentication system.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Victims of this breach have been notified via email or text message. Related information can also be found on a separate &lt;a href="https://mc.coupang.com/ssr/desktop/faqlist" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;information page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Coupang CEO Park Dae-joon &lt;a href="https://news.coupang.com/archives/58857/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;issued a separate statement&lt;/a&gt; on Nov. 30, saying, “We sincerely apologize for causing great inconvenience and concern to the public,” and “Coupang will do its best to prevent further damage by closely cooperating with the joint public-private investigation team including the Ministry of Science and ICT, the Personal Information Protection Commission, the Korea Internet &amp;amp; Security Agency, and the National Police Agency.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;South Korean President Lee Jae Myung this week referenced the data breach at Coupang in &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/boards-policy-regulation/south-koreas-lee-calls-tougher-penalties-after-coupang-data-breach-2025-12-02/"&gt;calling for increased penalties for corporate negligence&lt;/a&gt; in such scenarios. The breach is believed to be the worst in South Korea in over a decade. Bloomberg reports that the breach may be a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-12-03/coupang-breach-is-poised-to-be-a-landmark-case-for-south-korea"&gt;landmark case for South Korea&lt;/a&gt;. It could result in a record fine, &lt;a href="https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20251204006900315"&gt;potentially up to 1.2 trillion won (US$814M)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10629826"&gt;prime suspect is a former Coupang engineer&lt;/a&gt; who had worked on authentication systems. The police are investigating whether the former employee acted alone or collaborated with others on the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101486/coupang-leaks-personal-information-of-33-7-million-accounts-suspected-of-poor-authentication-key-management.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-802)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV25-803)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-805)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-806)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-807)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-018 - Vulnerability affecting React Server Components - CVE-2025-55182</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV25-808)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-809)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-810)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-804) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GISEC GLOBAL 2026 – The Middle East &amp;amp; Africa’s Largest Cybersecurity Event</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 77040032195727952.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
