<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 19:18:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Why outsourced cyber defenses create systemic risks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110657/why-outsourced-cyber-defenses-create-systemic-risks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing critical IT and cybersecurity once looked like a shortcut to efficiency. Today, it is a shortcut to systemic fragility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breaches at one vendor now cascade across hundreds of organizations. A corporate decision framed as a cost-saving measure can trigger risks that extend across industries, even nations. The &lt;a href="https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/feature/SolarWinds-hack-explained-Everything-you-need-to-know"&gt;SolarWinds breach&lt;/a&gt; showed how a compromised supplier became a launchpad for global espionage. &lt;a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/information/moveit-vulnerability"&gt;The MOVEit breach&lt;/a&gt; exposed how a single vulnerability could compromise sensitive data across governments, banks, and schools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you sit on a board, lead a cyber function, or regulate markets, you can no longer treat outsourcing as a local concern. It is a systemic risk. Left ungoverned, outsourcing can magnify operational weaknesses, fuel cybercrime, and expose firms to geopolitical pressure. Left unchecked, it poses a threat to global economic security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This piece will guide you through the drivers of outsourcing, the risks it has unleashed, how these risks now escalate into systemic threats, the governance gap that enables them to thrive, and the responsibilities each stakeholder must shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-outsourcing-took-off"&gt;Why outsourcing took off&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The rise of outsourcing wasn’t a conspiracy. It was a rational &lt;a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/operations/our-insights/global-business-services-sourcing-comes-of-age"&gt;response to competitive pressure.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First came the economics. Outsourcing promised lower costs. A CIO could reduce headcount, offshore operations, and still meet budget targets without raising capital. Then came the talent squeeze. Security engineers were scarce. Outsourcing gave firms access to global pools of expertise. Cloud adoption turbocharged the trend. Instead of building everything in-house, firms leaned on managed services and third-party platforms to scale fast.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trust was often assumed, not engineered. The &lt;a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2023/07/how-to-bridge-the-cybersecurity-trust-gaps-in-your-organization/"&gt;World Economic Forum has highlighted these “trust gaps.”&lt;/a&gt; Boards signed contracts with providers without embedding trust frameworks or demanding systemic assurances. Leaders gave vendors the keys to critical systems, with few checks on how those keys were safeguarded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You may save money and move faster. But if you fail to demand trust at the core, you inherit fragility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risk-categories-of-outsourced-it-cybersecurity"&gt;Risk categories of outsourced IT &amp;amp; cybersecurity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When you outsource, responsibility shifts, but accountability never leaves you. The risks fall into clear categories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="operational-risks"&gt;Operational risks&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The most basic risk is fragile continuity. &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-40074751"&gt;In 2017, British Airways outsourced parts of its IT operations. A system outage grounded flights worldwide&lt;/a&gt;. The vendor contract delivered savings, but it also created single points of failure. When that single point snapped, the damage was immediate and global.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c3drpgv33pxo"&gt;A recent cyber-attack targeting airport check-in systems caused significant disruptions&lt;/a&gt;, including delays and system failures, across multiple European airports, such as Heathrow. It also reveals that the attack exploited vulnerabilities in shared infrastructure, raising serious concerns about the security of aviation support systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cyber-risks"&gt;Cyber risks&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/feature/SolarWinds-hack-explained-Everything-you-need-to-know"&gt;SolarWinds&lt;/a&gt; remains the textbook case. Hackers compromised a widely used software update. Thousands of government agencies and Fortune 500 firms installed the backdoor, believing it came from a trusted vendor. &lt;a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/information/moveit-vulnerability"&gt;MOVEit&lt;/a&gt;, a more recent breach, showed the same weakness in a different form: data transfer software was compromised, exposing millions of records across multiple jurisdictions. One weak vendor poisoned an entire ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-agent-threats"&gt;AI-agent threats&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The rise of autonomous AI adds a new layer of complexity. &lt;a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2025/09/unsecured-ai-agents-cyberthreat/"&gt;WEF has flagged how cybercriminals are already deploying AI agents to automate attacks&lt;/a&gt;. Imagine outsourced IT monitored by tools vulnerable to hostile AI. A malicious agent can probe for weaknesses, adapt in real time, and exploit outsourced environments at scale. This is no longer science fiction; it is market reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="compliance-risks"&gt;Compliance risks&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cross-border outsourcing introduces accountability gaps. Regulators demand GDPR, DORA, or sector-specific compliance, but vendors spread data across multiple jurisdictions. When breaches occur, responsibility is blurred. Firms argue that vendors failed. Vendors say that clients misunderstood the model. Meanwhile, regulators and customers hold the original brand accountable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="geopolitical-risks"&gt;Geopolitical risks&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing to hostile or unstable regions turns business contracts into national security concerns. In 2021, the &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/news/kaseya-ransomware-attack-guidance-affected-msps-and-their-customers"&gt;Kaseya ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt;, launched through an IT management platform used by MSPs, spread through thousands of companies worldwide. The attackers operated from jurisdictions beyond the reach of effective law enforcement. Global security became hostage to one supply chain decision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="fresh-case-studies"&gt;Fresh case studies&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The risks are not historic. In 2023, hackers &lt;a href="https://therecord.media/boeing-cyberattack-parts-distribution-business"&gt;breached a Boeing subsidiary&lt;/a&gt;, disrupting the production of aircraft parts. A &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/hack-unitedhealths-tech-unit-impacted-1927-million-people-us-health-dept-website-2025-08-14/"&gt;breach at UnitedHealth crippled healthcare payments&lt;/a&gt; across the US, leaving hospitals scrambling. These are not niche events. They serve as reminders that outsourcing can turn corporate risks into public crises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-local-problems-to-systemic-threats"&gt;From local problems to systemic threats&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing risks do not stay contained. They scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SolarWinds showed how a single compromised supplier could infect the digital bloodstream of government and industry. The &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/news/attack-colonial-pipeline-what-weve-learned-what-weve-done-over-past-two-years"&gt;Colonial Pipeline ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt; disrupted fuel supply across the eastern United States. In 2025, ransomware at UnitedHealth halted healthcare reimbursements, disrupting a sector that affects millions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Economic disruption follows. &lt;a href="https://insights.integrity360.com/5-of-the-biggest-cyber-attacks-of-2025-so-far"&gt;Integrity360 has reported multiple 2025 global attacks with damages running into billions&lt;/a&gt;. A local failure in one vendor cascades through supply chains. If that vendor supports critical infrastructure, the consequences magnify.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Global interdependencies make the weakest link the decisive one. Your cybersecurity posture may be robust. But if your vendor is compromised, you inherit their weakness. And if their subcontractor is compromised, the weakness doubles. This is why outsourcing is no longer a firm-level risk. It is systemic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-governance-gap"&gt;The governance gap&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Why does this fragility persist? Because governance has lagged behind reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boards often focus on efficiency. They pressure executives to cut costs and accelerate digital adoption. But they fail to demand trust-based vendor oversight. They rarely ask how vendor risks are classified, monitored, or tested. They rarely challenge management on concentration risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regulators are fragmented. Some impose reporting rules. Others set sector-specific standards. But there is little global alignment. Cybercriminals exploit this patchwork. They attack through cross-border vendors, knowing compliance is reactive and uneven.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs face their own limits. They may demand audits, but their leverage over subcontractors is weak. Supply chain visibility fades after the first tier. Even when CISOs are aware of the risks, budget constraints, contracts, and governance inertia limit their ability to act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Add AI to the mix. Regulators have not yet prepared for AI-driven cybercrime. Many boards still view AI as an innovation story, rather than a threat multiplier. This blind spot will cost dearly when AI-driven attacks target outsourced environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="towards-responsible-outsourcing"&gt;Towards responsible outsourcing&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Abandoning outsourcing is unrealistic. The task is to govern it responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust by design.&lt;/strong&gt; WEF has recommended embedding trust frameworks into outsourcing contracts. This means defining expectations for transparency, accountability, and resilience upfront. You cannot assume trust; you must structure it.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI resilience.&lt;/strong&gt; Organizations must monitor outsourced environments for AI-agent threats. This requires investing in AI-native defenses, anomaly detection, and joint monitoring with vendors to ensure seamless integration.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendor stress tests.&lt;/strong&gt; Europe’s DORA and NIS2 regulations mandate stress testing of critical third parties. These should become global norms. Firms must treat vendors the way banks treat capital stress tests, by planning for failure before it occurs.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive practices.&lt;/strong&gt; Some firms are moving in the right direction. Banks are adopting multi-cloud strategies to reduce concentration risk. Zero-trust models ensure vendors only access what they need, when they need it. Continuous monitoring detects issues before they escalate and become more severe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The lesson is clear. Responsible outsourcing is not about cost arbitrage. It is about resilience design.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="who-must-do-what"&gt;Who must do what&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk ownership is collective. But responsibilities differ.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boards. &lt;/strong&gt;You must demand trust-based vendor oversight. You cannot relegate vendor risk to a quarterly risk report; you must build it into governance charters. Demand resilience metrics. Approve investments in redundancy. Ask about the exit strategy in case a critical vendor fails.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CISOs.&lt;/strong&gt; You carry the operational burden. Map your critical vendor dependencies. Negotiate accountability clauses in SLAs. Do not accept vague promises. Push for real-time risk monitoring. Run tabletop exercises that include vendor failure scenarios. Integrate AI threat detection into third-party tracking.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulators.&lt;/strong&gt; You must align standards across borders. Fragmentation is a gift to cybercriminals. Mandate stress tests for systemic vendors. Demand transparency on subcontractors. Penalize opacity. Encourage information sharing across sectors. You cannot stop outsourcing, but you can ensure it is not blind outsourcing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion-someone-else-cant-carry-your-risk"&gt;Conclusion: Someone else can’t carry your risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing will not disappear. In modern business, we weave it in, but if unmanaged, it risks systemic collapse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new dimension is AI. Cybercriminals are deploying autonomous agents to probe outsourced ecosystems. At the same time, trust gaps persist. Organizations outsource without embedding frameworks of accountability. Boards chase efficiency. Regulators remain reactive. CISOs lack visibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is not sustainable. If outsourcing is to serve global competitiveness rather than undermine it, trust and resilience must be at its core. Boards must lead with oversight. CISOs must incorporate transparency into their contracts and monitoring processes. Regulators must harmonize and stress test.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The choice is stark. Either you govern outsourcing with discipline, or outsourcing governs you with fragility. The elephant in the biz is not outsourcing itself. It is the delusion that someone else can carry your risk for you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110657/why-outsourced-cyber-defenses-create-systemic-risks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-832)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-833)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-834)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-835)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-836)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-837)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–838)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-839)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectWise security advisory (AV25-840)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New report explores use of robotics and unmanned systems in the fight against crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</link>
      <description>Europol has today published The Unmanned Future(s): The Impact of Robotics and Unmanned Systems on Law Enforcement. The report, produced by the Europol Innovation Lab, provides an in-depth analysis of how unmanned systems could change society, crime and law enforcement, and discusses the challenges and opportunities they present.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-841)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-821) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-842)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-843)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-845) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-846)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-847)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-848) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpol sweep takes down cybercrooks in 19 countries</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4111324/interpol-sweep-takes-down-cybercrooks-in-19-countries.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A ransomware expert lauded a recent crackdown on cybercrooks in Africa that resulted in the decryption of six ransomware strains, smashing of links to malicious websites, and hundreds of arrests as major action.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This may not be the same headline as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1308503/lockbit-ransomware-operations-seized-by-law-enforcement-in-operation-cronos.html" target="_blank"&gt;taking down LockBit&lt;/a&gt;, but I think it is significant,” said &lt;a href="http://www.sans.org/profiles/jon-dimaggio" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jon DiMaggio&lt;/a&gt;, chief security strategist, Analyst1 and co-author of an upcoming book on chasing ransomware gangs. “Because law enforcement can’t arrest Russian ransomware criminals, it’s smart to focus on areas of the world where we can make a difference and get people.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He was commenting &lt;a href="https://www.interpol.int/News-and-Events/News/2025/574-arrests-and-USD-3-million-recovered-in-coordinated-cybercrime-operation-across-Africa" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on the statement today by Interpol &lt;/a&gt;that in Operation Sentinel, which ran between October 27 and November 27 of this year, law enforcement agencies in 19 African countries arrested 574 suspects, decrypted six ransomware variants, took down 6,000 malicious links, cracked a business email compromise scam that almost cost a major petroleum company $7.9 million, and recovered approximately $3 million.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Interpol didn’t identify the ransomware strains that were decrypted. DiMaggio suspects they were modified variants of strains available on dark web sites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="important-to-disrupt-gangs-before-they-expand"&gt;Important to disrupt gangs before they expand&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In describing the operation, Interpol cited efforts in multiple countries. In Ghana, it said that an unnamed financial institution, which saw 100TB of its data encrypted, was one of the victims. Ghanaian authorities conducted advanced malware analysis that led to the creation of a decryption tool and the recovery of nearly 30TB of the data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ghanaian authorities also dismantled a major cyber-fraud network operating across Ghana and Nigeria that defrauded more than 200 victims of over $400,000. Using professionally designed websites and mobile apps, the scammers mimicked well-known fast-food brands, collecting payments but never delivering orders. Ten suspects were arrested in Ghana, and over 100 digital devices seized and 30 fraudulent servers taken offline. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Benin, 43 malicious domains were taken down, and 4,318 social media accounts linked to extortion schemes and scams were shut down, leading to 106 arrests. And in Cameroon, law enforcement reacted quickly after two victims reported a scam involving an online vehicle sales platform. The phishing campaign was traced to a compromised server, and an emergency bank freeze was issued within hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-very-good-thing"&gt;A ‘very good thing’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fact that the same operation broke ransomware operations and a business email compromise (BEC) operation is “unique,” said DiMaggio, because most people think of Africa as the source of BEC and fraud scams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fact that authorities are working to disrupt ransomware operations in Africa before they grow to the size of those run by gangs in other areas of the world “is a very good thing,” he said. Africa is “a few steps behind where the Russian ransomware scene is,” so targeting gangs there now before they grow bigger is important, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The breaking of a BEC operation could also be significant, he added, because, in aggregate, crooks around the world pull in more money from business email scams than from ransomware, DiMaggio said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110472/think-you-can-beat-ransomware-ransomhouse-just-made-it-a-lot-harder.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related content: RansomHouse strain upgraded&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operation Sentinel is the second major anti-cybercrime operation in Africa this year. In August, Interpol announced &lt;a href="https://www.interpol.int/en/News-and-Events/News/2025/African-authorities-dismantle-massive-cybercrime-and-fraud-networks-recover-millions" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the second stage of Operation Serengeti&lt;/a&gt; that saw the arrest of 1,209 people, the dismantling of over 11,400 malicious IT infrastructures, and the recovery of just over $97 million. This operation also dealt with high-impact cybercrimes including ransomware, online scams, and BEC scams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="other-enforcement-efforts"&gt;Other enforcement efforts&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These operations were among significant moves against threat actors globally in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operation Endgame, an ongoing international anti-botnet effort coordinated by Europol, &lt;a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-endgame-follow-leads-to-five-detentions-and-interrogations-well-server-takedowns" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;went after threat actors subscribing to the Smokeloader pay-per-install botnet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-endgame-strikes-again-ransomware-kill-chain-broken-its-source" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;took down some 300 servers&lt;/a&gt; behind the malware used to distribute ransomware, and, in November, &lt;a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;took down or disrupted 1,025 servers&lt;/a&gt; including the Elysium botnet, the enabler of the Rhadamanthys infostealer and VenomRAT remote access trojan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Separately, authorities in the US, Finland, and the Netherlands &lt;a href="https://www.politie.nl/en/news/2025/may/30/key-service-for-malware-developers-taken-offline.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;teamed up to take down AVCheck&lt;/a&gt;, one of the largest counter-antivirus services used by criminals around the world.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As well, the Five Eyes intelligence sharing group, consisting of the US, the UK, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand, &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa25-239a" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;accused China of supporting threat actors&lt;/a&gt; who are attacking critical infrastructure in a number of countries, &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/05/21/microsoft-leads-global-action-against-favored-cybercrime-tool/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;and Microsoft got a court order allowing it to seize &lt;/a&gt;and block 2,300 domains behind the distribution of another infostealer, Lumma Stealer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106753/how-to-create-a-ransomware-playbook-that-works.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related content: Create a ransomware playbook that works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="an-uphill-battle"&gt;An uphill battle&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/ed-dubrovsky/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ed Dubrovsky&lt;/a&gt;, chief operating officer of incident response firm Cypfer, said the breaking of six ransomware strains is good news. But, he added, the cybercrime industry is more than ever focused on data theft as opposed to data encryption, and in some cases, data destruction after theft.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Law enforcement action against cybercrime is of critical importance,” he added. “Without some level of deterrence, and given the upside from a financial [perspective] and other motives, cybercrime would have been much more prevalent and impactful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With that said, cybercrime is still a multibillion dollar market, and law enforcement suffers from limited resources and proper ongoing training. Some countries, such as the US, are far ahead of others from a sophistication and effectiveness perspective … Law enforcement is effective, partially, and in very specific areas of cybercrime, and in other areas, the effectiveness is still a work in progress.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some threat actors have great IT expertise, he added, and are taking advantage of AI. “Therefore, I believe law enforcement is achieving great impact in reducing cybercrime while also fighting an uphill battle.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attackers-likely-to-expand-efforts-worldwide"&gt;Attackers likely to expand efforts worldwide&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.queensu.ca/academia/leuprecht/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Christian Leuprecht&lt;/a&gt;, a Canadian university professor and expert on national security, cybercrime, and money laundering, noted Africa’s population is set to double in the next 25 years, and it has the youngest population structure of any continent. The combination of a highly innovative and increasingly sophisticated workforce in some of the most politically, economically, and socially unsustainable countries in the world will be likely to generate a host of sophisticated local threat actors vying for economic survival and prosperity, with a potentially global reach. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For now, he said, they are going after local targets, likely because they’re less resilient to attack and exploitation. But as local firms harden their cyber defenses, these African-based threat actors are bound to expand their operations globally. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More, better, and proactive local disruption and enforcement capacity against these threat actors is critical to prevent them from becoming global in scale, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The scale and sophistication of cyberattacks across Africa are accelerating, especially against critical sectors like finance and energy,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/director-neal-jetton/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Neal Jetton&lt;/a&gt;, Interpol’s director of cybercrime, said in a statement. “The outcomes from Operation Sentinel reflect the commitment of African law enforcement agencies, working in close coordination with international partners. Their actions have successfully protected livelihoods, secured sensitive personal data, and preserved critical infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operation Sentinel not only used the resources of law enforcement agencies, but also was assisted by efforts from cybersecurity companies including Team Cymru, The Shadowserver Foundation, Trend Micro, TRM Labs, and Uppsala Security. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4111324/interpol-sweep-takes-down-cybercrooks-in-19-countries.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 01:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow’s $7.75 billion cash deal for Armis illustrates shifting strategies</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4111449/servicenows-7-75-billion-cash-deal-for-armis-illustrates-shifting-strategies-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow has agreed to buy cybersecurity vendor Armis for $7.75 billion in cash, it announced Tuesday.  This builds on its December purchase of identity security vendor Veza, and the closing of its acquisition of AI vendor Moveworks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts and cybersecurity practitioners mostly applauded the move, but cautioned that this could force CIOs and CISOs away from a best-of-breed strategy and into a classic suite approach, where the individual elements may be merely good enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is an extension of what we have been seeing at the ERP application layer,” said &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/scott-bickley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Scott Bickley&lt;/a&gt;, an advisory fellow at the Info-Tech Research Group. “ServiceNow is basically saying ‘We don’t want to be a point solution. We want to be the platform by which you coordinate and solve all of your problems.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bickley noted that this trend has been ongoing for a few years, with many of the largest vendors trying to offer suites that deliver everything. “Microsoft was the initial poster child of this,” he said. “They are going to start to embed [AI and cybersecurity] capabilities into their suites and bundles, where you don’t necessarily have an opt-out solution. You will get ‘maybe good enough’ versus best of breed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But looking at ServiceNow’s two other recent acquisitions, &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4097411/servicenow-is-in-talks-to-buy-identity-security-firm-veza-for-over-1-billion-report.html"&gt;Veza&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3842626/servicenow-to-acquire-moveworks-to-strengthen-agentic-ai-and-enterprise-search.html" target="_blank"&gt;Moveworks&lt;/a&gt;, could suggest parallel strategies. “ServiceNow has hedged their bets without saying that they are hedging their bets,” Bickley said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.servicenow.com/company/leadership/pablo-stern.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pablo Stern&lt;/a&gt;, EVP and general manager of tech workflow products at ServiceNow, confirmed in an interview that the Armis acquisition is the largest in ServiceNow’s history. He added that the companies have been partnering “for well more than two years.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow’s &lt;a href="https://newsroom.servicenow.com/press-releases/details/2025/ServiceNow-to-acquire-Armis-to-expand-cyber-exposure-and-security-across-the-full-attack-surface-in-IT-OT-and-medical-devices-for-companies-governments-and-critical-infrastructure-worldwide/default.aspx" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;statement about the Armis deal&lt;/a&gt; described the two firms as creating “a unified, end-to-end security exposure and operations stack that can see, decide, and act across the entire technology footprint.” It said that it expects to fund the transaction through a combination of cash on hand and debt. The deal is expected to close in the second half of 2026, subject, as always, to regulatory approvals and closing conditions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pressure-from-agentic-ai"&gt;Pressure from Agentic AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The statement quoted ServiceNow COO Amit Zavery suggesting that agentic developments are a key part of the strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the agentic AI era, intelligent trust and governance that span any cloud, any asset, any AI system, and any device are non-negotiable if companies want to scale AI for the long-term,” Zavery said in the announcement.&lt;strong&gt; “&lt;/strong&gt;Together with Armis, we will deliver an industry-defining strategic cybersecurity shield for real-time, end-to-end proactive protection across all technology estates. Modern cyber risk doesn’t stay neatly confined to a single silo, and with security built into the ServiceNow AI Platform, neither will we.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The soaring popularity of autonomous agents that figure out on their own how to perform various tasks has concerned many cybersecurity executives, as the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109999/agentic-ai-already-hinting-at-cybersecuritys-pending-identity-crisis.html" target="_blank"&gt;risk of security holes created by enterprise agentic trials&lt;/a&gt; is becoming clear. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most cybersecurity practitioners saw the move as the latest indicator that CIOs and CISOs must rethink how they do their jobs, given how AI is forcing changes in data management and data leakage. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="visibility-is-the-key"&gt;Visibility is the key&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For decades, the CIO’s white whale has been a precise, real-time Configuration Management Database [CMDB]. Most are outdated the moment they are populated,” said Whisper Security CEO &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kakooch" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kaveh Ranjbar&lt;/a&gt;. The Armis acquisition “is an admission that in an era of IoT, OT, and edge computing, you cannot rely on manual entry or standard agents anymore. The system of action needs to own the system of record for the unmanaged world. For CIOs, this signals that automated, continuous discovery is now the only acceptable standard for IT asset management. You can’t automate workflows on assets you don’t know exist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The lesson, Ranjbar said, is different for the CISO. “CISOs have historically suffered from the swivel-chair problem: one screen shows the vulnerability and another screen is needed to patch it. This deal collapses that gap. It validates that visibility is the new perimeter. As OT and IT converge, the attack surface has become too complex for fragmented tools. CISOs should view this as a mandate to consolidate their visibility stacks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, the chief analyst at Greyhound Research, agreed that this acquisition will likely accelerate IT and security structural changes. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This acquisition represents a fundamental repositioning of ServiceNow from a coordination layer into an operational authority. Buying Armis is not about expanding a security portfolio. It is about owning the upstream constraint that determines whether modern enterprises can govern complexity at all,” Gogia said. But without knowing what is connected across IT, OT, IoT, and other physical environments, “workflow automation, AI governance, and risk prioritization all collapse into theatre,” he observed, adding that the deal could remove long standing fragmentation between discovery tools, CMDBs, service mapping, ticketing, change management, and remediation. “If executed well, it could finally address one of the enterprise’s most persistent failures,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia added, “continuous discovery tied to business context has the potential to turn the CMDB from a negotiated artefact into a living system. That would change how incidents are resolved, how changes are governed, how audits are passed, and how accountability is assigned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="reveals-architectural-debt"&gt;Reveals architectural debt&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Given that the deal is not expected to be closed until next summer, executives should temper their timeline expectations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2026 second half closing date “implies a prolonged transition period where integration depth, roadmap clarity, and packaging decisions will evolve. CIOs should plan for ambiguity, not assume instant unification. Early value will come from visibility, [therefore] full platform value will take time,” Gogia said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another consultant, &lt;a href="https://www.fusioncollective.net/meet-the-team/co-founder-managing-partner/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Yvette Schmitter&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of the Fusion Collective consulting firm, said the deal is sitting atop years of bad enterprise IT strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This acquisition exposes more than ServiceNow’s strategy. It reveals the architectural debt hiding in every enterprise security stack that CIOs have been promising to address ‘next quarter’ for the past three years,” Schmitter said. “ServiceNow just signaled that platform plays will dominate over point solutions, and they’re willing to fund it with debt to move quickly while enterprises are still running budget committee meetings about tool sprawl.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She observed, “the valuation for Armis tells you the market assigns premium multiples to cyber-physical capabilities spanning IT, OT, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; medical devices. Translation: that patchwork of legacy security tools you’ve been defending as ‘best of breed’ just became technical debt you can’t explain to the board. CIOs need to audit their current security tool sprawl and map total cost of ownership before vendors make that case for them with renewal pricing that reflects your lack of alternatives.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The question, she said, “is no longer whether to consolidate, but whether your organization controls the timing and terms of that consolidation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, said that Armis executives were evaluating going public before they decided to accept the ServiceNow offer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For Armis, skipping the IPO and joining ServiceNow is a signal that the market for standalone device‑security platforms is consolidating fast, and scale wins,” Levine said. “The line between workflow, risk, and security is disappearing, and ServiceNow wants to own the convergence point.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/profile/aaron-painter/" target="_blank"&gt;Aaron Painter&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of authentication vendor Nametag, added that part of the IT confusion is that product names no longer mean what they once meant. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many of the workflows ServiceNow already automates are now security workflows, even if they’re still labeled as operations. Onboarding and offboarding, incident response, asset exceptions, vendor access, and change management all involve decisions that directly shape security outcomes,” Painter said. “Looked at alongside ServiceNow’s earlier acquisition of Veza, the strategy becomes clearer: ServiceNow is trying to connect asset visibility with identity and access intelligence, so the platform understands not just what devices exist, but who has access, why they have it, and whether that trust still makes sense over time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4111420/servicenows-7-75-billion-cash-deal-for-armis-illustrates-shifting-strategies.html" target="_blank"&gt;CIO.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4111449/servicenows-7-75-billion-cash-deal-for-armis-illustrates-shifting-strategies-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-849)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-849</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-849</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 20:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing NIS2 — without getting bogged down in red tape</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108294/implementing-nis2-without-ending-up-in-a-paper-war.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3568787/eus-nis2-directive-for-cybersecurity-resilience-enters-full-enforcement.html"&gt;NIS2&lt;/a&gt; is symbolic of the core problem with European directives and regulations: They generate unnecessary red tape and too rarely have the desired effect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s the Supply Chain Act, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562107/general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr-requirements-deadlines-and-facts.html"&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; impact assessments, or the IT Security Act — the common theme is that companies have to produce mountains of documentation, something that neither increases actual security nor is realistically verifiable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A compliant entity is typically one that can provide comprehensive documentation of all processes and regular audits. This documentation is usually so detailed that its creation already entails an almost unreasonable effort, and manual review becomes practically impossible. Even if it were reviewed, the information would not be precise enough to demonstrate genuine security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-should-be-included-in-the-planning"&gt;Security should be included in the planning&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This leads to an absurd practice at many companies: The technical team builds functioning infrastructure, and separately, a compliance officer subsequently writes a lengthy justification as to why the solution is supposedly secure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s roughly equivalent to Volkswagen building a car and only afterwards someone writing 40 pages about why that car should meet safety standards. In real-world industry, of course, things work differently: Safety requirements are already integrated into the planning, minimum technological standards are defined, and quality processes automatically monitor implementation. Compliance results from technology — not from ring binders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In other areas, such as tax audits, this problem has long been recognized, and the automation of relevant processes is legally mandated (keyword: electronic cash register, audit-proof accounting software). This not only saves honest business owners enormous amounts of manual work but, above all, reduces the risk of fraud.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, few things are implemented as consistently in Germany as the collection of our taxes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike the issue of tax burden, companies should have an intrinsic interest in correctly implementing their IT security. The fine for a NIS2 violation can amount to up to €10 million or 2% of global annual revenue. The economic damage caused by successful cyberattacks is often existential and already amounts to hundreds of billions of euros per year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even though it is not explicitly required by law, it is now possible — not least thanks to AI-supported tools — to automate security processes and their complete documentation to such an extent that security, compliance, and auditability can be combined in a single technical process. This not only saves resources but also increases actual security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An example of a SaaS application in the cloud shows what this can look like in detail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="it-in-transition-from-text-documents-to-declarative-technology"&gt;IT in transition: From text documents to declarative technology&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 essentially requires three things: concrete security measures; processes and guidelines for managing these measures; and robust evidence that they work in practice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Process documentation — that is, policies, responsibilities, and procedures — is not fundamentally new for most larger companies. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567039/whip-your-information-security-into-shape-with-iso-27001.html"&gt;ISO 27001&lt;/a&gt;-based information security management systems, HR processes, and management manuals have often been in place for years. Therefore, two levels are crucial for NIS2: the technical measures and the evidence that they are effective.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is precisely where the transformation of recent years becomes apparent. Previously, concepts, measures, and specifications for software and IT infrastructures were predominantly documented in text form. Program code was too complex, and configurations were scattered across files, ticketing systems, or in the minds of individual administrators. Documents were then written afterward — often by colleagues from other disciplines. This approach was problematic for two main reasons: It doesn’t scale in growing, distributed environments, and it doesn’t align with the goal of consistently automating technical processes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern systems therefore rely on methods such as test-driven or behavior-driven development and &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/2259359/what-is-infrastructure-as-code-automating-your-infrastructure-builds.html"&gt;infrastructure as code (IaC)&lt;/a&gt;, which — when consistently applied — largely replace text documentation. The technical specifications required by NIS2 can directly reference these artifacts: IaC definitions define encryption, network segments, or backup scenarios, and CI/CD pipelines deploy them to production in an audit-proof manner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Changes are thus not only described with technical precision, but also traceable chronologically via commits and deployments. Evidence for aspects that cannot be fully declared — such as the security of the software supply chain or the application code — can be mapped via security checks in the CI/CD pipeline and ongoing evaluation by SIEM and CNAPP systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The following areas provide a particularly clear example of what this can look like in practice:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity and access management&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Vulnerability management in the software supply chain and in monitoring&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Incident handling&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Reporting obligations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="identity-and-access-management-policies-as-code-instead-of-excel-roles"&gt;Identity and access Management: Policies as code instead of Excel roles&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518296/what-is-iam-identity-and-access-management-explained.html"&gt;Identity and access management&lt;/a&gt; is one of the central pillars of NIS2. What’s required is not just “any” roles, but an access concept based on Need-to-Know, Least Privilege, and Separation of Duties. In practice, this can be effectively conceived in three levels: the deliberate granting of rights, a realistic lifecycle for these rights, and an architecture that prevents lateral movement as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of managing permissions in Excel, admin UIs, and scattered wikis, roles and access rights are defined as “policies as code” or IaC — for example, as Terraform modules or JSON/YAML policies in a Git repository. All changes are made exclusively via merge requests and deployed through a CI/CD pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This makes it clearly traceable who changed which permissions, who approved the change, and when it went live. The documentation and accountability requirements of NIS2 thus arise directly from Git history and pipeline logs, without anyone having to write additional Word documents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A role model alone does not guarantee the principle of least privilege. NIS2 requires that rights be regularly reviewed and unnecessary permissions removed. In cloud environments with hundreds of accounts, services, pods, and functions, this is virtually impossible to manage manually.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where cloud identity entitlement management (CIEM) systems come in. They read all effective permissions from the environment, correlate them with audit logs, and show which rights are actually being used and where overprivileging exists. This is particularly crucial for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2132294/what-are-non-human-identities-and-why-do-they-matter.html"&gt;non-human identities&lt;/a&gt; (service accounts, workloads), because this is precisely where very broad rights are often granted, which can later serve as a springboard for attackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some startups now even offer CIEM systems that can automatically generate IAM policies for the relevant roles using AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="vulnerability-management-and-software-supply-chain-sbom-instead-of-scanner-pdf"&gt;Vulnerability management and software supply chain: SBOM instead of scanner PDF&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second area that NIS2 and the new Implementing Regulation 2024/2690 for digital services are enshrining in law is vulnerability management in the company’s own code and supply chain. This requires regular vulnerability scans, procedures for assessment and prioritization, timely remediation of critical vulnerabilities, and regulated vulnerability handling and — where necessary — coordinated vulnerability disclosure. Cloud and SaaS providers also face additional supply chain obligations, for example, towards cloud, CI/CD, and registry service providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In traditional vulnerability management, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/568049/top-sast-and-dast-tools.html"&gt;SCA, SAST, and DAST scanners&lt;/a&gt; are simply “dragged across everything.” The result is endless lists of findings, most of which are false positives or irrelevant to the specific system. This data then ends up in Excel spreadsheets or a vulnerability database, where teams try to prioritize. Especially with zero-day vulnerabilities, this leads to frantic ad-hoc analyses: Which of our components are affected? Is the vulnerability even exploitable in our architecture? What do we do until a patch is available?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The modern approach is to consolidate all DevSecOps findings in a central system. Results from SCA, SAST, and DAST are combined there, enriched with context from the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573185/what-is-an-sbom-software-bill-of-materials-explained.html"&gt;software bill of materials (SBOM)&lt;/a&gt;, architecture, and exposure, and pre-filtered using AI. This drastically reduces false positives, leaving a significantly smaller set of truly relevant vulnerabilities, including an assessment of their criticality in the specific setup.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These consolidated findings can be directly forwarded to ticketing systems and the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3840447/security-operations-centers-are-fundamental-to-cybersecurity-heres-how-to-build-one.html"&gt;SOC&lt;/a&gt;, where they are treated like incidents, tracked, and evaluated for NIS2 reports. This transforms a proliferating scanner output into a manageable process that reflects both legal requirements and operational realities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="monitoring-incident-handling-and-reporting-center"&gt;Monitoring, incident handling, and reporting center&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The third area where NIS2 quickly becomes a paper tiger is the combination of monitoring, incident response, and the new reporting requirements. The directive sets clear deadlines: early warning within 24 hours, a structured report after 72 hours, and a final report no later than one month. Many organizations are reacting by creating new templates, Excel spreadsheets, and reporting manuals — often largely detached from their existing SOC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a critical situation, this means that the SOC tackles the incident while, simultaneously, an “NIS2 task force” tries to process information from tickets, emails, and ad-hoc chats so that it fits into a form. The result is duplicated work, loss of information, and reports that fill pages but reveal little about how well detection and response actually work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a cloud SaaS environment, a different approach is possible: Instead of treating NIS2 reporting as a separate document project, a modern DevSecOps-based SOC is built, so that all security-relevant signals converge in one place from the outset: cloud infrastructure, CI/CD pipelines, applications, IdP, and IAM.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The rules governing how this data is correlated, enriched, and transformed into incidents are defined and versioned as code. Threat detection and response logic, thresholds, and playbooks reside in the repository and are deployed via pipelines, just like application code. This allows for the automation of large portions of traditional SOC work: Raw logs are transformed into consistent, contextualized incidents without requiring manual copying and pasting of text snippets. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573629/cnapp-buyers-guide-top-tools-compared.html"&gt;Cloud-native application protection platforms (CNAPP)&lt;/a&gt; and similar platforms simultaneously handle data storage and archiving, ensuring that the evidence of monitoring activity is generated within the system rather than through separate documentation loops. Machine learning and AI components further assist in reducing false positives, clustering similar events, and highlighting unusual patterns — allowing the SOC to focus on the few incidents that truly require attention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the process level, playbooks and reporting channels remain important — but streamlined. An &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829684/how-to-create-an-effective-incident-response-plan.html"&gt;incident response playbook&lt;/a&gt; defines incident classes, escalation paths, and communication rules, including the criteria for when an incident is considered “NIS2 significant.” A reporting process governs who consolidates the information from the SOC and business units and submits it via the BSI reporting center.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The actual documentation is also generated largely automatically here: Incident tickets contain a timeline, affected services, impact, cause, and measures; a “NIS2-relevant” indicator and a reporting status link them to external reports. Key performance indicators (KPIs) such as MTTD, MTTR, or the time between detection and initial reporting can be calculated directly from &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/524286/what-is-siem-security-information-and-event-management-explained.html"&gt;SIEM&lt;/a&gt; and IR data — precisely the metrics that reveal whether NIS2 is a lived process or just another drawer in the document cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nis2-as-an-architecture-test-not-just-a-documentation-exercise"&gt;NIS2 as an architecture test, not just a documentation exercise&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 forces companies to explicitly define their security measures, processes, and documentation. This is inconvenient — ​​especially for organizations that have previously operated largely on an ad-hoc basis. Whether this becomes a mere formality or a genuine security improvement, however, depends not on the legal text, but on the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anyone attempting to simply “document away” the policy using Word, PowerPoint, and Excel will generate a lot of effort and little resilience. However, if IdP and IAM, CI/CD pipelines, SBOM and vulnerability tools, SIEM, and IR platforms are configured to provide the required controls and evidence almost incidentally, NIS2 compliance is achieved as a side effect of a modern security landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108294/implementing-nis2-without-ending-up-in-a-paper-war.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-851)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-851</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-851</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-852)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-852</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-852</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-853)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-853</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-853</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-850) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-850</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-850</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korean firm hit with US investor lawsuit over data breach disclosure failures</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4111091/south-korean-firm-hit-with-us-investor-lawsuit-over-data-breach-disclosure-failures.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A US federal securities class action lawsuit has alleged that South Korean ecommerce giant Coupang took nearly a month to disclose a massive data breach to regulators, violating SEC rules that require companies to report material cybersecurity incidents within four business days.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pacermonitor.com/public/case/61918598/Barry_v_Coupang,_Inc_et_al"&gt;The lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, filed December 18, came just two days after Coupang finally submitted a Form 8-K disclosure to the Securities and Exchange Commission — 28 days after discovering the breach on November 18.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The complaint alleges that CEO Bom Kim and CFO Gaurav Anand knew or recklessly disregarded that the company had “inadequate cybersecurity protocols” allowing a former employee to access customer data for nearly six months without detection. The breach exposed personal information from 33.7 million customer accounts, Coupang said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="disclosure-deadline-missed"&gt;Disclosure deadline missed&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SEC adopted cybersecurity disclosure rules in July 2023, requiring companies to disclose material incidents within four business days of determining materiality, under item 1.05 of Form 8-K. Companies can delay disclosure only if the US Attorney General determines it poses substantial national security or public safety risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ksfcounsel.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Coupang-Complaint-rd.pdf"&gt;The complaint&lt;/a&gt; alleges that Coupang did not receive such an exemption. The company should have filed by November 24, following its November 18 discovery of the breach, but waited until December 16.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Between discovery and disclosure, media reports prompted organizational upheaval. Park Dae-jun, CEO of Coupang’s South Korean operations, &lt;a href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/business/companies/20251210/coupang-ceo-resigns-over-data-breach"&gt;resigned December 10&lt;/a&gt; after stating he would “take full responsibility for both the incident and the handling of the case.” Harold Rogers, Coupang’s general counsel and chief administrative officer, assumed the role of interim CEO of the Korean subsidiary.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Coupang founder and CEO Bom Kim declined to appear at &lt;a href="https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10640779"&gt;a South Korean parliamentary hearing&lt;/a&gt; about the breach, citing business obligations — a decision lawmakers condemned as a “systematic evasion of corporate responsibility.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="authentication-keys-left-unrevoked-after-employee-departure"&gt;Authentication keys left unrevoked after employee departure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Investigators traced the breach to a former employee who retained valid authentication credentials after leaving the company in 2024, according to &lt;a href="https://www.asiafinancial.com/ex-chinese-worker-key-to-koreas-worst-data-breach-in-decade"&gt;statements by South Korean lawmaker Choi Min-hee&lt;/a&gt;. The individual, a 43-year-old Chinese national, had worked on authentication management systems and joined Coupang in November 2022.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rep. Choi Min-hee, chair of the National Assembly’s Science, ICT, Broadcasting and Communications Committee, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101486/coupang-leaks-personal-information-of-33-7-million-accounts-suspected-of-poor-authentication-key-management.html"&gt;released analysis results in a November 30 press release&lt;/a&gt; pointing to failures in basic security procedures. The company failed to renew or revoke signing keys — the cryptographic credentials used to issue access tokens—when the employee left.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Abandoning a long-term valid authentication key was not simply a deviation by an internal employee, but the result of organizational and structural problems at Coupang that neglected the authentication system,” Choi said in the press release.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Coupang’s own information to lawmakers indicated the company set token signing key validity periods of five to ten years, with rotation periods varying by key type.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="legal-test-case-for-sec-cybersecurity-rules"&gt;Legal test case for SEC cybersecurity rules&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Legal observers noted the Coupang lawsuit appears to be among the first securities class actions directly challenging compliance with the SEC’s 2023 cybersecurity disclosure guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is a specific reason why I find the new Coupang lawsuit particularly interesting, and that is because one of the suit’s major allegations is that the company allegedly failed to make the requisite disclosures under the SEC’s cybersecurity disclosure guidelines,” legal journal, The D&amp;amp;O Diary, wrote in an &lt;a href="https://www.dandodiary.com/2025/12/articles/securities-litigation/two-tech-companies-hit-with-data-breach-related-securities-suits/"&gt;analysis of the case&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The complaint also alleges Coupang made materially false statements in quarterly reports filed in August and November 2025. Those reports incorporated risk disclosures from the company’s 2024 Annual Report detailing encryption technology and security measures — statements the complaint said “materially understated Coupang’s risk of a material cybersecurity event.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When Coupang &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001794669/000119312525325098/d77776d8k.htm"&gt;finally filed its Form 8-K&lt;/a&gt;, the company stated it had activated incident response procedures, blocked unauthorized access, and reported the incident to Korean authorities. The filing acknowledged Korean regulators “will potentially impose financial penalties” but said the company could not reasonably estimate losses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="regulatory-scrutiny-in-south-korea"&gt;Regulatory scrutiny in South Korea&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In South Korea, Coupang faces potential fines up to 1.2 trillion won ($814 million) under the Personal Information Protection Act, which requires companies to notify regulators within 24 hours of discovering a breach and maintain appropriate safeguards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;South Korean police raided Coupang’s Seoul headquarters twice as part of their investigation. &lt;a href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/www/tech/2025/12/419_389929.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;President Lee Jae Myung called for expanded class action lawsuit provisions&lt;/a&gt;, saying “every Korean has been affected” by the breach affecting nearly two-thirds of the country’s 51.7 million population.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit seeks to establish a class of investors who purchased Coupang securities between August 6 and December 16. Multiple law firms have announced they are investigating similar claims. A case management conference is scheduled for March 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4111091/south-korean-firm-hit-with-us-investor-lawsuit-over-data-breach-disclosure-failures.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CERN: how does the international research institution manage risk?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109133/cern-how-does-an-international-research-institution-manage-risk.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are few research institutions in the world with the size and scope of the European Organization for Nuclear Research, CERN. Founded in 1954 by 12 European countries, the &lt;a href="https://home.cern/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;European Laboratory for Elementary Particle Physics&lt;/a&gt; is located in the Swiss town of Meyrin, in the canton of Geneva, although its facilities extend along the Franco-Swiss border. Among them is the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), the world’s largest particle accelerator. International collaboration is at the core of its origin: more than 3,500 people make up its permanent staff. A small village that expands to 17,000 when adding the scientific staff of around 950 institutions from more than 80 different countries that collaborate on projects at the center. In this homegrown ecosystem, IT risk management poses a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The main problem is that we are managing a huge organization,” explains Stefan Lüders, CERN’s CISO. “We are one of the most important particle physics research institutes on the planet. We do sophisticated and interesting things, which makes us a target for attacks from different communities.” He lists several of these potential threats: &lt;em&gt;script kiddies&lt;/em&gt; or hackers with basic knowledge, who all pose a potential security risk; ransomware or data exfiltration; sabotage of CERN’s work; espionage actions and criminal groups trying to infiltrate through computers or other devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is where people come in. Because we have a very large, heterogeneous and very fluctuating research community. There are many physicists who join the organization every year. They come in and leave to do their PhD, do research at CERN and then leave,” he describes, pointing to the challenge of “taking care of this community of users. The other challenge is the flexible and fast-developing world of IT.” This includes programming — importing open-source libraries, their security, etc. — and AI. “The more sophisticated AI becomes, the greater the likelihood that those AI-driven security or attack tools will try to infiltrate the organization.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="securing-cern"&gt;Securing CERN&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How do you ensure effective implementation of cybersecurity initiatives that don’t disrupt scientific work? “You can’t,” Lüders asserts. “Cybersecurity is inconvenient. Let’s face it.” Lüders equates it to locking your front door or using your PIN to get cash out of the ATM; they can be annoying, but necessary. “We try to explain to our community why security measures are needed,” he says. “And if we adapt our security measures to our environment, people adopt them. Yes, it makes the research a little more complicated, but only a little.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lüders insists on the research work factor. “We are not a bank. We don’t have billions of dollars. We are not a military base, which means we don’t have to protect a country. We do research, which means adapting the level of security and the level of academic freedom so that the two go hand in hand. And that’s an ongoing conversation with our user community.” This ranges from scientific personnel to industrial control systems management, IT or human resources. “To meet this challenge, it is essential to talk to people. That’s why, I insist, cybersecurity is a very sociological issue: talking to people, explaining to them why we do this.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, not everyone willingly uses multifactor authentication because “let’s face it, they’re a pain. It’s much easier to type in a password, and who even wants to type in a password? You just want to log in. But for protection needs, today we have passwords and multifactor authentication. So you explain to people what you’re protecting. We tell them why it’s important to protect their work, as well as research results. And the vast majority understand that you need a certain level of security,” he says. “But it’s a challenge because there are so many different cultures here, different nationalities, different opinions and thoughts, and different backgrounds. That’s what we are constantly trying to adapt to.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-full"&gt;&lt;img alt="Stefan Lüders, CISO del CERN y Tim Bell, líder de la sección de gobernanza, riesgo y cumplimiento de TI del CERN" class="wp-image-4081255" height="263" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Stefan-Luders-CISO-del-CERN-y-Tim-Bell-lider-de-la-seccion-de-gobernanza-riesgo-y-cumplimiento-de-TI-del-CERN.png" width="554" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stefan Lüders and Tim Bell of CERN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;CERN&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Employing proprietary technology can introduce risks, according to Tim Bell, leader of CERN’s IT governance, risk and compliance section, who is responsible for business continuity and disaster recovery. “If you’re a visitor to a university, you’ll want to bring your laptop and use it at CERN. We can’t afford to remove these electronic devices upon arrival at the facility. It would be incompatible with the nature of the organization. The implication is that we must be able to implement BYOD-type security measures.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because at the core of everything always remains the collaborative nature of CERN. “Academic papers, open science, freedom of research, are part of our core&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Cybersecurity needs to adapt to this,” Lüders notes. “We have 200,000 devices on our network that are BYOD.” How then does the adaptation of cyber protection apply? “It’s called defense in depth,” explains the CISO. “We can’t install anything on these end devices because they don’t belong to us, (…) but we have network monitoring.” In this way, even if you don’t have direct access to each device, you are warned when something is being done against the center’s policies, both at the level of cybersecurity and inappropriate uses, such as employing the technology they provide for particular interests.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These measures also extend to obsolete systems, which the organization is able to assimilate because they have a network resilient enough that even if one piece of equipment is compromised, it won’t damage any other CERN systems. The legacy technology problem extends to the equipment needed for the physics experiments being performed at the center. “These are protected by dedicated networks, which allows the network protection to kick in and protect them against any kind of abuse,” Lüders explains. On IoT connected devices not designed with cybersecurity in mind, “a problem for all industries,” Lüders is blunt: “You will never get security in IoT devices.” His solution is to connect them to restricted network segments where they are not allowed to communicate with anything else, and then define destinations to which they can communicate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="general-framework"&gt;General framework&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is part of a larger challenge: aligning the IT and OT sides so that security continuity is established throughout the organization. A challenge that goes through centralization. “Today the OT part, the controls systems at CERN, are using IT virtualization,” explains Lüders. “The strategy is to bring IT and control people together so that the control people can use the IT services to their advantage. From the technology department, a central system is provided with different functionalities for operations, as well as for other areas of the organization, accessible through a single point of entry. “That’s the power of centralization.” This system also includes new tools such as AI tools in LLM, where they have a working group in place to find the best way to employ them. “We are facing a big discovery and, later on, we will centralize it through a central IT service. And that’s how we do it with all technologies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just as the subjects they research at CERN are evolving, so is their IT governance framework. This has been keeping up with industry developments, Bell explains, hand in hand with audits that allow it to operate according to best practice. “The governance part is becoming more formal. In general, everything was well organized; it was just a matter of standardizing it and developing policy frameworks around it.” Despite the establishment of these standards, the result is the opposite of rigid, explains Bell, who exemplifies this with the case of a recent cybersecurity audit in which CERN was assessed against one of the international standards, which served to improve the level of maturity. “We are adopting a fairly flexible IT governance policy, learning from the experience of others in adopting industry standards.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109133/cern-how-does-an-international-research-institution-manage-risk.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–854)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-854</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-854</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-855)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-855</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-855</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-856)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-856</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-856</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV25-857)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av25-857</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av25-857</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-020 – Vulnerability Impacting WatchGuard Fireware OS - CVE-2025-14733</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-020-vulnerability-impacting-watchguard-fireware-os-cve-2025-14733</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-020-vulnerability-impacting-watchguard-fireware-os-cve-2025-14733</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-858)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-858</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-858</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-859)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-859</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-859</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-860)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-860</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-860</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV25-861)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-861</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-861</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB security advisory (AV25-862)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mongodb-security-advisory-av25-862</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mongodb-security-advisory-av25-862</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
