<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 03:51:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-033)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-033</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-033</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-034)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-034</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-034</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-035)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-035</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-035</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–036)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-036</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-036</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-037)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-037</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-037</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-038)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-038</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-038</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-039)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-039</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-039</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-040)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-040</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-040</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISO’s predictions for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116527/cisos-predictions-for-2026.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4102893/cybersecurity-leaders-top-seven-takeaways-from-2025.html"&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt; was defined by AI hype, new attack models, and intensifying global tensions. As 2026 begins, security teams are asking what the next phase will look like. Will AI continue to accelerate risk, or will controls and governance finally catch up?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSO spoke to 10 security leaders about their predictions and aspirations for 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="governance-scrambles-to-keep-pace-with-ai"&gt;Governance scrambles to keep pace with AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As AI becomes deeply embedded in day-to-day business operations, security leaders are being pushed to scale governance models far faster than before. For &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/barry-hensley/"&gt;Barry Hensley&lt;/a&gt;, CSO at Brown &amp;amp; Brown, this translates to strengthening data guardrails by expanding data loss protection and monitoring, tightening identity controls, and introducing governance across both human and machine identities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That push towards structure and oversight is also reshaping how organizations define security at scale. As United Airlines CISO &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/deneendefiore/"&gt;Deneen DeFiore&lt;/a&gt; puts it, 2026 security will be less about perimeter defense and more about operational resilience at scale. “Threat actors will increasingly use generative AI to automate reconnaissance, social engineering, and exploit chaining, while defenders will rely on AI to prioritize risk, accelerate detection, and reduce response times,” she says. “The differentiator won’t be whether organizations use AI, but how well they govern, tune, and trust it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Repurpose It CISO &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/noeltoal/"&gt;Noel Toal&lt;/a&gt; predicts that AI risk frameworks will increasingly reach board level. He believes these frameworks will give directors the structure and confidence to ask harder questions about AI exposure, triggering audits and help unlock long-needed security funding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;DeFiore also expects governance conversations to shift beyond traditional risk management and towards continuous cyber resilience. “Boards and regulators are already asking not just, ‘Can you prevent an attack?’ but “Can you continue operating when one happens?’” She believes that changes will drive deeper investment in identity security, segmentation, recovery testing, and third-party resilience rather than point solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-agents-to-reshape-the-threat-landscape"&gt;AI agents to reshape the threat landscape&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But those same AI technologies are also changing the threat landscape. Toal points to a recent &lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/disrupting-AI-espionage"&gt;Anthropic report&lt;/a&gt; that documented the first large-scale AI-enabled cyberattack as an early warning sign. “I guarantee attackers will be more focused on using AI agents for what they want than a lot of businesses, because businesses in general are still very slow to adopt AI agents.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In response, Toal says organizations will need to secure their &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt;AI agents with the same rigor applied to human users. “We’ll have to treat internal AI agents as identities, and monitor what they access, when they run, and whether their behavior makes sense,” he says. Without that shift, he cautions, organizations risk unleashing tools inside their networks that attackers could readily turn against them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Challenger CISO &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/katie-payten-gaicd-20bbb5/"&gt;Katie Payten&lt;/a&gt; agrees the rise of agentic AI fundamentally expands the identity attack surface. “The perimeter isn’t just the external perimeter anymore; identity is the perimeter.” She adds that as organizations deploy AI agents internally, governance must extend beyond human users. “Knowing what your agent has access to, how it’s making decisions, and taking responsibility for that will be essential.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As AI becomes more deeply integrated, the sensitive data these systems rely on will become “an increasingly attractive target”, with more &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4075912/ai-enabled-ransomware-attacks-cisos-top-security-concern-with-good-reason.html"&gt;AI-enabled attack methods&lt;/a&gt; “poised to occupy a growing share of the threat landscape,” according to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelagarvin/"&gt;Michael Garvin&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at Jaggaer. As a result, he believes data security posture management will also become more important. “Because AI depends on large volumes of high-quality, sensitive data, organizations will need better visibility into how that data is accessed, classified, and protected.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gergana-winzer-0939937/"&gt;Gergana Winzer&lt;/a&gt;, partner and cyber security mid-market lead at KPMG, the real threat with AI is not just scale, but autonomy. She warns that AI-driven attacks will increasingly make their own target and execution decisions, reducing the need for human involvement. “Everything can be automated today, not only on the side of companies, but also on the side of the criminals,” she says, raising questions about how AI-enabled threats could extend beyond the digital realm into the physical world through AI-powered drones, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security teams will consolidate visibility and automate response&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When asked about what else 2026 could mean for the global security industry, Ramsay Healthcare CISO &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/manal-alsharif/"&gt;Manal Al-Sharif&lt;/a&gt; believes AI will play a crucial role in helping consolidate telemetry into a single view. “When you bring everything in, it’s easy to triage and prioritize,” she says. “Having that single point of view means you’re correlating everything at the same time, so you know where you’re exposed most … [and] before those threats become incidents.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Garvin expects security strategies to evolve inside SOCs as AI becomes more embedded. “The biggest shift will be the deeper integration of AI into defensive security operations. Organizations will increasingly invest in securing AI models and data pipelines, and they will evolve penetration testing and adversarial testing approaches to evaluate AI systems with the same rigor applied to traditional applications.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nadiavp/"&gt;Nadia Veeran-Patel&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at LRMG, &lt;strong&gt;has already seen this reshape incident workflows firsthand.&lt;/strong&gt; “Our analysts were looking at incidents individually as they came through as alerts, but when AI brought them together as a collection, you suddenly realize those alerts are actually a series of events that led to something bigger.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;DeFiore also expects a fundamental shift in how security teams operate day to day. In 2026, she wants teams spending less time reacting to alerts and more time on anticipation and enablement, by using automation, better data, and tighter integration with IT and business partners to reduce friction and accelerate decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She adds what’s equally important is continued investment in people and culture. “Technology evolves quickly, but resilient organizations are built by teams that are well-trained, empowered, and aligned to a shared mission,” she says. “Creating clarity around risk ownership and decision-making is just as critical as any tool we deploy. Ultimately, success looks like a security program that enables innovation, withstands disruption, and earns trust at every level of the organization, from the boardroom to the front line.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Toal expects AI-driven orchestration to become a defining feature of modern SOCs in 2026, as AI increasingly isolates compromised endpoints, blocks malicious IPs, rolls back ransomware in real time, and maps an attacker’s path. “The mean time to response would be vastly reduced. Instead of taking hours to respond to an incident, you could start to respond hopefully within seconds … [and] engage properly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="smes-will-become-prime-targets-amid-rising-automation"&gt;SMEs will become prime targets amid rising automation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Winzer adds 2026 will mark a decisive shift, with SMEs becoming primary targets for ransomware. According to the &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/Tea/reports/2025-dbir-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf"&gt;2025 Verizon data breach report&lt;/a&gt;, ransomware made up 44% of all breaches globally, and SMEs represented a disproportionate percentage of victims.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Why? Because they’re easy now … the rationale is they have limited security maturity and they cannot absorb outages, so they end up paying [the ransomware], even though the government is saying, ‘Don’t pay’. But it’s really difficult for them to negotiate because they don’t have the budget to put proper recovery plans in place.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Winzer warns that AI-driven reconnaissance is accelerating this trend. “AI today is very capable. You can press a button and very quickly do a huge amount of damage within a few seconds.” Combined with gaps in mid-market MSSP coverage, which are “not necessarily as complete”, she says that makes it very easy for the attackers to go after SMEs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veeran-Patel has seen a similar escalation in criminal tactics. “We have seen attackers routinely employing what we call triple extortion, where they combine not only data encryption, data leaking/extortion, and also leveraging third parties, like customers, regulators, and vendors, to put pressure on their victims to pay the ransoms.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even so, Winzer is cautiously optimistic that vendors will begin delivering more tailored solutions to the mid-market. “They did not do before. Now they’re realizing this is a huge target, and it’s also an opportunity to provide services.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="supply-chains-remain-vulnerable-as-nation-state-activity-intensifies"&gt;Supply chains remain vulnerable as nation-state activity intensifies&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Winzer sees critical infrastructure as a primary cyber battlefield. Operational environments are “far more reachable,” she says, due to IT/OT convergence, cloud-connected control systems, and remote-access pathways that remain exposed even when partial segmentation exists.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Payten warns that data risk is increasingly hidden within complex supply chains, as organizations rely on expanding ecosystems of third-party and SaaS providers. That reliance, she says, quietly compounds exposure. “We’re using so many third parties, and those third parties use their own third parties; they become fourth parties,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The challenge is not just assessing vendors at the point of engagement but maintaining visibility over where sensitive data ultimately resides. “You can’t outsource your accountability,” Payten says. “You still own the data.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Healthcare and local councils remain high-risk targets as well, driven by low cyber budgets, sensitive population data and the high cost of downtime, Winzer adds. “Before [attackers] were going after the cash only. But now they’re looking at reputational damage, because that causes organizations to pay faster.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veeran-Patel expects nation-state pressure to intensify too, warning that geopolitical conflict is increasingly being played out in cyberspace. “Cyber warfare is a real thing,” she says. “Wars are no longer going to be fought on the front lines with soldiers on the ground. They are likely going to be fought with buttons.” Her concern is that many governments are still not treating the risk with the level of urgency it requires, despite signs of critical infrastructure in developing nations already being taken offline by hostile actors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="vendors-must-deliver-secure-by-design-products"&gt;Vendors must deliver secure-by-design products&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Al-Sharif believes 2026 will be the year when the industry confronts a long-ignored truth that non-malicious insiders are not the main problem. “My issue is with the technology makers,” she says. “They still give me a car with no brake, no lock, no seatbelts. They sell it to me and find a way for me to sign away my rights … my issue is that technology makers need to be held accountable for creating flawed technology.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She predicts insecure defaults will become untenable as incidents continue to trace back to weak authentication and outdated access controls. She says the problem is especially visible in healthcare, where connected devices still arrive with default passwords and cannot be patched without voiding warranties. “I want the government to make sure there’s a way to measure how secure those devices are before I connect a life support machine to them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Payten echoes concerns about insecure defaults and poorly secured connected devices. From routers to smart appliances, she highlights default credentials and weak configurations remain widespread. “There are still people with default passwords on their routers … and now there are so many connected devices.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="now-is-the-time-to-prepare-for-post-quantum-cryptography"&gt;Now is the time to prepare for post-quantum cryptography&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zoe-hearn-68478624/"&gt;Zoe Hearn&lt;/a&gt;, head of cybersecurity strategy and governance at Insignia Financial, says rising expectations from customers, regulators, and governments are pushing organizations to take a more proactive role in preparing for the post-quantum era. She points out how simply complying with emerging standards will not be enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With quantum-vulnerable encryption set to be phased out by 2030, now is the time to invest in future-ready security infrastructure,” she says. For Hearn, the shift demands leadership, not just technical uplift, as quantum risk increasingly becomes a board-level conversation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothyyoungblood/"&gt;Timothy Youngblood&lt;/a&gt;, CISO in residence at Astrix Security and former CISO at McDonald’s and T-Mobile, shares the same concern. He expects progressive enterprises to begin mapping their quantum security in preparation of the mainstream arrival of the technology. “The more progressive enterprises are going to start to assess their quantum security gaps, who are the partners that they need to address that,” he says. “It has the potential to be another Y2K. It’s a slow-moving Y2K. Of course, people are going to be caught off guard whenever quantum becomes mainstream, and that’s coming. It’s time to assess what the strategies are.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Toal believes boards will soon pay closer attention to quantum risk as well. He notes that attackers are already harvesting encrypted data today in anticipation of future decryption. “It might still be slightly behind AI recognition, but I think boards are going to realize they have a longer-term problem,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auditors, he predicts, will begin raising quantum preparedness in security reviews, forcing it onto roadmaps. “If they’re not addressing the fact that a minor breach today could become a major problem in the near future, that’s a gap boards will need to reckon with.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116527/cisos-predictions-for-2026.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV26-041)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-041</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-041</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft handed over BitLocker keys to law enforcement, raising enterprise data control concerns</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122151/microsoft-handed-over-bitlocker-keys-to-law-enforcement-raising-enterprise-data-control-concerns-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft gave Windows users’ BitLocker encryption keys for to US law enforcement officers, providing access to encrypted data, according to a news report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US Federal Bureau of Investigation approached Microsoft with a search warrant in early 2025, seeking keys to unlock encrypted data stored on three laptops in a case of alleged fraud involving the COVID unemployment assistance program in Guam. As the keys were stored on a Microsoft server, Microsoft adhered to the legal order and &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2026/01/22/microsoft-gave-fbi-keys-to-unlock-bitlocker-encrypted-data/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;handed over the encryption keys&lt;/a&gt;, Forbes reported on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There have been instances in the past where the big tech companies were approached by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3812874/how-law-enforcement-agents-gain-access-to-encrypted-devices.html"&gt;law enforcement&lt;/a&gt; for access to devices but have &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/554969/apple-vs-the-fbi-the-legal-arguments-in-a-nutshell.html"&gt;resisted&lt;/a&gt; handing encryption keys to authorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;BitLocker is a widely used tool for securing data at rest, whether by individuals or enterprises managing hundreds or thousands of Windows devices. By default, many Windows installations back up BitLocker recovery keys to Microsoft’s cloud services, where Microsoft can retrieve them if legally compelled with a valid order.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="custody-issue-not-bitlocker"&gt;Custody issue, not BitLocker&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;BitLocker is designed to provide encryption for entire volumes, addressing the threats of data theft or exposure from lost, stolen, or inappropriately decommissioned devices. As BitLocker is bunded with Windows 10 and Windows 11, it has effectively become the default full-disk encryption layer across Windows endpoints, say experts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“BitLocker itself does not fail here. The software does what it is built to do, encrypts the disk, integrates into Windows, allows for easy recovery,” said Sanchit Vir Gogia, chief analyst at Greyhound Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the encryption of BitLocker is robust, enterprises need to be mindful of who has custody of the keys, as this case illustrates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The encryption engine in BitLocker, using AES-128 or AES-256 in XTS mode, is built to resist modern cryptanalysis. Even the US Department of Homeland Security has admitted they lack the forensic tooling to break it directly. However, most enterprise fleets running Windows use tools like Intune and Autopilot to roll out and manage devices. In that flow, unless explicitly disabled, recovery keys are automatically backed up to Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4060101/entra-id-vulnerability-exposes-gaps-in-cloud-identity-trust-models-experts-warn.html"&gt;Entra ID.&lt;/a&gt; These keys are then viewable via the admin centre or retrievable through scripts,” Gogia said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="where-most-enterprises-go-wrong"&gt;Where most enterprises go wrong&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises using BitLocker should treat the recovery keys as highly sensitive, and avoid default cloud backup unless there is a clear business requirement and the associated risks are well understood and mitigated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The safest configuration is to redirect those keys to on-premises Active Directory or a controlled enterprise key vault. Even if stored in corporate-controlled directory or service such as Microsoft Entra ID or Intune, there should be strong governance on who can read the keys, with effective logging and just-in-time access, said Amit Jaju, a global partner at Ankura Consulting. This can cut Microsoft out of the recovery loop, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If keys have to reside in Microsoft’s cloud, use strong multi-factor authentication for admin roles, with conditional access and privileged-access workstations so a compromise of admin credentials does not automatically become a compromise of all keys, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises should ensure strict access control and separation of duties. “Only a small, vetted group such as security operations, endpoint engineering, should have rights to view or export recovery keys. Approvals should be workflow-based, not ad hoc. Every key retrieval should leave an auditable, immutable trail, and ideally be tied to an incident or ticket ID,” said Jaju.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should also ensure that when devices are repurposed, decommissioned, or moved across jurisdictions, keys should be regenerated as part of the workflow to ensure old keys cannot be used.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia warned of the long tail of insecure setups. Personal accounts linked during provisioning, or BYOD devices that silently sync keys to consumer dashboards, are invisible pathways for leakage. “If those keys sit outside your boundary, you no longer have a clean chain of custody. That’s not a theoretical risk. It’s something auditors are now actively checking,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As many breaches are not cryptographic but procedural, enterprises should have a formal playbook for when a recovery key can be used (lost PIN, internal investigation with legal approval, lawful order) and when it cannot (informal manager request to access an employee’s data), noted Jaju.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="geopolitics-reshaping-enterprise-data-and-key-control"&gt;Geopolitics reshaping enterprise data and key control&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geopolitical tensions are also reshaping global trade and technology policies, something enterprises increasingly need to factor into their security strategies. As governments assert greater control over data, trade secrets and proprietary information risk becoming entangled in broader state interests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia warned, “The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/568021/what-you-need-to-know-about-the-us-cloud-act-and-the-uk-copoa-act.html"&gt;US CLOUD Act&lt;/a&gt; allows law enforcement to compel US-based providers to hand over data and keys, even if that data is hosted in Europe or Asia. Similarly, Chinese data localisation rules require keys and data to be accessible to state regulators. In India, recent legislation has introduced broad access rights for security agencies. And the EU is debating whether sovereignty must include key custody by design, not just data residency.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If recovery keys are stored with a cloud provider, that provider may be compelled, at least in its home jurisdiction, to hand them over under lawful order, even if the data subject or company is elsewhere without notifying the company. This becomes even more critical from the point of view of a pharma company, semiconductor firm, defence contractor, or critical-infrastructure operator, as it exposes them to risks such as exposure of trade secrets in cross‑border investigations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaju added, “Enterprises should assume that where keys are held, they can potentially be compelled. So where practical, ensure that the entities controlling keys are legally anchored in the jurisdiction whose laws and due-process standards you trust most. Establish board-level oversight on cross-border data access, including a register of government data-access requests, where legally permitted. For multinational companies, legal and security teams must work together to understand mutual legal-assistance treaties, CLOUD Act implications, and local interception laws.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This article first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4122149/microsoft-handed-over-bitlocker-keys-to-law-enforcement-raising-enterprise-data-control-concerns.html"&gt;Computerworld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122151/microsoft-handed-over-bitlocker-keys-to-law-enforcement-raising-enterprise-data-control-concerns-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-043)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-043</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-043</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-044)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV26-045)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-046)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-048)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixes released for a serious Microsoft Office zero-day flaw</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123146/fixes-released-for-a-serious-microsoft-office-zero-day-flaw-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is warning admins of an Office security bypass zero day vulnerability that can be triggered simply by a user opening a document. The flaw is currently being actively exploited.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The vulnerability is serious,” said &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute. “The root cause is that Microsoft Office still supports the older OLE document format, which provides access to various OLE components. The effect is similar to what an attacker could do with Office Macros. But Office Macros are typically blocked for documents downloaded from the internet. Microsoft implemented similar protections for OLE components, but this recent exploit found a way to bypass them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite efforts by Microsoft and email gateway vendors, emails with malicious attachments are still a significant attack vector, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is important that organizations roll up this update quickly. Until it has been applied, filters on email gateways or endpoint protection signatures may help mitigate the threat.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fortunately the vulnerability, &lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2026-21509" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21509&lt;/a&gt;, which has a CVSS score of 7.8, is fixed automatically in Office 2021 and up, however, admins should note that these applications need a restart for the patch to take effect. For Office 2016 and Office 2019, &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/description-of-the-security-update-for-office-2016-january-26-2026-kb5002713-32ec881d-a3b5-470c-b9a5-513cc46bc77e" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;there’s a separate patch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bicer" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jack Bicer&lt;/a&gt;, director of vulnerability research at Action1, said that for security teams and CISOs “the urgency is real: don’t wait, prioritize this update immediately, and ensure all Office applications are restarted so the protections take effect without delay.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The flaw is exploited by sending malicious Office documents and convincing users to open them, “a classic technique that emphasizes the ongoing effectiveness of social engineering in real-world attacks,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has added the hole to its &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2026/01/26/cisa-adds-five-known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;catalogue of known exploited vulnerabilities.&lt;/a&gt; Vulnerabilities in the catalogue must be remediated by federal civilian executive branch agencies by a specified date.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked for comment, a Microsoft spokesperson said the company recommends impacted customers follow the guidance on its &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21509" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE page&lt;/a&gt;. It also points out that Microsoft Defender has detections in place to block exploitation, and Office’s default &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/what-is-protected-view-d6f09ac7-e6b9-4495-8e43-2bbcdbcb6653" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Protected View&lt;/a&gt; setting provides an extra layer of protection by blocking malicious files from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As a security best practice, we encourage users to exercise caution when downloading and enabling editing on files from unknown sources, as indicated in security warnings,” the spokesperson added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4123102/fixes-released-for-a-serious-microsoft-office-zero-day-flaw.html" target="_blank"&gt;Computerworld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123146/fixes-released-for-a-serious-microsoft-office-zero-day-flaw-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 23:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-002 -Vulnerability affecting GNU Inetutils Telnetd - CVE-2026-24061</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV26-049)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unplugged holes in the npm and yarn package managers could let attackers bypass defenses against Shai-Hulud</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122436/unplugged-holes-in-the-npm-and-yarn-package-managers-could-let-attackers-bypass-defenses-against-shai-hulud-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Javascript developers should consider moving away from the npm and yarn platforms for distributing their work because newly-found holes allow threat actors to run malicious worm attacks like Shai-Hulud, says an Israeli researcher.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The warning comes from &lt;a href="https://il.linkedin.com/in/orenyomtov" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oren Yomtov&lt;/a&gt; of Koi Security, &lt;a href="https://www.koi.ai/blog/packagegate-6-zero-days-in-js-package-managers-but-npm-wont-act" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;who blogged Monday of discovering&lt;/a&gt; six zero day vulnerabilities in several package managers that could allow hackers bypass defenses that had been recommended last November after Shai-Hulud roamed through npm and compromised over 700 packages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those defenses are:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disabling the ability to run lifecycle scripts, commands that run automatically during package installation,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;saving lockfile integrity checks (package-lock.json, pnpm-lock.yaml, and others) to version control (git). The lockfile records the exact version and integrity hash of every package in a dependency tree. On subsequent installs, the package manager checks incoming packages against these hashes, and if something doesn’t match, installation fails. If an attacker compromises a package and pushes a malicious version, the integrity check should catch the mismatch and block it from being installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those recommendations “became the standard advice everywhere from GitHub security guides to corporate policy docs” after November, says Yomtov, “because if malicious code can’t run on install, and your dependency tree is pinned, you’re covered.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="novembers-advice-still-valid-but-more-issues-need-addressing"&gt;November’s advice still valid, but more issues need addressing&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That advice is still valid, he added in an email interview.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the vulnerabilities he discovered — dubbed PackageGate — that allow hackers to get around those two defenses have to be addressed by all platforms, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So far, the pnpm, vlt, and Bun platforms have addressed the bypass holes, Yomtov said, but npm and yarn haven’t. He therefore recommends that JavaScript developers use pnpm, vlt or Bun.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He added that, in any case, JavaScript developers should keep whatever JavaScript package manager they use up to date to ensure they have the latest patches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="github-statement-bewildering"&gt;GitHub statement ‘bewildering’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, which owns and oversees npm through GitHub, referred questions about the vulnerabilities to GitHub. It said in a statement, “We are actively working to address the new issue reported as npm actively scans for malware in the registry.” In the meantime, it urges project developers to adopt &lt;a href="https://github.blog/security/supply-chain-security/strengthening-supply-chain-security-preparing-for-the-next-malware-campaign/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the recommendations in this blog&lt;/a&gt; issued after the Shai-Hulud attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The statement also notes that, last September, &lt;a href="https://github.blog/security/supply-chain-security/our-plan-for-a-more-secure-npm-supply-chain/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub said it is strengthening npm’s security&lt;/a&gt;, including making changes to authentication and token management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GitHub also warns that that, if a package being installed through git contains a prepare script, its dependencies and devDependencies will be installed. “As we shared when the ticket was filed, this is an intentional design and works as expected. When users install a git dependency, they are trusting the entire contents of that repository, including its configuration files.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yomtov found this explanation of intentional design “bewildering.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="not-the-complete-picture"&gt;Not the complete picture&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He says the scripts bypass vulnerability was reported through the HackerOne bug bounty program on November 26, 2025. While other JavaScript package managers accepted the reports, npm said the platform was working as intended, and that the ‘ignore scripts’ command should prevent the running of unapproved remote code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We didn’t write this post to shame anyone,” Yomtov said in the blog. “We wrote it because the JavaScript ecosystem deserves better, and because security decisions should be based on accurate information, not assumptions about defenses that don’t hold up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The standard advice, disable scripts and commit your lockfiles, is still worth following. But it’s not the complete picture,” he said. “Until PackageGate is fully addressed, organizations need to make their own informed choices about risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4122299/unplugged-holes-in-the-npm-and-yarn-package-managers-could-let-attackers-bypass-defenses-against-shai-hulud.html" target="_blank"&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122436/unplugged-holes-in-the-npm-and-yarn-package-managers-could-let-attackers-bypass-defenses-against-shai-hulud-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 01:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNAPP-Kaufratgeber</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3970431/cnapp-kaufratgeber.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cloud Sec Specialist 16z9" class="wp-image-3970439" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2287651213_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Gorodenkoff | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud Security bleibt ein diffiziles Thema und die Tools, mit denen sie sich gewährleisten lässt, werden zunehmend komplexer und schwieriger zu durchschauen – auch dank der ungebrochenen Liebe der Branche zu &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3825034/4-wege-aus-der-security-akronymholle.html" target="_blank"&gt;Akronymen&lt;/a&gt;. Mit CNAPP kommt nun ein weiteres hinzu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="cnapp-definition"&gt;CNAPP – Definition&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Abkürzung steht für Cloud-Native Application Protection Platform – und kombiniert die Funktionen von vier separaten &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495515/7-fundamentale-cloud-bedrohungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cloud-Security&lt;/a&gt;-Werkzeugen:   &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Infrastructure Entitlement Management (CIEM), um sämtliche Zugriffskontrollmaßnahmen und Risikomanagement-Tasks zu managen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Cloud Workload Protection Platform (CWPP), um Code in allen cloudbasierten Repositories abzusichern sowie Laufzeitschutz für die gesamte Entwicklungsumgebung und alle Code-Pipelines zu gewährleisten.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494345/der-kaufratgeber-fur-cloud-access-security-broker.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cloud Access Security Broker&lt;/a&gt; (CASB) für Authentifizierungs- und Encryption-Aufgaben.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495818/cloud-risiken-verwalten-so-wahlen-sie-das-passende-cspm-tool-aus.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cloud Security Posture Management&lt;/a&gt; (CSPM), das Threat Intelligence und Abhilfemaßnahmen kombiniert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Über diese vier „klassischen“ Elemente hat sich CNAPP inzwischen auch auf andere Bereiche ausgeweitet. Zum Beispiel:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495478/api-security-die-10-besten-api-tools.html" target="_blank"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;-, Skript-, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495329/cybersecurity-in-der-lieferkettewie-sie-ihre-software-supply-chain-schutzen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Supply-Chain&lt;/a&gt;– sowie Infrastructure-as-Code (&lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/3853753/opentofu-der-killer-fork.html" target="_blank"&gt;IaC&lt;/a&gt;)-Sicherheit,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492006/kubernetes-security-wie-sie-ihre-cluster-besser-absichern.html"&gt;Container&lt;/a&gt;– und Serverless-Security, sowie&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;weitere Posture-Management-Tools, einschließlich Daten- und SaaS-Applikationen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aus Anwendersicht ist CNAPP damit sowohl schwer zu verstehen als auch diffizil zu evaluieren – und entsprechend schwer einzukaufen, wie Forrester-Chefanalyst Andras Cser in &lt;a href="https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-cnapp-product-category-is-getting-crowded-with-capabilities/?ref_search=3408672_1741785037249" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;einem Blogbeitrag zum Thema&lt;/a&gt; nahelegt. Weil teilweise auch Security-Optionen außerhalb der Cloud abgedeckt würden, sei jede CNAPP-Kaufentscheidung und -Implementierung auch eine Team- oder abteilungsübergreifende Aufgabe, so der Analyst.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anders ausgedrückt: Geht‘s um CNAPP, muss eine ganze Menge Software abgestimmt, gemanagt, integriert und verstanden werden. Um Ihnen den Überblick zu erleichtern, haben wir die Details zu den wichtigsten Anbietern und Angeboten in diesem Kaufratgeber zusammengetragen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="der-cnapp-markt"&gt;Der CNAPP-Markt&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geprägt hat die Produktkategorie – beziehungsweise das Akronym – einmal mehr Gartner. Das Analystenhaus verwendete den Begriff CNAPP erstmals in seinem &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4005115" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;„Innovation Insight“-Report&lt;/a&gt; aus dem August 2021.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Schlüssel zum Verständnis dieser Produktkategorie liegt in den Integrationsherausforderungen für Unternehmensanwender: Im „&lt;a href="https://tanzu.vmware.com/content/blog/state-of-observability-2022-modernization" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;State of Observability Report&lt;/a&gt;“ von VMware geben 57 Prozent der Befragten an, dass innerhalb einer typischen Cloud-Anwendung bis zu 50 verschiedene Technologien zum Einsatz kommen – die im Schnitt mit zehn Monitoring-Tools gemanagt werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Und laut dem „&lt;a href="https://www.dynatrace.com/info/reports/state-of-observability-2024/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Observability Report 2024&lt;/a&gt;“ (Download gegen Daten) von Dynatrace besteht eine typische Enterprise-Umgebung im Schnitt aus einem Dutzend unterschiedlichen Cloud-Plattformen, wobei regelmäßig ein Mix aus Private-, Public- und Hybrid-Cloud-Strategien zur Anwendung kommt. Hinzu kommen dann noch verschiedene Instanzen virtueller Maschinen, Kubernetes-Container sowie Serverless- und Microservices-Tools.   &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese erhebliche Integrationsbelastung könnte auch ein Grund dafür sein, dass der CNAPP-Markt im zweiten Quartal 2024 ein Gesamtvolumen von 700 Millionen Dollar erreicht hat und damit im Jahresvergleich um 42 Prozent gewachsen ist – wie die Analysten der Dell’Oro Group &lt;a href="https://www.delloro.com/news/cnapp-market-grows-42-percent-in-2q-2024-as-cloud-security-remains-a-top-concern/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;berichten&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="cnapp-anbieter-und-ihre-angebote"&gt;CNAPP-Anbieter und ihre Angebote&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Idealfall sollte eine CNAPP-Lösung:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fehlkonfigurationen reduzieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;das Security-Niveau der Entwicklungspipeline optimieren, sowie&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;effektiv automatisieren.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Anbieter verfolgen mit Blick auf CNAPP zwei unterschiedliche Ansätze: Entweder sie fokussieren die &lt;strong&gt;DevSecOps&lt;/strong&gt;– oder die &lt;strong&gt;traditionelle IT-Security-Perspektive&lt;/strong&gt;. Ersteres hat einen stärkeren Fokus auf den Schutz der Applikationen selbst zur Folge (CIEM/CWPP), letzteres eine Ausweitung traditioneller Schutzmaßnahmen auf Netzwerkebene (CASB/CSPM). Bislang deckt kein CNAPP-Offering wirklich konsequent alle vier Bereiche ab.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Natürlich spielt künstliche Intelligenz (KI) auch in diesem Bereich zunehmend eine Rolle: Diverse CNAPP-Anbieter integrieren, beziehungsweise kombinieren KI-Agenten und agentenlose Lösungen in ihren Produkten, um ein umfassenderes Monitoring und eine möglichst breite Abdeckung und Scalability zu bieten. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.aquasec.com/de/demo/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aqua Security Platform&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;DevSecOps&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform mit verschiedenen Produkten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;„(No-)&lt;a href="https://www.aquasec.com/warranty-agreement/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Breach-Garantie&lt;/a&gt;“ bis zu einer Million Dollar;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: kostenlose Trial-Version; ab 850 Dollar pro Monat;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdstrike.de/platform/cloud-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CrowdStrike Falcon Cloud Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: DevSecOps / IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform mit verschiedenen Produkten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: Cloud Detection and Response&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;CDR), AppSec, Schwachstellenanalyse für Container-Images;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: Abonnement-Preis richtet sich nach den gewählten Produkten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.datatheorem.com/solutions/cnapp/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Theorem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: DevSecOps&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Separate Produkte für Cloud, Web und Supply Chain;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: Headliner Attack Policies, Artifact Scanning, zentrale Analyse-Engine, Kubernetes-Support;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: komplex und teuer; unterschiedliche Tarife für jedes Produkt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fortinet.com/de/products/forticnapp" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lacework FortiCNAPP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform mit verschiedenen Produkten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: Verhaltensbasierte Schutzregeln, SOAR, AppSec, Scans für Build- und Deployment-Pipelines;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: kostenlose Probeversion; richtet sich nach der Nutzungsdauer sowie den in Anspruch genommenen vCPUs;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://orca.security/platform/cnapp-cloud-security-platform/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orca CNAPP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform mit verschiedenen Produkten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: Side Scanning, Risikopriorisierung, AppSec-Pipelines, KI-Features;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: orientiert sich an Workloads, Storage Buckets und Datenbank-Scans sowie den eingesetzten Sensoren;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.de/cortex/cloud" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palo Alto Networks Cortex Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform mit verschiedenen Produkten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: CDR, AppSec-Integration, Laufzeitschutz und DSPM, Support für IBM und Akamai Clouds geplant;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: komplex und teuer; richtet sich nach den gewählten Modulen und abgesicherten Workloads;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qualys.com/apps/totalcloud/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualys Total Cloud CNAPP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: CDR, Container und IaC-Security, SaaS Posture Management, KI-Funktionen;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: kostenlose Probeversion; Abo-Modell auf Workload-Basis;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://de.sysdig.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sysdig Secure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: DevSecOps&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einzelprodukt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: „Next Generation“ CDR, Risikopriorisierung, KI-Funktionen und-Analysen;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: Festpreis pro Host Model; ab circa 500 Dollar pro Monat;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://de.tenable.com/cloud-security" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenable Cloud Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Standalone-Lösung oder als Bestandteil der Exposure-Management-Plattform Tenable One;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: Exposure Management, DSPM, KI Security, Kubernetes- und IaC-Support;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: kostenlose Probeversion; komplexes Preismodell, das sich an Nodes oder Workloads ausrichten lässt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tigera.io/tigera-products/multi-cloud-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tigera Calico Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: DevSecOps&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einzelprodukt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: fokussiert in erster Linie auf Container- und Kubernetes-Security;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: kostenlose Open-Source-Version; kommerzielle Optionen mit Abo-Abrechnungsmodell oder pro Node-Stunde;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.uptycs.com/products/cnapp" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uptycs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: XDR, AppSec, DSPM, KI- und ML-Funktionen;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: diverse Optionen; ab circa 5.000 Dollar pro Jahr (200 Cloud Assets);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/de-de/platform" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wiz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fokus: IT-Security&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Form: Einheitliche Plattform mit verschiedenen Produkten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besondere Features/Integrationen: Risikopriorisierung mit Graph-basierten &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2803932/was-ist-datenvisualisierung.html" target="_blank"&gt;Visualisierungen&lt;/a&gt; und Analysen von Code zu Cloud zu Runtime, KI-Funktionen, Container- und Kubernetes-Support;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preisgefüge: verschiedene Preispläne, die sich nach den Workloads richten;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-fragen-vor-dem-cnapp-investment"&gt;5 Fragen vor dem CNAPP-Investment&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bevor Sie sich für einen dieser CNAPP-Anbieter entscheiden, sollten Sie sich folgende Fragen stellen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welche Cloud-Artefakte lassen sich mit der gewählten Lösung scannen?&lt;/strong&gt; Einige Produkte (Lacework) fokussieren auf die drei großen IaaS-Anbieter, andere (Tigera) unterstützen nur die Kubernetes-Dienste der Hyperscaler. Wieder andere (Sysdig) nehmen vor allem Container und die verschiedenen Linux-Server, auf denen diese laufen, in den Fokus. Vor allem kommt es jedoch darauf an, die Artefakte kontinuierlich und (nahezu) in Echtzeit überwachen zu können.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wie werden Sicherheitsvorfälle gemeldet?&lt;/strong&gt; Gibt es separate Zugriffsregeln, damit sich verschiedene Mitarbeiter auf bestimmte Bereiche konzentrieren können? Gibt es separate oder kombinierte, vordefinierte Sicherheitsrichtlinien, um Daten mit und ohne Agenten zu erfassen? Wie aussagekräftig sind die Dashboards und die Visualisierungen, die diese liefern?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inwieweit werden die vier Management-Tool-Bereiche abgedeckt&lt;/strong&gt;? Einige Angebote bieten CWPP- und CSPM-Elemente, müssen aber, etwa für Kubernetes-Support, erweitert werden.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welche DevOps-Frameworks werden unterstützt? &lt;/strong&gt;Wie sieht es mit Blick auf Open-Source-&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492659/datenlecks-finden-so-verhindern-sie-repository-leaks.html" target="_blank"&gt;Repositories&lt;/a&gt; aus?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wie viel kostet die Lösung konkret? &lt;/strong&gt;Nur wenige CNAPP-Anbieter bieten eine wirklich transparente Preisgestaltung. Insbesondere bei komplexen Preismodellen (Data Theorem, Qualys, Orca) besteht deshalb Klärungsbedarf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3970431/cnapp-kaufratgeber.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 issues holding back CISOs’ security agendas</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117010/4-issues-holding-back-cisos-security-agendas.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many security leaders believe a cyberbreach is inevitable, with the timing being the only uncertainty. It’s a belief encapsulated in the common refrain that a breach is “not if, but when.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But a growing number of CISOs now expect an incident sooner than later: Some 76% said they feel at risk of experiencing a material cyberattack in the next 12 months, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/us/newsroom/press-releases/proofpoint-2025-voice-ciso-report"&gt;Voice of the CISO Report&lt;/a&gt; released by security tech company Proofpoint in August 2025. That’s up from 70% the prior year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report also found that 58% of CISOs believe their organization is unprepared to respond.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Besides the overall feeling of near inevitability of attack, security chiefs acknowledge that various challenges keep them from boosting their overall security posture and feeling more confident in their ability to block or respond to attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here, security leaders share four issues that hold back the enterprise security agenda.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-failure-to-train-and-empower-team-members-to-act-on-priorities"&gt;1. Failure to train and empower team members to act on priorities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs readily admit their security teams have more work to do than can be done. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4112130/stress-caused-by-cybersecurity-threats-is-taking-its-toll.html"&gt;That leads to a lot of stress&lt;/a&gt;: Some 80% of CISOs report being under high or extreme pressure today, according to the &lt;a href="https://nagomisecurity.com/ciso-pressure-index"&gt;2025 CISO Pressure Index&lt;/a&gt; from tech maker Nagomi Security, and 87% said that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3851735/cisos-are-taking-on-ever-more-responsibilities-and-functional-roles-has-it-gone-too-far.html"&gt;pressure has increased over the past 12 months&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, 67% report being burned out weekly or daily.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Every CISO feels very overwhelmed,” says &lt;a href="https://www.databricks.com/dataaisummit/speaker/omar-khawaja"&gt;Omar Khawaja&lt;/a&gt;, who leads Databricks’ field security practice, teaches at Carnegie Mellon University’s CISO program, and sits on the boards of HITRUST and FAIR Institute.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To cope, CISOs have become skilled at prioritizing, with tasks that reduce the most significant risks to the organization &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114020/cisos-top-10-cybersecurity-priorities-for-2026.html"&gt;topping their lists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Too often, however, CISOs don’t train their team members so they can competently make decisions and take actions that align with those priorities, says Khawaja, a former CISO at Highmark Health.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That keeps executives making all the priority calls, which ties them up and slows the whole team down.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should aim to have team members know when and how to make prioritization calls for their own areas of work, “so that every single team is focusing on the most important stuff,” Khawaja says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To do that, you need to create clear mechanisms and instructions for how you do decision-support,” he explains. “There should be criteria or factors that says it’s high, medium, low priority for anything delivered by the security team, because then any team member can look at any request that comes to them and they can confidently and effectively prioritize it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;2. Inability to keep pace with AI innovation and adoption&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Executives and employees alike have been rushing to adopt artificial intelligence, enticed by expectations that AI will transform workflows and save time, money, and effort.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But CISOs for the most part have not kept pace with their business colleagues’ rate of AI adoption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a survey of 921 IT and cybersecurity professionals conducted for Cyera’s &lt;a href="https://www.cyera.com/research-labs/2025-state-of-ai-data-security-report"&gt;2025 State of AI Data Security Report&lt;/a&gt;, 83% of organizations use AI but only 13% have strong visibility into how those systems access or handle sensitive data; only 16% treat AI as a distinct identity; only 11% of organizations can automatically block risky AI activity; and only 7% have a dedicated AI governance team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most CISOs are wrestling with how to secure AI,” says &lt;a href="file:///C:/Users/Owner/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/V6WVSWFS/Rob%20T.%20Lee"&gt;Robert T. Lee&lt;/a&gt;, chief AI officer and chief of research at SANS, a security training and certification firm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Lee, a good number of CISOs still either prohibit proposed AI use cases because of security concerns — what he terms the “&lt;a href="https://robtlee73.substack.com/p/the-framework-of-no-why-your-security"&gt;Security Framework of No&lt;/a&gt;” — or slow adoption while they evaluate the AI’s security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There is a general lack of knowledge on how to approach AI,” Lee says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fairness to CISOs, the business doesn’t always help matters here, Lee notes. “At many organizations their AI strategy is changing quickly; a new AI version comes out and so their agenda changes, and then a month later something else new comes out and it changes again. There is this moving target of what the security team is being asked to secure,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regardless, Lee says it’s clear that the security team’s inability to keep pace with AI innovation and the enterprise’s desire to quickly adopt is problematic. It stymies the organization’s agenda by slowing transformation. It also hinders the security department’s success, because the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3529615/companies-skip-security-hardening-in-rush-to-adopt-ai.html"&gt;business often bypasses security altogether&lt;/a&gt; rather than have to slow or stop its AI journey.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, CISOs and their organizations &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4044007/shadow-ai-is-surging-getting-ai-adoption-right-is-your-best-defense.html"&gt;end up with shadow AI&lt;/a&gt;, unmanaged agents, and opaque data flows that create a poorly secured expanded attack, Lee adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is still a need to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4033338/how-cybersecurity-leaders-are-securing-ai-infrastructures.html"&gt;adequately evaluate and secure AI deployments&lt;/a&gt;, Lee says, adding that organizations should not simply accept vendor assurances that their AI components are secure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Lee, the CISOs who keep pace with their organization’s AI strategy take a holistic approach, rather than work deployment to deployment. They establish a risk profile for specific data, so security doesn’t spend much time evaluating AI deployments that use low-risk data and can prioritize work on AI use cases that need medium- or high-risk data. They also assign security staffers to individual departments to stay on top of AI needs, and they train security teams on the skills needed to evaluate and secure AI initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-limited-adoption-of-ai-for-security-operations"&gt;3. Limited adoption of AI for security operations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Like their business colleagues, some CISOs are &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4042494/how-ai-is-reshaping-cybersecurity-operations.html"&gt;embracing AI to transform their operations&lt;/a&gt; — but they appear far from being a majority, despite the benefits the technology brings to cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.isc2.org/Insights/2025/12/2025-ISC2-Cybersecurity-Workforce-Study"&gt;2025 ISC2 Cybersecurity Workforce Study&lt;/a&gt; found that only 28% of the 16,000 enterprise leaders surveyed had integrated AI tools into their security operations. The study found 19% testing them and 22% in the early evaluation phase.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CISOs are playing a bit of catch-up” in terms of deploying AI at the same speed as the business, says &lt;a href="https://events.isc2.org/b/sp/jon-france-5332"&gt;Jon France&lt;/a&gt;, CISO of ISC2, a cybersecurity training and certification organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That slow pace exists even though use of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064158/agentic-ai-in-it-security-where-expectations-meet-reality.html"&gt;AI in security operations is proving beneficial&lt;/a&gt;, France adds, noting that 63% of those who are using AI security tools reported a significant boost to their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the ISC2 study, “In terms of where AI is expected to have the most impact on cybersecurity operations in the shortest amount of time, 40% pointed toward network monitoring for the highest positive impact, followed by security operations and security testing (both at 30%), vulnerability management (29%), threat modeling and endpoint protection (both at 28%).”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-the-lack-of-needed-talent-and-required-skills"&gt;4. The lack of needed talent and required skills&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although CISOs have long cited challenges in hiring enough qualified security workers, they’re increasingly citing it as a roadblock to advancing their security agendas.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2025 &lt;a href="https://www.accenture.com/us-en/insights/security/state-cybersecurity-2025"&gt;State of Cybersecurity Resilience&lt;/a&gt; from professional services firm Accenture found that 83% of IT executives identified their cyber talent shortage “as a major obstacle to achieving a strong security posture.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ISC2 study highlighted a two-headed problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First is the talent shortage, with 63% reporting in 2025 that they have a slight or significant cybersecurity shortage, a modest improvement over the 68% who said as much in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second is the skills gap. According to the report, 59% in 2025 have critical or significant skills needs, up from 44% in 2024, and 95% have at least one or more skills needs, up 5% on the previous year. Survey respondents said AI was the most pressing skills need (41%), followed by cloud security (36%), risk assessment (29%), application security (28%), security engineering and governance, (27%) and risk and compliance (also at 27%).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We need people who are suitable to discharge the duties of security roles today,” France says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Khawaja also cites the lack of “the right skills on the security team” as an obstacle for CISO success.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, Khawaja sees the challenge for CISOs not being about hiring for technical skills or even soft skills, but what he called “middle skills,” such as risk management and change management. These skills he sees becoming more crucial for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080670/what-does-aligning-security-to-the-business-really-mean.html"&gt;aligning security to the business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;getting users to adopt security protocols&lt;/a&gt;, and ultimately improving the organization’s security posture. “If you don’t have [those middle skills], there’s only so far the security team can go,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although CISOs are fighting labor market forces that are well beyond their direct control and influences, Khawaja and others say there are steps CISOs can take to address their talent and skills shortages, saying a solid talent strategy that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3963314/cisos-rethink-hiring-to-emphasize-skills-over-degrees-and-experience.html"&gt;focuses on hiring for skills and competencies&lt;/a&gt; can help CISOs get what they need to advance their security agendas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117010/4-issues-holding-back-cisos-security-agendas.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI overload to accelerate zero-trust data governance adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122266/50-of-organizations-will-adopt-zero-trust-data-governance-by-2028.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner has warned that the increasing volume of data generated by AI threatens the future reliability of large language models (LLMs).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So much so, that it predicts that 50% of organizations will implement a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;zero-trust stance&lt;/a&gt; for data governance by 2028 due to the proliferation of unverified AI-generated data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to data from a recent 2026 survey of CIOs and technology executives, 84% expect their companies to increase funding for generative AI. As organizations accelerate both the adoption and investment in AI initiatives, the volume of AI-generated data will continue to grow. This means that future generations of LLMs will increasingly be trained on the outputs of previous models, increasing the risk of “model crash,” where AI tools’ responses may no longer accurately reflect reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Organizations can no longer implicitly trust data or assume it was human generated. As AI-generated data becomes pervasive and indistinguishable from human-created data, a zero-trust posture establishing authentication and verification measures, is essential to safeguard business and financial outcomes,” said Wan Fui Chan, executive vice president at Gartner, in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chan also pointed out that “regulatory requirements for verifying ‘AI-free’ data are expected to intensify in certain regions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However, these requirements may differ significantly across geographies, with some jurisdictions seeking to enforce stricter controls on AI-generated content, while others may adopt a more flexible approach,” Chan said in the release.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLMs are typically trained using data extracted from the web, as well as a variety of other sources, including books, code repositories, and research articles. Some of these sources already contain AI-generated content, and if the current trend continues, almost all of them will eventually be filled with AI-generated data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In this evolving regulatory environment,” Chan continued, “all organizations will need the ability to identify and tag AI-generated data. Success will depend on having the right tools and a workforce skilled in information and knowledge management, as well as metadata management solutions that are essential for data cataloging.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, Gartner points out that proactive metadata management practices will become a key differentiator, as they will allow organizations to analyze, alert, and automate decision-making across all their data assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122266/50-of-organizations-will-adopt-zero-trust-data-governance-by-2028.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – January 2026 quarterly rollup (AV26-042) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming AI fatigue</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122255/overcoming-ai-fatigue.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is now &lt;a href="https://www.secondtalent.com/resources/ai-adoption-in-enterprise-statistics/"&gt;everywhere&lt;/a&gt; within enterprises. Many CISOs I speak with feel stuck between wanting to move forward and not knowing where to begin. The fear of getting both security’s use of AI and securing AI within the organization wrong often stops their process before it begins. That said, unlike other big technology waves such as cloud, mobile and DevOps, we actually have a chance to put guardrails around AI &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; it becomes fully entrenched in every corner of the business. It’s a rare opportunity, one we shouldn’t waste.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-ai-fatigue-to-some-much-needed-clarity"&gt;From AI fatigue to some much-needed clarity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A big part of the confusion comes from the word “AI” itself. We use the same label to talk about a chatbot drafting marketing copy and autonomous agents that generate and implement incident response playbooks. Technically, they’re both AI, but the risks are nowhere near the same. The easiest way to cut through the AI hype is to break AI into categories based on how independent the system is and how much damage it could do if something went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On one end, you have &lt;a href="https://teaching.pitt.edu/resources/what-is-generative-ai/#:~:text=Generative%20artificial%20intelligence%20(AI)%20tools%20use%20machine,pixel%20would%20come%20next%20in%20a%20pattern."&gt;generative AI&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn’t act on its own. It responds to prompts. It creates content. It helps with research or writing. Most of the risk here comes from people using it in ways they shouldn’t — sharing sensitive data, pasting in proprietary code, leaking intellectual property and so on. The good news is that these problems are manageable. Clear &lt;a href="https://www.isaca.org/resources/artificial-intelligence-acceptable-use-policy-template"&gt;acceptable-use policies&lt;/a&gt;, training people on what not to put into GenAI tools and implementing enforceable technical controls will handle a big chunk of the security considerations with generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The risk grows when companies let GenAI influence decisions. If the underlying data is wrong, poisoned or incomplete, then the recommendations built on top of that data will be wrong too. That’s where CISOs need to pay attention to data integrity, not just data protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the other end of the spectrum: &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/agentic-ai/"&gt;agentic AI&lt;/a&gt;. This is where the stakes are raised. Agentic systems don’t just answer questions — they take actions. They sometimes make choices. Some can trigger workflows or interact with internal systems with very little human involvement. The more independent the system, the bigger the potential impact. And unlike GenAI, you can’t rely on “better prompts” to fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an agentic AI drifts into “&lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/councils/forbestechcouncil/2025/04/17/five-potential-risks-of-autonomous-ai-agents-going-rogue/"&gt;bad behavior&lt;/a&gt;,” the consequences can land extremely fast. That’s why CISOs need to get ahead of this category now. Once the business starts depending on autonomous systems, trying to bolt on safeguards afterward is almost impossible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-cisos-actually-have-an-opening-here"&gt;Why CISOs actually have an opening here&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been in security long enough, you’ve probably lived through at least one technology wave where the business moved ahead and security was asked to play catch-up. Cloud adoption is one recent example. And once that train left the station, there was no looking back and there was certainly no slowing down.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is different. Most companies – even the most forward-thinking ones – are still figuring out what they want from AI and how to best deploy it. Outside of tech, many executives are experimenting without any real strategy at all. This creates a window for CISOs to set expectations early.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the moment to define the “unbreakable rules,” shape which teams will review AI requests and put some structure around how decisions are made. Security leaders today have more influence than they did in earlier technology shifts, and AI governance has quickly become one of the most strategic responsibilities in the role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-integrity-foundational-to-ai-risk"&gt;Data integrity: Foundational to AI risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When people talk about the CIA triad, “integrity” usually gets the least airtime. In most organizations, applications handle integrity quietly in the background. But AI changes how we think about it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If the data feeding your AI systems is compromised, incomplete, incorrect or manipulated, then the decisions built on top of that data can affect financial processes, supply chains, customer interactions or even physical safety. The job of the CISO now includes making sure AI systems rely on trustworthy data, not just protected data. Those two aren’t the same thing anymore.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-simple-tiered-approach-to-ai-governance"&gt;A simple, tiered approach to AI governance&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To make sense of all the different AI use cases, I recommend a tiered approach. It mirrors how many companies already handle third-party risk: the higher the risk, the more scrutiny and controls you apply.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-1-categorize-ai-usage"&gt;Step 1: Categorize AI usage&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A practical AI governance program begins by categorizing each use case according to two core metrics: the system’s level of autonomy and its potential business impact. Autonomy spans a spectrum, from reactive generative AI to assisted decision-making, to human-in-the-loop agentic systems and ultimately to fully independent AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Each AI use case must be evaluated for its impact on the business, categorizing the impact simply as low, medium or high.  Low-impact, low-autonomy systems may require only lightweight oversight, whereas high-autonomy, high-impact use cases demand formal governance, rigorous architectural review, continuous monitoring – and in some cases, explicit human oversight or the addition of a kill switch. This structured approach allows CISOs to quickly determine when stricter controls are needed and when concepts such as zero-trust principles should be applied inside AI systems themselves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-2-define-table-stakes-controls-for-all-ai"&gt;Step 2: Define table-stakes controls for all AI&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once risk tiering is in place, CISOs must ensure that foundational controls are consistently applied across all AI deployments. Regardless of the technology’s sophistication, every organization needs clear and enforceable acceptable use policies, security awareness training that addresses AI-specific risks and technical controls that prevent data leakage and undesirable behavior. Basic monitoring for anomalous AI activity further ensures that even low-risk generative AI use cases operate within safe and predictable boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-3-determine-where-ai-review-will-occur"&gt;Step 3: Determine where AI review will occur&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With these foundations established, organizations must determine where AI governance will actually occur. The right forum depends on organizational maturity and existing structures. Some companies may integrate AI reviews into an established architecture review board or a privacy or security committee; others may need a dedicated, cross-functional AI governance body. Regardless of the structure chosen, effective AI oversight requires input from security, privacy, data, legal, product and operations. Governance cannot be the responsibility of a single department — AI’s impact reaches across the entire enterprise, and so must its oversight.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="step-4-establish-unbreakable-rules-and-critical-controls"&gt;Step 4: Establish unbreakable rules and critical controls&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, before any AI use case is approved, the organization must articulate its non-negotiable rules and critical controls. These are the boundaries that AI systems must never cross, such as autonomously deleting data or exposing sensitive information. Some systems may require explicit human oversight, and any agentic AI that can bypass human-in-the-loop mechanisms must include a reliable kill switch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Least-privilege access and zero-trust principles should also apply within AI systems, preventing them from inheriting more authority or visibility than intended. These rules should be dynamic, evolving as AI capabilities and business needs change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-isnt-optional-anymore-but-good-governance-cant-be-optional-either"&gt;AI isn’t optional anymore, but good governance can’t be optional either&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs don’t have to become machine-learning experts or slow the business down. What they do need is a clear, workable way to judge AI risks and keep things safe as adoption grows. Breaking AI down into understandable categories, pairing that with a simple risk model and getting the right people involved early will go a long way toward reducing the overwhelm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI will reshape every corner of the enterprise. The question is who will shape AI. For the first time in a long time, CISOs have the chance to set the rules, not scramble to enforce them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Carpe diem!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122255/overcoming-ai-fatigue.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA releases technology readiness list for post-quantum cryptography</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122752/cisa-releases-technology-readiness-list-for-post-quantum-cryptography.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has released a new advisory mapping post-quantum cryptography (PQC) standards to common enterprise hardware and software categories, giving CIOs and security teams an early reference for evaluating quantum-safe technology readiness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Issued in response to a June 6, 2025 &lt;a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2025/06/11/2025-10804/sustaining-select-efforts-to-strengthen-the-nations-cybersecurity-and-amending-executive-order-13694" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;executive order&lt;/a&gt; on strengthening federal cybersecurity, the advisory identifies classes of IT products that already use, or are transitioning toward, NIST-standardized &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/654887/11-notable-post-quantum-cryptography-initiatives-launched-in-2023.html"&gt;PQC &lt;/a&gt;algorithms. CISA said the lists are intended to guide procurement and long-term migration planning as agencies assess systems that rely on public-key cryptography.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For enterprises, the guidance signals that quantum-safe cryptography is becoming a practical procurement consideration today, while also highlighting gaps. CISA noted that many listed product categories have implemented PQC for limited functions, such as key establishment, but are not yet fully quantum-resistant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;CISA noted PQC-ready product categories&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The advisory highlighted several technology categories where PQC-compatible solutions are already available (or are in active transition) to help organizations evaluate purchase decisions and plan migration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The advisory highlighted that several product categories under hardware and software are already using PQC Standards. These include cloud services (PaaS, IaaS), collaboration software (chat/messaging), web software (browsers and servers), and endpoint security (DAR security and full disk encryption).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several other categories, including networking hardware and software, SaaS, telecommunications hardware, computers (physical or virtual), storage area networks, ICAM hardware, password managers, and antivirus software, were highlighted for their potential for adopting PQC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA noted that none of these categories is fully quantum-resistant. “Most of these categories have implemented PQC for key encapsulation and key agreement but have not yet widely implemented PQC for digital signatures and authentication,” CISA said about the categories already using PQC Standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As a result, these categories are not considered to be fully quantum resistant; CISA includes them on this list because one of their main security services is quantum resistant, and Federal Civilian Executive Branch (FCEB) departments and agencies should procure them appropriately.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The advisory added a note for categories like operational technology (OT) and internet of things (IoT) devices that weren’t considered traditional IT products. “These also should be transitioning to PQC standards as well, but are out of scope for these lists,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pqc-standards-and-algorithm-roadmap"&gt;PQC standards and algorithm roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISA &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/resources-tools/resources/product-categories-technologies-use-post-quantum-cryptography-standards" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;advisory&lt;/a&gt; is aimed at aligning technologies with the nascent PQC standards now added into federal policy. NIST’s post-quantum &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3486075/nist-finally-settles-on-quantum-safe-crypto-standards.html?_conv_v=vi:1*sc:26*cs:1769510743*fs:1767608994*pv:102*exp:%7B%7D*seg:%7B%7D*ps:1769062947&amp;amp;_conv_s=sh:1769510742722-0.13430893266432276*si:26*pv:3&amp;amp;_conv_sptest=null"&gt;standardization project&lt;/a&gt; and its Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) publications formed the baseline for the advisory.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These include FIPS 203, which specifies the Module-lattice-Based Key Encapsulation Mechanism (ML-KEM) based on the CRYSTALS-KYBER algorithm for secure key establishment, FIPS 204, which defines the Module-Lattice-Based Digital Signature Algorithm (ML-DSA) rooted in CRYSTALS-Dilithium for secure digital signatures, and FIPS 205, which covers the Stateless Hash-Based Digital Signature Algorithm (SLH-DSA) derived from SPHINCS+ hash-based signature scheme. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These standards implement mathematical constructions designed to resist both classical and quantum cryptanalytic attacks. To qualify as PQC-ready under CISA’s view, products are expected to implement these &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/topics/risk-management/quantum" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PQC primitives&lt;/a&gt; for key establishment (enabling two parties to negotiate secure session keys) and digital signatures (for authentication and integrity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122752/cisa-releases-technology-readiness-list-for-post-quantum-cryptography.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Probleme, die CISOs behindern</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122799/4-probleme-die-cisos-behindern.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CISO ausgebremst " class="wp-image-4122807" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_513565255.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Lesen Sie, welche strategischen Probleme CISOs bei ihren Aufgaben behindern.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;alphaspirit.it – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Viele Sicherheitsverantwortliche glauben, dass ein Cybervorfall unvermeidlich ist – unklsar ist lediglich der Zeitpunkt. Diese Überzeugung spiegelt sich in der gängigen Redewendung wider, dass es nicht darum geht, „ob“, sondern „wann“ ein Angriff erfolgt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eine wachsende Zahl von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109550/die-wichtigsten-ciso-trends-fur-2026.html" target="_blank"&gt;CISOs&lt;/a&gt; rechnet jedoch eher früher als später mit einem Vorfall: Im &lt;a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/us/newsroom/press-releases/proofpoint-2025-voice-ciso-report" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Voice of the CISO Report&lt;/a&gt; 2025 von Proofpoint gaben rund 76 Prozent der Befragten an, dass sie sich in den nächsten 12 Monaten einem erheblichen Cyberangriff ausgesetzt sehen. Im Vorjahr lag dieser Wert noch bei 70 Prozent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zudem glauben 58 Prozent der befragten CISOs, dass ihr Unternehmen nicht darauf vorbereitet ist. Neben dem allgemeinen Gefühl, dass ein Angriff fast unvermeidlich ist, räumen die Sicherheitschefs ein, dass verschiedene Herausforderungen sie bei ihren Aufgaben behindern. In erster Linie sehen sie bei ihrer Arbeit vier Probleme:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-teammitglieder-werden-nicht-ausreichend-befahigt-nach-prioritaten-zu-handeln"&gt;1. Teammitglieder werden nicht ausreichend befähigt, nach Prioritäten zu handeln&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Viele CISOs geben offen zu, dass ihre Sicherheitsteams mehr Arbeit haben, als sie bewältigen können. Das führt zu viel Stress: Im &lt;a href="https://nagomisecurity.com/ciso-pressure-index" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 CISO Pressure Index&lt;/a&gt; von Nagomi Security bekundeten rund 80 Prozent der CISOs, dass sie derzeit unter hohem oder extremem Druck stünden , BBei 87 Prozent hat der Druck bei in den vergangenen 12 Monaten zugenommen. Darüber hinaus geben 67 Prozent Befragten an, wöchentlich oder täglich ausgebrannt zu sein.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Jeder CISO fühlt sich stark überfordert“, bestätigt Omar Khawaja, Leiter des Bereichs Field Security bei Databricks. „Um damit fertig zu werden, haben die CISOs gelernt, Prioritäten zu setzen.“ Bei den meisten stehe ganz oben auf ihrer Liste, die größten Risiken für das Unternehmen zu reduzieren, so Khawaja.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Allzu oft schulen CISOs ihre Teammitglieder jedoch nicht, damit sie kompetente Entscheidungen treffen und Maßnahmen ergreifen können, die mit diesen Prioritäten übereinstimmen“, so der ehemalige CISO bei Highmark Health.Dadurch müssten Führungskräfte weiterhin alle Prioritätsentscheidungen treffen, was das gesamte Team verlangsamen würde.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs sollten darauf hinarbeiten, dass ihre Teammitglieder wissen, wann und wie sie Prioritäten für ihre eigenen Arbeitsbereiche setzen müssen, „damit sich jedes einzelne Team auf die wichtigsten Dinge konzentriert“, fügt Khawaja hinzu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Dazu müssen Sie klare Mechanismen und Anweisungen für die Entscheidungsunterstützung schaffen“, erklärt er. „Es sollte Kriterien oder Faktoren geben, die festlegen, ob etwas vom Sicherheitsteam eine hohe, mittlere oder niedrige Priorität hat. Denn dann kann jedes Teammitglied jede Anfrage, die bei ihm eingeht, prüfen und sie sicher und effektiv priorisieren.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-mit-der-innovation-und-einfuhrung-von-ki-nicht-schritt-halten"&gt;2. Mit der Innovation und Einführung von KI nicht Schritt halten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Führungskräfte und Mitarbeiter haben sich gleichermaßen beeilt, künstliche Intelligenz einzusezten, angelockt von der Erwartung, dass KI Arbeitsabläufe verändern und Zeit, Geld sowie Aufwand sparen wird.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die meisten CISOs haben jedoch mit der Geschwindigkeit der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4055445/funf-ki-use-cases-fur-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;KI-Einführung&lt;/a&gt; durch ihre Geschäftskollegen nicht Schritt gehalten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut einer Umfrage unter 921 IT- und Cybersicherheitsexperten im Rahmen des &lt;a href="https://www.cyera.com/research-labs/2025-state-of-ai-data-security-report"&gt;2025 State of AI Data Security Report&lt;/a&gt; von Cyera nutzen 83 Prozent der Unternehmen KI. Aber nur 13 Prozent haben einen guten Überblick darüber, inwieweitdiese Systeme auf sensible Daten zugreifen oder wie sie mit ihnen umgehen; lediglich 16 Prozent behandeln KI als eigenständige Identität; nur elf Prozent der Unternehmen können riskante KI-Aktivitäten automatisch blockieren; und nur sieben Prozent verfügen über ein spezielles KI-Governance-Team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die meisten CISOs kämpfen mit der Frage, wie sie die KI-Nutzung absichern können”, betont Robert T. Lee, Chief AI Officer und Forschungsleiter bei SANS.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut Lee verbieten viele CISOs aufgrund von Sicherheitsbedenken immer noch vorgeschlagene KI-Anwendungsfälle – was er als „Security Framework of No” bezeichnet – oder verlangsamen die Einführung, während sie die Sicherheit der KI bewerten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Es herrscht ein allgemeiner Mangel an Wissen darüber, wie man mit KI umgehen soll“, so Lee. „Fairerweise muss man sagen, dass die Unternehmen den CISOs hier nicht immer helfen“, bemerkt der Experte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein anderer Punkt ist die häufig wechselnde KI-Strategie in vielen Unternehmen. „Eine neue KI-Version kommt heraus, und schon ändert sich die Agenda, und einen Monat später kommt etwas Neues heraus, und schon ändert sie sich wieder. Es ist also ein bewegliches Ziel, das das Sicherheitsteam schützen soll“, erklärt Lee.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unabhängig davon ist es laut Lee klar, dass die Unfähigkeit des Sicherheitsteams, mit den KI-Innovationen Schritt zu halten, und der Wunsch des Unternehmens nach einer schnellen Einführung problematisch sind. „Indem es die Transformation verlangsamt,  behindert dies nicht nur die Agenda des Unternehmens“,so der KI-Experte. „Es verhindert auch den Erfolg der Sicherheitsabteilung, da das Unternehmen oft die Security komplett umgeht, anstatt seine KI-Entwicklung zu verlangsamen oder zu stoppen.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Infolgedessen sähen sich CISOs und ihre Unternehmen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094347/schatten-it-viele-fachkrafte-nutzen-ki-ohne-erlaubnis.html" target="_blank"&gt;letztendlich mit Schatten-KI&lt;/a&gt;, unkontrollierten Agenten und undurchsichtigen Datenflüssen konfrontiert, die zu einem schlecht gesicherten, erweiterten Angriff führen, fügt Lee hinzu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Natürlich besteht nach wie vor die Notwendigkeit, KI-Implementierungen angemessen zu bewerten und zu sichern, betont er und ergänzt, dass Unternehmen nicht einfach die Zusicherungen der Anbieter akzeptieren sollten, dass ihre KI-Komponenten sicher sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nach Ansicht von Lee verfolgen CISOs, die mit der KI-Strategie ihrer Organisation Schritt halten, einen ganzheitlichen Ansatz, anstatt von Einsatz zu Einsatz zu arbeiten. Sie erstellen ein Risikoprofil für bestimmte Daten, sodass die Sicherheitsabteilung nicht viel Zeit mit der Bewertung von KI-Implementierungen verbringen muss und sich stattdessen auf KI-Anwendungsfälle konzentrieren kann, die Daten mit mittlerem oder hohem Risiko erfordern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Außerdem würden sie einzelnen Abteilungen Sicherheitsmitarbeiter zuweisen, um den KI-Bedarf im Blick zu behalten. Zudem würden Sicherheitsteams in den Fähigkeiten geschult, die zur Bewertung und Sicherung von KI-Initiativen erforderlich sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-begrenzte-einfuhrung-von-ki-fur-sicherheitsmasnahmen"&gt;3. Begrenzte Einführung von KI für Sicherheitsmaßnahmen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie ihre Kollegen aus dem Business  setzen auch einige CISOs auf KI, um ihre Abläufe zu transformieren – doch trotz der Vorteile, die diese Technologie für die Cybersicherheit mit sich bringt, scheinen sie bei weitem nicht die Mehrheit zu bilden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die &lt;a href="https://www.isc2.org/Insights/2025/12/2025-ISC2-Cybersecurity-Workforce-Study" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 ISC2 Cybersecurity Workforce Study&lt;/a&gt; zeigt, dass nur 28 Prozent der 16.000 befragten Unternehmensleiter KI-Tools in ihre Sicherheitsabläufe integriert hatten. Die Studie ergab, dass 19 Prozent sie testeten und 22 Prozent sich in der frühen Evaluierungsphase befanden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„CISOs haben etwas Aufholbedarf, wenn es darum geht, KI mit der gleichen Geschwindigkeit wie das Business einzusetzen“, betont Jon France, CISO von ISC2, einer Organisation für Cybersicherheitsschulungen und -zertifizierungen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieses langsame Tempo bestehe fort, obwohl sich der Einsatz von KI in Sicherheitsabläufen als vorteilhaft erweist, fügt France hinzu und merkt an, dass 63 Prozent derjenigen, die KI-Sicherheitstools einsetzen, von einer deutlichen Steigerung ihrer Produktivität berichten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In der ISC2-Studie gaben 40 Prozent der CISOs an, dass KI in kürzester Zeit den größten Einfluss auf Cybersicherheitsmaßnahmen haben wird, gefolgt von Sicherheitsmaßnahmen und Sicherheitstests (beide 30 Prozent), Schwachstellenmanagement (29 Prozent), Bedrohungsmodellierung und Endpunktschutz (beide 28 Prozent).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-mangel-an-benotigten-talenten-und-erforderlichen-fahigkeiten"&gt;4. Mangel an benötigten Talenten und erforderlichen Fähigkeiten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs berichten zwar schon seit langem von Schwierigkeiten bei der Einstellung ausreichend qualifizierter Sicherheitsmitarbeiter. Inzwischen sehen sie dieses Problem jedoch zunehmend als zentrales Hindernis für die Umsetzung ihrer Sicherheitsagenda.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In der Studie „2025 &lt;a href="https://www.accenture.com/us-en/insights/security/state-cybersecurity-2025" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;State of Cybersecurity Resilience&lt;/a&gt;” von Accenture identifizierten 83 Prozent der IT-Führungskräfte den Mangel an Cybertalenten „als großes Hindernis für die Erreichung einer starken Sicherheitslage”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Problem ist dabei laut ISC2-Studie zweigeteilt:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zunächst ist da der Fachkräftemangel: 63 Prozent der Befragten gaben 2025 an, dass sie einen leichten oder erheblichen Mangel an Cybersicherheitskräften haben, immerhin eine leichte Verbesserung gegenüber den 68 Prozent im Vorjahr.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zweitens wächst die Qualifikationslücke. Dem Bericht zufolge haben 59 Prozent im Jahr 2025 einen kritischen oder erheblichen Bedarf an bestimmten Fähifkeiten (2024: 44 Prozent). 95 Prozent berichten von mindestens einem Skill-Bedarf – 5 Prozent mehr als im Vorjahr. Als dringendste Kompetenz nannten die Befragten KI-Know-how (41 Prozent), gefolgt von Cloud-Sicherheit (36 Prozent), Risikobewertung (29 Prozent), Anwendungssicherheit (28 Prozent), Sicherheitstechnik und Governance (27 Prozent) sowie Risiko und Compliance (ebenfalls 27 Prozent).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Wir brauchen Menschen, die in der Lage sind, die Aufgaben von modernen Sicherheitsfunktionen zu erfüllen“, so France.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch Khawaja nennt den Mangel an „den richtigen Fähigkeiten im Sicherheitsteam“ als Hindernis für den Erfolg von CISOs. Er sieht die Herausforderung jedoch weniger im Fehlen von technischen Fähigkeiten oder sogar Soft Skills, sondern in sogenannten „Middle Skills“, etwa Risikomanagement und Change Management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Fähigkeiten werden nach Meinung von Khawaja immer wichtiger, um die Sicherheit besser mit dem Business zu verzahnen, die Benutzer zur Akzeptanz von Sicherheitsprotokollen zu bewegen und letztendlich die Sicherheitslage des Unternehmens zu verbessern. „Fehlen diese Fähigkeiten, kann das Sicherheitsteam nur begrenzt etwas ausrichten.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obwohl CISOs mit Arbeitsmarktbedingungen zu kämpfen haben, die weit außerhalb ihrer direkten Kontrolle und ihres Einflussbereichs liegen, gibt es laut Khawaja andere Maßnahmen, mit denen sie dem Mangel an Talenten und Fähigkeiten begegnen können. „Eine klare Talentstrategie, die sich auf die Einstellung von Mitarbeitern mit bestimmten Fähigkeiten und Kompetenzen konzentriert, kann CISOs dabei helfen, das zu bekommen, was sie zur Umsetzung ihrer Sicherheitsagenda benötigen.“ (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122799/4-probleme-die-cisos-behindern.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered polymorphic attack lures victims to phishing webpages</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123217/ai-powered-polymorphic-attacks-lures-victims-to-phishing-webpages.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-fueled attacks can transform an innocuous webpage into a customed phishing page. The attacks, revealed in a &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/real-time-malicious-javascript-through-llms/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; from Palo Alto Networks’ Unit 42, are clever in how they combine various obfuscation techniques. The combination though can be lethal, difficult to discover, and represent yet another new offensive front in the use of AI by bad actors to compromise enterprise networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack starts with an original and ordinary webpage then attackers add client-side API calls to LLMs that can dynamically generate malicious JavaScript code in real time. This polymorphic technique is dangerous for several reasons. First, it can bypass any built-in AI model security guardrails. Second, because it delivers its malware from a trusted LLM domain it may bypass typical network analysis. Without any runtime behavioral analysis screening, it won’t easily be discovered or blocked, because the assembly of the final malware code happens inside a client’s browser and leaves no static payload residue anywhere else in the process.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The analysts at Unit 42 wrote a proof-of-concept code that calls popular LLMs such as DeepSeek and Google’s Gemini into returning the malicious JavaScript. The key step is to use separate prompts to craft AI prompts that translate the malware and describe its functionality as plain text, which then generate different pieces of the actual malware code. The AI model can generate a variety of phishing code content and then assemble the various pieces, both of which make detection more difficult. The assembly, as mentioned, is happening at the very end of this malware supply chain, what SquareX &lt;a href="https://sqrx.com/lastmilereassemblyattacks" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;calls&lt;/a&gt; a last mile reassembling attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While this attack isn’t exactly novel, what is new is the type of code pieces that are generated by the AI that are more difficult to detect. The example used in the PoC described four code fragments in its prompting instructions, each fragment involving a different step in the malware’s operations. Each prompt would return a syntactically unique yet functionally identical variant of the malicious code, according to the analysts. Think of this as the AI version of custom-coded malware that was first invented decades ago by attackers looking to evade static signature detection algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are several ways the final malware assembly can be accomplished, including using a backend proxy server or a content delivery network to further hide the malware’s true nature by providing trusted domains to deliver the goods.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Unfortunately, at least some of this comes back to having the user as the last line of defense,” Allie Mellen, Forrester principal analyst, security and risk, told CSO. “This attack prevents the vendors from using some phishing detection techniques, but many of the core phishing detection capabilities are still relevant here.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jess Burn, a Forrester analyst for email security, agrees that there is some protection with existing defensive technologies. However, “even though this attack uses the browser and an LLM to build the phishing page on the fly, the issue is still how users got to that page in the first place. Well-tuned email and collaboration security tools that spot suspicious links, newly registered domains, look‑alike brands, and unusual sender behavior can still stop many of these campaigns at the message layer so the user never clicks through to the ‘magic’ page that turns malicious at runtime.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unit 42 of course recommends Palo Alto Networks’ products to help defend against this attack. Other solutions include using secure web gateways as well as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573875/secure-web-browsers-for-the-enterprise-compared-how-to-pick-the-right-one.html" target="_blank"&gt;secure enterprise browsers&lt;/a&gt; that can prevent last mile attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123217/ai-powered-polymorphic-attacks-lures-victims-to-phishing-webpages.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-050)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-050</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-050</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719 - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–051)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-051</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-051</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-052)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-052</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-052</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-053)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-053</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-053</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-054)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-054</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-054</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-055)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-055</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-055</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-056)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-056</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-056</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-057)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-057</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-057</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNU security advisory (AV26-047) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmarterTools security advisory (AV25-866) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL security advisory (AV26-058)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-059)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Spot at RSAC 2026 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 3143100.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
