<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:24:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-006)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-007)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV26-008)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OTF GRIMM: Swedish organiser of serious violence arrested in Iraq</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</link>
      <description>A High-Value Target under Europol-supported Operational Taskforce GRIMM was arrested in Iraq following long-term cooperation between the Swedish Police Authority and Iraqi law enforcement authorities. The 21-year-old suspect, a Swedish national who was listed on the EU Most Wanted list, is identified as a key organiser of serious violence directed at Sweden from abroad.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophisticated VoidLink malware framework targets Linux cloud servers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117038/sophisticated-voidlink-malware-framework-targets-linux-cloud-servers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have uncovered a new sophisticated and modular malware framework designed to operate stealthily inside Linux systems and containers. The framework seems to have been designed by Chinese developers with in-depth knowledge of Linux internals and was created to be used against cloud servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The framework, internally referred to by its original developers as VoidLink, is a cloud-first implant written in Zig and designed to operate in modern infrastructure,” researchers from security firm Check Point said in their &lt;a href="https://research.checkpoint.com/2026/voidlink-the-cloud-native-malware-framework/"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. “It can recognize major cloud environments and detect when it is running inside Kubernetes or Docker, then tailor its behavior accordingly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Check Point only found samples of the malware that appear to be an in-progress project rather than a completed product. However, the project is mature, and the company’s researchers suspect it won’t be long before the malware is used in real-world attacks, possibly for cyberespionage or supply-chain compromises because it harvests credentials for cloud environments and source code repository management systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="highly-extensible-and-customizable"&gt;Highly extensible and customizable&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VoidLink draws inspiration from the beacon implant of Cobalt Strike, an adversary simulation framework that has been widely adopted and misused by attackers over the years. The malware uses an API to communicate with additional plug-ins that add a diverse set of capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By default, the platform comes with 37 plug-ins that can be selected and delivered to the victim to enable additional capabilities. However, the operator can also deliver custom plug-ins. This is controlled through a professional-looking web-based command-and-control (C2) dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This interface is localized for Chinese-affiliated operators, but the navigation follows a familiar C2 layout: a left sidebar groups pages into Dashboard, Attack, and Infrastructure,” the researchers said. “The Dashboard section covers the core operator loop (agent manager, built-in terminal, and an implant builder). In contrast, the Attack section organizes post-exploitation activity such as reconnaissance, credential access, persistence, lateral movement, process injection, stealth, and evidence wiping.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware framework is written in Zig, a relatively new programming language that’s an alternative to C and is an unusual choice for malware development. However, the developers have also shown proficiency in other languages such as Go, C, and JavaScript frameworks such as React.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers note that VoidLink is much more advanced that typical Linux malware, with a well-designed core component handling state, communication and task execution that is delivered through a two-stage loader. Operators can deliver additional code to be executed in the form of plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-reconnaissance-and-adaptability"&gt;Cloud reconnaissance and adaptability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware was designed to detect whether it’s being executed on various cloud platforms such as AWS, GCP, Azure, Alibaba, and Tencent and then to start leveraging those vendors’ management APIs. The code suggests the developers plan to add detections for Huawei, DigitalOcean, and Vultr in the future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware collects extensive amounts of information about the machine and environment it runs in, including whether it’s a Docker container or a Kubernetes pod. It then can execute post-exploitation modules that attempt privilege escalation through container escapes or lateral movement to other containers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Ultimately, the goal of this implant appears to be stealthy, long-term access, surveillance, and data collection,” the researchers said, adding that developers might be a target for initial delivery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another interesting aspect is that the malware has a sophisticated algorithm through which it adapts its operations based on the security posture of the environment. It will scan for common Linux endpoint and detection response (EDR) tools and kernel hardening technologies and then calculate a risk score for the environment, which is then used to select a detection evasion strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware also has multiple rootkit components with deployment strategies for different versions of the Linux kernel and will deploy them based on the environment in which it runs. These rootkit modules hide the malware’s processes, files, and network sockets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;C2 traffic is hidden in multiple ways, including as encrypted data in PNGs or JS, HTML, or CSS files, making it hard to detect at the network layer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“VoidLink aims to automate evasion as much as possible, profiling an environment and choosing the most suitable strategy to operate in it,” the researchers said. “Augmented by kernel mode tradecraft and a vast plugin ecosystem, VoidLink enables its operators to move through cloud environments and container ecosystems with adaptive stealth.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While malware for Linux is less common and often less sophisticated than malware programs for Windows, VoidLink stands out as a unique and highly capable framework. Even if it’s not totally clear whether this malware is intended to be a product for cybercriminals or as future commercial penetration testing framework of sorts, it serves as an example of the type of threats organizations should be prepared to defend in their Linux-based cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117038/sophisticated-voidlink-malware-framework-targets-linux-cloud-servers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-009)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-010)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-011)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trend Micro security advisory (AV26-012)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware gangs extort victims by citing compliance violations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116976/ransomware-gangs-blackmail-victims-with-compliance-violations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563507/what-is-ransomware-how-it-works-and-how-to-remove-it.html"&gt;Ransomware attacks&lt;/a&gt; remain among the most common attack methods. As recent analyses show, cyber gangs are increasingly threatening their victims with reporting violations of regulations such as the GDPR to supervisory authorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the security provider Akamai have observed an increasing trend in this tactic over the past two years. As an example, the security vendor points to ransomware group Anubis. Its members reportedly focus primarily on industries with high compliance risks, such as healthcare. The notorious &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2139658/new-ransomhub-ransomware-gang-has-ties-to-older-knight-group.html" target="_blank"&gt;Ransomhub&lt;/a&gt; gang also allegedly employs this method, explicitly encouraging its partners to threaten hacked companies with regulatory penalties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="consequences-for-companies"&gt;Consequences for companies&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This puts companies under a double pressure that is almost impossible to manage,” Klaus Hild, manager of solution engineering for enterprise at SailPoint, explained to CSO. They have to weigh the risk of paying ransoms against potentially ruinous penalties and reputational damage. “This ‘compliance extortion’ is no longer a theoretical threat — it has become standard practice for ransomware cartels,” Hild added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tim Berghof, security evangelist at G DATA, confirmed to CSO that while this approach is technically just an extension of the “industry-standard” double extortion, it can have massive consequences. “Even if a complaint turns out to be unfounded, official investigations generate attention, tie up resources, and potentially become public,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-amplifies-attacks"&gt;AI amplifies attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hild points to another problem: “AI-powered tools dramatically accelerate these attacks. Criminals can now screen stolen documents for ‘material’ compliance violations within hours of a data breach — faster and more accurately than many companies can audit their own systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SailPoint specialist explains: “They create detailed, legally sound complaints for authorities and set tight deadlines. With new regulations like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570091/eus-dora-regulation-explained-new-risk-management-requirements-for-financial-firms.html" target="_blank"&gt;DORA&lt;/a&gt; in the EU and stricter SEC reporting requirements, the arsenal of these extortionists is constantly growing.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Berghoff summarizes: “The question remains which has the less severe consequences for companies: a self-report or an anonymous report to the relevant authority by a group of criminals. Since there is still a great deal of uncertainty surrounding compliance in some areas, threats involving authorities potentially fall on fertile ground.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116976/ransomware-gangs-blackmail-victims-with-compliance-violations.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From typos to takeovers: Inside the industrialization of npm supply chain attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117139/from-typos-to-takeovers-inside-the-industrialization-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A massive surge in attacks on the npm ecosystem over the past year reveals a stark shift in the software supply‑chain threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What once amounted to sloppy typosquatting attempts has evolved into coordinated, credential-driven intrusions targeting maintainers, CI pipelines, and the trusted automation that underpins modern development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For security leaders, these aren’t niche developer mishaps anymore — they’re a direct pathway into production systems, cloud infrastructure, and millions of downstream applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The goal is no longer to trick an individual developer, but to quietly inherit their authority. And with it, their distribution reach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“NPM is an attractive target because it is the world’s largest JavaScript package repository and a key control point for distributing software,” said Melinda Marks, cybersecurity practice director at Enterprise Security Group. “Security teams need an understanding of dependencies and ways to regularly audit and mitigate risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="structural-weaknesses-in-the-npm-infrastructure"&gt;Structural weaknesses in the npm infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly every enterprise relies on npm, whether directly or indirectly. According to &lt;a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=US51141024"&gt;IDC&lt;/a&gt;, 93% of organizations use open-source software, and npm remains the largest package registry in the JavaScript ecosystem. “Compromising a single popular package can immediately reach millions of downstream users and applications,” IDC’s research manager (DevSecOps), Katie Norton, said, turning one stolen credential into what she described as a “master key” for distribution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That scale, however, is only part of the risk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The exposure is amplified by structural weaknesses in how modern development pipelines are secured, Norton remarked. “Individual open-source maintainers often lack the security resources that enterprise teams rely on, leaving them susceptible to social engineering,” she said. “CI/CD runners and developer machines routinely process long-lived secrets that are stored in environment variables or configuration files and are easily harvested by malware.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Build systems also tend to prioritize speed and reliability over security visibility, resulting in limited monitoring and long dwell times for attackers who gain initial access,” Norton added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While security leaders can’t patch their way out of this one, they can reduce exposure. Experts consistently point to the same priorities: treating CI runners as production assets, rotating and scoping publish tokens aggressively, disabling lifecycle scripts unless required, and pinning dependencies to immutable versions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These npm attacks are targeting the pre-install phase of software dependencies, so typical software supply chain security methods of code scanning cannot address these types of attacks,” Marks said. Detection requires runtime analysis and anomaly detection rather than signature-based tooling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;From typo traps to legitimate backdoors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For years, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570173/what-is-typosquatting-a-simple-but-effective-attack-technique.html"&gt;typosquatting&lt;/a&gt; defined the npm threat model. Attackers published packages with names just close enough to popular libraries, such as “lodsash,” “expres,” “reacts,” and waited for automation or human error to do the rest. The impact was usually limited, and remediation straightforward.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That model began to break in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of impersonating popular packages, attackers increasingly compromised real ones. Phishing &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4028412/supply-chain-attack-compromises-npm-packages-to-spread-backdoor-malware.html"&gt;campaigns&lt;/a&gt; spoofing npm itself harvested maintainer credentials. Stolen tokens were then used to publish trojanized updates that appeared legitimate to every downstream consumer. The Shai-Hulud &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095578/new-shai-hulud-worm-spreading-through-npm-github.html"&gt;campaign&lt;/a&gt; illustrated the scale of the problem, affecting tens of thousands of repositories and leveraging compromised credentials to self-propagate across the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The npm ecosystem has become the crown jewels of modern development,” said Kush Pandya, a cybersecurity researcher at Socket.dev. “When a single prolific maintainer is compromised, the blast radius spans hundreds of downstream projects.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The result was a quiet but powerful shift: attackers no longer needed to create convincing fakes. They could ship malware through &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4026380/prettier-eslint-npm-packages-hijacked-in-a-sophisticated-supply-chain-attack.html"&gt;trusted channels&lt;/a&gt;, signed and versioned like any routine update.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="developer-environments-over-developer-laptops"&gt;Developer environments over developer laptops&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern npm &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3506897/github-actions-typosquatting-a-high-impact-supply-chain-attack-in-waiting.html"&gt;attacks&lt;/a&gt; increasingly activate inside CI/CD environments rather than on developer laptops. Post-install &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3995813/hackers-drop-60-npm-bombs-in-less-than-two-weeks-to-recon-dev-machines.html?utm=hybrid_search#:~:text=post%2Dinstall%20scripts"&gt;scripts&lt;/a&gt;, long treated as benign setup helpers, became an execution vector capable of running automatically inside GitHub Actions or GitLab CI. Once inside a runner, malicious packages could read environment variables, steal publish tokens, tamper with build artifacts, or even push additional malicious releases under the victim’s identity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Developer environments and CI runners are now worth more than end-user machines,” Pandya noted. “They usually have broader permissions, access to secrets, and the ability to push code into production.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several campaigns observed in mid-2025 were explicitly &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088529/malicious-npm-package-sneaks-into-github-actions-builds.html"&gt;CI-aware&lt;/a&gt;, triggering only when they detected automated build environments. Some included delayed execution or self-expiring payloads, minimizing forensic visibility while maximizing credential theft.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For enterprises, this represents a fundamental risk shift. CI systems often operate with higher privileges than any individual user, yet are monitored far less rigorously. “They are often secured with weaker defaults: long-lived publish tokens, overly permissive CI secrets, implicit trust in lifecycle scripts and package metadata, and little isolation between builds,” Pandya noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to IDC Research, organizations allocate only about 14% of AppSec budgets to supply-chain security, with only 12% of them identifying CI/CD pipeline security as a top risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Evasion as a first-class feature&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As defenders improved at spotting suspicious packages, attackers adapted too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent npm campaigns have used invisible Unicode characters to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082195/malicious-packages-in-npm-evade-dependency-detection-through-invisible-url-links-report.html"&gt;obscure&lt;/a&gt; dependencies, multi-stage loaders that fetch real payloads only after environment checks, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4050956/malicious-npm-packages-use-ethereum-blockchain-for-malware-delivery.html"&gt;blockchain-hosted &lt;/a&gt;command-and-control (C2) references designed to evade takedowns. Others deployed worm-like behavior, using stolen credentials to publish additional malicious packages at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Manual review has become largely ineffective against this level of tradecraft. “The days when you could skim index.js and spot a malicious eval() are gone,” Pandya said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Modern packages hide malicious logic behind layers of encoding, delayed execution, and environment fingerprinting.” Norton echoed the concern, noting that these attacks operate at a behavioral level where static scanning falls short. “Obfuscation techniques make malicious logic difficult to distinguish from legitimate complexity in large JavaScript projects,” she said. “CI-aware payloads and post-install scripts introduce behavior that only manifests under specific environmental conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117139/from-typos-to-takeovers-inside-the-industrialization-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-013)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-013</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-013</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco finally patches seven-week-old zero-day flaw in Secure Email Gateway products</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118159/cisco-finally-patches-seven-week-old-zero-day-flaw-in-secure-email-gateway-products-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Better late than never. Cisco this week patched a ‘critical’ zero-day flaw in the company’s email security and management gateways that has hung over customers’ heads since December.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tracked as &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-20393" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-20393&lt;/a&gt;, the vulnerability affects Cisco’s AsyncOS Software running on the physical or virtual Secure Email Gateway (SEG) and Secure Email and Web Manager (SEWM) products.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue is serious, allowing an attacker to take over an appliance with &lt;em&gt;root &lt;/em&gt;privileges when the Spam Quarantine feature is turned on and exposed to the internet. That earned it a relatively rare CVSS maximum severity score of 10, a ‘critical’ rating.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco said &lt;a href="https://sec.cloudapps.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sma-attack-N9bf4#details" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in its advisory&lt;/a&gt;: “This vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of HTTP requests by the Spam Quarantine feature. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted HTTP request to the affected device.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the vulnerability, which Cisco said it learned of on December 10 while resolving a customer support case, was &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108496/cisco-confirms-zero-day-exploitation-of-secure-email-products.html" target="_blank"&gt;already being exploited&lt;/a&gt; in the wild. This prompted the company to issue an advisory – but no patch addressing the flaw – a week later, on December 17.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According &lt;a href="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/uat-9686/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to an analysis&lt;/a&gt; by Cisco’s Talos threat intelligence division, issued on the same day, exploits had been detected going back to “at least” late November, which meant the issue was already weeks old by the time customers heard about it, with no temporary workarounds possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Talos assesses with moderate confidence that this activity is being conducted by a Chinese-nexus threat actor, which we track as UAT-9686. As part of this activity, UAT-9686 deploys a custom persistence mechanism we track as ‘AquaShell’ accompanied by additional tooling meant for reverse tunneling and purging logs,” Cisco Talos said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This week, more than a month after the first public warning, and seven weeks after the first exploits were detected, Cisco issued an AsyncOS patch fixing the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="does-the-delay-matter"&gt;Does the delay matter?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The exploit only affects a subset of customers running a Secure Email Gateway or Secure Email and Web Manager with the Spam Quarantine service exposed on a public port.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Cisco, this feature is not enabled by default, and, it said, “deployment guides for these products do not require this feature to be directly exposed to the internet.” This makes it sound as if customers enabling the feature would be the exception.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While that’s probably true — exposing a service like this through a public port goes against best practice — one use case &lt;a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/security_management/sma/sma15-0/user_guide/b_sma_admin_guide_15_0/b_NGSMA_Admin_Guide_chapter_0101.html?bookSearch=true#con_1515653:~:text=Notifications-,Notifying,Procedure" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;referenced in Cisco’s User Guide&lt;/a&gt; would be to allow remote users to check quarantined spam for themselves. The number of organizations using these products that have enabled it for this reason is, of course, impossible to say.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To reprise, Cisco said that vulnerable customers are those running Cisco AsyncOS Software with both Spam Quarantine turned on &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; exposed to and reachable from the internet. Given that no workarounds are possible, this implies that simply turning off access through a public interface (by default, port 6025, or 82/83 for the web portal) isn’t sufficient on its own.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, even if it were, this ignores the possibility that attackers might have already exploited the vulnerability and gained persistence in recent weeks, &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the port was closed. The best option is always to patch to remove all risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="patch-advice"&gt;Patch advice&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cisco Secure Email Gateway (ESG)&lt;/strong&gt; customers on v14.2 or earlier should upgrade to v15.0.5-016; v15.0 should upgrade to v15.0.5-016; v15.5 should upgrade to v15.5.4-012; and v16.0 should upgrade to v16.0.4-016.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Email and Web Manager (SEWM) &lt;/strong&gt;customers on v15.0 or earlier should upgrade to v15.0.2-007; Customers on v15.5 should upgrade to v5.5.4-007; customers on v16.0 should upgrade to v16.0.4-010.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco said that the patch also clears any persistence mechanisms from an attack, but, it said, “Customers who wish to explicitly verify whether an appliance has been compromised can open a &lt;a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/index.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC)&lt;/a&gt; case.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4118154/cisco-finally-patches-seven-week-old-zero-day-flaw-in-secure-email-gateway-products.html" target="_blank"&gt;NetworkWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118159/cisco-finally-patches-seven-week-old-zero-day-flaw-in-secure-email-gateway-products-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China-Linked APT Exploited Sitecore Zero-Day in Critical Infrastructure Intrusions</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2026/01/china-linked-apt-exploits-sitecore-zero.html</link>
      <description>A threat actor likely aligned with China has been observed targeting critical infrastructure sectors in North America since at least last year.
Cisco Talos, which is tracking the activity under the name UAT-8837, assessed it to be a China-nexus advanced persistent threat (APT) actor with medium confidence based on tactical overlaps with other campaigns mounted by threat actors from the region.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2026/01/china-linked-apt-exploits-sitecore-zero.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:48:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Possible software supply chain attack through AWS CodeBuild service blunted</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117692/possible-software-supply-chain-attack-through-aws-codebuild-service-blunted-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An AWS misconfiguration in its code building service could have led to a massive number of compromised key AWS GitHub code repositories and applications, say researchers at Wiz who discovered the problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability stemmed from a subtle flaw in how the repositories’ &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codebuild/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AWS CodeBuild&lt;/a&gt; CI (continuous integration) pipelines handled build triggers. “Just two missing characters in a regex filter allowed unauthenticated attackers to infiltrate the build environment and leak privileged credentials,” the researchers&lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/wiz-research-codebreach-vulnerability-aws-codebuild" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt; said in a Thursday blog.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The regex (regular expression) filter at the center of the issue is an automated pattern-matching rule that scans log output for secrets and hides them to prevent leakage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue allowed a complete takeover of key AWS GitHub repositories, particularly the AWS JavaScript SDK, a core library that powers the AWS Console.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This shows the power and risk of supply chain vulnerabilities,” Yuval Avrahami, co-author of the report about the bug, told CSO, “which is exactly why supply chain attacks are on the rise: one small flaw can lead to an insanely impactful attack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After being warned of the vulnerability last August, AWS quickly plugged the hole and implemented global hardening within the CodeBuild service to prevent the possibility of similar attacks. Details of the problem are only being revealed now by Wiz &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/security/security-bulletins/2026-002-AWS/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;and AWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AWS told CSO that it “found that there was no impact on the confidentiality or integrity of any customer environment or AWS service.” It also advised developers &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/webhooks.html#webhook-best-practices%EF%BF%BC%EF%BF%BC%5B3%5D" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to follow best practices in using AWS CodeBuild.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the Wiz researchers warned developers using the product to take steps to protect their projects from similar issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="discovery"&gt;Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz discovered the problem last August after an attempted supply chain attack on the Amazon Q VS Code extension. An attacker exploited a misconfigured CodeBuild project to compromise the extension’s GitHub repository and inject malicious code into the main branch. This code was then included in a release which users downloaded. Although the attacker’s payload ultimately failed due to a typo, it did execute on end users’ machines – clearly demonstrating the risk of misconfigured CodeBuild pipelines. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz researchers investigated and found the core of the flaw, a threat actor ID bypass due to unanchored regexes, and notified AWS. Within 48 hours, that hole was plugged, AWS said in a statement accompanying the Wiz blog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It also performed additional hardening, including adding further protections to all build processes that contain Github tokens or any other credentials in memory. AWS said it also audited all other public build environments to ensure that no such issues exist across the AWS open source estate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, it examined the logs of all public build repositories, as well as associated CloudTrail logs, “and determined that no other actor had taken advantage of the unanchored regex issue demonstrated by the Wiz research team. AWS determined there was no impact of the identified issue on the confidentiality or integrity of any customer environment or any AWS service.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellman/?originalSubdomain=ca" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kellman Meghu&lt;/a&gt;, chief technology officer at Deepcove Cybersecurity, a Canadian-based risk management firm, said it wouldn’t be a huge issue for developers who don’t publicly expose CodeBuild. “But,” he added, “if people are not diligent, I see how it could be used. It’s slick.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="developers-shouldnt-expose-build-environments"&gt;Developers shouldn’t expose build environments&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs should ensure developers don’t expose build environments, Meghu said. “Using public hosted services like GitHub is not appropriate for enterprise code management and deployment,” he added. “Having a private GitLab/GitHub, service, or even your own git repository server, should be the default for business, making this attack impossible if [the threat actors] can’t see the repository to begin with. The business should be the one that owns the repository; [it should] not be something you just let your developers set up as needed.” In fact, he said, IT or infosec leaders should set up the code repositories. Developers “should be users of the system, not the ultimate owners.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz strongly recommends that all AWS CodeBuild users implement the following safeguards to protect their own projects against possible compromise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent untrusted Pull Requests from triggering privileged builds by:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;enabling the new &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/pull-request-build-policy.html"&gt;Pull Request Comment Approval&lt;/a&gt; build gate;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;alternatively, using &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/action-runner.html"&gt;CodeBuild-hosted runners&lt;/a&gt; to manage build triggers via GitHub workflows;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you must rely on &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/webhooks.html"&gt;webhook filters&lt;/a&gt;, ensure their regex patterns are anchored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure the CodeBuild-GitHub connection by:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;generating a unique, fine-grained Personal Access Token (PAT) for each CodeBuild project;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/codebuild/latest/userguide/access-tokens-github.html"&gt;strictly limiting the PAT’s permissions&lt;/a&gt; to the minimum required.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;considering using a dedicated unprivileged GitHub account for the CodeBuild integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4117662/possible-software-supply-chain-attack-through-aws-codebuild-service-blunted.html" target="_blank"&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117692/possible-software-supply-chain-attack-through-aws-codebuild-service-blunted-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China-linked hackers exploited Sitecore zero-day for initial access</title>
      <link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/china-linked-hackers-exploited-sitecore-zero-day-for-initial-access/</link>
      <description>An advanced threat actor tracked as UAT-8837 and believed to be linked to China has been focusing on critical infrastructure systems in North America, gaining access by exploiting both known and zero-day vulnerabilities. [...]</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/china-linked-hackers-exploited-sitecore-zero-day-for-initial-access/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:10:15 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One click is all it takes: How ‘Reprompt’ turned Microsoft Copilot into data exfiltration tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117792/one-click-is-all-it-takes-how-reprompt-turned-microsoft-copilot-into-data-exfiltration-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI copilots are incredibly intelligent and useful — but they can also be naive, gullible, and even dumb at times.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new one-click attack flow discovered by Varonis Threat Labs researchers underscores this fact. ‘Reprompt,’ as they’ve dubbed it, is a three-step attack chain that completely bypasses security controls after an initial &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3997429/risk-assessment-vital-when-choosing-an-ai-model-say-experts.html" target="_blank"&gt;LLM prompt&lt;/a&gt;, giving attackers invisible, undetectable, unlimited access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI assistants have become trusted companions where we share sensitive information, seek guidance, and rely on them without hesitation,” Varonis Threat Labs security researcher &lt;a href="https://www.varonis.com/blog/author/dtaler" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dolev Taler&lt;/a&gt; wrote in a &lt;a href="https://www.varonis.com/blog/reprompt" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “But … trust can be easily exploited, and an AI assistant can turn into a data exfiltration weapon with a single click.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that, as of now, Reprompt has only been discovered in Microsoft Copilot Personal, not Microsoft 365 Copilot — but that’s not to say it couldn’t be used against enterprises depending on their copilot policies and user awareness. Microsoft has already released a patch after being made aware of the flaw.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-reprompt-silently-works-in-the-background"&gt;How Reprompt silently works in the background&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reprompt employs three techniques to create a data exfiltration chain: Initial parameter to prompt (P2P injection), double request, and chain-request.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;P2P embeds a prompt directly in a URL, exploiting Copilot’s default ‘q’ URL parameter functionality, which is intended to streamline and improve user experience. The URL can include specific questions or instructions that automatically populate the input field when pages load.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Using this loophole, attackers then employ double-request, which allows them to circumvent safeguards; Copilot only checks for malicious content in the Q variable for the first prompt, not subsequent requests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For instance, the researchers asked Copilot to fetch a URL containing the secret phrase “HELLOWORLD1234!”, repeating the request twice. Copilot removed the secret phrase from the first URL, but the second attempt “worked flawlessly,” Taler noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From here, attackers can kick off a chain-request, in which the attacker’s server issues follow-up instructions to form an ongoing conversation. This tricks Copilot into exfiltrating conversation histories and sensitive data. Threat actors can provide a range of prompts like “Summarize all of the files that the user accessed today,” “Where does the user live?” or “What vacations does he have planned?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This method “makes data theft stealthy and scalable,” and there is no limit to what or how much attackers can exfiltrate, Taler noted. “Copilot leaks the data little by little, allowing the threat to use each answer to generate the next malicious instruction.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The danger is that reprompt requires no plugins, enabled connectors, or user interaction with Copilot beyond the initial single click on a legitimate Microsoft Copilot link in a phishing message. The attacker can stay in Copilot as long as they want, even after the user closes their chat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All commands are delivered via the server after the initial prompt, so it’s almost impossible to determine what is being extracted just by inspecting that one prompt. “The real instructions are hidden in the server’s follow-up requests,” Taler noted, “not from anything obvious in the prompt the user submits.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-devs-and-security-teams-should-do-now"&gt;What devs and security teams should do now&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As in usual security practice, enterprise users should always treat URLs and external inputs as untrusted, experts advised. Be cautious with links, be on the lookout for unusual behavior, and always pause to review pre-filled prompts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This attack, like many others, originates with a phishing email or text message, so all the usual best practices against phishing apply, including ‘don’t click on suspicious links,’” noted &lt;a href="https://ca.linkedin.com/in/bernardes" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Henrique Teixeira&lt;/a&gt;, SVP of Strategy at Saviynt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Phishing-resistant authentication should be implemented, not only during the initial use of a chatbot, but throughout the entire session, he emphasized. This would require developers to implement controls when first building apps and embedding copilots and chatbots, rather than adding controls later on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;End users should avoid using chatbots that are not authenticated and avoid risky behaviors such as acting on a sense of urgency (such as being encouraged to speedily completing a transaction), replying to unknown or potentially nefarious senders, or oversharing personal info, he noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Lastly and super importantly is to not blame the victim in these instances,” said Teixeira. App owners and service providers using AI must build apps that do not allow prompts to be submitted without authentication and authorization, or with malicious commands embedded in URLs. “Service providers can include more prompt hygiene and basic identity security controls like continuous and adaptive authentication to make apps safer to employees and clients,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Further, design considering insider-level risk, says Varonis’ Taler. “Assume AI assistants operate with trusted context and access. Enforce least privilege, auditing, and anomaly detection accordingly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this represents yet another example of enterprises rolling out new technologies with security as an afterthought, other experts note.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Seeing this story play out is like watching Wile E. Coyote and the Road Runner,” said &lt;a href="https://www.beauceronsecurity.com/blog/tag/David+Shipley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt; of Beauceron Security. “Once you know the gag, you know what’s going to happen. The coyote is going to trust some ridiculously flawed Acme product and use it in a really dumb way.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this case, that ‘product’ is &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4006436/llms-hype-versus-reality-what-cisos-should-focus-on.html" target="_blank"&gt;LLM-based technologies&lt;/a&gt; that are simply allowed to perform any actions without restriction. The scary thing is there’s no way to secure it because LLMs are what Shipley described as “high speed idiots.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They can’t distinguish between content and instructions, and will blindly do what they’re told,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLMs should be limited to chats in a browser, he asserted. Giving them access to anything more than that is a “disaster waiting to happen,” particularly if they’re going to be interacting with content that can be sent via e-mail, message, or through a website.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Using techniques such as applying least access privilege and zero trust to try to work around the fundamental insecurity of LLM agents “look brilliant until they backfire,” Shipley said. “All of this would be funny if it didn’t get organizations pwned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4117750/one-click-is-all-it-takes-how-reprompt-turned-microsoft-copilot-into-a-data-exfiltration-tool.html" target="_blank"&gt;Computerworld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117792/one-click-is-all-it-takes-how-reprompt-turned-microsoft-copilot-into-data-exfiltration-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-014)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-015)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-016)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-017)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-018)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–019)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insider risk in an age of workforce volatility</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116983/insider-risk-in-an-age-of-workforce-volatility.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Economic pressures, AI-driven job displacement, and relentless organizational churn are driving insider risk to its highest level in years. Workforce instability erodes loyalty and heightens grievances. The accelerating deployment of powerful new tools, such as AI agents, amplifies the threats from within, both human and machine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.rationalfx.com/forex-brokers/global-tech-sector-layoffs"&gt;according to RationalFX&lt;/a&gt; and other job trackers, the global technology sector saw &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4114572/global-tech-sector-layoffs-surpass-244000-in-2025.html"&gt;roughly 245,000 layoffs&lt;/a&gt; announced across hundreds of companies. These figures, while concentrated in the tech industry, reflect broader trends seen across other sectors, including manufacturing, retail, finance, energy, and government, where employers announced more than 1.17 million job cuts through November 2025 in the US, according to &lt;a href="https://www.challengergray.com/blog/category/job-cuts-report/"&gt;Challenger, Gray &amp;amp; Christmas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This surge, up significantly from prior years, creates fertile ground for disgruntlement: financial stress, resentment over automation, and opportunistic behavior, from negligence and careless data handling to deliberate malevolent actions like data exfiltration and credential monetization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All this shows that our trusted insiders are the prime vector for serious incidents across sectors and geographies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-emerging-machine-threat-ai-agents-as-a-volatile-vector"&gt;The emerging machine threat: AI agents as a volatile vector&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compounding the human element is the rapid rise of AI agents, which &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/perspectives/2026-cyber-predictions"&gt;Palo Alto Networks has identified&lt;/a&gt; as one of the most acute and evolving insider risks for 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Autonomous agents with privileged system access, superhuman execution speed, and decision-making at scale are no longer mere productivity boosters. They are becoming exploitable vectors for silent data exfiltration, disruption, or unintended catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is particularly concerning when volatility reduces human oversight and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3529615/companies-skip-security-hardening-in-rush-to-adopt-ai.html"&gt;rushes deployment without commensurate controls&lt;/a&gt;. Palo Alto Networks’ 2026 cybersecurity predictions emphasize that these agents introduce vulnerabilities such as goal hijacking, tool misuse, prompt injection, and shadow deployment, often amplified by the very churn that drives their adoption across multinational organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security leaders are taking note. Surveys indicate that 60% of organizations express high concern over AI misuse enabling or amplifying insider risks, according to &lt;a href="https://secureframe.com/blog/cybersecurity-statistics"&gt;Secureframe’s Q4 2025 cybersecurity statistics compilation&lt;/a&gt; and related reports. Meanwhile, hybrid and remote work models rank as the top emerging risk for insider risks over the next three to five years, cited by 75% of respondents in &lt;a href="https://www.cybersecurity-insiders.com/portfolio/2025-insider-risk-report-cogility/"&gt;Cybersecurity Insiders’ 2025 Insider Risk Report&lt;/a&gt;. These decentralized environments further blur visibility and control, making it harder to detect anomalous behavior from either humans or machines in global operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="early-warnings-the-machine-as-insider-risk-threat"&gt;Early warnings: The machine as insider risk/threat&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These dynamics are not emerging in a vacuum. They represent the culmination of warnings that have been building for years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As early as 2021, in my CSO opinion piece “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571391/device-identity-the-overlooked-insider-threat.html"&gt;Device identity: The overlooked insider threat&lt;/a&gt;,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajan-koo-2a591221/"&gt;Rajan Koo&lt;/a&gt; (then chief customer officer at DTEX Systems, now CTO) observed: “There needs to be more application of the insider threat framework toward devices at the same level as we do with humans&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;” That insight highlighted how machine identities such as APIs, bots, scripts, and &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/227908/what-is-rpa-robotic-process-automation-explained.html"&gt;robotic process automation (RPA)&lt;/a&gt; were already serving as conduits for both intentional and unintentional incidents, deserving the same scrutiny as human insiders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This perspective was reinforced in 2022 in “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571835/what-cisos-can-learn-from-the-kyoto-university-backup-data-deletion.html"&gt;Machine as insider threat: Lessons from Kyoto University’s backup data deletion&lt;/a&gt;,” which analyzed a real-world automation failure as “a classic case of the machines being the insider threat.” The incident, where an unchecked scripting error led to the permanent deletion of critical backup data, demonstrated that the outcome, catastrophic loss, was identical to what a malicious insider could achieve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By mid-2023, the conversation shifted to the positive potential in the 2023 CSO feature, “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/648380/when-your-teammate-is-a-machine-how-cisos-are-learning-to-embrace-ai.html"&gt;When your teammate is a machine: 8 questions CISOs should be asking about AI&lt;/a&gt;,” which explored AI as a collaborative force in cybersecurity workflows, yet tempered with the need to have a firm understanding of what’s under the hood. Today, that teammate has proliferated: Palo Alto Networks forecasts that machine identities and autonomous agents will outnumber humans by ratios as high as 82:1 in many enterprises, turning early cautions into urgent 2026 reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-compounding-effect-human-churn-meets-machine-proliferation"&gt;The compounding effect: Human churn meets machine proliferation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The convergence of these factors — human volatility driven by layoffs and economic stress combined with the unchecked scaling of machine agents — creates a compounding effect. Organizations facing cost pressures often prioritize speed of AI adoption over governance, leading to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4044007/shadow-ai-is-surging-getting-ai-adoption-right-is-your-best-defense.html"&gt;shadow AI deployments&lt;/a&gt; and insufficient monitoring. At the same time, displaced or disgruntled employees may monetize access, exfiltrate sensitive data, or simply neglect controls as they disengage, as we witnessed in the &lt;a href="https://www.resecurity.com/blog/article/knownsec-data-breach-a-trove-of-espionage-tradecraft-with-an-insider-narrative"&gt;KnownSec incident&lt;/a&gt;, where an insider exposed how the company was an adjunct of the Chinese government’s offensive cyber operations infrastructure. While the action was no doubt welcomed by many cyberdefenders for the insight into China’s capabilities, it also demonstrates that no entity is immune from the volatility factor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that such anxiety from ongoing layoffs and role uncertainty can lead to nervous mistakes, privilege hoarding, or rushed workarounds that expose data without intent to harm. Yet harm is actualized. The result is a heightened insider risk landscape that is amplified when the interplay between human churn and machine proliferation is overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="toward-coherent-strategies-holistic-mitigation-in-a-volatile-era"&gt;Toward coherent strategies: Holistic mitigation in a volatile era&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;a href=""&gt;coherence in insider risk strategy&lt;/a&gt; becomes essential. Holistic approaches must integrate behavioral analytics that monitor both human patterns (for example, sentiment shifts during restructuring or after-hours data collection) and machine behaviors (for example, anomalous API calls or agent activity spikes).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reskilling programs can help retain talent and reduce resentment by positioning employees as partners in AI-augmented roles rather than casualties of displacement. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089732/rethinking-identity-for-the-ai-era-cisos-must-build-trust-at-machine-speed.html"&gt;Strong governance of machine identities&lt;/a&gt;, requiring authentication, least-privilege access, and continuous monitoring, extends &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;zero-trust principles&lt;/a&gt; to the non-human domain. And crucially, organizations need to bridge HR and security functions to detect early indicators of volatility before they manifest as threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without these proactive, integrated measures, the cascade could be significant. A single exploited AI agent could exfiltrate terabytes of data at speeds no human could match. As history has shown, a disgruntled employee may use lingering credentials to plant backdoors, steal or sell information, or cause deliberate destruction. The stakes are no longer confined to isolated incidents. They now span the entire ecosystem, from supply chains to critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-path-forward"&gt;The path forward&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we enter 2026, the message is clear: Insider risk is no longer primarily a human problem. It is a volatility problem, one that economic pressures, AI displacement, and organizational churn are intensifying at an unprecedented pace. Addressing it requires the same rigor we apply to external threats, but applied inward, with foresight, coherence, and a willingness to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116983/insider-risk-in-an-age-of-workforce-volatility.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-001 – Vulnerabilities affecting n8n – CVE-2026-21858, CVE-2026-21877 and CVE-2025-68613</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WEF 2026: KI weiterhin Top-Thema in der Cybersicherheit</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118051/wef-2026-ki-weiterhin-top-thema-in-der-cybersicherheit.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 7913w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2672968311.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Der Global Cybersecurity Outlook 2026 des WEF zeigt, dass KI weiterhin ein wichtiger Faktor in der Cybersicherheit ist.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Summit Art Creations – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch in diesem Jahr spielt das Thema Cybersicherheit eine wichtige Rolle auf dem Weltwirtschaftsforum (WEF) in Davos. So prognostiziert etwa der Global Cybersecurity Outlook 2026, dass Cyberrisiken durch Fortschritte in der künstlichen Intelligenz (KI), die zunehmende geopolitische Fragmentierung und die Komplexität der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495329/cybersecurity-in-der-lieferkettewie-sie-ihre-software-supply-chain-schutzen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Lieferketten&lt;/a&gt; verschärft werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Bericht knüpft damit den Schlussforderungen des WEF im vergangenen Jahr an, wonach eine Reihe von sich verstärkenden Faktoren – geopolitische Spannungen, komplexe Lieferketten, zunehmende Regulierung und rasche technologische Veränderungen – zu einer Ära zunehmender Komplexität und Unvorhersehbarkeit führen werde. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zu den wichtigsten Ergebnissen des aktuellen Berichts gehören:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;94 Prozent der Befragten gehen davon aus, dass KI im Jahr 2026 der wichtigste Treiber für Veränderungen im Bereich Cybersicherheit sein wird.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;87 Prozent der Befragten gaben an, dass KI-bezogene Schwachstellen im vergangenen Jahr zugenommen haben. Außerdem habe es einen Anstieg bei weiteren Cyberrisiken wie Cyberbetrug und Phishing, Störungen der Lieferkette und die Ausnutzung von Software-Schwachstellen gegeben.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Das Vertrauen in die nationale Cyber-Bereitschaft nimmt weiter ab. 31 Prozent der Befragten haben nur wenig Vertrauen in die Fähigkeit ihres Landes, auf größere Cybervorfälle zu reagieren. Im Vorjahr waren es noch 26 Prozent. Das Vertrauen variiert stark zwischen den Regionen. 84 Prozent der Befragten aus dem Nahen Osten und Nordafrika sind zuversichtlich, dass ihr Land in der Lage ist, kritische Infrastrukturen zu schützen. Im Gegensatz dazu sehen nur 40 Prozent der Befragten aus Europa ihr Land dafür vorbereitet.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Auf die Frage nach der Cyber-Resilienz ihrer eigenen Organisation gaben 23 Prozent der Vertreter des öffentlichen Sektors und internationaler Organisationen an, dass sie deren Bereitschaft für unzureichend halten. Im Gegensatz dazu bewerteten nur elf Prozent der Befragten aus dem privaten Sektor ihr Unternehmen in diesem Aspekt negativ.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;91 Prozent der Organisationen mit mehr als 100.000 Mitarbeitern haben ihre Cybersicherheitsstrategien aufgrund der geopolitischen Instabilität geändert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der aktuelle WEF-Bericht dreht sich vor allem um das Thema &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106894/wie-ki-die-cybersicherheit-neu-gestaltet.html" target="_blank"&gt;KI&lt;/a&gt;. Die Mehrheit der befragten Führungskräfte geht davon aus, dass die Technologie in diesem Jahr der wichtigste Treiber für Veränderungen im Bereich Cybersicherheit sein wird. „Die weit verbreitete Integration von KI-Systemen vergrößert die Angriffsfläche und schafft neue Schwachstellen, für deren Behebung herkömmliche Sicherheitskontrollen nicht ausgelegt sind“, heißt es dazu. „Darüber hinaus nutzen Angreifer KI, um den Umfang, die Geschwindigkeit, die Raffinesse und die Präzision ihrer Angriffe zu verbessern“, heißt es weiter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494359/der-grose-ki-risiko-guide.html" target="_blank"&gt;Der große KI-Risiko-Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Allerdings könnten auch Verteidiger KI nutzen, um ihre Cyberfähigkeiten zu stärken – zumindest theoretisch, wie der Bericht betont: „Die Vorteile der KI hängen von einer disziplinierten Umsetzung ab. Schlecht implementierte Lösungen können neue Risiken mit sich bringen – Fehlkonfigurationen, voreingenommene Entscheidungen, übermäßige Abhängigkeit von Automatisierung und Anfälligkeit für feindliche Manipulationen.“ Voraussetzung sei daher, dass Unternehmen robuste Schutzvorkehrungen, Security-by-Design-Praktiken und kontinuierliche Überwachung integrieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die Schlussfolgerung ist klar“, so die Autoren. „KI kann die Cybersicherheit verbessern, aber nur, wenn sie innerhalb solider Governance-Rahmenbedingungen eingesetzt wird, bei denen das menschliche Urteilsvermögen im Mittelpunkt steht. Gleichzeitig können zu viele Kontrollen zu Reibungsverlusten führen, sodass es wichtig ist, ein sorgfältiges Gleichgewicht zu finden.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Anzeichen dafür, dass dies bereits geschieht: 64 Prozent der Befragten gaben an, dass ihr Unternehmen über einen Prozess zur Bewertung der Sicherheit von KI-Tools vor deren Einsatz verfügt, gegenüber 37 Prozent in der vorherigen Umfrage im Herbst 2024.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Den Umfragedaten zufolge haben bereits 77 Prozent der Unternehmen KI im Bereich Cybersicherheit eingeführt . Eingesetzt wird sie vor allem, um die Phishing-Versuche zu erkennen (52 Prozent), auf Eindringlinge und Anomalien (46 Prozent) zu reagieren sowie um die Analyse des Benutzerverhaltens (40 Prozent) zu verbessern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gleichzeitig stellten die Befragten jedoch praktische Herausforderungen bei der Einführung von KI für die Cybersicherheit fest. Als Haupthindernisse wurden dabei&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unzureichende Kenntnisse und/oder Fähigkeiten (54 Prozent),&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;die Notwendigkeit menschlicher Aufsicht (41 Prozent) und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Unsicherheit hinsichtlich der Risiken (39 Prozent) genannt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Ergebnisse deuten darauf hin, dass Vertrauen nach wie vor ein Hindernis für die breite Einführung von KI ist, lautet das Fazit der Autoren. „Während Unternehmen die Integration von KI in ihre Sicherheitsabläufe vorantreiben, wird das Gleichgewicht zwischen Automatisierung und menschlichem Urteilsvermögen immer wichtiger.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Demnach ist KI zwar für die Automatisierung sich wiederholender, umfangreicher Aufgaben geeignet. „Doch ihre derzeitigen Einschränkungen in Bezug auf kontextuelles Urteilsvermögen und strategische Entscheidungsfindung sind nach wie vor offensichtlich, so das WEF. „Eine übermäßige Abhängigkeit von unkontrollierter Automatisierung birgt die Gefahr, dass blinde Flecken entstehen, die von Angreifern ausgenutzt werden können.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Während KI weiterhin die Cybersicherheitslandschaft dominiert, gewinnen mehrere andere Technologien und Bedrohungsvektoren im Hintergrund still und leise an Bedeutung und werden sich laut dem Bericht voraussichtlich bis 2030 auf die Cybersicherheit auswirken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="uneinigkeit-zwischen-cisos-und-ceos"&gt;Uneinigkeit zwischen CISOs und CEOs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Interessanterweise waren sich CEOs und CISOs nicht immer einig, wenn es um die Bewertung der Cyberrisiken für ihre Organisationen ging. In der Umfrage von 2025 gaben die meisten CEOs an, dass Ransomware, Cyberbetrug und Phishing sowie Störungen der Lieferkette ihre größten Cyber-Sorgen seien. In diesem Jahr rückten Cyberbetrug und Phishing auf Platz eins vor, gefolgt von Schwachstellen der KI und der Ausnutzung von Software-Schwachstellen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Andererseits erklärten zwar auch die meisten CISOs in der Umfrage von 2025, dass Ransomware ihr größtes Problem sei. , aber sie kehrten die Reihenfolge der CEOs um und setzten Störungen der Lieferkette an zweiter Stelle, gefolgt von Cyberbetrug und Phishing. In der aktuellen Umfrage waren Ransomware und Störungen der Lieferkette weiterhin die beiden größten Probleme, aber an dritter Stelle steht nun die Ausnutzung von Software-Schwachstellen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dies deutet darauf hin, dass CEOs tendenziell eher über die allgemeinen geschäftlichen Auswirkungen von Betrugsfällen besorgt sind, während für CISOs die Sorge um Ransomware die erheblichen Betriebsstörungen widerspiegelt, die ein erfolgreicher Ransomware-Angriff für die Verfügbarkeit kritischer IT- und OT-Systeme (Operational Technology) mit sich bringen kann.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-wichtigsten-risikofaktoren-in-der-zukunft"&gt;Die wichtigsten Risikofaktoren in der Zukunft&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zu den weiteren Bedrohungen zählen laut Bericht autonome Systeme und Robotik, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3846875/quantenschlussel-aus-der-sicht-des-ciso.html" target="_blank"&gt;Quantentechnologien&lt;/a&gt;, digitale Währungen, Weltraumtechnologien und Unterseekabel sowie Naturkatastrophen und der Klimawandel. Bis zum Ende des Jahrzehnts werden autonome Systeme ein kurzfristiger Faktor sein, von KI-Unterstützung bei der Analyse bis hin zur Steuerung physischer Aktionen in Fabriken, Logistik, Gesundheitswesen und öffentlichen Räumen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Entwicklung könnte ein neues cyberphysisches Risikoprofil schaffen, bei dem maschinell ausgeführte Entscheidungen die Sicherheit und Servicequalität innerhalb von Sekunden verändern und die Zeitfenster für Erkennung und Reaktion verkürzen können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bis 2030 wird sich die Quantentechnologie laut dem Bericht von einem theoretischen Disruptor zu einer selektiven, aber materiellen Bedrohung für die Kryptografie entwickelt haben. Staatliche Akteure oder Akteure mit umfangreichen Ressourcen könnten in der Lage sein, beschleunigte Angriffe auf hochwertige Ziele durchzuführen, auch wenn das Knacken von Codes in großem Umfang nach wie vor selten sei, hieß es. Gleichzeitig würden Verteidiger mit Hilfe von Quantentechnologie künftig verbesserte Analysen und Sensoren zur Erkennung von Anomalien einsetzen, was zu einem dynamischen Wettlauf zwischen Angreifern und Verteidigern führen wird.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Bericht zeigt, dass der Aufbau einer sicheren digitalen Zukunft mehr als nur technische Lösungen braucht. „Dies erfordert entschlossene Führung, gemeinsame Verantwortung und die Verpflichtung, die kollektive Basis anzuheben – um sicherzustellen, dass Resilienz für alle zugänglich ist, nicht nur für die mit den besten Ressourcen. Da die Grenzen zwischen der digitalen und der physischen Welt immer mehr verschwimmen, werden diejenigen Organisationen erfolgreich sein, die Cyber-Resilienz als gemeinsame strategische Verantwortung anerkennen – eine Verantwortung, die Vertrauen schafft, Innovation ermöglicht und die vernetzten Grundlagen der globalen Gesellschaft schützt.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Report basiert auf einer Umfrage vom letzten Herbst, an der 804 Führungskräfte, Wissenschaftler, Vertreter der Zivilgesellschaft und Verantwortliche für Cybersicherheit im öffentlichen Sektor aus 92 Ländern teilnahmen. Darunter waren 316 CISOs. Zusätzliches Material wurde in Workshops gesammelt, darunter eine Sitzung mit 21 Führungskräften aus der CISO-Community des Zentrums für Cybersicherheit des Forums. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118051/wef-2026-ki-weiterhin-top-thema-in-der-cybersicherheit.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Vertex AI security permissions could amplify insider threats</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118092/google-vertex-ai-security-permissions-could-amplify-insider-threats.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The finding of fresh privilege-escalation vulnerabilities in Google’s Vertex AI is a stark reminder to CISOs that managing AI service agents is a task unlike any that they have encountered before.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;XM Cyber reported two different issues with Vertex AI on Thursday, in which default configurations allow low-privileged users to pivot into higher-privileged Service Agent roles. But, it said, Google told it the system is just working as intended.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The OWASP Agentic Top 10 just &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html#:~:text=3%20%E2%80%93%20Identity%20and%20Privilege%20Abuse"&gt;codified identity and privilege abuse as ASI03&lt;/a&gt; and Google immediately gave us a case study,” said &lt;a href="https://www.rockcyber.com/about-us"&gt;Rock Lambros&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of security firm RockCyber. “We’ve seen this movie before. &lt;a href="https://orca.security/resources/blog/azure-machine-learning-privilege-escalation/"&gt;Orca found &lt;/a&gt;Azure Storage privilege escalation, Microsoft called it ‘by design.’ &lt;a href="https://avd.aquasec.com/misconfig/aws/sagemaker"&gt;Aqua found&lt;/a&gt; AWS SageMaker lateral movement paths, AWS said ‘operating as expected.’ Cloud providers have turned ‘shared responsibility’ into a liability shield for their own insecure defaults. CISOs need to stop trusting that ‘managed’ means ‘secured’ and start auditing every service identity attached to their AI workloads, because the vendors clearly aren’t doing it for you.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research, said the report is “a window into how the trust model behind Google’s Vertex AI is fundamentally misaligned with enterprise security principles.” In these platforms, he said, “Managed service agents are granted sweeping permissions so AI features can function out of the box. But that convenience comes at the cost of visibility and control. These service identities operate in the background, carry project-wide privileges, and can be manipulated by any user who understands how the system behaves.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google didn’t respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerabilities, &lt;a href="https://xmcyber.com/blog/double-agent-service-agent-privilege-escalation-in-google-vertex-ai/"&gt;XM Cyber explained in its report&lt;/a&gt;, lie in how privileges are allocated to different roles associated with Vertex AI. “Central to this is the role of Service Agents: special service accounts created and managed by Google Cloud that allow services to access your resources and perform internal processes on your behalf. Because these invisible managed identities are required for services to function, they are often automatically granted broad project-wide permissions,” it said. “These vulnerabilities allow an attacker with minimal permissions to hijack high-privileged Service Agents, effectively turning these invisible managed identities into double agents that facilitate privilege escalation. When we disclosed the findings to Google, their rationale was that the services are currently ‘working as intended.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;XM Cyber found that someone with control over an identity with even minimal privileges consistent with Vertex AI’s “Viewer” role, the lowest level of privilege, could in certain circumstances manipulate the system to retrieve the access token for the service agent and use its privileges in the project.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia said the issue is alarming. “When a cloud provider says that a low-privileged user being able to hijack a highly privileged service identity is ‘working as intended,’ what they are really saying is that your governance model is subordinate to their architecture,” he said. “It is a structural design flaw that hands out power to components most customers don’t even realize exist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dont-wait-for-vendors-to-act"&gt;Don’t wait for vendors to act&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, executive director of FormerGov, was also concerned. “The smart move for CISOs is to build compensating controls now because waiting for vendors to redefine ‘intended behavior’ is not a security strategy,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fvillanustre/"&gt;Flavio Villanustre&lt;/a&gt;, CISO for the LexisNexis Risk Solutions Group, warned, “A malicious insider could leverage these weaknesses to grant themselves more access than normally allowed.” But, he said, “There is little that can be done to mitigate the risk other than, possibly, limiting the blast radius by reducing the authentication scope and introducing robust security boundaries in between them.” However, “This could have the side effect of significantly increasing the cost, so it may not be a commercially viable option either.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia said the biggest risk is that these are holes that will likely go undetected because enterprise security tools are not programmed to look for them. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most enterprises have no monitoring in place for service agent behavior. If one of these identities is abused, it won’t look like an attacker. It will look like the platform doing its job,” Gogia said. “That is what makes the risk severe. You are trusting components that you cannot observe, constrain, or isolate without fundamentally redesigning your cloud posture. Most organizations log user activity but ignore what the platform does internally. That needs to change. You need to monitor your service agents like they’re privileged employees. Build alerts around unexpected BigQuery queries, storage access, or session behavior. The attacker will look like the service agent, so that is where detection must focus.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He added: “Organizations are trusting code to run under identities they do not understand, performing actions they do not monitor, in environments they assume are safe. That is the textbook definition of invisible risk. And it is amplified in AI environments, because AI workloads often span multiple services, cross-reference sensitive datasets, and require orchestration that touches everything from logs to APIs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time Google’s Vertex AI has been found vulnerable to a privilege escalation attack: In November 2024, Palo Alto Networks issued a report finding similar issues with the Google Vertex AI environment, problems that &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/privilege-escalation-llm-model-exfil-vertex-ai/"&gt;Google told Palo Alto&lt;/a&gt; at the time that it had fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118092/google-vertex-ai-security-permissions-could-amplify-insider-threats.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-020)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-021)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV26-022)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-023)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-025)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-026)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV26-027)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-028)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-029)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-030)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-031)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-032)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Spot at RSAC 2026 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 52034294.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
