<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-725)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond silos: How DDI-AI integration is redefining cyber resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087578/beyond-silos-how-ddi-ai-integration-is-redefining-cyber-resilience.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As organizations migrate toward hybrid and multi-cloud architectures, the boundaries between network and security operations have eroded, revealing critical visibility gaps. This issue is forcing a strategic shift for enterprise security leaders: the integration of DDI (DNS, DHCP and IP address management) with current artificial intelligence (AI) platforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For a comprehensive overview of DDI approaches and technical best practices, see &lt;a href="https://insights.infoblox.com/resources-reference-architectures/infoblox-reference-architecture-best-practices-architecture-for-infoblox-universal-ddi" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Infoblox DDI Reference Architecture&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.solarwinds.com/ip-address-manager/use-cases/ddi-dns-dhcp-ipam" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SolarWinds DDI overview&lt;/a&gt;. Using real-world operational models, we’ll demonstrate how DDI data, analyzed through AI engines, transforms reactive postures into predictive, autonomous defense mechanisms. The dual use is clear. DDI-AI fusion functions as a defensive shield for contextual threat detection and machine-speed response and also as an offensive capability via AI-powered breach and attack simulation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="introduction-the-new-terrain-of-cyber-complexity"&gt;Introduction: The new terrain of cyber complexity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today’s enterprise resembles a living organism: a sprawling ecosystem spanning datacenters, public clouds, remote users and billions of IoT devices. This complexity has surpassed human capacity for oversight. Siloed security operations once sufficed, but now leave organizations open to sophisticated, automated threats. The gap between network operations and security is a liability, not an inconvenience. Adversaries exploit these seams with unprecedented precision, launching attacks that bypass legacy controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ddi-as-the-nervous-system-of-enterprise-security"&gt;DDI as the nervous system of enterprise security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;DDI, including DNS, DHCP and IP address management, is the nervous system of the network. It records every connection, every name resolution and every IP allocation, maintaining the only comprehensive, authoritative record of normal network behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By itself, DDI data is simply a massive stream of logs. For best practices and solutions, see &lt;a href="https://www.auvik.com/franklyit/blog/what-is-ddi-meaning/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Auvik DDI guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://efficientip.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/wp-10-Key-Best-Practices-for-Efficient-IP-Address-Management-IPAM-EN-190930.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;EfficientIP’s IPAM management reference&lt;/a&gt;. When processed through machine learning, this dataset becomes the foundation for cyberdefense. AI serves as the analytical layer, transforming raw DDI logs into prioritized threat signals at the speed required for modern defense.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="DDI integration with AI security: defensive and offensive strategies" class="wp-image-4087582" height="1024" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/defensive-and-offensive-ai.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Sunil Gentyala&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="i-the-defensive-shield-ai-driven-ddi-for-enterprise-fortification"&gt;I. The defensive shield: AI-driven DDI for enterprise fortification&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The primary challenge for a modern SOC (security operations center) is not a lack of data, but a lack of actionable context. A traditional SIEM (security information and event management) system might flag a suspicious DNS query, but it often cannot definitively answer critical follow-up questions, such as:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who made this query?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What is the device profile?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Is this behavior normal for this specific user or device?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What other related activities occurred?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The integration of DDI and AI directly addresses this contextual deficit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-data-points-to-high-fidelity-detection"&gt;From data points to high-fidelity detection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;DDI data provides the raw, immutable facts of network behavior. When this data is fed into modern AI analytics platforms, security moves beyond simple, signature-based rules to enable high-fidelity, behavioral threat detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Machine learning models establish a precise baseline of normal activity for every device on the network. This allows the AI to correlate multiple, seemingly minor anomalies into a single, high-confidence attack narrative. For example:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siloed alert (noise):&lt;/strong&gt; A single “Abnormal DHCP Request” alert is generated. A SOC analyst is likely to ignore this as a transient network glitch.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siloed alert (noise):&lt;/strong&gt; A separate “Suspicious DNS Query” alert for a new .xyz domain is logged, one of thousands of similar alerts.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated AI (signal):&lt;/strong&gt; The AI-driven platform observes both events originating from the same device (identified by its MAC address from the DHCP log). It concurrently pulls context from the IPAM database, noting this device is in a critical server subnet. The AI correlates these events and automatically escalates them as a single, high-priority incident: “Potential C2 Beaconing from Critical Asset.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This contextual correlation is the key to defeating alert fatigue. It also enables the detection of sophisticated, low-and-slow attacks like DNS tunneling and DGAs (domain generation algorithms), where the AI recognizes the pattern of malicious queries, not just a single bad domain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="soc-revolution-from-human-speed-to-machine-speed-response"&gt;SOC revolution: From human-speed to machine-speed response&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Detection alone is only half the battle. In the time a human analyst triages the first alert, adversaries can already exfiltrate data or establish deep persistence. Integrating DDI analytics into SOAR (security orchestration, automation and response) enables closed-loop, autonomous action.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consider the following automated response playbook:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detect:&lt;/strong&gt; AI engines surface a unique C2 signature in DNS logs.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchestrate &amp;amp; enrich:&lt;/strong&gt; The SOAR platform is automatically triggered. It first queries the IPAM database to identify the device, its registered owner and its business criticality.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respond (DDI action 1):&lt;/strong&gt; The SOAR platform instructs the DNS firewall (a component of the DDI system) to instantly block the malicious domain enterprise-wide, severing C2 communication.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respond (DDI action 2):&lt;/strong&gt; Simultaneously, it instructs the DHCP server to place the device’s MAC address into a quarantine VLAN or deny it a new lease, effectively isolating it from the network.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report:&lt;/strong&gt; The SOAR platform opens a ticket in the IT service management tool, attaching all correlated logs, the device owner’s contact info and a summary of the automated actions taken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This entire process executes autonomously in the time it would take a human analyst to simply triage the first alert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ddi-as-the-bedrock-of-a-zero-trust-architecture"&gt;DDI as the bedrock of a zero-trust architecture&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implementing &lt;a href="https://efficientip.com/solutions/zero-trust-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;zero-trust security&lt;/a&gt; is a top priority for modern security leaders. The “never trust, always verify” model relies on continuous, dynamic risk assessment. DDI data provides the foundational source of truth required to make these verify decisions in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DHCP:&lt;/strong&gt; Who is this device, based on MAC, OS fingerprint and user association?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IPAM:&lt;/strong&gt; What context do I have? It provides the business context — is this a corporate-owned laptop, a BYOD phone or an IoT camera? What subnet is it on? Who is the registered owner?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNS:&lt;/strong&gt; What does it want to do? It shows precisely what resources, internal or external, the device is attempting to access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An AI-driven policy engine can consume this DDI-fueled context in real time. When a user’s device (identified via DHCP) on the guest subnet (context from IPAM) suddenly makes a DNS query for an internal Finance-DB server, the AI can instantly block the request as a policy violation, all without human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ii-the-offensive-spear-ai-powered-red-teaming-and-resilience-testing"&gt;II. The offensive spear: AI-powered red-teaming and resilience testing&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A modern defense cannot be purely reactive. CSOs must be able to answer the question, “Are our controls working right now?” Offensive AI, which uses AI to simulate attacks and test defenses, provides this continuous validation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="beyond-pentesting-ai-driven-breach-and-attack-simulation-bas"&gt;Beyond pentesting: AI-driven breach and attack simulation (BAS)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional penetration testing is a manual, expensive, point-in-time snapshot. By the time the report is delivered weeks later, network configurations and security policies have often drifted, rendering the findings obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-powered BAS platforms change this. They &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/3875421" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;act as a persistent, automated red team, safely launching real-world attack scenarios 24/7/365&lt;/a&gt;. An AI-driven BAS can:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuously scan for and validate exploitable vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Simulate multi-stage attacks, from an initial phishing link to lateral movement and data exfiltration.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Use DDI data offensively, just as a real attacker would: It can query public DNS to map an organization’s attack surface or probe internal DNS to find critical servers.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Test the effectiveness of security controls by confirming if an attack path is actually blocked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-ai-vs-ai-feedback-loop-building-true-resilience"&gt;The AI vs. AI feedback loop: Building true resilience&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The real strategic value emerges when an organization pits its offensive AI against its defensive AI. This creates a powerful, closed-loop feedback system for building resilience:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test:&lt;/strong&gt; The offensive AI (BAS) launches a simulated DNS tunneling attack.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validate:&lt;/strong&gt; The defensive AI (monitoring DDI logs) is supposed to detect this pattern.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detect &amp;amp; remediate:&lt;/strong&gt; If the attack is not detected, a critical gap is identified. The security team can then fine-tune the defensive AI model or the DDI policy. If it is detected, the test validates that the SOAR playbook triggers correctly.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retest:&lt;/strong&gt; The offensive AI runs the test again, confirming the remediation was successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This continuous, automated AI versus AI sparring session moves security from a reactive, hope-based posture to one of proven, measurable resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="iii-the-2025-horizon-next-gen-ddi-ai-trends-threats"&gt;III. The 2025+ horizon: Next-gen DDI-AI trends &amp;amp; threats&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="generative-ai-the-soc-analysts-copilot"&gt;Generative AI: The SOC analyst’s copilot&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Generative AI’s arrival in the SOC will not replace analysts; it will amplify them. Instead of crafting SQL queries, analysts use natural language: “Summarize anomalous DNS activity from finance endpoints in the last 48 hours, cross-reference with non-corporate DHCP leases and flag top risks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GenAI parses terabytes of data, generates executive summaries and recommends automated playbooks — transforming junior staff into elite threat hunters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="securing-ai-defending-the-defenders"&gt;Securing AI: Defending the defenders&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As defenses increasingly depend on AI, adversaries target the AI itself. Adversarial AI encompasses:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evasion:&lt;/strong&gt; Predators mutate command-and-control channels and DGA patterns to avoid AI detection.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data poisoning:&lt;/strong&gt; Internal threats inject malicious DDI data, corrupting AI training sets and blind-spotting detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For leaders, AI and its pipelines become crown jewels, demanding isolation, continuous monitoring and adversarial testing as vigorously as any other strategic asset.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="federated-learning-global-threat-intelligence-local-privacy"&gt;Federated learning: Global threat intelligence, local privacy&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Historically, threat intelligence meant siloed organizations learned only from attacks that breached their own defenses. Federated learning enables distributed AI training: models learn from anonymized DDI data across organizations worldwide, sharing insights without ever exposing proprietary data. The result is earlier recognition of emerging TTPs (tactics, techniques and procedures), accelerating the global cyber immune response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="iv-practical-application-from-data-points-to-attack-narrative"&gt;IV. Practical application: From data points to attack narrative&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The original simulation data provides a perfect example of the difference between siloed analysis and an integrated AI-driven approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-table"&gt;&lt;div class="overflow-table-wrapper"&gt;&lt;table class="has-fixed-layout"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suspicion Level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Node-1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;IP Conflict&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Node-2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Abnormal DHCP Request&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Node-5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Abnormal DHCP Request&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Node-8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Suspicious DNS Query&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Node-9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Normal DHCP Lease&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This simulation demonstrates how AI can quickly sift through network data to pinpoint potential threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="siloed-manual-analysis-a-junior-analyst-sees-five-separate-low-priority-alerts"&gt;Siloed, manual analysis: A junior analyst sees five separate, low-priority alerts.&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node-1:&lt;/strong&gt; “IP Conflict.” A network admin is notified. They close the ticket as a “transient network glitch.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node-2&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Node-5:&lt;/strong&gt; “Abnormal DHCP.” These are logged and ignored as noise.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node-8:&lt;/strong&gt; “Suspicious DNS Query.” This is lost in the noise of thousands of other DNS alerts.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node-9:&lt;/strong&gt; “Normal DHCP Lease, High.” This alert is contradictory and makes no sense. It’s ignored. Result: A real attack is missed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="unified-ai-driven-analysis"&gt;Unified AI-driven analysis&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this kind of contextual correlation, the AI platform ingests all five events simultaneously and builds a coherent narrative.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial recon (Node-5):&lt;/strong&gt; The AI sees Node-5 (a user laptop) make an Abnormal DHCP Request. It interprets this as probing the network to map the DHCP server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C2 communication (Node-8):&lt;/strong&gt; Moments later, the same device (correlated by its MAC address) makes a Suspicious DNS Query to a newly registered domain — a clear C2 beacon.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack staging (Node-1):&lt;/strong&gt; The IP Conflict on Node-1 is now re-contextualized not as a glitch, but as a deliberate ARP spoofing attempt by the attacker on Node-5 to perform a man-in-the-middle attack.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lateral movement (Node-9):&lt;/strong&gt; The contradictory “Normal DHCP Lease, High” alert is instantly understood. The AI sees that the attacker on Node-5 has spoofed the MAC address of a critical file server (Node-9) to request its IP lease. The lease itself is “normal,” but the context of that server’s identity being used by a laptop is a “High” severity indicator of compromise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-driven-conclusion"&gt;AI-driven conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The AI correlates these five low-priority events into a single, critical priority incident: “Active Lateral Movement and C2 Attack Detected from Node-5.” It automatically triggers the SOAR playbook to quarantine Node-5 before the attacker can exfiltrate data from the file server.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="v-best-practices-for-a-successful-ddi-ai-integration"&gt;V. Best practices for a successful DDI-AI integration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Integrating DDI and AI is a strategic journey, not a single product deployment. Success requires a cultural and operational shift.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foster NetSecOps fusion:&lt;/strong&gt; DDI is typically owned by NetOps, but its value lies in security. Tear down silos and align network and security teams through shared training, processes and objectives.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data quality is paramount:&lt;/strong&gt; “Garbage in, gospel out” applies. Invest in IPAM hygiene, standardize &lt;a href="https://efficientip.com/blog/ipam-best-practices-simplifying-network-management/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DDI processes&lt;/a&gt; and automate data validation.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure the AI stack:&lt;/strong&gt; Defend AI models, training pipelines and integrations from adversarial manipulation and drift. Treat AI like any other mission-critical system.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defense in depth:&lt;/strong&gt; DDI-AI is a force multiplier, not a silver bullet. Enrich endpoint, perimeter and cloud defenses with context — but do not replace them.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://bluecatnetworks.com/blog/security-automation-cloud-integration-keys-to-ddi-solution-success/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Leverage open ecosystems&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid closed, bolt-on solutions. Pursue open, extensible platforms (XDRs, modern SIEMs) with APIs and integration support for evolving needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="strategic-imperative-not-future-fiction"&gt;Strategic imperative, not future fiction&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers are all-in on automation, scale and speed. Human-only defenses — no matter how capable the team — have already lost the cyberwar of attrition. The deep integration of DDI with defensive and offensive AI is no longer aspirational; it is organizationally existential.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CIOs and cybersecurity leaders must build cross-functional alliances, invest in clean data infrastructure, harden and monitor AI pipelines and embrace perpetual BAS through AI. Only with this holistic, adaptive cyber posture can organizations remain resilient by detecting, defeating and learning from attacks before adversaries adapt their playbooks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087578/beyond-silos-how-ddi-ai-integration-is-redefining-cyber-resilience.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global experts advance the joint fight against crypto-enabled crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</link>
      <description>The criminal use of cryptocurrency is becoming increasingly professionalised, but so too is the global response. Participants at the 9th Global Conference on Criminal Finances and Cryptoassets emphasised three priorities: developing common standards, deepening cooperation and investing in capacity. These are essential if authorities and industry are to keep pace with evolving threats and recover illicit cryptoassets at scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI startups leak sensitive credentials on GitHub, exposing models and training data</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087983/ai-startups-leak-sensitive-credentials-on-github-exposing-models-and-training-data.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly two-thirds of the world’s top private AI companies have exposed API keys and access tokens on GitHub, according to new research from cloud security firm Wiz, raising concerns that rapid growth is outpacing security discipline.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz found verified secret leaks in 65% of the Forbes AI 50 companies, representing a combined valuation of more than $400 billion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the severity of the issue, nearly half of Wiz’s disclosure attempts either failed to reach the affected companies or received no response, suggesting limited preparedness to handle security reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The leaks included credentials that could have exposed private AI models, training data, and internal organizational details, suggesting how speed-to-market pressures continue to outpace secure development practices in the AI sector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Think API keys, tokens, and sensitive credentials, often buried deep in deleted forks, gists, and developer repos most scanners never touch,” Wiz said in a blog. “Some of these leaks could have exposed organizational structures, training data, or even private models.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some of the leaked credentials belonged to major AI platforms such as Hugging Face, Weights &amp;amp; Biases, and LangChain, which could have granted access to private models or sensitive training datasets, according to Wiz.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="wider-implications"&gt;Wider implications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts have said that misconfigured cloud storage has been a recurring problem for more than a decade, citing past incidents such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3816939/abandoned-aws-s3-buckets-open-door-to-remote-code-execution-and-supply-chain-compromises.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;AWS S3 leaks.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But while the pattern is familiar, the potential damage has grown as exposed assets now include AI models, training data, and complex development pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Speed vs security seems to be the underlying root cause leading to cloud misconfigurations, inadequate secret management, lack of security or privacy by design, and tooling gaps,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunilvarkey1/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sunil Varkey&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity analyst. “The impacts can be severe, extending well beyond typical data exposure, as an AI leak can disrupt multiple levels of an organization at once, including technology, business, legal, ethical, and strategic competitiveness.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The scale of exposure points to “a glaring DevSecOps chasm” between AI startups and more mature SaaS or cloud firms, according to &lt;a href="https://sure-shield.com/our-team/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chandrasekhar Bilugu&lt;/a&gt;, CTO of SureShield. “AI teams, racing to prototype, often store secrets like configuration files in public repositories, with many missing even basic scanning of deleted forks or gists,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With companies exposing API keys and tokens on GitHub, the real-world risk is catastrophic: attackers can hijack proprietary models for competitive sabotage, siphon customer PII for identity theft (affecting billions in potential GDPR fines), or pivot into supply chain chaos,” Bilugu added. “In AI, where training data is a precious commodity, a single leaked token grants access to thousands of private models with IP theft or model poisoning that follows.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The findings suggest that as AI adoption accelerates, developers and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066733/cisos-rethink-the-security-organization-for-the-ai-era.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;CISOs alike will need to tighten oversight&lt;/a&gt; of development pipelines and secret storage practices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="compliance-and-governance"&gt;Compliance and governance&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Wiz findings highlight how exposed API keys can escalate into full-scale compromises across AI ecosystems, according to &lt;a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=PRF005665" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sakshi Grover&lt;/a&gt;, senior research manager for IDC Asia Pacific Cybersecurity Services. “Stolen credentials can be used to manipulate model behavior or extract training data, undermining trust in deployed systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Grover noted that such exposures are often linked to the way AI development environments operate. “AI projects often operate in loosely governed, experimentation-driven environments where notebooks, pre-trained models, and repositories are shared frequently, leaving secrets unscanned or unrotated,” Grover added.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She pointed to data from IDC’s Asia/Pacific Security Study, which showed that 50% of enterprises in APAC alone plan to invest in API security when selecting CNAPP vendors, reflecting how exposed APIs have become a major attack vector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With regulators sharpening their focus on AI safety and data protection, secret management and API governance are likely to become auditable elements of emerging AI compliance frameworks, Grover said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087983/ai-startups-leak-sensitive-credentials-on-github-exposing-models-and-training-data.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 10:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and UEFA united for fair and safe football</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</link>
      <description>Today, 5 November 2025, Europol and UEFA have renewed and extended their Memorandum of Understanding, focused on preventing and combating crime while protecting the integrity of European football. The memorandum was signed at UEFA headquarters in Nyon by the Executive Director of Europol, Catherine De Bolle, and by the President of UEFA, Aleksander Čeferin. Europol and UEFA committed to cooperate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden hosts naval exercise with 200 special tactics operators</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</link>
      <description>Preparing to fight terrorism on land and seaThe exercise scenario focused on the deployment of special intervention units and naval assets during day- and night-time, simulating terrorist and hostage incidents on board of cruise liners and ferries. Day after day, the participants faced new challenges on the water and on some of the archipelago’s many islands, slowly preparing them for...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senate moves to restore lapsed cybersecurity laws after shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088018/senate-moves-to-restore-lapsed-cybersecurity-laws-after-shutdown.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Two cybersecurity laws that lapsed during the government shutdown moved closer to restoration on Monday after the Senate voted 60-40 to advance legislation extending them through January 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The continuing resolution would restore the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 and the Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act, which &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065998/cisa-2015-cyber-threat-info-sharing-law-lapses-amid-government-shutdown.html" target="_blank"&gt;expired on October 1&lt;/a&gt; when Congress failed to pass a spending bill before the fiscal year deadline. The measure required additional procedural votes in the Senate this week before moving to the House for approval and then to President Trump’s desk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The lapse stripped companies of the legal protections that had encouraged voluntary sharing of cyber-threat indicators with federal agencies and other organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without liability shields, antitrust exemptions, or Freedom of Information Act protections, many firms faced new legal exposure and slowed information exchange. Security experts warned the interruption risked slowing threat-intelligence flows at a time of rising nation-state and ransomware activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“After a record-breaking shutdown, we can now see the light at the end of the tunnel,” Senator Kevin Cramer &lt;a href="https://www.cramer.senate.gov/news/press-releases/senate-advances-bipartisan-bills-takes-key-step-toward-ending-schumer-shutdown" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt; following Sunday’s procedural vote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-the-bill-restores"&gt;What the bill restores&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The continuing resolution temporarily extended both cybersecurity statutes.  &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/house-bill/5371/text" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Section 141 of the bill&lt;/a&gt; extends CISA 2015’s sunset date through January 2026, stating: “Section 111(a) of the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (6 U.S.C. 1510(a)) shall be applied by substituting the date specified in section 106 of this Act for ‘September 30, 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The legislation reinstated the legal and procedural safeguards that allow companies to share threat data with the government, and it renews authorization for CISA to provide network-security services, including the EINSTEIN intrusion-detection system, to civilian agencies under the Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The short-term extension, however, sets up another expiration in two months, leaving open whether Congress will pursue a full reauthorization or opt for another stopgap.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kevin Kirkwood, CISO at Exabeam, said the brief lapse presents an opportunity to reconsider how the threat-sharing framework operates. “At its core, CISA aimed to foster collaboration between the private sector and government by encouraging voluntary sharing of threat intelligence—something that absolutely matters in today’s threat landscape,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The problem isn’t with the sharing, it’s with the inevitable bloat that comes when federal agencies expand their footprint under the banner of cybersecurity coordination,” Kirkwood added. “This is the moment to rethink what version 2.0 should look like. We need a leaner, more focused model that preserves the flow of intelligence but resists the gravitational pull of centralized bureaucracy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-the-lapse-meant-for-enterprises"&gt;What the lapse meant for enterprises&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The expiration of CISA 2015 eliminated legal protections for sharing threat information, disrupting the real-time intelligence exchanges that had become routine over the past decade. Without its statutory shields, organizations faced potential liability for monitoring networks, sharing defensive measures, and coordinating responses with peers and federal agencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The law had explicitly authorized private entities to take defensive measures against cyberattacks, monitor their own and customers’ networks with consent, and exchange indicators to strengthen detection and response. It also protected shared data from public disclosure under FOIA and shielded participating companies from antitrust claims tied to joint defense activities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that previously shared threat data automatically needed lawyers to review each exchange, determining what laws might be violated and whether existing agreements covered the information transfer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The expiration of the Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act also ended statutory authority for CISA to operate the EINSTEIN program and other network-security services for civilian agencies, adding operational strain across government networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="broader-provisions-and-workforce-impact"&gt;Broader provisions and workforce impact&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond restoring the cybersecurity laws, the continuing resolution included measures to protect federal employees affected by the shutdown. The bill will “protect federal workers from baseless firings, reinstate those who have been wrongfully terminated during the shutdown, and ensure federal workers receive back pay,” Senator Tim Kaine &lt;a href="https://www.kaine.senate.gov/press-releases/kaine-statement-on-funding-deal-to-reopen-government-protect-federal-employees-and-vote-to-protect-health-care" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;, adding that the provisions were critical for earning his support.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA’s workforce shrank by nearly a third during the shutdown through buyouts, deferred resignations, and layoffs, falling from roughly 3,300 to about 2,200 employees. Divisions, including Stakeholder Engagement and Infrastructure Security, were hit hardest. The new workforce protections could reverse some of those losses once the bill becomes law.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The continuing resolution extended current government funding levels through January 2026, according to Cramer’s office. Eight Democrats joined Republicans to advance the bill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Suppose the resolution clears both chambers as expected. In that case, Congress will face another funding deadline early next year — and with it, another test of how well Washington can balance political gridlock with national cyber resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088018/senate-moves-to-restore-lapsed-cybersecurity-laws-after-shutdown.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korean hackers exploit Google’s safety tools for remote wipe</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088037/north-korean-hackers-exploit-googles-safety-tools-for-remote-wipe.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;North Korea-linked threat actors have found a novel way to weaponize Google’s own security ecosystem, using it to wipe espionage data from victim phones remotely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to findings by Genians Security Center (GSC), the attackers leveraged the Android device-tracing and management service “Find Hub” to remotely wipe data on Android phones and tablets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While Find Hub is intended to safeguard Android devices, this is the first confirmed case in which a state-sponsored threat actor obtained remote control by compromising Google accounts, then used the service to perform location tracking and remote wipe,” GSC researchers said in a blog post. “This development demonstrates a realistic risk that the feature can be abused within APT campaigns.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GSC has attributed these activities to the KONNI APT group, known to be associated with the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2066558/north-korean-kimsuky-groups-attack-chain-blends-with-legitimate-traffic.html"&gt;Kimsuky&lt;/a&gt; or APT37 groups.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The campaign was further bolstered by social engineering via the popular Korean messenger KaKaoTalk, where victims were sent malicious apps disguised as psychological “stress-relief” programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-the-lost-phone-feature-to-a-wipe-bomb"&gt;From the lost phone feature to a wipe bomb&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GSC found that the attackers compromised legitimate Google accounts to take full advantage of Find Hub’s remote-management functionality. Once logged in, they could track location and execute wipe commands on Android devices, effectively deleting personal data and disabling the device’s normal alert channels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A notable finding is that immediately after confirming through Find Hub’s location query that the victim was outside, the threat actor executed a remote reset command on the victim’s devices,” the researchers added. “The remote reset halted normal device operation, blocking notification and message alerts from messenger applications and effectively cutting off the account owner’s awareness channel, thereby delaying detection and response.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By cutting the device off, the attacker creates a silent window for further propagation and control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The blog &lt;a href="https://www.genians.co.kr/en/blog/threat_intelligence/android" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;explained&lt;/a&gt; that initial access was obtained through spear-phishing emails impersonating South Korea’s National Tax Service (NTS). Victims received an email with an attachment that, once executed, installed malicious scripts (Autolt-based) or dropped a RAT to steal Google credentials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To prevent the unauthorized abuse of remote wipe features through compromised Google accounts, service providers should review and implement real-time security verification measures, such as additional authentication processes that confirm the legitimate device owner,” researchers recommended.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-social-engineering-link"&gt;The social engineering link&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The threat continues beyond device wiping, with attackers distributing malware by compromising &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/538482/data-protection-android-messaging-malware-targets-tibetan-activists.html"&gt;KakaoTalk&lt;/a&gt; accounts of trusted contacts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;GSC found that malicious files disguised as “stress-relief programs” were sent to close contacts via the messenger. “Among the victims was a professional psychological counselor who supports North Korean defector youths during resettlement by addressing psychological difficulties and providing services such as career guidance, educational counseling, and mentoring to help stabilize their well-being,” researchers added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While one attack vector used device neutralization to disable alerts, the other launched the malware distribution via compromised chat accounts. GSC called this mix unprecedented among known state-sponsored APT actors and that it shows the attacker’s “tactical maturity and advanced evasion strategy”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reinforcing verification of files received via messenger platforms before opening and execution, and using clear warning prompts to help users avoid downloading or running malicious files, might help against this vector, the blog noted. The Genians findings, like the recent &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4070281/clayrat-spyware-turns-phones-into-distribution-hubs-via-sms-and-telegram.html"&gt;ClayRat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3840157/badbox-android-botnet-disrupted-through-coordinated-threat-hunting.html"&gt;Badbox 2.0&lt;/a&gt; campaigns, highlight a growing trend of attackers exploiting trusted apps and built-in services instead of relying on complex zero-day exploits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088037/north-korean-hackers-exploit-googles-safety-tools-for-remote-wipe.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake number, real damage: Europol urges action against caller ID spoofing</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</link>
      <description>Europol is calling for a coordinated European response to tackle caller ID spoofing, an in increasingly common tool, used for online fraud and social engineering scams. Caller ID spoofing occurs when criminals falsify the information displayed on phones, making numbers appear legitimate to deceive victims. This practice is driving substantial financial and societal harm, with an estimated EUR 850 million lost worldwide each year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU-Kommission will DSGVO für KI und Cookie-Tracking lockern</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088083/eu-kommission-will-dsgvo-fur-ki-und-cookie-tracking-lockern.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 4032w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2645792213.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Die vorgeschlagenen Änderungen der EU-Kommission durch das „Digital Omnibus”-Paket  gefährden laut Datenschützern die DSGVO.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Alicia97 – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut einem durchgesickerten Entwurf, über den die deutsche Interessenvertretung &lt;a href="https://netzpolitik.org/2025/digitaler-omnibus-eu-kommission-will-datenschutzgrundverordnung-und-ki-regulierung-schleifen/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Netzpolitik.org&lt;/a&gt; berichtet, würde das bevorstehende „Digital Omnibus”-Paket der EU-Kommission die Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (DSGVO) massiv verändern. Der Vorschlag soll am 19. November 2025 offiziell vorgestellt werden. Datenschützer befürchten jedoch, dass dies die DSGVO schwächen könnte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So bemängelt der Datenschutzrechtler Max Schrems, dass viele Elemente der vorgeschlagenen Reform gegen die Rechtsprechung des Europäischen Gerichtshofs (EuGH), europäische Konventionen und die Europäische Charta der Grundrechte verstoßen würden. „Das wäre der extremste Angriff auf die Privatsphäre der Europäer seit in Krafttreten der DSGVO.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cookies-unterliegen-der-dsgvo"&gt;Cookies unterliegen der DSGVO&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Entwurf würde Artikel 88a in die DSGVO aufnehmen, um die „Verarbeitung personenbezogener Daten auf und von Endgeräten” abzudecken. Dadurch würde die Cookie-Regulierung von der ePrivacy-Richtlinie in die DSGVO verlagert werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Derzeit verlangt Artikel 5 Absatz 3 der ePrivacy-Richtlinie, dass Websites die ausdrückliche Zustimmung einholen müssen, bevor sie nicht essenzielle Cookies auf den Geräten der Nutzer speichern oder darauf zugreifen dürfen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Kommission argumentierte, dass dies aufgrund sich überschneidender Zuständigkeiten der nationalen Behörden zu Rechtsunsicherheit und „höheren &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/compliance/" target="_blank"&gt;Compliance&lt;/a&gt;-Kosten“ geführt habe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nach der vorgeschlagenen Änderung könnten Webseiten Daten, die über Cookies gesammelt wurden, auf der Grundlage einer „geschlossenen Liste von Zwecken mit geringem Risiko“ oder auf jeder anderen Rechtsgrundlage gemäß der DSGVO, einschließlich berechtigter Interessen, verarbeiten. Dies würde eine wesentliche Veränderung vom Opt-in- zum Opt-out-Tracking bedeuten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anstatt die Nutzer im Voraus um ihre Zustimmung zu bitten, könnten Unternehmen sie standardmäßig tracken und es den Einzelnen überlassen, später Widerspruch einzulegen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Zwar ist die Einwilligung erforderlich, um die Kontrolle der betroffenen Personen zu gewährleisten, doch ist sie nicht immer die am besten geeignete Rechtsgrundlage für die anschließende Verarbeitung“, &lt;a href="https://cdn.netzpolitik.org/wp-upload/2025/11/EU-Kommission-Digital-Omnibus-A-Data-Act-und-DSGVO.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;heißt es in dem Entwurf&lt;/a&gt;. „Darüber hinaus führte das duale System aus ePrivacy-Richtlinie und Datenschutz-Grundverordnung dazu, dass verschiedene nationale Behörden für die Überwachung der Vorschriften der beiden Rechtsrahmen zuständig waren.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Datenschutzgruppen werfen der Kommission vor, sie nutze die „Cookie-Müdigkeit“ als Vorwand, um die Datenschutzstandards zu verwässern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die DSGVO, der ePrivacy-Rahmen und das KI-Gesetz sind keine Hindernisse für Innovation – sie sind die Grundlage des menschenzentrierten digitalen Modells Europas“, schrieb die Bürgerrechtsvereinigung &lt;a href="https://edri.org/our-work/consultation-response-to-the-european-commissions-call-for-evidence-on-the-digital-omnibus/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;European Digital Rights (EDRi)&lt;/a&gt; in einem Blogbeitrag im Oktober 2025. „Unter dem Vorwand der Kohärenz scheint die Kommission jedoch bereit zu sein, den ePrivacy-Schutz zu schwächen. “&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Entwurf enthält auch einen Artikel 88b, der vorsieht, dass Browser oder Betriebssysteme die Einwilligungspräferenzen der Nutzer automatisch übermitteln müssen, sobald technische Standards definiert sind, wodurch die derzeitige Flut von Cookie-Bannern möglicherweise auslaufen würde.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für Medienunternehmen gibt es jedoch eine Ausnahmeregelung. Nachrichtenorganisationen könnten weiterhin eine ausdrückliche Einwilligung verlangen, was die Kommission mit dem Schutz der „wirtschaftlichen Grundlage“ des Journalismus begründete.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="grunes-licht-fur-ki-training"&gt;Grünes Licht für KI-Training&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus befasst sich der Änderungsvorschlag direkt mit einer der umstrittensten Fragen des &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491652/ai-act-wie-europas-ki-gesetz-cisos-fordert.html" target="_blank"&gt;EU-Datenschutzrechts&lt;/a&gt;: ob Unternehmen KI-Systeme mit personenbezogenen Daten trainieren dürfen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Entwurf sieht vor, dass das Training, Testen und Validieren von KI auf der Grundlage des „berechtigten Interesses“ der DSGVO durchgeführt werden darf, sofern Unternehmen Schutzmaßnahmen wie Datenminimierung, Transparenz und ein bedingungsloses Widerspruchsrecht implementieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die Verarbeitung personenbezogener Daten für das KI-Training kann daher zum Zwecke eines berechtigten Interesses durchgeführt werden”, heißt es im Entwurf, wobei hinzugefügt wird, dass Entwickler sicherstellen müssen, dass das Training „für die betroffene Person und die Gesellschaft insgesamt von Vorteil ist”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Kommission führte die Notwendigkeit, Verzerrungen zu erkennen und genaue Modellergebnisse zu gewährleisten, als Beispiele für „vorteilhafte” Zwecke an.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Datenschutzanwälte warnten jedoch, dass die Berufung auf ein berechtigtes Interesse für die KI-Verarbeitung die Tür für groß angelegtes Data Mining ohne individuelle Zustimmung öffnen könnte, was die DSGVO ursprünglich verhindern sollte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Entwurf würde auch eine begrenzte Ausnahme für Daten besonderer Kategorien (sensible Daten) einführen, die versehentlich in KI-Datensätzen auftauchen. Wenn es einen „unverhältnismäßigen Aufwand“ erfordern würde, solche Daten zu entfernen, könnten Unternehmen sie unter Schutzmaßnahmen, die ihre Verwendung oder Offenlegung verhindern, aufbewahren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="schutz-sensibler-daten-eingeschrankt"&gt;Schutz sensibler Daten eingeschränkt&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eine weitere umstrittene Änderung des Vorschlags wäre die Einschränkung der Definition sensibler Daten gemäß Artikel 9 der DSGVO. Ein stärkerer Schutz würde nur dann gelten, wenn Informationen direkt Merkmale wie Herkuft, Religion oder Gesundheit offenlegen, wobei Daten, die diese Merkmale nur durch Analyse oder Schlussfolgerungen implizieren, ausgeschlossen wären.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Für die meisten Arten von personenbezogenen Daten, die in Artikel 9 Absatz 1 aufgeführt sind, bestehen keine derartigen erheblichen Risiken, wenn die Daten nicht von Natur aus sensibel sind“, heißt es in dem Entwurf.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kritiker warnen, dass dies Unternehmen ermöglichen könnte, aus scheinbar neutralen Daten geschützte Merkmale wie sexuelle Orientierung oder politische Meinungen abzuleiten, ohne dass höhere rechtliche Schutzmaßnahmen ausgelöst werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das &lt;a href="https://www.europeanlawinstitute.eu/fileadmin/user_upload/p_eli/Publications/ELI_Response_-_Simpler__fairer__more_effective.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;European Law Institute&lt;/a&gt; räumte in seiner Stellungnahme vom 14. Oktober 2025 ein, dass begrenzte Aktualisierungen der DSGVO notwendig sein könnten, warnte jedoch, dass „Verbesserungen nicht auf Kosten des Schutzes der Grundrechte gehen dürfen“.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die vorgeschlagenen Änderungen könnten die Datenverwaltung von Unternehmen in ganz Europa erheblich verändern. Unternehmen würden für die meisten Tracking-Cookies keine Einwilligungsmanagementsysteme mehr benötigen, müssten jedoch detaillierte Unterlagen führen, um die Verarbeitung unter „berechtigtem Interesse“ zu rechtfertigen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das European Digital Rights Network kritisierte die Konsultation als „ausgeschlossen durch Design“ mit „außerordentlich kurzen“ Fristen und Realitätschecks, die sich „fast ausschließlich auf die Stimmen der Industrie“ konzentrierten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088083/eu-kommission-will-dsgvo-fur-ki-und-cookie-tracking-lockern.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-724) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-726)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New UK laws to strengthen critical infrastructure cyber defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-uk-laws-to-strengthen-critical-infrastructure-cyber-defenses/</link>
      <description>The United Kingdom has introduced new legislation to boost cybersecurity defenses for hospitals, energy systems, water supplies, and transport networks against cyberattacks, linked to annual damages of nearly £15 billion ($19.6 billion). [...]</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-uk-laws-to-strengthen-critical-infrastructure-cyber-defenses/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:08:54 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-619) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory Under Siege: Why Critical Infrastructure Needs Stronger Security</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/active-directory-under-siege-why.html</link>
      <description>Active Directory remains the authentication backbone for&amp;nbsp;over 90% of Fortune 1000 companies. AD's importance has grown as companies adopt hybrid and cloud infrastructure, but so has its complexity. Every application, user, and device traces back to AD for authentication and authorization, making it the ultimate target. For attackers, it represents the holy grail: compromise Active</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/active-directory-under-siege-why.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:37:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-727)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-728)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-729)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-730)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November Patch Tuesday: Zero day Windows kernel flaw in servers, controllers, and PCs</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088341/november-patch-tuesday-zero-day-windows-kernel-flaw-in-servers-controllers-and-pcs.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A zero day elevation of privilege Windows kernel flaw in servers, controllers, and desktops is being actively exploited and needs to be patched immediately.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the advice of &lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/profile/satnam-narang" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Satnam Narang&lt;/a&gt;, senior staff research engineer at Tenable, on one of the two biggest vulnerabilities that needs to be addressed from among the 63 holes identified by Microsoft in today’s November Patch Tuesday releases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Separately, SAP today released four HotNews Notes and two HighPriority Notes among its 26 new and updated security patches. One patch deletes the SQL Anywhere Monitor because of hard-coded credentials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also today, Adobe released eight updates, while Mozilla released three.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="windows-kernel-flaw"&gt;Windows kernel flaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The most urgent of the Microsoft holes to be addressed is &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2025-62215" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-62215&lt;/a&gt; (the Windows kernel vulnerability),” Narang told &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt; in an email. “While there is a substantial prerequisite to exploit the bug, Microsoft confirmed active exploitation is underway. The consequences cannot be ignored, as elevation of privilege vulnerabilities are the keys to opening other doors within the organization. This is how attackers go from initial foothold to full-blown breach.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, &lt;a href="https://www.action1.com/team/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mike Walters&lt;/a&gt;, president of Action1, points out, this vulnerability impacts servers and domain controllers as much as desktops.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ivanti.com/blog/authors/chris-goettl" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Goettl&lt;/a&gt;, vice president of product management at Ivanti, notes that this vulnerability affects all currently supported Windows OS editions plus the Windows 10 machines covered by the ESU (Extended Security Updates) program, “which means running Windows 10 past the end-of life (EOL) is not a hypothetical risk.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.immersivelabs.com/author/ben-mccarthy" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ben McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;, lead cyber security engineer at Immersive, explained how this hole can be exploited. An attacker with low-privilege local access can run a specially crafted application that repeatedly attempts to trigger a race condition. The goal is to get multiple threads to interact with a shared kernel resource in an unsynchronized way, confusing the kernel’s memory management and causing it to free the same memory block twice. This successful “double free” corrupts the kernel heap, allowing the attacker to overwrite memory and hijack the system’s execution flow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft says while the attack complexity to exploit this hole is high — successful exploitation requires an attacker to win a race condition — the privileges required are low. And the prize is great: An attacker who successfully exploited this vulnerability could gain SYSTEM privileges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those in the Windows ESU program should note that, according to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholasacarroll/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nick Carroll&lt;/a&gt;, cyber incident response manager at Nightwing, some users have been reporting issues enrolling in the Extended Security Update program. Microsoft has recently released an out-of-band update to address issues when users try to enroll in the Windows 10 Consumer Extended Security Update program, he said. Admins planning to participate in the program should make sure to update and install &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/november-11-2025-kb5071959-windows-10-version-22h2-os-build-19045-6466-out-of-band-565c78a7-5b5f-4cbd-8ca8-2a73a48f4e2b" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;KB5071959&lt;/a&gt; to address the enrollment issues. After that is installed, users should be able to install other updates such as today’s KB5068781, which is the latest update to Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="flaw-in-visual-studio-copilot-extension"&gt;Flaw in Visual Studio Copilot Extension&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second major vulnerability is &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2025-62222" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-62222&lt;/a&gt;, a remote code execution flaw in Microsoft Visual Studio Code Copilot Chat Extension. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While it is rated as less likely to be exploited, Narang said, it “underscores a growing interest in finding bugs in generative AI or agentic AI, which encompasses large language models, whether foundational models or open source models, and the AI-assisted code editing tools.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/microsoft-patch-tuesday-november-2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Researchers at Cisco Systems said&lt;/a&gt; exploitation is not trivial for this vulnerability, as it requires multiple steps: prompt injection, Copilot Agent interaction, and triggering a build. Cisco notes that Microsoft assessed that the attack complexity is “high”, and that exploitation is “less likely”.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs should already be addressing emerging AI risks with governance and policy enforcement, added Narang. “If Shadow AI and unchecked sanctioned AI usage run rampant through their organization, CSOs must modify their strategy to govern this emerging, complex attack surface before it’s too late.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="kerberos-vulnerability"&gt;Kerberos vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the fixes released is one for &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-60704" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-60704&lt;/a&gt;, a Kerboros delegation vulnerability in Active Directory dubbed CheckSum by researchers at Silverfort, who discovered it. If exploited, an attacker could impersonate an authenticated user, escalate privileges and stay hidden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because Kerberos is a way to enable applications to authenticate securely on behalf of users, abuse of it can  be dangerous, Silverfort says in an explanation of this vulnerability. Using a man-in-the-middle technique, the flaw allows researchers to impersonate arbitrary users and ultimately gain control over the entire domain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Any organization using Active Directory with the Kerberos delegation capability turned on is impacted,” says Silverfort. “This means thousands of companies around the world are affected by this vulnerability.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="microsoft-graphics-component-flaw"&gt;Microsoft Graphics Component flaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tyler Reguly, associate director of R&amp;amp;D at Fortra, was drawn to &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-60724" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-60724&lt;/a&gt;, one of several vulnerabilities rated critical in severity. It’s a heap-based buffer overflow in Microsoft Graphics Component that could allow an unauthorized attacker to execute code over a network.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He notes that Microsoft says, “in the worst-case scenario, an attacker could trigger this vulnerability on web services by uploading documents containing a specially crafted metafile without user interaction.”   &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If I’m a CISO, then CVE-2025-60724 has me worried this month,” he told &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt;. “We have a vulnerability that Microsoft and CVSS agree is critical and an attack vector that requires no user interaction and no privileges, just the ability to upload a file. We know nothing about the file type, the technologies that are impacted (other than GDI+ in the title), or the services impacted. Do I need to worry about my SharePoint infrastructure? What about third-party software – my wiki or my bug tracker? This is definitely one that feels a little spooky without a lot of extra details being provided.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco explains the vulnerability can be triggered by convincing a victim open a document that contains a specially crafted metafile.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the worst-case scenario,” its researchers write, “an attacker could trigger this vulnerability on web services by uploading documents containing a specially crafted metafile without user interaction. An attacker doesn’t require any privileges on the systems hosting the web services. Successful exploitation of this vulnerability could cause RCE or information disclosure on web services that are parsing documents that contain a specially crafted metafile, without the involvement of a victim user.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-patches"&gt;SAP patches&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The patches released by SAP today include some Notes that are updates to previously related fixes. That includes two HotNews patches. But there are new two patches, rated high priority by Onapsis, dealing with SAP Commerce Cloud (with a CVSS score of 7.5) and SAP CommonCryptoLib (also with a score of 7.5).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the notes, &lt;a href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3666261" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#3666261&lt;/a&gt;, has a CVSS score of 10. It deals with an insecure key and secret management vulnerability in SQL Anywhere Monitor with hard-coded credentials. SQL Anywhere Monitor is a browser-based administration tool that gives admins information about the health and availability of SQL Anywhere databases, MobiLink servers, and MobiLink server farms. It can also provide information about the availability of web servers, proxy servers, and host computers;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The patch removes SQL Anywhere Monitor completely, &lt;a href="https://onapsis.com/blog/sap-security-patch-day-november-2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;say researchers at Onapsis&lt;/a&gt;. As a temporary workaround, SAP recommends that admins stop using this tool and delete any instances of SQL Anywhere Monitor database.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another note to pay attention to, &lt;a href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3668705" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;#3668705&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-42887" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-42887&lt;/a&gt;) patches a code injection vulnerability in SAP Solution Manager. Due to missing input sanitization in a remote-enabled function module, authenticated attackers are able to inject malicious code into the system. Rated with a CVSS score of 9.9, this vulnerability is patched by adding an input check that rejects most of the non-alphanumeric characters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CVE-2025-42887 is particularly dangerous because it allows an attacker to inject code from a low-privileged user, which leads to a full SAP compromise and all data contained in the SAP system,” notes  Joris van de Vis, director of security research at SecurityBridge. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Onapsis CTO Juan Pablo Perez-Etchegoyen also says admins need to deal quickly with Note #&lt;a href="https://me.sap.com/notes/3633049" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;3633049&lt;/a&gt;. “Despite this being a CVSS 7.5,” he said in an email to &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt;, “it is a memory corruption potentially exploitable remotely pre-authentication, and these types of vulnerability tend to be very critical because of their nature and potential for denial of service and system compromise.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, with many of these vulnerabilities, patching alone is not enough: architecture, exposure, segmentation, and monitoring still matter, advises Mike Walters of Action1. “CSOs need to involve not just patching teams, but also service owners (print, scan, document sharing, remote access), network/security teams (for segmentation and exposure control), and logging/monitoring teams (for post-patch verification),” he said.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088341/november-patch-tuesday-zero-day-windows-kernel-flaw-in-servers-controllers-and-pcs.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 03:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-731)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Chargeback: 4.3 million cardholders affected, EUR 300 million in damages</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</link>
      <description>On 4 November 2025, an international coordinated action day targeted three major fraud and money laundering networks as part of Operation “Chargeback.” Led by the Cybercrime Department (Landeszentralstelle Cybercrime) of the General Prosecutor's Office (Generalstaatsanwaltschaft) in Koblenz, Germany, and the German Federal Criminal Police Office (Bundeskriminalamt), the operation has been investigating these networks since December 2020. More than 60 house searches were conducted and a total of 18 arrest warrants executed. The criminal networks are suspected of misusing credit card data from over 4.3 million cardholders across 193 countries. In total, the estimated damage from the fraud scheme exceeds EUR 300 million, with attempted damages amounting to over EUR 750 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>54 individuals arrested in action against labour exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</link>
      <description>Over the last weeks, law enforcement, border guards and labour and tax authorities across Europe joined forces to identify and tackle labour exploitation. This recent edition of the EMPACT Joint Action Days targeted trafficking in human beings for labour exploitation purposes, with a special emphasis on the agricultural sector, gastronomy, and temporary work agencies. In particular, the involved authorities also took measures against the exploitation of non-EU nationals and refugees. Led by France and the Netherlands, and carried out by authorities from 32 countries with support from Europol and the European Labour Authority (ELA), the action days resulted in the arrest of 54 individuals and identification of 404 potential victims of human trafficking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the checklist: Shifting from compliance frameworks to real-time risk assessments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088198/beyond-the-checklist-shifting-from-compliance-frameworks-to-real-time-risk-assessments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To keep up with a quickly changing threat environment, organizations are reassessing how they assess risk. They no longer view them only as a once-a-year exercise. They recognize their value as important tools for making informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While many still confuse gap analysis with risk assessment, the difference is important. A &lt;a href="https://www.knbbs.com/why-conduct-information-security-gap-analysis-and-how-to-do-it-effectively/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gap analysis&lt;/a&gt; measures how well a company follows a specific set of controls, often linked to frameworks like &lt;a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/iso-iec-27000-family" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ISO&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt;. A risk assessment, on the other hand, can be customized to look at any threat. This allows security leaders to focus their assessments where they are most needed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I had just started a new role as a CISO and quickly realized that access control was a big issue. Every user in every system seemed to have admin privileges. I decided to assess every critical system for the threat of unauthorized access and tailored the assessment by focusing on that threat. We asked questions like:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What types of data does your system store?” (for impact calculation)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“How many users have administrative permissions?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Can granular user access be assigned based on need?” (RBAC)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“What authentication methods are used?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Are there audit logs?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Combine the access control assessment results with a well-written report that assigns the risk to the business owner, and I had an effective tool for bringing awareness and change to the organization around managing access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="beyond-frameworks-why-static-models-fall-short"&gt;Beyond frameworks: Why static models fall short&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity frameworks provide necessary structure, but they are largely static and cannot substitute for real-time risk processes. Most compliance frameworks require an annual risk assessment because they often lag behind in covering rapidly evolving threats. Relying only on framework-based assessments risks overlooking important issues. This includes matters that go beyond static controls, such as AI adoption, cloud service updates and third-party dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These gaps highlight the importance of combining a solid compliance stance while regularly tailoring assessments to current realities. Frameworks are updated on multi-year cycles, while threats evolve daily. Organizations must focus on what really matters: key business assets, changing technologies and real-world operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="focused-risk-assessments-less-is-more"&gt;Focused risk assessments: Less is more&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional framework reviews can involve hundreds of controls and questions, which may be appropriate for large compliance engagements but are often impractical for smaller teams or fast-moving environments. A focused risk assessment, by contrast, can be built around 20–40 targeted questions. These assessments concentrate on high-probability, high-impact threats and the few controls that materially reduce risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one real-world example, I designed a 26-question assessment that helped a mid-sized organization zero in on its most pressing vulnerabilities. The result was a clear, actionable roadmap that delivered immediate value without the overhead of a full framework review.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This method is particularly beneficial when resources are scarce for organizations. By narrowing the scope, teams are able to rapidly identify and solve the highest priority risks, providing a good foundation for further action like targeted remediation or complete framework alignment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="frequency-over-formality"&gt;Frequency over formality&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the most overlooked aspects of risk assessments is cadence. While gap analyses are sometimes done yearly or to prepare for large-scale audits, risk assessments need to be continuous or performed on a regular schedule. Threats do not respect calendar cycles. Major changes, including new technologies, mergers, regulatory changes or implementing AI, need to trigger reassessments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Integrating risk assessments into regular governance practices, such as quarterly reviews of high-risk assets, evaluations after significant changes and annual assessments, helps organizations stay ahead of evolving threats. Moving to a dynamic approach to risk management from a static one is essential for developing long-term strength.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="designing-an-effective-risk-assessment"&gt;Designing an effective risk assessment&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A modern risk assessment begins with business context. What are the critical assets, processes and outcomes that must be protected? From there, organizations can identify the most likely threat paths and the controls that reduce those risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rather than cataloging every control in a framework, the focus should be on threat-and-control alignment. For example, if ransomware is a major concern, the assessment should focus on controls related to backups, restores, authentication and user awareness. Many organizations regularly back up their data, but they often neglect to test their restoration process. This leaves them at risk when it really counts. In this context, relying solely on backups provides a false sense of security; the real value lies in the ability to restore. A good assessment can uncover these issues and put focus on their priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Emerging vectors such as AI, cloud misconfigurations and software vulnerabilities should be explicitly included. These areas often fall outside traditional frameworks but represent significant risk. To assess AI risk for example, ask these questions:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“How do you use AI?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“What data does your AI have access to?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Do you make business decisions using AI?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Is AI used for automation?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With these simple questions, you can uncover hidden exposures, which are especially critical when sensitive data is involved or decision-making is automated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A simple, repeatable scoring model that rates likelihood and impact helps turn findings into remediation priorities. Consistency across assessments enables trend analysis and supports executive decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="executive-grade-outputs"&gt;Executive-grade outputs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk assessments should culminate in outputs that business leaders can act on. This includes a concise risk heat map, a prioritized remediation roadmap and clear asks, such as budget, ownership and timelines. These deliverables convert technical findings into strategic decisions. They also help build trust with stakeholders, especially in organizations that may be new to formal risk management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="target-for-smaller-teams"&gt;Target for smaller teams&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Targeted risk assessments can be viewed as a low-cost, fundamental option. They are best suited to companies that have limited budget or are not prepared for a full review of the framework. With reduced scope, shorter turnaround and transparent business value, such assessments enable rapid establishment of trust, delivering prioritized outcomes. They help to create a roadmap for deeper engagement and make cybersecurity accessible to smaller teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By starting small, organizations can build credibility and expand into broader programs, such as continuous monitoring, remediation or full framework alignment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-pragmatic-mindset"&gt;A pragmatic mindset&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk assessments are not just checkboxes. They are tools for making decisions. The best programs are aligned with the business, focused, consistent and made to change over time. For many organizations, a short, focused assessment gives executives the evidence they need to justify budgets and demonstrate due diligence. It delivers immediate value and creates a pathway to sustained risk management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088198/beyond-the-checklist-shifting-from-compliance-frameworks-to-real-time-risk-assessments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malicious npm package sneaks into GitHub Actions builds</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088529/malicious-npm-package-sneaks-into-github-actions-builds.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A malicious npm package named “@acitons/artifact” was found impersonating the legitimate “@actions/artifact” module, directly targeting the CI/CD pipelines within GitHub Actions workflows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Veracode findings, the package was uploaded on November 7 and was designed to trigger during the build process of GitHub-owned repositories. Once executed inside a CI/CD runner, the payload captures any tokens available to that build environment and then uses those credentials to publish malicious artifacts–effectively impersonating GitHub itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This incident isn’t just about a malicious npm package, it is about the blind trust many organizations place in the modern supply chain,” said Randolph Barr, CISO at Cequence Security. “Most organizations focus their controls on runtime environments, yet the CI/CD pipeline often runs with higher privilege than any developer. A single typosquatted dependency can silently execute code during a build, access repository tokens, and impersonate an organization, just as this attack attempted to do with GitHub’s own repositories.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malicious package picked up over 260k downloads before detection, and a total of six versions were uploaded–none detectable by “any popular anti-virus” products, Veracode researchers noted in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GitHub says that the packages were uploaded internally as part of its red teaming efforts. “The packages referenced in Veracode’s blog were part of a tightly controlled exercise conducted by GitHub’s Red Team,” a GitHub spokesperson told CSO. “GitHub takes security seriously and regularly tests its security posture through rigorous, realistic Red Team exercises to ensure resilience against current threat actor techniques. At no point were GitHub systems or data at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hijacking the GitHub Actions build process&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the surface, @acitons/artifact package looked normal with its metadata describing it as “actions artifact lib,” and its homepage and repository URLs closely mirroring those of the legitimate GitHub project. But embedded inside was a post-install hook that downloaded and executed an obfuscated shell script named “harness.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veracode’s &lt;a href="https://www.veracode.com/blog/malicious-npm-package-targeting-github-actions/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; showed that this script, compiled with a shell-script compiler tool, contained a time-based kill switch set to deactivate after November 6, 2025–likely to evade detection after a brief active window. Once invoked, the harness would fetch a JavaScript file (“verify.js” meant to check whether the build environment belonged to GitHub and, if so, exfiltrate &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4052826/ghostaction-campaign-steals-3325-secrets-in-github-supply-chain-attack.html"&gt;GitHub Action&lt;/a&gt; tokens. These tokens could then be misused to impersonate GitHub and publish malicious releases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Typosquatting is a well-known and growing threat vector in software supply chains whereby attackers publish packages with similar names as legitimate ones and then wait for a mistake to happen, bringing the victim to their repository to install malicious code by mistake,” explained Boris Cipot, Senior Security Engineer at Black Duck. “This attack strategy is designed to exploit typos and to leverage the automated nature of CI/CD pipelines.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cipot added that the use of a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081790/typo-hackers-sneak-cross-platform-credential-stealer-into-10-npm-packages.html?utm=hybrid_search#:~:text=npm%20postinstall%20script"&gt;post-install hook&lt;/a&gt; and a short-lived obfuscated payload shows a deliberate attempt to blend in with normal build activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="lessons-in-defense"&gt;Lessons in defense&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Barr pointed out that higher privileges in CI/CD pipelines make them an ideal target. Attackers who compromise a build runner can inject code at the source, sign releases with legitimate credentials, or push authentic-looking artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mitigations, Cipot recommended, would include short-lived, scoped tokens with regular secret rotations. Automated scanning for suspicious packages using tools like Socket.dev or Phylum might also help stay ahead of the threat. Other ways to verify package authenticity include checksum validation and emerging standards like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572893/sigstore-explained-how-it-helps-secure-the-software-supply-chain.html"&gt;Sigstore&lt;/a&gt;, he added. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, advises an immediate response for teams potentially affected. “Search source code, lockfiles, caches, and registries for @acitons and 8jfiesaf83 then quarantine any runners that fetched them,” he said. “Rotate all tokens and review artifacts and package publish history for the period from October 29 to November 6, 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088529/malicious-npm-package-sneaks-into-github-actions-builds.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google asks US court to shut down Lighthouse phishing-as-a-service operation</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088993/google-asks-us-court-to-shut-down-lighthouse-phishing-as-a-service-operation.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google is asking to a US court for help in dismantling the infrastructure behind the Lighthouse phishing-as-a-service operation, the latest effort by a technology company to use the legal system to put a dent in cybercrime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whether it will do more than that is an open question.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a blog Monday, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/legal-action-and-legislation-fight-scammers/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google’s general counsel Halimah DeLaine Prado said&lt;/a&gt; the court action is needed because the gang behind this scam exploits Google and other brands by illegally displaying their trademarks and services on fraudulent websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We found at least 107 website templates featuring Google’s branding on sign-in screens specifically designed to trick people into believing the sites are legitimate,” she wrote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threat actors who buy access to the Lighthouse service send text messages to people, including employees of organizations, with branding appearing to come from a legitimate provider. They hope the branding is convincing enough to induce an unwary person to click a link and share information such as email credentials, banking information and more. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="many-court-orders-sought"&gt;Many court orders sought&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google’s action follows that of other technology companies, most notably Microsoft, as well as some countries, to dampen the efforts of threat actors through the courts. For example, &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/09/16/microsoft-seizes-338-websites-to-disrupt-rapidly-growing-raccoono365-phishing-service/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in September, Microsoft got a court order allowing it to seize 338 websites &lt;/a&gt;associated with the distribution of RacoonO365, a phishing kit used to steal Microsoft 365 credentials. Since July 2024, RaccoonO365’s kits have been used to steal at least 5,000 Microsoft credentials from people in 94 countries, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In January, Microsoft &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/01/10/taking-legal-action-to-protect-the-public-from-abusive-ai-generated-content/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;got a US court order allowing it to seize a website&lt;/a&gt; behind a foreign-based threat actor distributing tools for bypassing safety guardrails of generative AI services of several tech companies, including its own. The threat actor’s software exploited exposed customer credentials scraped from public websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And in August, &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-coordinated-disruption-actions-against-blacksuit-royal" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the US Justice Department announced coordinated actions&lt;/a&gt; against the BlackSuit (Royal) Ransomware group which included the takedown of four servers and nine domains, with the help of the FBI and international law enforcement agencies in the United Kingdom, Germany, Ireland, France, Canada, Ukraine, and Lithuania. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, threat actors can be resilient. For example, in 2020 Microsoft, Symantec, ESET, communications provider NTT, and Lumen Technologies combined with others to&lt;a href="https://www.security.com/threat-intelligence/trickbot-botnet-ransomware-disruption" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt; get a US court order&lt;/a&gt; directing web hosting providers to take down the IT infrastructure distributing the Trickbot botnet. But a&lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/cybersecurity-101/what-is-trickbot" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ccording to researchers at Huntress&lt;/a&gt;, TrickBot is still being used by threat actors for remote access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Google blog also said the company is urging the US Congress to adopt the Guarding Unprotected Aging Retirees from Deception (GUARD) Act, which would enable state and local law enforcement to utilize federal grant funding to investigate financial fraud and scams specifically targeting retirees; the Foreign Robocall Elimination Act, which would establish a taskforce focused on how to best block foreign-originated illegal robocalls before they ever reach American consumers; and the &lt;a href="https://www.cbo.gov/publication/61864" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Scam Compound Accountability and Mobilization&lt;/a&gt; (SCAM) Act, which would develop a national strategy to counter scam compounds, enhance sanctions, and support survivors of human trafficking within these compounds. Scam compounds are physical installations where significant transnational criminal organizations carry out cyber-enabled fraud operations, frequently using the forced labor of victims of human trafficking&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google refused a request for an interview to get more details about its announcement, explaining it had nothing more to say beyond DeLaine Prado’s blog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="will-have-minimal-impact"&gt;Will have ‘minimal impact’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/ed-dubrovsky/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ed Dubrovsky&lt;/a&gt;, chief operating officer of incident response firm Cypher, is skeptical of the effectiveness of court action. Phishing-as-a-service operations don’t have to be on American soil, he explained, so court orders and legislation will likely have minimal impact on smishing or phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However,” he added, “I can understand that even small steps can lead to broader impact, and that might be why Google is taking these steps.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But this and similar court actions won’t change threat actor behavior or the need for IT departments to have controls to face cyber risks, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellman/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kellman Meghu,&lt;/a&gt; principal security architect at Canadian incident response firm DeepCove Cybersecurity, believes Google and other tech firms around the world are looking to the courts and legislatures in part to stop scams, but also to protect themselves from being sued if they can shut down a criminal online service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The reality now is that there is very little to no risk to running scams,” he told CSO in an email, “since the chance of suffering any ramifications is barely a reality. [Running a malicious online operation] gives attackers the chance to just keep trying things until eventually something works. Driving real legislation and legal impacts that can span borders would be very valuable to reduce this threat, if in fact they can build legislation that is effective, and could go a long way in reducing the risk of constant attempts to compromise users.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But global efforts to fight cybercrime can only be effective if tech companies around the world work with governments to share information on cyber crime, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, he doubts many competitive technology suppliers would join an effort because they have a vested interest in saying that they are safer, better, faster than the competition, so they can sell more services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="any-reduction-in-scams-would-help-it-departments"&gt;‘Any reduction in scams would help IT departments’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich,&lt;/a&gt; dean of research at the SANS Institute, said Google has a huge problem with scammers paying for ads that direct victims to fraudulent websites and malware. “Any reduction in these scams would be a significant help to IT departments,” he said, “making it easier to defend networks against these scams.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposed US legislation doesn’t necessarily add any substantial new barriers for scammers, he added, but it would provide more funding for state and local law enforcement agencies that are often overwhelmed by complaints from victims of cybercrime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, he argued that robocalls could be fought more effectively by telecommunication providers, without new legislation, and they have taken some steps to do so.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue of scam compounds is likely not going to be significantly affected by any legislation, as they are too ephemeral and agile and would easily evade sanctions, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Among the issues mentioned, the paid-for Google ads advertising malicious resources is by far the most significant problem for security teams,” Ullrich said. “Google must step up its game in blocking them, and finding legal ways to eradicate the origin may be more effective than the current ‘whack the mole’ tactic, which is not working.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088993/google-asks-us-court-to-shut-down-lighthouse-phishing-as-a-service-operation.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What CISOs need to know about new tools for securing MCP servers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087656/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-new-tools-for-securing-mcp-servers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Model Context Protocol allows AI agents to connect to data sources but the first iteration of this standard &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4015222/mcp-uses-and-risks.html"&gt;lacked serious security&lt;/a&gt;. Over the past few months, a multitude of vendors appeared to help solve the problem. Is the technology now ready for prime-time, or is it still too early to put into production?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some progress has been made on the core protocol side. In March, support was added for OAuth authentication, and in June, the protocol added support for third-party authentication servers such as Auth0, Okta, or a company’s own identity management system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The MCP standards body also launched an official &lt;a href="https://modelcontextprotocol.info/tools/registry/"&gt;MCP registry&lt;/a&gt; in September, in order to address the problem of malicious MCP servers masquerading as legitimate ones.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But significant security gaps remain. For example, authentication is optional, and the systems are vulnerable to prompt injections, tool poisoning, token theft, cross-server attacks, message tampering and more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies looking to get ahead of the competition when it comes to building agentic AI systems have to do a lot of security heavy lifting to keep these tools from exposing all their corporate secrets and sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, over the past few months, vendors have been stepping up. Today, the major AI platforms have added security infrastructure, as have core technology providers, existing cybersecurity vendors, and a fleet of emerging players.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="challenges-of-different-uses-of-mcp-servers"&gt;Challenges of different uses of MCP servers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are three main types of MCP server deployments, and each one has their own security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When a company sets up an internal MCP server, on infrastructure they control, to access internal data or tools, to be used by AI agents that they also control. First, a low-risk use of this might be to allow employees to use AI agents to search through non-sensitive documents or databases, such as product descriptions. A higher-risk use case might be to allow access to customer data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second, a company might allow their AI agents to access external data sources or tools via MCP servers. Here, one concern might be that the information the AI agents get back might include malicious instructions because either the server or the data source is compromised by an attacker.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The third deployment type is that of an internal MCP server exposing a company’s data or tools to the outside world. Again, this could be a low-risk use case if the MCP server provides access to product descriptions or user manuals. But it could also be extremely risky if MCP servers that allow external partners to connect in and place orders, submit invoices, and change their payment addresses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are ways to ease into MCP deployments, says Anh Hatzopoulos, co-founder and CEO at PepperMill, a no-code AI platform. For example, an MCP server that goes and gets public LinkedIn information is going to be safer than one that handles financial transactions, she says. “With moving money, I’m surprised that people are going hard at it right now, given the security problems with MCPs. But someone has to do it — and someone will discover those security problems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, for many tech companies, especially SaaS vendors, MCP servers are already a must-have. “They can’t wait,” says Peter Nebel, chief strategy officer at cloud consultancy AllCloud. “If they wait, their competition will be there before them and have the MCP advantage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that have already released official MCP servers for public use include PayPal, Notion, HubSpot, CloudFlare, Atlassian, Slack, and GitHub. There are also third-party providers building MCP servers. Zapier, for example, currently offers MCP connections to 8,000 different apps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If a vendor doesn’t offer their own, official MCP server, someone else might set up unofficial ones that use the vendor’s APIs. For example, there are already MCP servers out there for LinkedIn, Spotify, eBay, YouTube, AWS, Zillow, and many other platforms, some more trustworthy than others. Developers and power users are downloading them and using them to give their AI agents access to those platforms, but it’s not always obvious where some of these less-than-official MCP servers are coming from, who’s maintaining them, and what else they do under the covers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pulse MCP &lt;a href="https://www.pulsemcp.com/servers"&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt; over 6,000 servers. MCP marketplace MCP.so currently &lt;a href="https://mcp.so/"&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt; more than 16,000. And a GitHub search for “MCP server” produces more than 45,000 results.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-look-for-in-an-mcp-security-platform"&gt;What to look for in an MCP security platform&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whether a company connects their own agents to third-party MCP servers, their own MCP servers to third-party agents, or their own servers to their own agents, there’s going to be the potential for data leakage, prompt injections and other security threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That means companies will need to check for authorizations and permissions, implement fine-grained access controls, and log everything, says AllCloud’s Nevel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are some other MCP security tools that vendors are offering today:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCP server detection&lt;/strong&gt;: It’s easy for company employees to download and run their own MCP servers. These servers could boost their productivity or they could be a new attack vector. Some MCP security vendors are offering scanning services to help companies find all instances of shadow MCP servers in their environments.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runtime protection&lt;/strong&gt;: AI agents communicate with MCP servers in plain English. That creates the potential for prompt injections, data leaks and other security issues. Many MCP security vendors offer tools to monitor all communications for these and similar problems.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication and access controls&lt;/strong&gt;: The core MCP protocol now supports OAuth, but that’s just the start. For additional security, vendors offer zero trust and least privilege control frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logging and observability&lt;/strong&gt;: Vendors can provide platforms to collect MCP logs, alert security teams about security events or policy violations, collect compliance data, or feed logs into existing security infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="vedors-offering-mcp-security-tools"&gt;Vedors offering MCP security tools&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Below, we divide in three sections the list of vendors offering MCP security tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="hyperscalers"&gt;Hyperscalers&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For companies all-in on a particular cloud platform, going with the MCP tools provided by that particular hyperscaler can be an easy way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AWS launched its own agentic AI platform in July. Amazon Bedrock AgentCore includes a gateway that supports multiple protocols, including MCP, an identity management system and observability. In October, AWS followed this up with a set of guidelines for securing MCP servers with &lt;a href="https://builder.aws.com/content/33oERPjcEutnPmaud1BvlPRP9zR/security-guidelines-for-model-context-protocol-in-aws"&gt;zero trust&lt;/a&gt; best practices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft announced a basic Azure MCP server in April, added support for the Azure Key Vault in May, announced MCP support in the Azure AI Foundry Agent Service in June, and announced Azure API Management support in August. Azure API Management means that MCP servers can have secure and governed access to resources, with observability and control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In October, Microsoft announced the Microsoft Agent Framework, which includes support for both MCP and the Agent2Agent protocol, protection against prompt injection, PII detection, and multi-agent observability to ensure that the systems are doing what they’re supposed to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud announced its MCP Toolbox for Databases in April with authentication and observability built in. In September, it released a reference architecture for securing MCP servers on the Google Cloud Platform, based around a centralized MCP proxy architecture. It uses the Google Identity Platform to validate identities and issue OAuth tokens, uses Model Armor to check messages for prompt injections, jailbreaks, or sensitive data, and a Secret Manager to store API keys, credentials, and sensitive configuration values. Its Artifact Registry can store MCP server images and scan them for vulnerabilities before they are deployed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google also recommends using network-level security controls to isolate MCP servers and reduce the risk of lateral movement. Finally, Google’s Security Command Center can identify unauthorized access and data exfiltration attempts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="major-technology-providers"&gt;Major technology providers&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare: Cloudflare announced &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/zero-trust-mcp-server-portals/"&gt;MCP Server Portals&lt;/a&gt;, which enable enterprises to centralize, secure, and observe every MCP connection. This feature is part of Cloudflare One, the company’s secure access service edge (SASE) platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks: The company launched the &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/blog/2025/06/securing-ai-agent-innovation-prisma-airs-mcp-server/"&gt;Prisma AIRS MCP Server&lt;/a&gt; in June. It sits between the AI agent and the MCP server and detects malicious content in data, helping protect against prompt injection attacks, as well as web and DNS attacks. Another tool, MCP Security in Cortex Cloud WAAS, sits at the network boundary, and inspects MCP communications for malicious activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne: &lt;a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/avoiding-mcp-mania-how-to-secure-the-next-frontier-of-ai/"&gt;SentinelOne Singularity Platform&lt;/a&gt; offers visibility into the MCP interaction chain, as well as alerts and automated incident response, for both local and remote MCP servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VMware: In August, parent company Broadcom &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4045708/vmware-explore-2025-broadcom-tackles-agentic-ai-security-challenges.html"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that VMware Cloud Foundation will offer more security for agentic workflows, including MCP servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="startups"&gt;Startups&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Acuvity: &lt;a href="https://acuvity.ai/"&gt;Acuvity&lt;/a&gt; secures MCP servers by hardening them with least-privilege execution, immutable runtimes, continuous vulnerability scanning, authentication, and threat detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Akto: API security company Akto launched an &lt;a href="https://www.akto.io/mcp-security"&gt;MCP security&lt;/a&gt; solution in June, claiming to be the first dedicated security solution specifically built to protect MCP servers. It includes a discovery tool for finding the MCP servers deployed in corporate environments, security testing tools, and monitoring and threat detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Invariant Labs: Their &lt;a href="https://github.com/invariantlabs-ai/mcp-scan"&gt;MCP-Scan&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source scanner that performs static analysis of MCP servers and does real-time monitoring to detect tool poisoning attacks, rug pulls, and prompt injection attacks. A commercial product, Invariant Guardrails, is a proxy that sits between AI agents and MCP servers and protects against project injections and other MCP security threats, and allows companies to impose rules such as prohibiting PII from going to external email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Javelin: The company’s &lt;a href="https://www.getjavelin.com/ai-security"&gt;AI Security Fabric platform&lt;/a&gt; includes MCP security, such as functionality to scan for risky servers, or to block or require review of agent tools or data requests. In addition, MCP guardrails stop unsafe calls and poisoned inputs in real-time and prevent prompt injections and data leakage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lasso Security: Open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/lasso-security/mcp-gateway"&gt;MCP gateway&lt;/a&gt; that allows configuration and lifecycle management of MCP servers and sanitizes sensitive information in MCP messages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.mcptotal.io/"&gt;MCPTotal&lt;/a&gt;: Offers a hub to manage, run and monitor MCP servers in a secure, sandboxed environment, as well as a gateway to protect AI workflows interacting with both internal and external MCP servers, and a governance tool to monitor and enforce AI tool use policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Noma: Recently launched &lt;a href="https://noma.security/solutions/ai-agent-security/"&gt;AI Agent Security&lt;/a&gt; solution offers support for discovery of MCP connections, vulnerability scanning, access policy enforcement, real-time prompt guardrails, and audit trails.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obot: The &lt;a href="https://obot.ai/"&gt;Obot MCP gateway&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source platform to manage MCP servers, define security access policies, and track usage and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operant: Operant &lt;a href="https://www.operant.ai/solutions/mcp-gateway"&gt;MCP Gateway&lt;/a&gt; automatically catalogs MCP tools, discovers AI agents, and tracks traffic between agents and servers to eliminate MCP blind spots. It can also identify threat vectors such as tool poisoning, jailbreaks and unauthorized access, prevent data leaks, and establish a centralized governance framework for agents and tools across the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Solo: The company’s &lt;a href="https://www.solo.io/products/agentgateway-enterprise"&gt;Agent Gateway&lt;/a&gt; was overhauled in August to support MCP and A2A protocols and protects against malicious prompts and data leaks, enforces strong authentication, and centralizes logging and tracing for every interaction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Teleport: Its &lt;a href="https://goteleport.com/use-cases/secure-model-context-protocol/"&gt;Secure MCP&lt;/a&gt; tool for its Infrastructure Identity Platform allows companies to unify how they govern human, machine, workload, device, and AI identities. MCP Security provides identity, access control, governance, and audit tools in a zero trust and least privilege environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087656/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-new-tools-for-securing-mcp-servers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-732)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-732</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-732</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-733)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-733</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-733</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-734)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-734</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-734</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-735)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-735</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-735</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–736)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-736</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-736</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.06</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-677) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 20:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK cybersecurity bill brings tougher rules for critical infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088549/uk-cybersecurity-bill-brings-tougher-rules-for-critical-infrastructure.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The UK government has introduced a new legislation to harden national cyber defenses across critical infrastructure, imposing turnover-based penalties and granting ministers emergency powers to intervene during major cyber incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Cyber Security and Resilience Bill, unveiled Tuesday, would require organizations in healthcare, energy, water, transport, and digital services to meet mandatory security standards and report significant cyber incidents within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that fail to comply could face daily fines of up to $132,000 (£100,000) or penalties tied to annual turnover, the Department for Science, Innovation and Technology (DSIT) &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tough-new-laws-to-strengthen-the-uks-defences-against-cyber-attacks-on-nhs-transport-and-energy" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill, expected to receive Royal Assent in 2026, updates the UK’s Network and Information Systems Regulations (NIS) 2018, expanding coverage to include managed service providers (MSPs), data centers, and key suppliers for the first time. It supports the government’s &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/missions" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Plan for Change&lt;/a&gt; strategy aimed at strengthening national resilience while driving economic growth, the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="turnover-linked-penalties-and-a-behavioural-shift"&gt;Turnover-linked penalties and a behavioural shift&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill marks a turning point in how the UK enforces cybersecurity compliance. “The penalties change behaviour in a way flat fines never could,” said Sanchit Vir Gogia, chief analyst and CEO at Greyhound Research. “For large operators, every breach now carries a cost proportionate to their market reach. That link between impact and liability forces investment before the incident, not after it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The legislation introduced significantly tougher enforcement powers than those found in the EU’s NIS2 Directive or GDPR, said Madelein van der Hout, senior analyst at Forrester. “The bill sets a precedent for stricter cybersecurity enforcement by combining turnover-based penalties with emergency government powers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposal followed a series of damaging cyber incidents that exposed vulnerabilities in UK infrastructure. In 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2099498/suspected-chinese-hack-of-britains-ministry-of-defence-payroll-linked-to-government-contractor-minister-confirms.html"&gt;hackers compromised&lt;/a&gt; a Ministry of Defence payroll system via a contractor, exposing data of 270,000 armed services members. The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2138778/london-hospitals-face-days-of-disruption-after-ransomware-attack-on-supply-chain-partner.html"&gt;Synnovis ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt; on an NHS pathology provider disrupted more than 11,000 medical appointments, costing roughly $43 million (£32.7 million). The British Library breach in late 2023 caused losses of up to $9 million (£7 million), and recent attacks on Marks &amp;amp; Spencer and Jaguar Land Rover have renewed pressure on policymakers to act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An independent &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/independent-research-on-the-economic-impact-of-cyber-attacks-on-the-uk"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; cited by DSIT estimated that cyberattacks cost the UK economy about $19.4 billion (£14.7 billion) each year or about 0.5% of the GDP.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="msps-and-data-centers-under-scrutiny"&gt;MSPs and data centers under scrutiny&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, medium and large managed service providers (MSPs) would fall within the scope of cybersecurity regulation. They must report significant incidents promptly to both government and customers, maintain detailed response plans, and demonstrate readiness to handle cascading impacts, the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hout said the new framework will “reshape the MSP sector,” creating stronger detection and faster response cycles. “For enterprise clients, it promises earlier alerts and greater assurance that their providers adhere to minimum security standards.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill’s 24-hour reporting mandate will pressure MSPs and digital service providers to upgrade operations. “Many organisations will find their processes too slow and fragmented to meet that clock,” Gogia warned. Shivraj Borade, senior analyst at Everest Group, added that the rule will prompt MSPs to “invest in SOC maturity, rapid triage, and legal alignment,” which will fundamentally alter pricing and client relationships.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The legislation also shifted accountability between enterprises and their service partners. “For the first time, we place more responsibility with the MSSP where it normally lies with the enterprise,” said Hout. “It raises expectations for both parties: MSSPs will carry greater legal accountability, and enterprises must perform tighter due diligence.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the bill, data centers will also come under direct regulatory oversight for the first time, joining a broader group of operators responsible for managing power flow to smart devices and electric vehicle chargers. Organizations in scope must notify regulators and the National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) within 24 hours of a significant cyber incident and submit a full report within 72 hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="emergency-powers-and-expanded-oversight"&gt;Emergency powers and expanded oversight&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Under the bill, the technology secretary would gain authority to direct regulators and organizations, including NHS trusts and utilities, to take “specific, proportionate steps” to prevent or mitigate cyberattacks where national security is threatened. These interventions could include enhanced monitoring or temporary network isolation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The emergency powers recognize that cyber incidents evolve faster than committees can respond,” Gogia said. “Allowing the government to instruct critical sectors during live threats makes the system capable of acting in minutes, not weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regulators would also be empowered to designate critical suppliers, such as diagnostics providers or chemical manufacturers, to ensure they meet baseline cybersecurity standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088549/uk-cybersecurity-bill-brings-tougher-rules-for-critical-infrastructure.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV25-737)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-737</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-737</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-738)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-738</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-738</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-739)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-739</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-739</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-740)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-740</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-740</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-741)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-741</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-741</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-742)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-742</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-742</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-743)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-743</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-743</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel security advisory (AV25-744)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av25-744</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av25-744</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-745)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-745</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-745</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-746)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-746</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-746</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-747)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-747</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-747</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV25-748)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av25-748</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av25-748</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-749)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-749</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-749</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
