<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:23:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>7 signs your cybersecurity framework needs rebuilding</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094743/7-signs-your-cybersecurity-framework-needs-rebuilding.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity frameworks are the guidelines enterprises use to guard against cyberattacks. The typical framework describes the steps needed to address various cybersecurity risks, detecting latent vulnerabilities, and generally improving the enterprise’s digital defense. Any gaps discovered in the attack surface indicates that immediate steps should be taken to rebuild and strengthen cyber resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mitsloan.mit.edu/faculty/directory/keri-pearlson"&gt;Keri Pearlson&lt;/a&gt;, a senior lecturer and principal research scientist at the MIT Sloan School of Management, says there are many signs that indicate an existing cybersecurity framework needs attention. “If your cybersecurity framework hasn’t been reviewed in the last two months, if you haven’t been dynamically updating things, or if your team hasn’t yet incorporated AI into your cybersecurity thinking, you need to review and possibly rebuild your framework,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Are you risking enterprise security by relying on an outdated security framework? Here are warning signs that indicate it may be time for a much-need overhaul.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-not-having-a-dynamic-process-for-recognizing-changes"&gt;1. Not having a dynamic process for recognizing changes&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake, Pearlson says, is failing to recognize that the current plan is out of date or simply not working. Breaches happen, but that doesn’t always mean your cyber framework needs rebuilding. It does, however, indicate that the framework needs to be rethought and redesigned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building a cyber-resilient organization requires thinking differently, Pearlson states. The best approach, she suggests, is deploying a dynamic process that watches for changes in the environment and initiates a rebuilding process.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The key is to have the right sensing and responding mechanism — which is likely a combination of technology and human activities,” she says, noting that technology can sense change and identify anomalies, and people can evaluate whether the change is a risk that requires attention and investment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-experiencing-a-successful-cyberattack-of-any-size"&gt;2. Experiencing a successful cyberattack — of any size&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nothing highlights a weak cybersecurity framework better than a breach, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-bucher-7194057/"&gt;Steven Bucher&lt;/a&gt;, CSO at Mastercard. “I’ve seen firsthand how even a minor incident can reveal outdated protocols or gaps in employee training,” he states. “If your framework hasn’t kept pace with evolving threats or business needs, it’s time for a rebuild.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber threats are always evolving, so staying proactive with regular reviews and fostering a culture of cybersecurity awareness will help catch issues before they become crises, Bucher says. “Ultimately, keeping your framework robust and up-to-date is the best way to protect your organization and maintain trust.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-continuous-oversight-becomes-a-challenge"&gt;3. Continuous oversight becomes a challenge&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your framework can’t provide continuous oversight, or support proactive risk management, then it’s time to rebuild by aligning with established standards, such as the &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework"&gt;NIST Cybersecurity Framework&lt;/a&gt;, and integrating industry-specific compliance requirements as needed, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidefloyd/"&gt;Dave Floyd&lt;/a&gt;, vice president of cybersecurity sales and service for Hughes Network Systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The best approach to rebuild a cybersecurity framework is to begin with the NIST framework and then overlay it with industry-specific compliance requirements, Floyd advises. This approach ensures that best practices and regulatory obligations for healthcare, financial, and other enterprises are fully addressed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-your-formal-framework-review-process-is-measured-in-years"&gt;4. Your formal framework review process is measured in years&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If there haven’t been any material changes to your framework in the past three-plus years, it’s a strong indication that your framework may be outdated, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandra-mcleod-7a6a61b/"&gt;Sandra McLeod&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at Zoom. “The cybersecurity landscape has evolved rapidly, especially with the rise of generative AI — your framework should reflect these shifts.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;McLeod recommends a complete a biannual framework review combined with a cursory review during the gap years. “This helps to ensure that the framework stays aligned with evolving threats, business changes, and regulatory requirements.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ideally, security leaders should always have their security framework in mind while maintaining a rough, running list of areas that could be improved, streamlined, or clarified, McLeod suggests. “These informal insights should be brought into discussions during the cursory reviews to keep continuous improvement top of mind.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-youre-continually-chasing-alerts-without-performing-predictive-assessments"&gt;5. You’re continually chasing alerts without performing predictive assessments&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your organization is continually in a reactive state instead of a proactive posture, it’s time to re-evaluate the framework, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nimabaiati/"&gt;Nima Baiati&lt;/a&gt;, executive director and general manager of commercial software and security solutions at Lenovo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an organization is stuck in a cycle of continually chasing alerts and incidents, as well as reporting events after the fact &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3511388/want-to-get-ahead-four-activities-that-can-enable-a-more-proactive-security-regime.html"&gt;instead of performing predictive threat assessments&lt;/a&gt;, data analysis, and forward planning, it’s time for a change, Baiati advises. “Of course, there will still be some reactive situations, but if they consume most of the bandwidth of daily operations, it’s probably just a matter of time before more significant incidents occur.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Baiati suggests beginning with a solid understanding of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567279/how-to-establish-your-business-s-risk-tolerance.html"&gt;your organization’s risk appetite&lt;/a&gt; and overall business strategy. “Security, when done right, can be a competitive advantage, since it minimizes operational disruption and optimizes trust,” he states. For example, financial institutions have a low appetite for risk and a critical need to protect the integrity of their data and their reputation. Their business strategy and security are &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080670/what-does-aligning-security-to-the-business-really-mean.html"&gt;inherently connected&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also, because team members are more mobile than ever, endpoint security is now a focus for network security and needs to be included in the cybersecurity framework. “To build strong endpoint security, organizations should take a comprehensive, layered approach that safeguards all aspects of their digital environment — firmware, hardware, software, and the supply chain,” Baiati says. “Evaluate both on-device and cloud-based AI applications to ensure effective, real-time threat detection and response.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-kris-and-kpis-are-trending-negatively"&gt;6. KRIs and KPIs are trending negatively&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If there’s a sense that key risk indicators (KRIs) and key performance indicators (KPIs) are headed in an unanticipated direction, your framework may need to be re-evaluated, says &lt;a href="https://www.protiviti.com/us-en/sameer-ansari"&gt;Sameer Ansari&lt;/a&gt;, head of the data privacy team lead at audit, risk, and compliance consultancy Protiviti.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations that view their cybersecurity framework as a compliance checklist rather than as a tool to inform proper risk decisions are courting danger, Ansari warns. “Organizations should consider key business objectives and risks that they may face and apply the framework through that lens.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When building or updating a framework, many cybersecurity leaders find themselves caught up in benchmarking or comparing themselves to other firms instead of focusing on what matters to their organization, Ansari says. Worse yet is believing that quantity is more important than quality. “Some cybersecurity chiefs will try to combine several different frameworks, creating an unmanageable ‘Frankenstein framework’ that becomes very hard to manage and sustain,” he warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-youve-taken-a-compliance-based-approach"&gt;7. You’ve taken a compliance-based approach&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A common mistake many cybersecurity leaders make is designing a framework that’s primarily designed to “pass the audit,” says &lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/daniel-tobok/"&gt;Daniel Tobok&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of incident response firm CYPFER, instead of targeting business objectives. He cautions that a compliance-only approach often excludes critical input from non-IT stakeholders and typically results in a framework that looks good on paper but fails to deliver meaningful protection in practice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ideally, a cybersecurity framework should evolve continuously, with priority given to the highest-risk areas, Tobok advises. “However, a full rebuild may be necessary when the existing framework no longer protects the organization effectively, or when the cost of incremental fixes outweighs the benefits.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He adds that rebuilding is also warranted immediately after a major enterprise shift, such as a change to the business model, an amended regulatory environment, or an extended threat landscape, all of which can make the existing framework outdated or insufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094743/7-signs-your-cybersecurity-framework-needs-rebuilding.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe tightens the net on sanctions evasion</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</link>
      <description>Europol is reinforcing its support to EU Member States in enforcing EU sanctions, as criminal networks develop ever more sophisticated methods to bypass restrictive measures linked to Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strike against synthetics: authorities seize tonnes of chemicals in Central and Eastern Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/strike-against-synthetics-authorities-seize-tonnes-of-chemicals-in-central-and-eastern-europe</link>
      <description>Emerging trends and strategies to combat synthetic drug trafficking were key topics at Europol’s annual Drugs Conference last week. In this context, the agency has supported two major operations in recent weeks targeting the entire supply chain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/strike-against-synthetics-authorities-seize-tonnes-of-chemicals-in-central-and-eastern-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-760)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-761)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-762)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 arrested for smuggling migrants from Türkiye to France and Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</link>
      <description>On 13 November 2025, the German Federal Police, in close cooperation with French border police and with the support of Europol and Eurojust, have dismantled a criminal network believed to have smuggled nearly 600 people into Europe between 2021 and 2023.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-763)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–764)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-765)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-767)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telecom security reboot: Why zero trust is the only way forward</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095382/telecom-security-reboot-why-zero-trust-is-the-only-way-forward.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Telecom networks are everywhere. They keep the world moving — all the way from managing data, powering business, connecting people across continents and whatnot. For a long time, security in this space was pretty straightforward: build a wall, keep threats outside and trust everything inside. Back when networks were locked down and closed, that was enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But those days are over. Now, workloads sprawl across hybrid clouds, edge devices multiply and third-party vendors are everywhere. The old perimeter? It’s gone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s where zero trust comes in. Not just the latest buzzword, but a must-have survival tool. The problem is, a lot of companies think zero trust is something you can just buy off the shelf. That’s not how it works.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The misunderstanding holding telecom back&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Everywhere you look in telecom, “zero trust” pops up — in boardrooms, strategy docs and vendor pitches. But somewhere along the way, people lost sight of what it really means. Too many leaders treat it like a compliance box to tick or another software rollout.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The truth’s pretty stark: Zero trust is a mindset. It’s about swapping assumptions for constant proof. When that mindset becomes part of the culture, security finally stops being just another chore and becomes how you operate. But most telcos haven’t made that mental shift. They’re living with a false sense of safety and attackers are taking full advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;IT and OT: Impact is linked&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most OT attacks start in IT environments these days. Once attackers get hold of admin credentials or find a weak interface, they can jump straight into the network gear or base-station controllers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bridging this isn’t about shuffling org charts. It’s about seeing everything at once and building a single rulebook. Shared access policies, clear patch priorities and unified threat detection — when you get all that working together, zero trust finally turns into something real.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The real enemies: Persistence and patience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Telecom operators aren’t just up against lone hackers or ransomware gangs anymore. The big threat is patient, well-funded groups — nation-state actors who know how to stay invisible. Attacks like Salt Typhoon have proven these groups can live inside telecom networks for months, quietly stealing data with real geopolitical stakes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA has flagged Volt Typhoon and other China-linked groups for &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa23-144a" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;breaking into telecom operators all over the world since 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Building trust where none exists&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust isn’t just a tech upgrade — it’s about habits. And three habits matter most: always verify, give only what’s needed and make sure problems can’t spread.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always verify:&lt;/strong&gt; Logging in isn’t the end of the check. Every person, device and system gets watched — where they’re connecting from, what they’re doing and if it all looks normal.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Least privilege:&lt;/strong&gt; The less power someone or something has, the less damage they can do if things go sideways. Tightening that up slashes risk — no fancy new tools required.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Segment the network:&lt;/strong&gt; Stop trouble from spreading. Slice networks into smaller, isolated zones — micro-segments. When networks are divided this way, potential breaches can be minimised.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The elephant in the room: legacy tech&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest — legacy infrastructure isn’t going anywhere. Network hardware built decades ago still runs the show, designed for nonstop uptime when trust used to be automatic. Swapping it all out for something new? That’s a massive risk, not to mention wildly expensive. But pretending you can just leave everything as is — that’s worse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, what actually works? You wrap old systems in modern “security shells.” Think secure gateways, centralized authentication and session monitoring. These layers let you boost security now, without gambling with service outages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust isn’t about chasing some perfect setup. It’s about uplifting security posture, step by step. Every verified connection, every workload you isolate, makes your network tougher.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Compliance that works across borders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust doesn’t toss out your compliance rules — it builds on them. Whether you’re dealing with ISO 27001, the NIST Cybersecurity Framework, the EU’s NIS2 Directive or any other local telecom regulation, the bottom line stays the same: keep checking your risks, control who gets in and prove you’re on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once you bake zero trust into these frameworks, compliance stops being a headache. Instead of just ticking boxes, compliance becomes part of everyday security. As threats shift, your protections shift with them. No matter where your network lives, you’re covered and ready for inspection.&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="measurable-momentum-6-kpis-for-the-first-180-days"&gt;Measurable momentum: 6 KPIs for the first 180 days&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Executives don’t want vague promises — they want proof. In the first six months of rolling out zero trust, here’s what you actually track:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You see fewer privileged accounts floating around.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Strange activity gets spotted faster.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Access approvals don’t drag on — governance finally moves at the speed of business.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;More endpoints and workloads are under watch.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;There’s a drop in hackers sneaking around your network.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;IT and OT teams? They’re running real joint-response drills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These aren’t just stats to show off. They prove zero trust isn’t hype — it works. Progress you can point to and build on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;From buzzword to baseline&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust isn’t just talk anymore. It’s how you measure if a network’s really secure. For telecom, adopting it isn’t for show — it’s survival.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner says that by 2027, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/apac/security-risk-management-australia/featured-topics/zero-trust-architecture" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;70% of organizations will start with zero trust for security&lt;/a&gt;. That’s up from less than 20% today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’re still clinging to old perimeter defenses, you’re fighting yesterday’s battles. The leaders see zero trust as a journey. They’re building the networks we’ll all count on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095382/telecom-security-reboot-why-zero-trust-is-the-only-way-forward.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-768)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-769)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 arrests in Bulgaria in a large art trafficking investigation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</link>
      <description>On 19 November 2025, a coordinated effort led by Bulgarian authorities and supported by Europol, resulted in the dismantling of a criminal network involved in large-scale trafficking of cultural goods across Europe and beyond. This operation was conducted under the framework of a Europol operational taskforce. The action day involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Albania, France, Germany, Greece,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years on: remembering the victims of the 13 November terrorist attack in Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</link>
      <description>Today marks ten years since one of the deadliest terrorist attacks in recent European history was carried out in Paris - at the Stade de France, in the streets and inside the Bataclan concert hall. On 13 November 2015, 132 people lost their lives and many more were injured during what became a night of profound tragedy for France and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and partner countries combat online radicalisation on gaming platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</link>
      <description>Conducted on 13 November 2025, this operational action by the European Union Internet Referral Unit (EU IRU) involved the referral of thousands of URLs leading to dangerous and illicit online material. This includes around 5 408 links to jihadist content, 1 070 links to violent right-wing extremist and terrorist content, and 105 links to racist and xenophobic content.This joint action...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUR 47 million in crypto traced to disrupt digital piracy services</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November, Europol, in collaboration with the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional), organised an "Intellectual Property Crime Cyber-Patrol Week”. A total of 30 investigators participated in this operation hosted at the EUIPO headquarters in Alicante, Spain, where they used advanced Open-Source Intelligence Techniques (OSINT) and cutting-edge online investigative tools...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the winners of the 2025 Europol photo competition</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</link>
      <description>Three awards were given out, each decided by a different group of voters:the international law enforcement community represented at Europol’s headquarters,members of the public,and the Heads of Communication of the European law enforcement authorities.The winners of Capture25The Europol Community Vote by the Liaison Bureaux went to Johan Jacob Kleist from Denmark with his photo of a ‘police officer patrolling beneath...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-770)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-771)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-772)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-773)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-766) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16.6 million packages of fake and harmful toys taken off EU markets</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</link>
      <description>Fake toys are poisoning, deafening and injuring children across Europe, while causing major losses to the EU economy. 26 countries, coordinated by Europol, co-led by France, Spain and Romania, and supported by the EUIPO and OLAF, have once again led initiatives to take down the producers and importers of counterfeit toys. With the global toy market valued at up to EUR 300 billion annually, it also remains the second-most counterfeited industry globally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help4U: A new digital platform to support young people facing online sexual abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</link>
      <description>A new digital platform, Help4U, developed by Europol and CENTRIC, has been launched to support children and teenagers facing sexual abuse or online harm. Designed to be simple, private, and accessible, Help4U supports young people with finding trusted advice, understanding their rights, and connecting with people who can help. The platform offers clear, practical guidance for anyone under 18 who needs help, as well as information for parents, teachers, and professionals supporting them.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qilin Ransomware Turns South Korean MSP Breach Into 28-Victim 'Korean Leaks' Data Heist</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/qilin-ransomware-turns-south-korean-msp.html</link>
      <description>South Korea's financial sector has been targeted by what has been described as a sophisticated supply chain attack that led to the deployment of Qilin ransomware.
"This operation combined the capabilities of a major Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) group, Qilin, with potential involvement from North Korean state-affiliated actors (Moonstone Sleet), leveraging Managed Service Provider (MSP)</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/qilin-ransomware-turns-south-korean-msp.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-774)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-775)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New ClickFix attacks use fake Windows Update screens to fool employees</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096241/new-clickfix-attacks-use-fake-windows-update-screens-to-fool-employees.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs and Windows admins should disable the ability of personal computers to automatically run commands to block the latest version of the ClickFix social engineering attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This advice comes from researchers at Huntress, &lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/blog/clickfix-malware-buried-in-images" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;who this week warned&lt;/a&gt; that a new version of ClickFix-based attacks, where employees are tricked into running malicious commands, is circulating.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest tactics of this campaign include steganography — hiding malware in the pixels of an image — and a “highly convincing” fake Windows Update screen that asks the user to open a Run prompt, then paste in and run a malicious command.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That command delivers the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3993289/feds-and-microsoft-crush-lumma-stealer-that-stole-millions-of-passwords.html" target="_blank"&gt;LummaC2&lt;/a&gt; and Rhadamanthys infostealers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress notes that its report comes after the November 13 &lt;a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Operation Endgame law enforcement takedowns&lt;/a&gt; targeting the Rhadamanthys infrastructure. As of November 19, multiple active domains continued to host the Windows Update Lure page associated with the Rhadamanthys campaign. All of these lures point to the same hex-encoded URL structure previously linked to the deployment of Rhadamanthys, although it appears this payload is no longer being hosted. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first step defenders should take is to stop the ability of this malware to run, says the report. “The most effective way to mitigate ClickFix is by disabling the Windows Run box,” says Huntress, either by modifying the Windows Registry or deploying GPO (group policy object) rules to block interaction with the Windows Run box.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After that, the report recommends the standard response for fighting all social engineering attacks: Effective employee security awareness training. “Ensure users are trained on the ClickFix methodology,” says the report, “emphasizing that legitimate CAPTCHA or Windows Update processes will never require pasting and running commands.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="clickfix-warnings"&gt;ClickFix warnings&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/08/21/think-before-you-clickfix-analyzing-the-clickfix-social-engineering-technique/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;have been warning about ClickFix attacks&lt;/a&gt; (sometimes called pastejacking) since at least early 2024. They often start with a phishing lure that pulls the victim to a realistic fake landing page that purports to be a Windows Update page or a government department website. The heart of the attack is in giving users instructions that involve clicking on prompts and copying, pasting, and running commands directly in  the Windows &lt;em&gt;Run&lt;/em&gt; dialog box, Windows Terminal, or Windows PowerShell. This leads to the downloading of scripts that launch malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Two new tactics are used in the latest ClickFix campaign, says Huntress:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the use since early October of a fake blue Windows Update splash page in full-screen, displaying realistic “Working on updates” animations that eventually conclude by prompting the user to follow the standard ClickFix pattern: open the Run prompt (Win+R), then paste and run the malicious command.&lt;br /&gt;Why would an employee do this? Because the request is part of an alleged test to prove the victim is human. A screen saying “Human Verification. Follow 3 quick steps to verify you’re not a robot.” is displayed. It’s like a CAPTCHA request, which is familiar to employees these days. In this case, the three steps are: press the Windows button + R (which opens the Run box); press CTRL + V (which pastes in a command that was automatically copied to the clipboard); and then press Enter to “verify” (which actually runs the command that triggers downloading of scripts).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;steganography, which conceals the final malware stages within an image. Rather than simply appending malicious data to a file, the malicious code is encoded directly within the pixel data of PNG images, relying on specific colour channels to reconstruct and decrypt the payload in memory;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an email, report co-author Ana Pham said steganography is not new to malware operations. “What stands out here is the implementation: rather than simply appending malicious data to an image file, this campaign encodes the payload directly into the RGB pixel values of PNG images, extracting shellcode by reading specific color channels and applying XOR decryption. It’s a more involved approach than basic file-appending techniques, designed to evade signature-based detection.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Windows Update-themed tactic is particularly effective because it mimics something users expect to see: a full-screen Windows Update splash page with realistic animations, she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Given how convincing this lure is compared to standard ‘robot verification’ pages, it’s reasonable to expect other threat actors will adopt similar approaches,” she added. “The source code for these lures contains Russian-language comments and isn’t heavily obfuscated, meaning it could be shared or copied by other groups relatively easily.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attacks-are-now-rampant"&gt;Attacks are now ‘rampant’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ClickFix has become rampant among Huntress’ customers, she said, and is one of the most prevalent threats seen this year. In the past six months, the company has seen a 313% increase in ClickFix-related incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress responded to 76 separate incidents tied to this specific campaign over a one month period from late September through October, with attacks targeting organizations across multiple regions, including the United States, Europe/Middle East/Africa, and Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What ties the incidents together is a specific indicator, Pham said: the initial payload, which ultimately delivers the steganographic loader, always contains a URL where the second octet is encoded in hexadecimal format.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Palo Alto Networks Unit 42 threat intelligence division have also reported seeing more ClickFix attacks. &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/preventing-clickfix-attack-vector/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In a July report&lt;/a&gt;, they said attackers lure victims into copying and pasting commands to apply quick fixes to common computer issues such as performance problems, missing drivers, or pop-up errors. Fake tech support forums are one way these attack start. Threat actors have also been known, in other campaigns, to use fake DocuSign and Okta single-sign-on pages to trick users. Payloads include infostealers, remote access trojans (RATS), or tools that disable security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This delivery method bypasses many standard detection and prevention controls” says the Palo Alto report. “There is no exploit, phishing attachment, or malicious link. Instead, potential victims unknowingly run the command themselves, through a trusted system shell. This method makes infections from ClickFix more complicated to detect than drive-by downloads or traditional malware droppers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In yet another instance, researchers at NCC Group today &lt;a href="https://www.nccgroup.com/research-blog/fake-captcha-led-to-lumma/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;issued this report&lt;/a&gt; on a ClickFix attack they discovered in May that involved a drive-by compromise and the use of a fake CAPTCHA popup, with the goal of installing the Lumma C2 Stealer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-csos-should-do"&gt;What CSOs should do&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But CSOs aren’t without defenses. One is disabling the Windows Run dialogue through registry modifications or Group Policy. As well, they should audit the RunMRU registry key (which keeps a copy of the most recently executed commands from the Run window) during investigations to check if users have executed suspicious commands through the Run dialog. Palo Alto Networks notes some key indicators for suspicious RunMRU contents could be obfuscated content, keywords related to the download and execution of payloads from unknown or suspicious domains, and keywords indicating calls to administrative interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pham also said leaders should deploy endpoint monitoring for suspicious process chains, particularly watching for &lt;em&gt;explorer.exe&lt;/em&gt; spawning &lt;em&gt;mshta.exe&lt;/em&gt;, or PowerShell with unusual command-line arguments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks also warned that some attackers aim to avoid exposing their activity in the RunMRU registry key by presenting instructions to launch a terminal for PowerShell (Windows 11) or Command Prompt (Windows 10). EDR telemetry or Windows Event Logs will show signs of this tactic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While security awareness training is important, it shouldn’t be the only line of defense, said Pham.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“ClickFix succeeds because it exploits user trust and habitual behavior,” she said. “Users instinctively trust CAPTCHA checks and Windows update screens as routine parts of their day. Even well-trained users can be caught off guard by a convincing full-screen Windows Update animation. The most effective [mitigation] approach combines user education with technical controls: disabling the Run dialog, monitoring for suspicious process behavior, and maintaining robust endpoint detection. Defense in depth matters here, training reduces the likelihood someone falls for the lure, but technical controls provide a safety net when they do.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At this time Huntress doesn’t have enough evidence to determine whether this specific campaign was run by a particular threat actor or multiple groups of threat actors, Pham noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096241/new-clickfix-attacks-use-fake-windows-update-screens-to-fool-employees.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 01:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alliances between ransomware groups tied to recent surge in cybercrime</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096263/alliances-between-ransomware-groups-tied-to-recent-surge-in-cybercrime.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A seasonal surge in malicious activity combined with alliances between &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3509281/top-10-ransomware-groups-to-watch.html"&gt;ransomware groups&lt;/a&gt; led to a 41% increase in attacks between September and October. Cybercriminal group Qilin continues to be the most active &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563507/what-is-ransomware-how-it-works-and-how-to-remove-it.html"&gt;ransomware&lt;/a&gt; paddlers, responsible for 170 of 594 attacks (29%) in October, &lt;a href="https://insights.nccgroup.com/review-of-october-2025-threat-intelligence-report%20"&gt;NCC Group reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sinobi and Akira followed with 15% of ransomware attacks rounding up the top three most active ransomware groups in October 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ramp-up in ransomware attacks follows several months of relative stability in the number of attacks from April to August, including a dip between April and June.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Activity began to pick up at the end of the Northern Hemisphere summer, with September recording a 28% month-on-month increase – momentum that has now accelerated into October’s spike, NCC reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The October surge indicates that threat actors are intensifying their operations ahead of what is typically the most active period for cyber crime. “The fourth ‘golden quarter’ of the year sees peak consumer spending from Black Friday, Cyber Monday, and Christmas, presenting greater opportunity for cyber threat actors,” according to NCC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NCC Group’s stats are derived from actively monitoring leak sites favoured by each ransomware group. Of the 594 attacks in October, industrials remained the most targeted sector, with 28% (167) of all attacks. Consumer discretionary (which includes automotive manufacturers, retail businesses, and leisure facilities) suffered 124 attacks. Healthcare moved to third place with 64 attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;North America was hit hardest by ransomware attacks, suffering over half of these incidents (62%), compared to Europe (17%) and Asia (9%).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An annual &lt;a href="https://www.guidepointsecurity.com/newsroom/active-ransomware-groups-reach-an-all-time-high-guidepoint-security-finds/"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; from Guidepoint Security found a 57% year-over-year increase in active ransomware groups. At the same time ransomware victim numbers have stabilized at approximately 1,500-1,600 per quarter since Q4 2024, according to figures from Guidepoint.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ransomware-groups-alliances-axis-of-evil"&gt;Ransomware groups’ alliances: axis of evil&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;New players and alliances between ransomware groups contributed to the overall increase in ransomware attacks in October.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, the &lt;a href="https://flashpoint.io/blog/lockbit-5-0-analysis-technical-deep-dive-into-the-raas-giants-latest-upgrade/"&gt;newly relaunched LockBit 5.0 group&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4070290/lockbit-dragonforce-and-qilin-form-a-cartel-to-dictate-ransomware-market-conditions.html"&gt;aligned itself with other prominent ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) groups DragonForce and Qilin.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alliances between threat groups enable the sharing of tools, infrastructure and tactics to make their attacks more effective.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The alliance between LockBit, DragonForce and Qilin combines technical expertise, resources and infrastructure, creating a network capable of sustaining large-scale ransomware operations whilst complicating attribution and response for organisations and law enforcement,” according to NCC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although no coordinated attacks have been confirmed yet these loose alliances could act as a recruiting tool for affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The partnership is also likely aimed at rebuilding LockBit’s reputation within the cybercrime community, reassuring affiliates of its continued relevance and operational capacity following the 2024 law enforcement disruptions,” NCC adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, new entrants in the form of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4054790/ransomware-upstart-the-gentlemen-raises-the-stakes-for-ot%E2%80%91heavy-sectors.html"&gt;The Gentlemen ransomware group&lt;/a&gt; burst onto the threat landscape with 21 attack claims against healthcare, financial services and IT firms, among others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Part of the reason we are seeing more ransomware groups and variants in the landscape is the increasingly lowered technical barrier to entry for cyber crime,” according to NCC. “Ransomware builders have been consistently leaked or released, meaning that threat actors with low levels of technical sophistication are still able to conduct effective campaigns.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ransomware-groups-change-tactics-to-evade-law-enforcement"&gt;Ransomware groups change tactics to evade law enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest quarterly &lt;a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/tr-rapid7-q3-2025-threat-landscape-report/"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; from Rapid7 also found that newly forged alliances are leading to a spike in ransomware activity while adding that tactical innovations, from refined extortion to double extortion and use of zero day, are also playing a part in increased malfeasance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The quarter also saw 88 active ransomware groups, up from 65 in Q2 and 76 in Q1, signalling an increase in activity as well as highlighting the changing shape of a febrile threat environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Groups such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079316/cross-platform-ransomware-qilin-weaponizes-linux-binaries-against-windows-hosts.html"&gt;Qilin&lt;/a&gt;, SafePay, and WorldLeaks led a wave of alliances targeting industries like business services, manufacturing, and healthcare, Rapid7 reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These same groups began experimenting with file-less operations, single-extortion data leaks, and affiliate service offerings such as ransom negotiation assistance, where a more senior member of the group partners with a less experienced player to extort the victim.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber extortion incident response firm Coveware reports that remote access compromise, phishing/social engineering, and software vulnerability exploitation remain at the core of intrusion activity, but the distinctions between them are increasingly blurred.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Adversaries increasingly obtain access not just by logging into a system, but by convincing someone else to provision it for them,” Coveware explains. “Campaigns that blurred these lines, such as those impersonating SaaS support teams or abusing help-desk processes to gain OAuth authorization, demonstrated how human trust can be engineered into a technical foothold.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Credential-based intrusions through VPNs, cloud gateways, and SaaS integrations continued to serve as the prime vector of ransomware attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Coveware Q3 2025 ransomware &lt;a href="https://www.coveware.com/blog/2025/10/24/insider-threats-loom-while-ransom-payment-rates-plummet#payments"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; identified Akira and Qilin as the two most prominent ransomware variants doing the rounds. Some ransomware groups are rebranding as data-theft-only outfit, ditching file encryption as an extortion tactic, Coveware adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="review-and-reinforce-cybersecurity-measures"&gt;Review and reinforce cybersecurity measures&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Matt Hull, head of threat intelligence at NCC Group, said more than 200 ransomware variants have been identified so far this year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As ransomware activity accelerates and notable attacks continue to cause widespread economic and operational disruption, vigilance is more critical than ever. Organisations should use this moment to reinforce their security measures and test incident response plans,” Hull said. “Proactive monitoring, staff awareness, and secure backups remain key as we move into the year’s peak threat season.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096263/alliances-between-ransomware-groups-tied-to-recent-surge-in-cybercrime.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-776)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-777)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grafana security advisory (AV25-778)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688) – Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neue ClickFix-Kampagne nutzt Fake-Windows-Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096763/neue-clickfix-kampagne-nutzt-fake-windows-updates.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Windows Update" class="wp-image-4000198" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/winUpdate.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Cyberkriminelle nutzen eine gefälschte Windows-Update-Seite, um Mitarbeiter anzugreifen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;PixieMe / Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forscher des Security-Anbieters Huntress sind kürzlich auf eine neue ClickFix-Kampagne gestoßen, die auf Mitarbeiter in Unternehmen zielt. Laut &lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/blog/clickfix-malware-buried-in-images" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Forschungsbericht &lt;/a&gt;haben die Angreifer ihre Malware dabei in den Pixeln eines Bildes versteckt, das eine Windows-Update-Seite vortäuscht. Dort werden die Benutzer aufgefordert, auf Ausführen zu klicken, um einen bösartigen Befehl einzufügen und auszuführen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieser Befehl liefert Infostealer LummaC2 und Rhadamanthys aus. Huntress weist darauf hin, dass sein Bericht nach dem 13. November veröffentlicht wurde, als der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089207/operation-endgame-schaltet-schadsoftware-ab.html" target="_blank"&gt;Ermittlungserfolg gegen Rhadamanthys&lt;/a&gt; bekannt gegeben wurde. Demnach hosteten mehrere aktive Domains noch am 19. November die gefälschte Windows Update -Seite, die mit der Rhadamanthys-Kampagne in Verbindung steht. „Alle Fake-Seiten verweisen auf dieselbe codierte URL-Struktur, die zuvor mit dem Einsatz von Rhadamanthys in Verbindung stand“, so die Forscher. Die Payload wird jedoch offenbar nicht mehr gehostet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="clickfix-angriffe-sind-nichts-neues"&gt;ClickFix-Angriffe sind nichts Neues&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experten &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4018769/clickfix-attacken-bedrohen-unternehmenssicherheit.html" target="_blank"&gt;haben bereits zuvor vor ClickFix-Angriffen&lt;/a&gt; (manchmal auch als „Pastejacking“ bezeichnet) gewarnt. Sie beginnen oft mit einem Phishing-Köder, der das Opfer auf eine realistisch aussehende gefälschte Landing Page lockt, die vorgibt, eine Windows Update-Seite oder eine Website einer Regierungsbehörde zu sein. Der Kern des Angriffs besteht darin, den Benutzern Anweisungen zu geben, die das Klicken auf Eingabeaufforderungen und das Kopieren, Einfügen und Ausführen von Befehlen direkt im Windows-Dialogfeld „Ausführen“, Windows Terminal oder Windows PowerShell beinhalten. Dies führt zum Herunterladen von Skripten, die Malware starten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ana Pham von Huntress betont gegenüber CSO, dass Steganografie für Malware-Operationen nichts Neues ist. „Das Besondere daran ist die Umsetzung: Anstatt einfach nur schädliche Daten an eine Bilddatei anzuhängen, verschlüsselt diese Kampagne die Payload direkt in den RGB-Pixelwerten von PNG-Bildern, extrahiert Shellcode durch das Auslesen bestimmter Farbkanäle und wendet eine XOR-Entschlüsselung an.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dies sei aufwendiger als einfache Techniken zum Anhängen von Dateien, die darauf ausgelegt sind, signaturbasierte Erkennung zu umgehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die Taktik mit dem Windows Update-Motiv ist besonders effektiv, weil sie etwas nachahmt, was die Nutzer erwarten: eine Vollbild- -Seite von Windows Update mit realistischen Animationen“, sagt sie. „Der Quellcode dieser Köder enthält Kommentare in russischer Sprache und ist nicht stark verschleiert, sodass er relativ leicht von anderen Gruppen geteilt oder kopiert werden kann.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forscher der NCC Group haben kürzlich einen weiteren &lt;a href="https://www.nccgroup.com/research-blog/fake-captcha-led-to-lumma/"&gt;Bericht&lt;/a&gt; über einen ClickFix-Angriff veröffentlicht, den sie im Mai 2025 entdeckt haben. Konkret geht es dabei um eine Drive-by-Kompromittierung und die Verwendung eines gefälschten CAPTCHA-Popups – mit dem Ziel, den Lumma C2 Stealer zu installieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tipps-zum-schutz"&gt;Tipps zum Schutz&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der erste Schritt zur Verteidigung gegen Clickfix-Angriffen besteht laut dem Huntress-Experten Pham darin, die Ausführung der Malware zu unterbinden. „Die effektivste Methode zur Abwehr von ClickFix ist die Deaktivierung des Windows-Ausführungsfelds“, so Huntress, „entweder durch Änderungen in der Windows-Registry oder durch Einsatz von GPO-Regeln (Group Policy Object), um die Interaktion mit dem Windows-Ausführungsfeld zu blockieren.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zudem wird eine Standardmaßnahme zur Bekämpfung aller Social-Engineering-Angriffe empfohlen: eine effektive Schulung der Mitarbeiter zum Thema Sicherheitsbewusstsein. „Stellen Sie sicher, dass die Anwender die ClickFix-Methodik kennen“, heißt es in dem Bericht. „Betonen Sie, dass legitime CAPTCHA- oder Windows-Update-Prozesse niemals das Einfügen und Ausführen von Befehlen erfordern.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Außerdem sollten CISOsSie den RunMRU-Registrierungsschlüssel (der eine Kopie der zuletzt ausgeführten Befehle aus dem Ausführungsfenster speichert) überprüfen, um festzustellen, ob Benutzer verdächtige Befehle über den Ausführungsdialog ausgeführt haben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pham empfiehlt außerdem den Einsatz von Endpoint-Monitoring überwachung für verdächtige Prozessketten –  insbesondere mit Blick auf Fälle, in denen explorer.exe mshta.exe oder PowerShell mit ungewöhnlichen Befehlszeilenargumenten startet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Sicherheitsbewusstseinstrainings sind zwar wichtig, sollten aber nicht die einzige Verteidigungslinie sein“, so Pham. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096763/neue-clickfix-kampagne-nutzt-fake-windows-updates.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI browsers can be tricked with malicious prompts hidden in URL fragments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097087/ai-browsers-can-be-tricked-with-malicious-prompts-hidden-in-url-fragments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have demonstrated another indirect prompt injection attack against AI-powered browsers and browser assistants that could lead to phishing, sensitive data exfiltration, credential theft, or malware downloads. The attack, dubbed HashJack, relies on rogue prompts added to URLs after the hash (#) symbol, also known as a named anchor or URL fragment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“HashJack is the first known indirect prompt injection that can weaponize any legitimate website to manipulate AI browser assistants,” researchers from Cato Networks said in the &lt;a href="https://www.catonetworks.com/blog/cato-ctrl-hashjack-first-known-indirect-prompt-injection/"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. “As a result, AI browsers —  including Comet (Perplexity), Copilot for Edge (Microsoft), and Gemini for Chrome (Google) — can be used to enable a wide range of malicious attacks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-client-side-attack"&gt;A client-side attack&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The # character inside a URL has multiple uses: The portion after it tells the browser to jump to a specific section of the loaded page; it can tell JavaScript code on the page what to display in an in-page dynamic navigation scenario; or it can be used to save state information about the user interface, such as user-selected options.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One important aspect is that URL fragment data is never sent to the web server or over the network. It’s only meant for the browser or the code already loaded on the client side. And it turns out that since AI browser assistants are designed to analyze the currently open website for context, they also read the URL fragments passed after #, and these can hide malicious prompts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The client-side nature of this attack means traditional network defenses, such as IPS/IDS and network firewalls, can’t detect it. Server logs don’t capture the portion of URLs after # because it’s never sent to the server, and browser defenses like Content Security Policy (CSP) don’t trigger because nothing on the actual web page is changed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tricking-users-into-clicking-poisoned-links"&gt;Tricking users into clicking poisoned links&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HashJack is essentially a social engineering attack because it relies on tricking users to click on specially crafted URLs inside emails, chats, websites, or documents. However, this attack can be highly credible because it points to legitimate websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine a spoofed email that claims to be from a bank advising customers about suspicious activity in their accounts. Hovering over the link included in the email shows that it points to the bank’s real website, HTTPS and everything, but it’s a long link and somewhere in it there’s the # character followed by a prompt for the AI assistant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many users are likely to trust such a message since it points to the real bank’s website and because long links with a lot of parameters and paths in them are not unusual. But the prompt that follows the # symbol will cause the AI browser assistant to provide attacker-altered instructions to the user, such as calling an attacker-controlled phone number or WhatsApp link for further customer support about the supposed situation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In another scenario, a prompt included in the link can tell an AI browser that acts like an agent —  for example, Perplexity’s Comet —  to take information about the user’s account, transaction history, phone number, and so on from the opened bank site and append it as parameters in a request to the attacker’s server.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other attacks could involve the prompt causing the AI assistant to display fake information that would mislead the user: fake investment advice promoting a certain stock, fabricated news, dangerous medical advice like wrong doses for medicine, malicious instructions that could open a backdoor on the computer, instructions to re-authenticate that include a link to a phishing site, a link to download malware, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;URL fragments cannot modify page content. They are only used for in-page navigation using the code that’s already there, so they are normally harmless. However, it now turns out that they can be used to modify the output of in-browser AI assistants or agentic browsers, which gives them an entirely new risk profile.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This discovery is especially dangerous because it weaponizes legitimate websites through their URLs,” the researchers said. “Users see a trusted site, trust their AI browser, and in turn trust the AI assistant’s output-making the likelihood of success far higher than with traditional phishing.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Different behavior across AI assistantsThe impact was different between the tested AI assistants and across the various scenarios. For example, while prompt injections managed to influence the text output on all the products tested, injecting malicious links proved harder on Gemini Assistant for Chrome, where some links were rewritten as search URLs, and on Edge with Microsoft Copilot, which prompted for additional confirmation when clicking on links in messages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perplexity’s Comet, which is an agentic browser that does more than a built-in AI assistant, was the most susceptible one because it also could fetch attacker URLs in the background, with context information attached as parameters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and Perplexity deployed fixes, but Google did not consider the HashJack technique a vulnerability because it views this as part of intended behavior. It’s worth noting that Cato also tested Claude for Chrome and OpenAI’s Operator browser, but the HashJack technique didn’t work on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097087/ai-browsers-can-be-tricked-with-malicious-prompts-hidden-in-url-fragments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall ransomware attacks offer an M&amp;A lesson for CSOs</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097078/sonicwall-ransomware-attacks-offer-an-ma-lesson-for-csos.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The recent ransomware attacks on organizations with SonicWall SSL VPNs may teach more lessons than just the need for patch management and identity and access control. Some of the victim firms had vulnerable SonicWall devices on their IT networks as legacies of past mergers or acquisitions, suggesting infosec leaders need to be more involved in preparing for M&amp;amp;A deals or risk their organizations being stung by hackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the conclusion &lt;a href="https://reliaquest.com/blog/threat-spotlight-akira-ransomwares-sonicwall-campaign-creates-enterprise-m&amp;amp;a-risk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;from a report this week by researchers at ReliaQuest.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They looked at a series of attacks between June and October using the Akira ransomware strain to target SonicWall SSL VPNs, and found a link: In almost every incident, hackers gained a foothold on an enterprise network by compromising a SonicWall device inherited from a smaller acquired business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When asked, ReliaQuest wouldn’t say how many incidents it had investigated. But the report does say that in each case, IT wasn’t aware the devices were currently in their environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Standard M&amp;amp;A due diligence is not enough,” says the report. “Security teams must proactively secure inherited technologies, prioritizing early visibility into new environments, like remote access tools, to address risky configurations and outdated credentials before attackers exploit them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The warning isn’t new. Experts have been saying for years that examining a potential acquisition’s finances isn’t enough. Scrutinizing its IT assets also has to be involved, so boards understand both the financial and the cyber risks of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Exhibit A: The discovery in 2018 by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567795/marriott-data-breach-faq-how-did-it-happen-and-what-was-the-impact.html" target="_blank"&gt;Marriott that data on hundreds of millions of guests from the reservation system of its Starwood chain of hotels&lt;/a&gt; had been stolen. Marriott bought Starwood in 2016. Its network had been infiltrated two years earlier, and the breach was undetected for four years, even after the Marriott acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security leaders do need to be involved in the M&amp;amp;A process,” said &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/fred-chagnon" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fred Chagnon&lt;/a&gt;, a principal research director at Info-Tech Research, which did a case study on the Marriott-Starwood incident.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One reason why CSOs/CIOs and their equivalents aren’t brought in, he said, is that cyber risk is invisible compared to the hard numbers that can be found in financial records. As a result, “we’ve had difficulty in this industry in communicating cyber risks as financial liabilities” to CEOs and boards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders have to push the message that security risk is enterprise risk, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, he added, the board has to be reminded that it is responsible for assessing the cyber as well as the financial risks of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related content: &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/415233/why-and-when-cios-deserve-a-seat-at-the-ma-negotiating-table.html" target="_blank"&gt;Why, and when, CIOs deserve a seat at the M&amp;amp;A negotiating table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Should infosec leaders be asked to be part of an M&amp;amp;A team, the actual assessment of the potential acquisition should be contracted to a third party expert, Chagnon added. That’s because the security team won’t have time to do it themselves, and the other side will likely be more willing to divulge sensitive IT information to a third party than to a competitor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The majority of M&amp;amp;A activities still follow a security checklist approach, noted&lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/ed-dubrovsky/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt; Ed Dubrovski&lt;/a&gt;, chief operating officer of incident response firm Cypfer, “which essentially is really a glorified third party vendor assessment. Such activities meet the check-in-the-box requirements but do nothing really to address the real core of the issue: lack of current and relevant information about possible risks.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those doing cybersecurity assessments of a potential acquisition should start with an inventory or list of IT assets before asking if the organization has an information security policy and underlying policies, he added. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After an acquisition, CSOs should treat the new network as a third party connection request and keep it segmented until the core risks have been quantified before attempting to integrate environments, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The reality is that the combined risk posture is [only] as good as the riskiest party,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity posture of an acquisition should be a high priority for inspection during the due diligence period, agreed &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fsmontenegro/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fernando Montenegro&lt;/a&gt;, vice president and cybersecurity practice lead at advisory firm Futurum, regardless of the size of the business being acquired.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The security team must be properly connected to the rest of the organization, including the corporate development (corpdev) group that typically spearheads mergers and acquisitions, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The challenge here is that security teams should work with corpdev to have the right framework to analyze these deals, including interviews with key executives at the target company, access to any audit/compliance documentation, and a thorough look at the digital footprint and internal state of the acquired company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ideally, he added, the program includes both ‘outside-in’ and ‘inside-out’ perspectives on the potential acquisition, a thorough review of their security program, history of any security incidents, key third-party relationships they may have, and more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On top of that, there will be numerous considerations about what the IT integration will look like, including network connectivity and business application connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In its report, ReliaQuest notes that SonicWall devices are often used by small and mid-sized firms, which are often M&amp;amp;A targets of larger companies. However, it said, it can’t be sure firms were targeted by Akira operators because they’d swallowed organizations that had SonicWall devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It did say that in the incidents examined, once inside the victims’ networks, the attackers immediately looked for privileged accounts, such as those originating from old managed service provider (MSP) or administrator logins, that had been transferred over during the M&amp;amp;A process. “Crucially, these credentials were often unknown to the acquiring company, and left unmonitored and unrotated post-acquisition,” the report says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We asked ReliaQuest how often vulnerabilities in technology acquired from an M&amp;amp;A cause later breaches of security controls. In response, a spokesperson said, “the fact that we’ve seen consecutive breaches of Akira targeting smaller organizations where they are leveraging vulnerabilities means that larger organizations should address the risks during onboarding and understand the scope before purchasing.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097078/sonicwall-ransomware-attacks-offer-an-ma-lesson-for-csos.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSPM buyer’s guide: How to choose the best cloud security posture management tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-security-posture-management-cspm-explained"&gt;Cloud security posture management (CSPM) explained&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud security posture management (CSPM) combines threat intelligence, detection, and remediation that works across complex collections of cloud-based applications. After companies move to the cloud, many are under the impression that their cloud hosting providers are solely responsible for security, a misconception that can lead to data breaches and other security issues. While the responsibility for securing cloud infrastructure falls to cloud services providers, it’s up to customers to configure the cloud and secure their applications and sensitive corporate data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But securing cloud-based apps and data isn’t simple as there are many threat vectors that operate across neat defensive boundaries. This is why many enterprises have found a need to expand their posture management to more comprehensive products such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573629/cnapp-buyers-guide-top-tools-compared.html"&gt;cloud-native application protection platforms&lt;/a&gt; (CNAPP) or secure service edge (SSE) product lines. CNAPP integrates CSPM with other tools that include &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/557365/what-is-a-cloud-access-security-broker-and-why-do-i-need-one.html"&gt;cloud access security brokers (CASBs)&lt;/a&gt; and tools that directly protect cloud workloads, APIs and infrastructure and include those from vendors such as Wiz, Palo Alto Networks’ Cortex line, Tenable, Crowdstrike and others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SSE products are more network-focused and integrate CSPM with a different set of tools including software-defined wide area networking, secure web gateways and zero trust network access and include vendors such as Zscaler, Cisco, Palo Alto Networks’ Prisma line, Fortinet and Netskope.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ Download our editors’ PDF &lt;a href="https://us.resources.csoonline.com/resources/download-our-cloud-security-posture-management-platform-cspm-enterprise-buyers-guide/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;cloud security posture management (CSPM) enterprise buyer’s guide&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; today! ]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="in-this-buyers-guide"&gt;In this buyer’s guide&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud security posture management (CSPM) explained&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to look for in cloud security posture management (CSPM) tools&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Leading vendors for cloud security posture management (CSPM)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to ask your cloud security posture management (CSPM) provider&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Essential reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s where &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574539/how-automation-in-cspm-can-improve-cloud-security-2.html"&gt;CSPM tools&lt;/a&gt; can help. These tools continuously and automatically check for misconfigurations that can result in data leaks and data breaches. CSPM tools manage cloud security risks on an ongoing basis and ensure compliance in the cloud so enterprises can continuously make any necessary changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CSPM solutions use best practices and compliance (PCI, SOC2, etc.) templates to identify drifts and insecure configurations in cloud infrastructure (AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud) in the compute, storage, and network areas,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrascser/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Andras Cser&lt;/a&gt;, a principal analyst at Forrester Research. “CSPM tools can alert and optionally remediate the insecure configurations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSPM tools look at workloads to see what’s happening and they provide context, so organizations know which of the vulnerabilities or issues is most important, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/charliewinckless/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Charlie Winckless&lt;/a&gt;, a senior director analyst at Gartner. “These tools enable companies to prioritize which risks are real, which risks are important, and which risks they may be able to delay fixing a little bit,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud technologies have been classified as infrastructure as a service (IaaS), platform as a service (PaaS) and software as a service (SaaS). The differences among these three designations are becoming blurred to the point where the labels don’t have much meaning anymore. As enterprises purchase more diverse cloud offerings, the notion of having a single tool such as CSPM that covers all these bases becomes appealing. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-look-for-in-cloud-security-posture-management-cspm-tools"&gt;What to look for in cloud security posture management (CSPM) tools&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations evaluating various CSPM tools should ensure that they cover all the cloud platforms they’re using, says Winckless. “You want to be able to normalize the configuration risks across the major cloud platforms,” he says. “Most organizations that are purchasing these tools will probably be multicloud. They’ll be using at least two clouds, maybe more, since the cloud providers themselves do offer some of this functionality built into their platforms.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Philip Bues, cloud security research manager at IDC, says the new reality for most organizations is a hybrid multicloud environment, “so you want something that’s going to be able to give you really deep visibility throughout all the environments and workloads that you have. And that’s what the CSPM solution should be able to provide you.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other features organizations should look for in CSPM tools include the following:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive threat detection:&lt;/strong&gt; Because threats in multicloud environments are complex, these tools must gather threat intelligence from multiple sources to give companies clear views of their risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated data security:&lt;/strong&gt; Keeping data safe in the cloud requires a multipronged defense that gives companies deep visibility into the state of their data. This includes enabling organizations to monitor how each storage bucket is configured across all their storage services to ensure their data isn’t inadvertently exposed to unauthorized applications or users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated alert remediation:&lt;/strong&gt; Organizations must ensure that the CSPM tools they select can automate routine security monitoring, audits, and remediations across their cloud environments. This allows security teams to prioritize and remediate the risks that can potentially cause the most damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="benefits-of-cspm-tools"&gt;Benefits of CSPM tools&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSPM tools offer multiple benefits that help companies boost security, minimize their risk exposure in cloud environments, and reduce costs. These benefits include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proactively identifying and addressing risks before cybercriminals can exploit them using real-time visibility and automatic detection of vulnerabilities, misconfigurations, and security gaps.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Continuously monitor configurations as they relate to industry benchmarks and standards to ensure compliance with best practices and regulations.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Automating policy enforcement and remediation, which cuts the time and expense of manually resolving security issues across cloud environments.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Integrating devops workflows with CSPM processes to embed security throughout the software development life cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="pitfalls-of-cspm-tools"&gt;Pitfalls of CSPM tools&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are some pitfalls that companies need to be aware of when it comes to CSPM tools, including:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not understanding the requirements of CSPM tools:&lt;/strong&gt; This is one of the biggest mistakes that organizations can make when they’re shifting workloads to the cloud because things that weren’t connected before are now interconnected, says IDC’s Bues. The best way to implement CSPM tools is to ensure teams receive the proper training and proper awareness for how this solution is supposed to work within the environment. “You don’t want to have the security team with little or no cloud experience or developers with limited security experience trying to manage this new CSPM solution,” he says. “You should have the developers and the security team working together because everyone has different needs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not opting for a multicloud CSPM tool: &lt;/strong&gt;Another mistake companies make is selecting tools that offer a one-size-fits-all approach offered by public cloud vendors that don’t offer a unified view across all their cloud environments. Organizations should opt for CSPM tools that provide multicloud monitoring and protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinking they’re too small or not mature enough: &lt;/strong&gt;A company that assumes it’s too small or not mature enough to consider security will always put the business at risk as it typically only thinks about security after an issue or breach occurs. However, companies of all sizes should ensure they protect their assets across teams by implementing CSPM tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leading-vendors-for-cloud-security-posture-management-cspm"&gt;Leading vendors for cloud security posture management (CSPM)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vendors have been incorporating CSPM functions into their overall CNAPP or SSE platforms, including CrowdStrike, Palo Alto Networks, Wiz, Zscaler and Tenable. This means that the modern standalone CSPM tool has all but disappeared. One extreme example is Check Point Systems, who has gotten out of CSPM entirely and has taken its CNAPP efforts to integrate with Wiz’ product line. But it is important to start with this function as you investigate how to protect your cloud estate, and to help with these efforts, we have highlighted a few of the CSPM tools based on discussions with analysts and our own independent research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/platform/singularity-cloud-cspm/"&gt;SentinelOne Singularity CSPM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is part of a collection of integrated modules that together comprise a comprehensive CNAPP solution. You can pinpoint cloud misconfigurations and monitor changes continuously to public clouds from AWS, Azure and Google Cloud. It also includes an offensive detection engine called Verified Exploit Paths and AI-based threat-detection research to help augment its protective features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sweet.security/product/runtime-cspm"&gt;Sweet.Security Runtime CNAPP’s&lt;/a&gt; CSPM&lt;/strong&gt; module is just part of a comprehensive CNAPP solution that offers application, data and API security modules. It monitors changes in near real-time and helps to remediate cloud workload misconfigurations and protects development pipelines. It combines its runtime instrumentation with other metadata to provide overall risk assessment scoring. It also offers a unified management of security issues, such as exposed APIs that are linked to misconfigured identities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/cloud-security/solutions/cspm"&gt;Tenable CSPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is part of its overall cloud security platform, which integrates a wide collection of tools including the traditional CNAPP suite along with more development-oriented protection for AI, code pipelines, data and threat detection tools. It provides continuous security scans across AWS, Azure and Google Cloud along with producing audit reports and integration with its cloud infrastructure entitlement management tools as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="questions-to-ask-your-cloud-security-posture-management-cspm-provider"&gt;Questions to ask your cloud security posture management (CSPM) provider&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When investigating the best CSPM fit for your enterprise security needs, ask potential vendors these questions:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can you calculate your baseline so you can track changes to your cloud-based assets?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Does the CSPM platform work for all three of the major public clouds (Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, and Microsoft Azure) as well as various Kubernetes and other container-based implementations? What about support for common SaaS apps such as Box, Salesforce, ServiceNow, and Workday? Each product’s coverage varies. Some products place agents in your cloud, some use read-only access to scan your environment and resources, and some have writing access to enable changes to remediate issues in your accounts.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How real-time is it for notifications about these changes, policy violations, and other unusual events? Does it track misconfigured weak security groups, remote access, app control mistakes, and network changes? All cloud providers offer built-in activity monitoring, but if you use multiple clouds, you want your CSPM platform to parse this rich supply of data and make actionable sense of it.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How real-time is it to automate remediation? The best CSPM platforms will continuously scan for vulnerable systems and some offer ways that they can detect when a new virtual machine has created an insecure situation for example.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What other security and notification tools does it integrate with, such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/524286/what-is-siem-security-information-and-event-management-explained.html"&gt;security information event management (SIEM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570673/5-tips-for-getting-started-with-soar.html"&gt;security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR)&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How many compliance/auditing reporting frameworks are supported on each cloud provider? Each tool supports a different framework collection, which isn’t necessarily the same across all the clouds either to make things harder for you, too.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What is the cost? Some vendors offer a limited free trial or tier; others charge per host or in more complex ways that might mean a surprise when the bill comes due. Few are like Sysdig that offer a public and transparent pricing webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="essential-reading"&gt;Essential reading&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573629/cnapp-buyers-guide-top-tools-compared.html"&gt;CNAPP buyers guide: Top tools compared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2075321/top-12-data-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;Top 12 data security posture management (DSPM) tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574539/how-automation-in-cspm-can-improve-cloud-security-2.html"&gt;How automation in CSPM can improve cloud security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1303467/is-your-cloud-security-strategy-ready-for-llms.html"&gt;Is your cloud security strategy ready for LLMs?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/202183/what-is-data-governance-a-best-practices-framework-for-managing-data-assets.html"&gt;What is data governance? Best practices for managing data assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story was first published in October 2023 and updated in November 2025.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Teams’ guest chat feature exposes cross-tenant blind spot</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097381/microsoft-teams-guest-chat-feature-exposes-cross-tenant-blind-spot.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A newly highlighted flaw in Microsoft’s cross-tenant collaboration model shows that once a user accepts a guest invitation in Teams, their Defender for Office 365 protections are dropped entirely, leaving them exposed inside an external tenant even while logged in with their home account.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Ontinue threat researcher Rhys Downing, one of Microsoft’s recently enabled features, “MC1182004,” that allows Teams users to initiate chats with any email address, opens an attack vector for threat actors who know cross-tenant security limitations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many organizations assume their controls ‘follow’ the user wherever they go,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/julianbrownlowdavies/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Julian Brownlow Davies&lt;/a&gt;, senior vice president, offensive security strategy &amp;amp; operations at Bugcrowd. “In reality, attackers can spin up a poorly secured tenant, invite your users in with what looks like a perfectly legitimate Microsoft Teams email, and deliver links and files that never touch your own Defender stack at all.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This means the full suite of Defender protections, including URL scanning, safe links, file sandboxing, and zero-hour auto purge, can simply be disabled, turning a harmless-looking collaboration invite into an attack path.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft did not immediately respond to CSO’s request for comments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;New default triggers architectural flaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Downing explained in a &lt;a href="https://www.ontinue.com/resource/blog-microsoft-chat-with-anyone-understanding-phishing-risk/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that the issue isn’t a software bug in Teams, but an architectural reality of cross-tenant collaboration. When a user joins another tenant as a guest, the hosting (resource) tenant’s security settings apply–not the user’s original (home) tenant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, all protections provided by Defender for Office 365 are bypassed if the resource tenant has them disabled or never had them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making an attack easier is the default-enabled feature in Teams, &lt;a href="https://mc.merill.net/message/MC1182004" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MC1182004&lt;/a&gt;, that allows users to start a chat with any email address, even if the recipient isn’t yet part of Teams. That means attackers can simply spin up a Microsoft 365 tenant, invite victims via email, and deliver phishing links or malware-all without triggering the victim’s own security stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Davies echoed Downing’s argument that this is an architectural consequence of how &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/648486/beware-of-overly-permissive-azure-ad-cross-tenant-synchronization-policies.html"&gt;cross-tenant collaboration&lt;/a&gt; works. “At Bugcrowd, we see the same pattern across crowdsourced testing programs, particularly in our Red Team engagements: much of the risk now lives in the connectivity between tenants, identity systems, and collaboration tools, rather than in the individual apps themselves,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mitigations include vetting collaborations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, warns that this is not a mere “bypass bug,” but a blind spot in many organizations’ mental model of cross-tenant risk. “Security teams should respond by treating external guest access as a trust boundary that needs explicit governance rather than a convenience feature that can stay on by default,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Restricting B2B guest invitation to a vetted allow-list of trusted partner domains, and implementing cross-tenant access policies in Microsoft Entra ID to block suspicious guest-tenant access was recommended by Downing to stay ahead of this inherent threat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another key mitigation includes disabling the default “chat with Anyone” feature in Teams, which allows unsolicited external invitations to reach users. This is a practical step for many organizations that can simply do so through the Teams admin center by tightening external policies. Together with the Entra ID &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4060101/entra-id-vulnerability-exposes-gaps-in-cloud-identity-trust-models-experts-warn.html"&gt;warning&lt;/a&gt; from September, the disclosure underscores that a real danger sits in the gaps across Microsoft tenants, where convenience defaults and misplaced trust continue to outpace security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097381/microsoft-teams-guest-chat-feature-exposes-cross-tenant-blind-spot.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-779)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-780)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow is in talks to buy identity security firm Veza for over $1 billion: report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097423/servicenow-is-in-talks-to-buy-identity-security-firm-veza-for-over-1-billion-report-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow is reportedly in advanced talks to acquire Veza, an identity security startup, for more than $1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For ServiceNow customers deploying AI agents across their organizations, the acquisition would address a critical gap: controlling what those agents can access and do. Veza’s technology maps permissions across enterprise systems, showing exactly which users, applications, and AI agents have access to what data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deal could be announced next week, The Information &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/servicenow-advanced-talks-buy-security-startup-least-1-billion" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deal would follow ServiceNow’s &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3842626/servicenow-to-acquire-moveworks-to-strengthen-agentic-ai-and-enterprise-search.html"&gt;$2.85 billion acquisition of Moveworks&lt;/a&gt;, announced in March. That purchase brought AI assistants and enterprise search capabilities to ServiceNow’s platform. Adding Veza would provide the identity security layer needed to govern those AI systems as they access data across cloud services, SaaS applications, and internal systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow and Veza did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="managing-machine-identities"&gt;Managing machine identities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow said in March that it deployed thousands of AI agents for customers across IT, HR, customer service, and security operations. As these agents take on more autonomous tasks, enterprises face mounting pressure to understand what they can access and whether those permissions align with security policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“ServiceNow is trying to build an enterprise platform where AI agents don’t just chat, but actually take meaningful actions inside the business,” said Akshat Tyagi, associate practice leader at HFS Research. “Moveworks gave them a strong automation layer, but trust and governance were the missing pieces. Handing over real-time authority to agents unless identity, permissions, and access rules are rock solid is a bluff no enterprise wants to play.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza addresses what security experts call the non-human identity problem. Every AI agent, API integration, and automated workflow creates service accounts and tokens that need management, according to the company. In most enterprises, these machine identities far outnumber human users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza’s Authorization Graph technology maps permissions across systems to show not just who has access, but what they can effectively do with that access. According to its website, the company manages more than 20 billion permissions for customers, including Blackstone, Expedia, and Workday. Veza has raised $235 million since its inception in 2020 and employed more than 190 people as of April 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tyagi said existing identity and access management tools were designed for human accounts but struggle with machine identities, API keys, and autonomous agents making real-time decisions. “This creates blind spots around privilege sprawl and cross-system access paths,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The two companies already work together. ServiceNow Ventures &lt;a href="https://veza.com/company/press-room/veza-strategic-announcement-servicenow-capitalone/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;invested in Veza in August 2023&lt;/a&gt; alongside Capital One Ventures. The companies have more than 250 joint customers, the report added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="customer-integration-questions"&gt;Customer integration questions&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For those joint customers, the acquisition would mean significant changes in how the two systems work together. Enterprises using both ServiceNow and Veza today run them as separate systems. Integration would allow ServiceNow’s AI agents to natively query and enforce access policies based on Veza’s permission intelligence, without customers building custom connections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That integration will take time, according to Tyagi. “ServiceNow is already a big and complex system, and adding a full identity security engine won’t be instant plug-and-play,” he said. Customers should expect changes to licensing and the introduction of new modules as the two platforms merge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations using Veza without ServiceNow will want clarity on whether the product remains available as a standalone offering. Those using ServiceNow with other identity vendors will need to know if their existing tools remain supported or if ServiceNow will push customers toward its own integrated stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow unveiled AI agents for security and risk management at its &lt;a href="https://www.servicenow.com/company/media/press-room/ai-driven-security-and-risk.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Knowledge 2025 conference&lt;/a&gt; in May, positioning them as tools for autonomous enterprise defense. Veza would provide the authorization controls those security agents need to safely investigate and remediate threats across systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza treats access as a relationship problem, connecting identities, permissions, and data to show effective access rather than just theoretical permissions, according to Tyagi.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="market-implications"&gt;Market implications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acquisition would give ServiceNow a more complete offering against rivals building AI-powered enterprise platforms. Salesforce, Microsoft, and Oracle all offer AI agents, but none had combined front-end automation with identity security in the way ServiceNow was attempting with Moveworks and Veza, according to Tyagi.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This deal can shake up the identity security landscape because it pulls deep authorization intelligence into a major enterprise platform instead of keeping it as a standalone specialty,” Tyagi said. Standalone identity vendors like CyberArk, SailPoint, and Okta may face pressure to find their own platform partnerships or acquisition targets, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097423/servicenow-is-in-talks-to-buy-identity-security-firm-veza-for-over-1-billion-report-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-781)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25-782)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-784)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-783)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-785)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-786)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-787)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
