<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:31:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-044)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV26-045)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-046)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered polymorphic attack lures victims to phishing webpages</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123217/ai-powered-polymorphic-attacks-lures-victims-to-phishing-webpages.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-fueled attacks can transform an innocuous webpage into a customed phishing page. The attacks, revealed in a &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/real-time-malicious-javascript-through-llms/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; from Palo Alto Networks’ Unit 42, are clever in how they combine various obfuscation techniques. The combination though can be lethal, difficult to discover, and represent yet another new offensive front in the use of AI by bad actors to compromise enterprise networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack starts with an original and ordinary webpage then attackers add client-side API calls to LLMs that can dynamically generate malicious JavaScript code in real time. This polymorphic technique is dangerous for several reasons. First, it can bypass any built-in AI model security guardrails. Second, because it delivers its malware from a trusted LLM domain it may bypass typical network analysis. Without any runtime behavioral analysis screening, it won’t easily be discovered or blocked, because the assembly of the final malware code happens inside a client’s browser and leaves no static payload residue anywhere else in the process.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The analysts at Unit 42 wrote a proof-of-concept code that calls popular LLMs such as DeepSeek and Google’s Gemini into returning the malicious JavaScript. The key step is to use separate prompts to craft AI prompts that translate the malware and describe its functionality as plain text, which then generate different pieces of the actual malware code. The AI model can generate a variety of phishing code content and then assemble the various pieces, both of which make detection more difficult. The assembly, as mentioned, is happening at the very end of this malware supply chain, what SquareX &lt;a href="https://sqrx.com/lastmilereassemblyattacks" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;calls&lt;/a&gt; a last mile reassembling attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While this attack isn’t exactly novel, what is new is the type of code pieces that are generated by the AI that are more difficult to detect. The example used in the PoC described four code fragments in its prompting instructions, each fragment involving a different step in the malware’s operations. Each prompt would return a syntactically unique yet functionally identical variant of the malicious code, according to the analysts. Think of this as the AI version of custom-coded malware that was first invented decades ago by attackers looking to evade static signature detection algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are several ways the final malware assembly can be accomplished, including using a backend proxy server or a content delivery network to further hide the malware’s true nature by providing trusted domains to deliver the goods.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Unfortunately, at least some of this comes back to having the user as the last line of defense,” Allie Mellen, Forrester principal analyst, security and risk, told CSO. “This attack prevents the vendors from using some phishing detection techniques, but many of the core phishing detection capabilities are still relevant here.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jess Burn, a Forrester analyst for email security, agrees that there is some protection with existing defensive technologies. However, “even though this attack uses the browser and an LLM to build the phishing page on the fly, the issue is still how users got to that page in the first place. Well-tuned email and collaboration security tools that spot suspicious links, newly registered domains, look‑alike brands, and unusual sender behavior can still stop many of these campaigns at the message layer so the user never clicks through to the ‘magic’ page that turns malicious at runtime.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unit 42 of course recommends Palo Alto Networks’ products to help defend against this attack. Other solutions include using secure web gateways as well as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573875/secure-web-browsers-for-the-enterprise-compared-how-to-pick-the-right-one.html" target="_blank"&gt;secure enterprise browsers&lt;/a&gt; that can prevent last mile attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123217/ai-powered-polymorphic-attacks-lures-victims-to-phishing-webpages.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-048)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-002 -Vulnerability affecting GNU Inetutils Telnetd - CVE-2026-24061</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV26-049)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical RCE bugs expose the n8n automation platform to host‑level compromise</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124343/critical-rce-bugs-expose-the-n8n-automation-platform-to-host%e2%80%91level-compromise.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Two critical sandbox escape flaws in the popular n8n workflow automation platform are allowing authenticated users to achieve remote code execution on affected instances.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to new JFrog findings, sandboxing safeguards meant to contain untrusted workflow logic can be bypassed, exposing enterprise automation environments to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113980/critical-rce-flaw-allows-full-takeover-of-n8n-ai-workflow-platform.html" target="_blank"&gt;full host&lt;/a&gt; compromise. Enterprises that rely on n8n to orchestrate integrations, automate internal processes, and streamline cloud services and on-prem systems are at risk. JFrog’s researchers said n8n’s sandboxing mechanism can fail in specific configurations when users evaluate expressions or run custom scripts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sandbox escapes can expose sensitive credentials, APIs, and infrastructure from affected workflow engines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="expression-engine-sandbox-escape-enables-javascript-rce"&gt;Expression engine sandbox escape enables JavaScript RCE&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the issues identified by JFrog affects n8n’s JavaScript expression engine, designed to evaluate user-supplied expressions during workflow execution safely. According to the researchers, flaws in how expressions are sanitized allow an attacker with permission to create or edit workflows to escape the sandbox and execute arbitrary JavaScript on the underlying host.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JFrog explained in a blog &lt;a href="https://research.jfrog.com/post/achieving-remote-code-execution-on-n8n-via-sandbox-escape/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that the expressions engine’s protections can be bypassed by carefully crafted payloads that exploit assumptions in the sandboxing logic. Once escaped, the attacker is no longer limited to expression evaluation and can run arbitrary commands in the context of the n8n service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When the expression engine encounters a {{}} block, it processes the enclosed content by bypassing it to a JavaScript Function constructor, which then executes the supplied code,” the researchers said. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4115417/malicious-npm-packages-target-n8n-automation-platform-in-a-supply-chain-attack.html"&gt;n8n&lt;/a&gt; uses an AST-based sandbox to neutralize dangerous JavaScript constructs before execution. A missed edge case in the outdated “with statement” allows attackers to bypass these checks and achieve arbitrary code execution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability has been assigned &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2026-1470" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-1470&lt;/a&gt; and carries a critical severity rating of CVSS 9.9 out of 10, owing to the ease with which sandbox restrictions can be broken and the level of access gained post-exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Python code node escape breaks isolation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JFrog also identified a separate sandbox escape affecting n8n’s Python Code node when the platform is configured to use its “Internal” execution mode. In this case, restrictions intended to contain Python code execution can be bypassed, again allowing authenticated users to run arbitrary code outside the sandbox.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second issue, tracked as &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2026-0863"&gt;CVE-2026-0863&lt;/a&gt;, received a high severity rating of CVSS 8.5 out of 10. While the exploitation depends on specific configuration choices, JFrog noted that internal execution mode is commonly used in self-hosted enterprise deployments for performance and operational simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers demonstrated how Python sandbox constraints can be evaded, granting access to system resources that should be off-limits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="urgent-need-to-update"&gt;Urgent need to update&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both issues have been patched, and enterprises running n8n should ensure they are on updated versions. Until patches are applied, organizations are recommended to carefully review who has permissions to create or edit workflows, particularly in environments where n8n has access to internal networks, secrets, or privileged APIs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CVE-2026-1470 has been &lt;a href="https://github.com/n8n-io/n8n/releases" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;fixed&lt;/a&gt; in version 1.123.17, 2.4.5, and 2.5.1, while CVE-2026-0863 is resolved in version 1.123.14, 2.3.5, and 2.4.2. Upgrading to any of these versions mitigates the risk of exploitation, researchers noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124343/critical-rce-bugs-expose-the-n8n-automation-platform-to-host%e2%80%91level-compromise.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skills CISOs need to master in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117799/skills-cisos-need-to-master-in-2026.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Three decades ago, when Steve Katz became the world’s first CISO at Citicorp/Citigroup, he quickly realized that his role was more than solving problems with tech. Katz had to communicate well, meet with C-level executives, and do anything in his power to reduce risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The basic philosophy that I’ve had is data security, information security, information risk is a business risk issue, not a technology issue,” he said in an &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xVGQdR09hPE?si=PgPr4pmNg1GET1eE"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Katz realized that effective CISOs need a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573867/top-skill-building-resources-and-advice-for-cisos.html"&gt;blend of technical and soft skills&lt;/a&gt;: they have to understand emerging technologies as well as business strategy. And in 2026, the story gets even more complicated, as CISOs operate in a difficult context, marked by tight budgets and geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the role evolved, some skills that once served CISOs are no longer differentiators. In their place, new capabilities are taking the spotlight, especially those tied to emerging tech. Today’s CISOs are navigating a world built on cloud-native infrastructure, facing AI-generated attacks, and shifting regulatory rules.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this context, the CISO needs to be an enabler of growth, not a blocker.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In 2026, the CISO who thrives will look much more like a business value and resilience executive than a technical gatekeeper,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/darrenargyle/"&gt;Darren Argyle&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of Cyber Resilience and former group chief information security risk officer at Standard Chartered Bank.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs today are expected to influence strategy, secure investment, and guide transformation, not just protect the perimeter. And without the right mix of skills, doing all of that simply isn’t possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="must-have-skills-for-cisos-in-2026"&gt;Must-have skills for CISOs in 2026&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ask security professionals what makes a strong CISO in 2026, and three qualities come up time and again: a deep understanding of the business and the wider world, strong knowledge of AI, and the ability to shape and influence culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That first one — understanding the business and the world it operates in — is foundational. CISOs who grasp the broader context are better equipped to spot emerging threats, align security with business goals, and make smarter decisions that build resilience and support growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This knowledge also puts them in a position to shape key decisions before risks even surface, which is exactly where modern CISOs need to be. “CISOs must deliberately cultivate the ability to influence strategy, not just enforce controls,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rbird/"&gt;Richard Bird&lt;/a&gt;, CSO at Singulr AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If CISOs operate as a “business translator,” framing security as a driver of value rather than just a cost, they can earn a comfortable seat at the leadership table. “A CISO who is seen to understand the business is accepted into the fold, rather than positioned as just a guardian at the gate,” says &lt;a href="https://www2.withsecure.com/en/expertise/people/christine-bejerasco"&gt;Christine Bejerasco&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at WithSecure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This collaboration is often useful to both sides. “As security becomes more deeply integrated into strategic decision-making, the ability to articulate value in both directions is essential,” adds &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/blake-entrekin/"&gt;Blake Entrekin&lt;/a&gt;, deputy CISO at HackerOne.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But having social power and influence within an organization isn’t solely about access to the boardroom. It also comes from building trust and security awareness at all levels, which can be achieved by showing genuine interest in people’s day-to-day work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Think about how you can embed security into different areas of the organization by leveraging the work of the people already there, and how you can train them just enough to weave security into their existing processes,” Bejerasco says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second essential pillar of skills centers on artificial intelligence. CISOs need to understand the current state of AI and be up to date on the latest threats and misuse cases. This knowledge helps them “bring some sanity into an organization that’s often in a mad rush to incorporate AI into everything,” says Bejerasco. “You are no longer the detractor preventing the adoption of new technology. You become the saner voice in the room.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Understanding where AI systems excel and where they fall short allows CISOs to guide adoption. But technical knowledge isn’t enough. They also need to communicate it clearly, translating complex risks into business language that the board can understand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They can say something along the lines of: “Here’s the risk in financial, operational, and reputational terms, and here’s the investment trade-off,” Argyle says. “The irreplaceable CISOs will use AI as a force multiplier for business cost–benefit analysis but keep the judgment and storytelling firmly human. If you can’t credibly challenge the way your organization is using AI and data, you’re flying blind.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When it comes to training, Argyle recommends that CISOs take “reputable courses in AI governance, secure use of LLMs, data protection, and model risk,” ideally from universities or industry-recognized providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A mistake CISOs can make is assuming they already know enough about AI to make informed decisions, when the field is evolving too quickly for static knowledge to suffice. “AI will continue to compress the time between reconnaissance and exploitation, requiring CISOs to anticipate how adversaries may use AI and how defenders can leverage the same tools to stay ahead,” Entrekin says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lastly, in 2026, the third must-have is building a strong security culture across every level of the organization, because, as Argyle puts it, “cyber is 20% technology and 80% behaviour.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The standout CISOs will be those who can shift the boardroom narrative to one of active support for culture change,” he says. “You know culture is taking hold when teams across the business apply secure-by-design principles as second nature.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="top-technical-skills"&gt;Top technical skills&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to strong knowledge of AI systems, today’s CISOs need a solid foundation in the technologies that define modern enterprise environments. The &lt;a href="https://www.isc2.org/certifications/cissp"&gt;(ISC)² CISSP&lt;/a&gt; is still widely regarded as the gold standard for broad expertise in security architecture, risk management, and governance. “Regulators will expect this, and it still appears in pretty much all CISO jobs,” Argyle says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://cyberleadershipinstitute.com/cyber-leadership-program-version-2/"&gt;Cyber Leadership Program&lt;/a&gt; from the Cyber Leadership Institute is also highly valued. This program focuses on the leadership and influence skills CISOs need to shape strategy and secure investment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other useful certifications are those connected to cloud security architecture, such as &lt;a href="https://www.isc2.org/certifications/ccsp"&gt;CCSP&lt;/a&gt;. “If you don’t have an understanding of cloud security, these courses can help you understand shared responsibility models, identity-driven security, and how modern infrastructure operates at scale,” says Bejerasco.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, Bird emphasizes the growing importance of financial fluency in cybersecurity leadership. “A modern risk quantification or cyber economics course is critical, since boards increasingly expect CISOs to express risk in financial terms rather than technical scores,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="top-soft-skills"&gt;Top soft skills&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Apart from technical skills, CISOs are also judged on how they strategize, communicate and lead. In 2026, they are expected to face pressure from all sides, including boards, regulators and vendors, not just attackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Strategic judgment is foundational,” says Bird. “Especially knowing when not to act as much as when to intervene.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sharpening strategic judgment starts with pattern recognition — connecting the dots between incidents, threat intelligence, and the company’s broader business context. Then, CISOs need to distil that complexity into a few clear, actionable choices, each with defined risks, benefits and costs. “That’s how you move from doom report to strategic advisor,” says Argyle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Strategic thinking will have a growing ethical dimension in 2026. One of the clearest tests, Bird says, will come in AI-driven environments, where CISOs must navigate complex decisions in the absence of clear legal guardrails. It’s the kind of area, he argues, that can “separate leaders from operators, notably when legal guidance lags behind technological reality.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Critical decisions sometimes have to be made in the heat of the moment if disaster strikes. In those situations, the ability to stay calm under pressure is essential. “The CISO’s job in the first 72 hours is to lower the temperature, create clarity from ambiguity, and protect trust with the boardroom, authorities, regulators, customers and staff,” says Argyle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another soft skill to master in 2026 is the ability to build coalitions and negotiate well with product, data, legal, HR, finance, procurement and external partners. This means CISOs need to learn how to influence without having direct authority. “Security cannot operate in isolation,” says Entrekin. “Influence and collaboration are key.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Closely linked to this is the ability to communicate well, to speak regulatory language and move fluently between technical, legal and business worlds. “Being able to talk to the board in business terms reduced my required three times a year board reporting to two times a year,” Bejerasco says. “They understood and got confident that they understood that I had it covered. That was helpful for both me and for them as well.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All these skills have to be passed on to others in the team. A key part of the CISO’s role is to mentor, create opportunities for growth, and help team members gradually step into leadership themselves. “Investing in people ensures continuity, resilience, and long-term organizational capability,” says Entrekin.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="low-cost-strategies-for-gaining-top-skills"&gt;Low-cost strategies for gaining top skills&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many CISOs and fractional CISOs want to keep learning, but there isn’t always a budget to match that ambition. Formal courses and certifications can run into the thousands of dollars, plus time away from the job. Yet the experts argue that there are low-cost solutions to this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of these is tapping into regional CISO communities. This can mean joining peer groups and roundtables where professionals compare playbooks and swap incident stories. CISOs can also find mentors or mentor younger professionals in turn, strengthening their skills while giving back to the community. “Regional CISOs communities can offer shared knowledge, peer support, and access to collective expertise at little or no cost,” Entrekin says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vendors, cloud providers, and partners also tend to have free training, as well as reference architectures and playbooks. “A smart CISO will negotiate learning access and workshops as part of contracts,” Argyle says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another low-cost strategy is to use large language models to explore emerging topics. These tools can summarize papers or threat intelligence reports, generate practice scenarios and act as a “sparring partner” for strategies. AI subscriptions are relatively affordable, and executives can repurpose decommissioned hardware from within the organization. This kind of setup allows CISOs to explore AI capabilities, limitations, and risks firsthand, without needing a large budget or a formal program.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bejerasco also &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4027000/the-books-shaping-todays-cybersecurity-leaders.html"&gt;recommends reading books&lt;/a&gt;: “Books on negotiation, leadership, decision-making, and strategy are especially helpful and directly applicable to the CISO role, often more so than formal training.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But another overlooked resource is the CISO’s own team. Argyle suggests creating internal “learning loops”: short, low-cost brown-bag sessions where risk experts, engineers, architects and product owners teach each other. “Lack of budget is a constraint, but it’s not an excuse,” he says. “The best CISOs I know have always been self-directed learners.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="less-relevant-courses"&gt;Less relevant courses&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not all courses and certifications add value to a CISO’s résumé. Credentials that are useful early in a cybersecurity career can become far less relevant by the time a security professional reaches an executive role. Examples include generic, entry-level security certifications, as well as tool-specific credentials that focus on button-clicking rather than system architecture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They are not useless, but they should no longer be treated as signals of senior security leadership,” Bird says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other credentials that are less useful as differentiators for CISOs in 2026 include single-vendor, product-specific certifications. Deep expertise in one specific firewall or endpoint solution might have been valuable in the past, but for someone in a CISO role, it just doesn’t carry a lot of weight.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“At the CISO level, it’s rarely decisive now, architectures are heterogeneous, and we’re increasingly buying platform outcomes, not hero products,” Argyle says. “These certs are fine for specialists, but they don’t move the needle much for an executive.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Courses that focus purely on memorizing standards and passing exams — without requiring participants to grapple with real-world trade-offs — are also of diminishing value at the executive level. “As a CISO you’re expected to turn compliance into outcomes, not just recite clauses from a standard,” Argyle says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, though, certifications are necessary but not sufficient. They need to be backed by experience. Employers are looking for leaders who can run security programmes end-to-end, make tough trade-offs under pressure, manage incidents with confidence, and engage with the board with confidence. In a competitive job market, a long list of certifications won’t get anyone far unless it’s backed by real-world experience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117799/skills-cisos-need-to-master-in-2026.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delegation is a risk decision every leader makes, not an ops choice</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123227/delegation-is-a-risk-decision-every-leader-makes-not-an-ops-choice.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You make delegation decisions every day.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://url.usb.m.mimecastprotect.com/s/0RCcCrgGYGT4ygEJiNuYH4IlYH?domain=substack.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sometimes they look like management choices&lt;/a&gt;: who owns a workflow, which team runs a tool, how quickly something should ship. Other times, they barely register at all. You accept a default setting. You enable automation. You let a system act on your behalf because it saves time and seems low risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What we tend not to account for is that we will often own the outcomes of those actions, even when they feel misaligned with our intent or unfair in hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most organizations still talk about delegation as an operational concern. It shows up in org charts, staffing models, workflow ownership, and efficiency debates about scale, speed, and cost. The underlying assumption is that delegation is a question of execution, not exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That framing no longer holds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The most consequential delegation decisions being made today are not primarily about people. They are about authority moving into systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judgment, execution, interaction, and follow-through are increasingly being handed to software that can act on an organization’s behalf, often across multiple functions and systems at once.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In some cases, that transfer of authority is explicit. More often, it happens quietly through configuration settings, vendor defaults, and internal deployments that never trigger formal review because they appear narrow in scope or low risk. A customer support workflow gains the ability to issue credits. A finance system can initiate payments within limits. A productivity agent can move laterally across internal systems without human involvement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These decisions are still discussed as operational choices. Who owns the workflow, which team runs the tool, and how quickly it can be deployed remain the dominant questions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What gets lost in that framing is that these are not simply efficiency decisions. They are authority transfers, and authority always carries risk because it creates outcomes that persist even when intent, context, or oversight changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Delegation, in this context, is not an ops choice. It is a risk decision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-concrete-enterprise-example"&gt;A concrete enterprise example&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consider how many organizations automated refunds and credits during the COVID-19 travel disruptions. &lt;a href="https://url.usb.m.mimecastprotect.com/s/fxWICnGAzAhr48vBIJhjHJHONt?domain=substack.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Airlines&lt;/a&gt; and booking platforms, overwhelmed by volume and operational pressure, delegated financial decision-making to automated systems that could issue credits, delay refunds, or apply preset rules at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In many cases, those systems operated exactly as configured. They stayed within internal thresholds, followed approved logic, and reduced immediate operational load. The problem surfaced later. Customers challenged outcomes. Regulators intervened. Audits examined controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What became clear was not a lack of tooling or intent, but an ownership gap. Authority to make binding financial decisions had been delegated to systems without clear articulation of who had accepted the regulatory and consumer-protection risk embedded in those configurations. When enforcement followed, the question was not whether the systems worked, but who had authorized them to act that way on the organization’s behalf.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What made this pattern durable was not the crisis itself, but how quickly emergency delegation became normalized infrastructure. The systems behaved as designed. The risk had simply never been owned explicitly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-quiet-moment-risk-moves"&gt;The quiet moment risk moves&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every delegation decision implicitly answers a set of questions, whether leaders articulate them or not. Who is allowed to act, on whose behalf, under what constraints, and who ultimately absorbs the downside when outcomes diverge from intent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk moves at the moment authority moves. It does not wait for scale, visibility, or failure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most organizations assume delegation is temporary and easily reversible. They expect to pilot, monitor, and adjust as they go. In practice, once authority has shifted into systems, it hardens quickly. Dependencies form. Teams adapt their workflows. Customers normalize the behavior. Control mechanisms lag behind operational reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where risk ownership gaps emerge. Authority persists, but accountability fragments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-as-the-first-signal-not-the-whole-story"&gt;Security as the first signal, not the whole story&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams are often the first to surface delegation risk, not because everything is a breach, but because security is where authority is most formally encoded. Permissions, identities, scopes, and automated actions make delegated authority visible in ways other functions do not see as quickly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Automated remediation systems illustrate this clearly. These tools are designed to act quickly using valid permissions: disabling accounts, quarantining assets, blocking access, or triggering downstream workflows. When those systems act at scale, the actions are authorized and logged, yet the operational impact can be severe. Entire teams can be locked out of systems. Production workloads can be disrupted. Business-critical services can halt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is no intrusion to investigate and no policy violation to point to. The question becomes whether the system was ever meant to hold that much authority without tighter constraints and broader alignment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security surfaces the signal first because it deals in failure modes and observability. What follows, however, is not a security problem. It is an enterprise one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="this-is-an-enterprise-risk-decision"&gt;This is an enterprise risk decision&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security risk is often the first visible signal, but it is rarely the full exposure. Delegation decisions create compound enterprise risk that spans operational resilience, financial integrity, legal accountability, reputation, and long-term strategy. No single function sees that full picture on its own.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operationally, automated actions scale faster than human oversight, allowing small misconfigurations to propagate widely before intervention is possible. Financially, systems increasingly touch revenue, pricing, credits, payments, and contractual obligations, meaning losses can accumulate quietly before they are recognized. From a legal and regulatory perspective, intent offers little protection when outcomes cause harm; regulators and courts expect demonstrable governance over automated decision-making. Reputationally, customers experience outcomes, not internal distinctions between human and automated action. Strategically, authority that is vaguely defined tends to calcify into infrastructure, limiting future flexibility and slowing the organization’s ability to adapt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why understanding delegation risk cannot sit with security alone. Meaningful risk assessment for AI deployments requires cross-functional coordination across security, product, legal, finance, compliance, operations, and leadership. Each function holds part of the risk surface, and none can define the organization’s exposure in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aligning AI deployment decisions to risk appetite is not about finding a universally correct answer. Different organizations will make different tradeoffs based on their goals, constraints, and tolerance for uncertainty. What matters is that those tradeoffs are made deliberately, with a shared understanding of the risks being taken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You cannot protect your investment, whether financial, reputational, or strategic, without understanding as much of the risk landscape as possible. Security teams often surface these issues first because they are trained to think in failure modes, but the consequences of delegation decisions are organizational, not technical.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Delegation risk does not belong to security, product, or legal alone. It belongs to leadership because it reflects how the organization chooses to exercise power.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-personal-delegation-becomes-market-risk"&gt;When personal delegation becomes market risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This same delegation dynamic is already emerging at the individual level as personal agents and AI systems increasingly act on people’s behalf at work and at home. Individuals are delegating purchasing, scheduling, research, communication, and decision support to tools that operate across platforms with minimal friction. In isolation, these choices feel personal and low risk. Structurally, they mirror enterprise delegation decisions exactly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What changes at the individual level is not accountability, but awareness. When you delegate authority to a system in your job, responsibility is often traceable through roles, policies, and escalation paths. When you delegate authority to a personal agent, that same accountability collapses inward. The system may act autonomously, but outcomes still attach to the person who empowered it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thinking clearly about delegation at work therefore sharpens judgment at home. The same questions apply in both contexts: what authority have I granted, under what constraints, and am I prepared to own the outcomes if they diverge from my intent?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A visible example of this dynamic appeared when &lt;a href="https://url.usb.m.mimecastprotect.com/s/KLd_CoABOBf6AOEWhVi5HplgmT?domain=substack.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Instacart&lt;/a&gt; confirmed that it uses individualized pricing based on factors such as order history, demand, and market conditions. In effect, the system was delegated discretion over price negotiation at the individual level, without users having visibility into how that discretion was exercised. While the practice aligned with internal policy and commercial goals, many users experienced the outcomes as arbitrary or unfair because pricing authority operated without transparent constraints or explanation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No single human made those pricing decisions in real time. Yet the consequences were real for consumers, and the trust impact was immediate. The issue was not a breach or a policy violation. It was delegated authority operating without shared understanding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As personal agents begin interacting directly with enterprise agents in B2C environments, this pattern will intensify. Customer-side agents will negotiate, transact, and make requests directly with company-side systems, often without human awareness on either end. Misaligned assumptions, misunderstood intent, and automated escalation can occur at machine speed, with outcomes neither party explicitly anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In that environment, responsibility becomes difficult to trace unless authority, constraints, and accountability were deliberately designed from the start. What looks like consumer convenience today becomes institutional exposure tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wherever authority is delegated, whether by an organization or an individual, responsibility remains with the principal. Only the scale changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-this-matters-to-you-regardless-of-role"&gt;Why this matters to you, regardless of role&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is not only a leadership problem. It is an individual one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Employees at every level increasingly rely on AI systems to draft communications, make recommendations, trigger actions, and interface with other tools, often using personal or semi-approved systems inside professional environments. When those systems act in ways that create harm, confusion, or exposure, responsibility rarely stays with the software. It flows back to the human who relied on it, the manager who normalized its use, or the organization that failed to set boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Understanding delegation as a risk decision is therefore not just about governance maturity. It is a form of professional self-protection in an environment where tools can act faster, farther, and more persistently than their users expect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a world of agent-to-agent interaction, your tools do not simply reflect your intent. They can commit you to outcomes you did not explicitly choose.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When individual delegation scales across a workforce or customer base, personal exposure becomes enterprise risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-business-case-leaders-recognize"&gt;The business case leaders recognize&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Closing the gap between delegation decisions and risk ownership is not about slowing innovation. It is about protecting core business fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From a P&amp;amp;L perspective, delegated systems directly influence revenue, cost, and margin. When authority is unclear, losses appear as leakage, remediation expense, customer churn, and operational rework. These costs compound over time and rarely surface as a single, contained incident.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From an audit standpoint, informal delegation creates weaknesses in internal controls. Auditors expect clear ownership, documented authority, and effective oversight. When those elements are retrofitted after deployment, findings follow, confidence erodes, and leadership attention is diverted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regulators increasingly expect organizations to demonstrate governance over automated and algorithmic decision-making, particularly where systems interact directly with consumers. Claims that a system was authorized or that no one anticipated a specific outcome do not meet that bar. Traceability, accountability, and documented risk ownership matter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the executive and board level, delegation failures undermine credibility. In moments of stress, leadership is judged not on whether tools were innovative, but on whether risks were understood, owned, and managed. Ambiguity in those moments reads as negligence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Explicit delegation preserves strategic optionality. When authority is bounded and revisable, organizations retain the ability to adapt. When it is vague, it becomes permanent by default.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-delegation-becomes-personal"&gt;When delegation becomes personal&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Delegation is happening around you and through you, whether or not you approve systems or set policy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, nothing goes wrong. That is what makes the risk invisible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But when something does go wrong, the question will not be whether the system was efficient or well-intentioned. It will be who understood the risk, who accepted it, and who is prepared to own the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Delegation does not remove responsibility. It redistributes it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Understanding that is no longer optional.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This &lt;a href="https://url.usb.m.mimecastprotect.com/s/0RCcCrgGYGT4ygEJiNuYH4IlYH?domain=substack.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;story was originally published &lt;/a&gt;on Command Line with Camille&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123227/delegation-is-a-risk-decision-every-leader-makes-not-an-ops-choice.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Always-on privileged access is pervasive — and fraught with risks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123184/always-on-privileged-access-is-pervasive-and-fraught-with-risks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Privileged access management (PAM) has always been about ensuring least privilege. But the nature of enterprise cybersecurity — on top of the complexity of system operations — has prompted far too many users to log in at the highest possible privilege and stay there, even when most of their tasks do not require it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114758/enterprises-still-arent-getting-iam-right-2.html"&gt;One recent study&lt;/a&gt; put the percentage of end-users logging in at their highest level of privilege at 91%.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research, sees the widespread use of unnecessarily high privileges as the result of years of enterprise tech governance neglect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises are running complex, interdependent technology estates where privileged access underpins stability, recovery, and continuity,” he says. “In many environments, privileged access was granted years ago to support systems that no longer have clear owners, clean documentation, or modern authentication paths. That access now props up integrations, batch jobs, recovery scripts, vendor tooling, and fragile automation chains.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Gogia sees enterprises maintaining this status quo on privileges because reining it in “feels less like tightening security and more like introducing existential operational risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They are choosing predictability over disruption,” he explains. “Always-on privilege becomes the safest option in environments where architectural certainty no longer exists. It accumulates quietly over time as systems evolve faster than governance models. Mergers, cloud migrations, outsourcing, platform layering, and emergency fixes all leave behind privileged identities that nobody revisits. Over years, this creates an estate where privilege is deeply embedded into how work gets done.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because of that complexity, Gogia says, always-on becomes not just the easiest tactic, but the default one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises often fall back to permanent privilege because it works,” he says. “It keeps pipelines running, integrations stable, and systems responsive. Vaulting credentials does not solve the problem if those credentials never expire. Zero trust principles are sound, but their implementation frequently assumes a cleanliness that enterprise estates simply do not have. This mismatch explains why many organizations buy &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572787/7-top-privileged-access-management-tools.html"&gt;PAM tools&lt;/a&gt;, deploy them partially, and quietly allow exceptions to proliferate until the exception becomes the norm.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, PAM — and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518296/what-is-iam-identity-and-access-management-explained.html"&gt;identity access management (IAM)&lt;/a&gt; — has become misaligned with how modern enterprise systems operate, Gogia says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many tools still assume relatively static infrastructure, limited identity volumes, and manual intervention points,” he notes. “Modern enterprises operate dynamic, ephemeral environments where workloads spin up and down constantly, identities are created programmatically, and access requirements change in real-time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-perils-of-persistent-privilege"&gt;The perils of persistent privilege&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://moorinsightsstrategy.com/team/robert-kramer/"&gt;Robert Kramer&lt;/a&gt;, vice president and principal analyst for Moor Insights &amp;amp; Strategy, agrees that excessive credentials are caused by decades of lax IT governance. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They are stuck in legacy habits, stuck in their legacy operational ways,” Kramer says. “There should be a shift to more of a just-in-time model. Barely 1% of organizations have implemented that.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The executive overseeing the 91% report — &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/charleshchu/"&gt;Charles Chu&lt;/a&gt;, general manager for IT and developer products at CyberArk — said staying logged in at the highest level certainly has a cybersecurity risk, but it also introduces the IT risk of massive system damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An accidental typo, for example, could cause massive damage if the typist is logged in at the highest level, Chu contends. “I could fat finger something and delete it by accident. Is it really so onerous to log in or out of something?” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That last question is not rhetorical. Chu suggests that some PAM packages are indeed too difficult to use, therefore causing user friction. “If the PAM tool itself is onerous to use, [end-users] will find ways to bypass it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://kunkleconsulting.net/owner"&gt;JR Kunkle&lt;/a&gt;, president of Kunkle Consulting and former risk consultant with Deloitte &amp;amp; Touche, agrees about the typo risk. “Most interruptions in computers are due to errors or mistakes,” he says. “IT staff using an admin-level [privilege] can cause a production outage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Kunkle, who also worked as an IT manager with Limited Brands and Honda, says defaulting to high privilege access can also undermine legal, compliance, and privacy efforts. “If the admin looks at sensitive data [that the admin was not supposed to see], it’s pretty easy for them to cover their tracks by erasing the access logs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most observers, however, put the blame of excessive credentials on IT pros themselves. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is negating the controls that they have put in place. You could take down an entire company through carelessness or fat-fingering,” says &lt;a href="https://acceligence.com/talent/profiles/justin-greis/"&gt;Justin Greis&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of consulting firm Acceligence and former head of the North American cybersecurity practice at McKinsey. “It’s just human nature to take the easy road” and cut corners when it comes to privileged access. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.digicert.com/blog/author/jason-sabin"&gt;Jason Sabin&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at DigiCert, is more blunt: “If an enterprise [IT worker] uses root, they are an idiot. You can screw up your world. You should never use root. Embrace least privilege. You should never use elevated privileges for ordinary mundane tasks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="paradigm-shift-ahead"&gt;Paradigm shift ahead&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forrester analyst &lt;a href="https://www.forrester.com/analyst-bio/geoff-cairns/BIO20052"&gt;Geoff Cairns&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3952041/malicious-actors-increasingly-put-privileged-identity-access-to-work-across-attack-chains.html"&gt;stresses the cybersecurity risks at play&lt;/a&gt; when organizations do not rein in excessive credential use. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Persistent standing privilege, yes, I think that is rampant,” he says. “It is something that attackers can target and then leverage to move laterally through systems and create havoc. The elevated privilege makes that all the more impactful.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yet Cairns sees the hard road ahead in tackling this issue in modern enterprise environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is a challenging problem to solve in a very complex IT landscape, with on-prem, cloud, SaaS” and it is going to get exponentially worse with “the explosion of non-human identities,” including autonomous agents, Cairns says. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Greyhound Research’s Gogia agrees that non-human identities (NHIs) are going to make the problem of excess credential use far worse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The center of gravity has shifted away from human administrators. The most dangerous and least governed privilege now sits with non-human identities. Service accounts, APIs, cloud roles, CI/CD pipelines, SaaS connectors, automation frameworks, and autonomous systems operate continuously with standing access,” he says. “These identities authenticate programmatically, at machine speed, often across environments, and frequently with broader permissions than any individual would ever be granted.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And the increasing proliferation of NHIs engaging with enterprise systems is pushing PAM and IAM toward a paradigm shift.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Traditional PAM and IAM models were designed for humans who log in, perform tasks, and log out. They struggle when identities never log out,” Gogia says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Machine privilege is not an edge case,” he adds. “It is the majority case in modern environments. Enterprises attempting to apply human-style access reviews and approval workflows to these identities quickly discover that governance collapses under scale. This is where always-on privilege stops being a failure of discipline and becomes a failure of design assumptions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123184/always-on-privileged-access-is-pervasive-and-fraught-with-risks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sicarii ransomware locks your data and throws away the keys</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123492/sicarii-ransomware-locks-your-data-and-throws-away-the-keys.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A newly observed Sicarii ransomware strain contains a critical encryption key handling defect that can leave encrypted data unrecoverable, even if a victim pays the ransom or uses a provided decryptor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts at the Halcyon Ransomware Research Center found that Sicarii generates fresh &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3995036/breaking-rsa-encryption-just-got-20x-easier-for-quantum-computers.html"&gt;RSA key&lt;/a&gt; pairs for each execution and then discards the private key, leaving no recoverable key material for the encrypted systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations affected by this variant cannot rely on ransom negotiation or third-party decryptors to restore files unless there is evidence that the underlying flaw has been fixed in the specific sample that infected them. “The issue appears to stem from poor encryption key management rather than deliberate design,” said Sakshi Grover, senior research manager, cybersecurity at IDC. “This reflects a broader trend in the ransomware ecosystem, where low barriers to entry and rapid monetization take precedence over technical robustness.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sicarii was first disclosed in December 2025, and has only a small track record of claimed victims, but its unusual technical attributes have forced researchers to claim it could have been &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053635/when-ai-nukes-your-database-the-dark-side-of-vibe-coding.html"&gt;vibe coded&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Encryption defect breaks standard RaaS model&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ransomware typically encrypts files using a public-key &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/565965/preparing-for-the-day-quantum-computing-cracks-public-key-cryptography-what-to-do-now.html"&gt;scheme&lt;/a&gt; where the attacker retains the private key or can regenerate it later, enabling a decryptor to work if the ransom is paid. Sicarii deviates from this model. In Halcyon observed samples, it generates a new RSA key pair entirely on the victim system during each execution and immediately discards the private key once encryption completes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The victims end up with no viable path to recover encrypted data, even if they cooperate with attackers or use a published decryptor tool. According to a Halcyon &lt;a href="https://www.halcyon.ai/ransomware-alerts/alert-sicarii-ransomware-encryption-key-handling-defect"&gt;alert&lt;/a&gt;, enterprises should assume failed recovery through ransom-related decryptors unless there is independent verification that the defect was eliminated in that strain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A Sicarii ransomware represents a nightmare scenario where traditional ransomware response strategies fail entirely,” said Agnidipta Sarkar, chief evangelist at ColorTokens. “As no decryptor can reconstruct the discarded private keys, enterprises will stare at ‘assume total data destruction,’ amplifying financial, operational, and reputational damage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Absence of a decryptor-based recovery forces organizations to plan for complete recovery through backups and alternate operational restoration methods, changing the cost-benefit analysis for them. This also heightens the importance of pre-existing, secure backup infrastructure and rapid isolation. Halcyon urged organizations to focus on immediate containment and restoration rather than ransom-based recovery. Affected systems should be isolated, the scope of infection identified, and operations restored only from known-good, offline, or immutable backups.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises must invest in proactive zero trust micro-segmentation that is designed to be adopted in hours, leveraging existing EDR, agents, agentless mechanisms to contain threats at the initial access point, preventing encryption from spreading,” Sarkar added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Unusual technical profile hints at vibe-coding&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One possible explanation for Sicarii’s broken encryption flow is immature or poorly implemented development practices. The ransomware’s failure to retain usable keys is inconsistent with established ransomware design and suggests it may have been assembled without rigorous testing or a clear understanding of operational consequences, or even vibe-coded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Halcyon assesses with moderate confidence that the developers may have used AI-assisted tooling, which could have contributed to this implementation error,” the researchers said in the alert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A Check Point Research’s &lt;a href="https://research.checkpoint.com/2026/sicarii-ransomware-truth-vs-myth/"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month had also highlighted a set of unusual and internally inconsistent characteristics. According to the analysis, Sicarri incorporates Israeli and Jewish activity symbolism in its branding and messaging, yet much of its underground activity appears in Russian. Also, the Hebrew language used in the malware and communications contains errors indicative of non-native or automated translation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond encryption, Check Point observed Sicarii performing credential harvesting, network reconnaissance, vulnerability scanning, and data exfiltration, indicating the operation includes tooling atypical to financially motivated ransomware. “Sicarii significantly raises the risk profile of ransomware incidents, shifting the impact from financial extortion to potential permanent data loss and prolonged business disruption,” Grover added. “In regulated industries, this can further escalate compliance, legal, and operational consequences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123492/sicarii-ransomware-locks-your-data-and-throws-away-the-keys.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – January 2026 quarterly rollup (AV26-042) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France Fines National Employment Agency €5m Over 2024 Data Breach</title>
      <link>https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/france-finesemployment-agency-5m/</link>
      <description>The French data protection regulator said that France Travail’s response to a 2024 data breach violated GDPR</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/france-finesemployment-agency-5m/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto unveils Quantum-Safe Security to mitigate cryptographic risk</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123719/palo-alto-warns-of-quantum-risk-to-digital-security.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks unveiled its Quantum-Safe Security solution at the company’s virtual Quantum-Safe Summit Tuesday. The solution is designed to help organizations prepare for the post-quantum era by addressing the transition from current cryptography to quantum-resistant algorithms without disrupting business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the platform’s key features is its continuous, real-time cryptographic visibility. Quantum-Safe acts as a central intelligence layer, collecting telemetry and logs from network infrastructure — such as PAN-OS NGFW and Prisma Access — and enriching them with data from an ecosystem of third-party security tools, according to the company. The feature enables the discovery and cataloging of applications, systems, infrastructure, and IoT devices, and it facilitates analysis of cryptographic traffic behavior, including protocols, encryption algorithms, key exchange mechanisms, certificates, and libraries used.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the summit, Palo Alto CEO Nikesh Arora stressed that quantum computing is reaching a turning point similar to that of artificial intelligence. “It’s no longer a laboratory project, and its ability to solve problems at high speed is approaching production environments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Arora and other technology experts, the technology poses a critical security challenge. “Quantum computers will be able to break cryptographic keys much faster than current systems, putting everything from private communications to digital assets like Bitcoin at risk,” he explained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Due to the threat of “harvest now, decrypt later” techniques,  in which encrypted data collected today could be decrypted more readily in the future with quantum computing, urgency to address post-quantum cryptography is rising.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Regulators and companies are already demanding quantum transition plans to protect critical infrastructure and ensure operational continuity,” Arora said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To that end, Palo Alto’s Quantum-Safe Security solution offers advanced cryptographic risk assessment and prioritization, correlating encryption strength with business criticality and data lifecycle. This identifies immediate exposures (“harvest now, decrypt later” risks) and high-value assets requiring priority migration, providing security teams with a clear, impact-based roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another key feature is its remediation approach, which guides the transition in several stages. The solution helps modernize infrastructures to achieve a “quantum ready” state, activate post-quantum or hybrid (quantum-safe) algorithms, and, in the case of legacy systems or devices that cannot be upgraded, apply virtual patching through encryption translation. This mechanism enables vulnerable traffic to be re-encrypted in real-time with secure quantum standards, without modifying existing applications or code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Quantum-Safe Security also incorporates a robust governance and ongoing compliance framework. It automates crypto hygiene management, maintains a dynamic cryptographic inventory (CBOM), and detects deviations or the use of weak ciphers in real-time. Furthermore, it facilitates regulatory compliance through automated reporting and audits aligned with global standards and regulations such as NIST, FIPS 140-3, and DORA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The solution is designed to integrate with existing security and operations systems, including SIEM, EDR, load balancers, and vulnerability management tools, enabling a scalable, gradual transition compatible with complex business environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Waiting for the hardware to be available to act could leave critical systems years behind, with serious risks to security and operational continuity,” Arora noted at the event. “The ability to break cryptography will force companies, governments, and regulators to anticipate, adapt, and protect critical data before this technology becomes fully operational. Those who act proactively will be able to mitigate risks and ensure business continuity in the new quantum era,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123719/palo-alto-warns-of-quantum-risk-to-digital-security.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST’s AI guidance pushes cybersecurity boundaries</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123196/nists-ai-guidance-pushes-cybersecurity-boundaries.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For years, US cybersecurity guidance rested on a reassuring premise: New technologies introduce new wrinkles, but not fundamentally new problems. Artificial intelligence, according to that view, is still software, just faster, more complex, and more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The controls that protect traditional systems, the thinking went, can largely be adapted to protect AI, too. That assumption surfaced at a recent National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) &lt;a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/get-involved/attend-events/cyber-ai-workshop-2"&gt;workshop on AI and cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI systems in many ways are just smart software, fancy software with a little bit extra,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/victoriayanpillitteri/"&gt;Victoria Pillitteri&lt;/a&gt;, supervisory computer scientist in the Computer Security Division at NIST, told attendees as she summarized that long-standing view. “That means we can leverage the robust body of [cybersecurity] knowledge that already exists with some modifications, with some considerations, but we do not and should not start from scratch,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But as discussions during the event turned to AI agents and adversarial manipulation, that concept began to fray. Experts described ways in which AI strains the fundamental assumptions those frameworks rely on, namely that systems behave deterministically, that boundaries between components are stable, and that humans remain firmly in control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those concerns are now moving beyond internal discussion and into public standards development. On Jan. 8, NIST’s Center for AI Standards and Innovation (CAISI) issued a &lt;a href="https://public-inspection.federalregister.gov/2026-00206.pdf"&gt;formal Request for Information (RFI)&lt;/a&gt; on the secure practices and methodologies of AI agent systems, one of the most challenging aspects of AI &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089732/rethinking-identity-for-the-ai-era-cisos-must-build-trust-at-machine-speed.html"&gt;when it comes to identity management and cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The RFI focuses on AI systems capable of taking autonomous actions that affect real-world environments and explicitly asks for input on novel risks, security practices, assessment methods, and deployment constraints.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, what should matter is that NIST is shifting from a broad, &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.600-1.pdf"&gt;principle-based AI risk management&lt;/a&gt; framework toward more operationally grounded expectations, especially for systems that act without constant human oversight. What is emerging across NIST’s AI-related cybersecurity work is a recognition that AI is no longer a distant or abstract governance issue, but a near-term security problem that the nation’s standards-setting body is trying to tackle in a multifaceted way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nists-wide-ranging-cybersecurity-and-ai-portfolio"&gt;NIST’s wide-ranging cybersecurity and AI portfolio&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although the purpose of the workshop was to solicit feedback specifically on NIST’s preliminary Cybersecurity Framework Profile for Artificial Intelligence (&lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2025/NIST.IR.8596.iprd.pdf"&gt;Cyber AI Profile&lt;/a&gt;), which is an adaptation of the community profiles emerging from &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework"&gt;NIST’s Cybersecurity Framework&lt;/a&gt;, experts addressed many other NIST practices and methodology initiatives that deal with AI-related threats and security opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These efforts show how NIST is attacking AI security from multiple angles — development, deployment, identity, privacy, and adversarial abuse — and include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Risk Management Framework. &lt;/strong&gt;Released on Jan. 26, 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework"&gt;NIST’s AI RMF&lt;/a&gt; was developed to better manage risks to individuals, organizations, and society associated with AI. “What we’re trying to do with the AI Risk Management Framework is understand how we trust AI, which operates in many ways differently in some of these tasks that we know very well,” particularly regarding how high-impact applications affect cybersecurity, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mcs729/"&gt;Martin Stanley&lt;/a&gt;, principal researcher for AI and cybersecurity at NIST, said at the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Center for AI Standards and Innovation (CAISI). &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/caisi"&gt;NIST’s CAISI&lt;/a&gt; serves as the “industry’s primary point of contact within the US government to facilitate testing and collaborative research related to harnessing and securing the potential of commercial AI systems,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/maiahamin/"&gt;Maia Hamin&lt;/a&gt;, a technical staff member of CAISI, the center that develops best practices and standards for improving AI security and collaboration. It also “leads evaluations and assessments of US and adversary AI systems, including adoption of foreign models, potential security vulnerabilities, or potential for foreign influence,” she told workshop attendees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIST AI 100-2 E2025, Adversarial Machine Learning: A Taxonomy and Terminology of Attacks and Mitigations. &lt;/strong&gt;This &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/ai/100/2/e2025/final"&gt;NIST report&lt;/a&gt;, published in March 2025,provides a taxonomy of concepts and defines terminology in the field of adversarial machine learning (AML). “Adversarial machine learning or adversarial AI is the field that studies attacks on AI systems that exploit the statistical and data-driven nature of this technology,” NIST research team supervisor &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/avassilev/"&gt;Apostol Vassilev&lt;/a&gt; said at the workshop. “Hijacking, prompt injection, indirect prompt injection, data poisoning, all these things are part of the field of study of adversarial AI,” he clarified.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dioptra. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://pages.nist.gov/dioptra/"&gt;Dioptra&lt;/a&gt; is a NIST software test platform for assessing the trustworthy characteristics of AI. “You have multiple dimensions along which you want to analyze these as you want to identify how accurate they are for a particular task,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/harold-booth-38ba4539/"&gt;Harold Booth&lt;/a&gt;, NIST supervisory computer scientist, said at the event. “You want to be able to identify how robust they are to various kinds of attacks,” Booth said. “You want to know how well they do against various kinds of data sets.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIST SP 800-218A, Secure Software Development Practices for Generative AI and Dual-Use Foundation Models: An SSDF Community Profile. &lt;/strong&gt;The &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-218A.pdf"&gt;AI SSDF community profile&lt;/a&gt; adds “practices, tasks, recommendations, considerations, notes, and informative references that are specific to AI model development throughout the software development life cycle.” NIST’s Booth told the workshop attendees, “This particular profile is very focused on what is new with respect to doing development for AI systems. So all the concerns that exist for normal software development still pertain. But what we were really focused on was what’s new.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PETs Testbed. &lt;/strong&gt;NIST’s &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/applied-cybersecurity/privacy-engineering/pets-testbed"&gt;PETs Testbed&lt;/a&gt; provides the capability to investigate privacy-enhancing technologies (PETs) and their respective suitability for specific use cases, helping organizations evaluate and manage privacy risks. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gshowarth/"&gt;Gary Howarth&lt;/a&gt;, who leads the privacy engineering program at NIST, said that within a few weeks, NIST will release a new version of its privacy framework that is complementary to AI risk management and cybersecurity threat modeling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIST Special Publication 800-63 Digital Identity Guidelines. &lt;/strong&gt;NIST recently updated its 2017 &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/identity-access-management/projects/nist-special-publication-800-63-digital-identity-guidelines"&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on digital identity to better embrace the process and technical requirements for meeting digital identity assurance levels, given the rapid pace of digital technical change. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-galluzzo-a100563b/"&gt;Ryan Galluzzo&lt;/a&gt;, identity program lead for NIST Applied Cybersecurity Division, stressed at the workshop that “AI agents are starting to change the kind of context and conversation around traditional cybersecurity controls. Within the context of this project, our intent is really to focus on those issues of access, those issues of how to identify agents that are operating within my enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-limits-of-ai-is-just-software"&gt;The limits of ‘AI is just software’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIST’s instinct to frame AI as an extension of traditional software allows organizations to reuse familiar concepts — risk assessment, access control, logging, defense in depth — rather than starting from zero. Workshop participants repeatedly emphasized that many controls do transfer, at least in principle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But some experts argue that the analogy breaks down quickly in practice. AI systems behave probabilistically, not deterministically, they say. Their outputs depend on data that may change continuously after deployment. And in the case of agents, they may take actions that were not explicitly scripted in advance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, the risk is not that AI is unrecognizable, but that it appears recognizable enough to lull organizations into applying controls mechanically. Treating AI as “just another application” can obscure new failure modes, particularly those involving &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110008/top-cyber-threats-to-your-ai-systems-and-infrastructure.html"&gt;indirect manipulation through data or prompts&lt;/a&gt; rather than direct exploitation of code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI agent systems really face a range of security threats and risks,” CAISI’s Hamin said at the workshop. “Some of these overlap with traditional software, but others kind of arise from the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109999/agentic-ai-already-hinting-at-cybersecuritys-pending-identity-crisis.html"&gt;unique challenge of combining AI model outputs&lt;/a&gt;, which are non-deterministic, with the affordances and abilities of software tools.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cisos-should-watch-out-for-framework-fatigue"&gt;CISOs should watch out for framework fatigue&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In kicking off the workshop, NIST senior policy advisor &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kmegas/"&gt;Katerina Megas&lt;/a&gt; explained that NIST reached out to the CISO community to ask them what they need in terms of AI security guidance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Before we started down any path, we spoke to the CISO community, and we asked them, ‘So how are you all dealing with artificial intelligence? How is this affecting your day-to-day? Is this something that keeps you up at night?’ And overwhelmingly, the answer was yes, this is absolutely something that is top of mind for us. Our leadership is asking us, what are we doing?” she said at the event.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the CISOs also told NIST that they were overwhelmed with AI documentation. A lot of these publications had some overlap, but were not identical, Megas said. “If you were a consumer of all of these documents, it was very difficult for you to look at them and understand how they relate to what you are doing and also understand how to identify where two documents may be talking about the same thing and where they overlap.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If the guidance is super long, then people may not actually use it,” one workshop attendee, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/naveenkm94/"&gt;Naveen Konrajankuppam Mahavishnu&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder and CTO at Aira Security, tells CSO, suggesting that much of the material can be reduced to more digestible components.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We can have a very detailed version, maybe a hundred pages long, but also have some sort of checklist that kind of summarizes the entire 100-page paper or something into a few pages where people can easily consume it, and then they can start implementing it,” Mahavishnu says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123196/nists-ai-guidance-pushes-cybersecurity-boundaries.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU’s answer to CVE solves dependency issue, adds fragmentation risks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123225/eus-answer-to-cve-solves-dependency-issue-adds-fragmentation-risks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The security community has offered broad support for the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118848/new-eu-vulnerability-database-launched.html"&gt;creation of an EU-hosted vulnerability database&lt;/a&gt; as a means of reducing dependence on US databases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, some experts have expressed concerns that the potential fragmentation of security intelligence risks impeding rapid vulnerability identification and remediation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Global Cybersecurity Vulnerability Enumeration database (&lt;a href="https://gcve.eu/"&gt;GCVE.eu&lt;/a&gt;) aggregates vulnerability advisories from more than 25 public sources into a single, searchable resource. Entries are normalized, structured, and cross-referenced across identifiers (e.g., CVE IDs, GCVE IDs, vendor IDs).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The platform is hosted by Computer Incident Response Center Luxembourg (CIRCL) in a Luxembourg-based data centre, with co-funding from the EU’s Federated European Team for Threat Analysis (FETTA) project.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The emergence of GCVE.eu follows a funding scare that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3963190/cve-program-faces-swift-end-after-dhs-fails-to-renew-contract-leaving-security-flaw-tracking-in-limbo.html"&gt;threatened the continuation of the long-established Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) program last year&lt;/a&gt;. The CVE program — which underpins the US National Vulnerability (NVD) database — is operated by the Mitre Corp., with funding from the cyber division of the US Department of Homeland Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="combatting-flaw-fragmentation-mapping-and-interoperability"&gt;Combatting flaw fragmentation: Mapping and interoperability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaya Baloo, co-founder, COO, and CISO at vulnerability remediation startup AISLE, says that GCVE must prioritize mapping and interoperability with CVE entries in order to be viable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Without enforceable interoperability commitments, ‘independent allocation’ becomes a polite way of saying defenders will need to check multiple incompatible systems to know if they’re vulnerable,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;David Lindner, CISO at application security vendor Contrast Security, agreed that GCVE poses a risk of creating a new silo that mirrors but doesn’t align with the NVD.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For a CISO the hard part is preventing identification collision where teams waste time triaging the same vulnerability under two different flags,” says Lindner. “To avoid this confusion and make the project viable the GCVE must prioritize an automated cross-mapping standard that bridges these databases in real-time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Simply switching from the US-run NVD to a European GCVE fails to solve the problem of dependency but only succeeds in changing the location of the silo, according to Lindner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Success requires a federated approach where vendors and researchers contribute to a unified intelligence layer ensuring that no matter which database claims the entry the industry sees a single actionable truth rather than a fragmented mess,” Lindner argues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Brian Blakley, CISO at Bellini Capital, warns that if GCVE offers only duplication without differentiation then it is liable to create a headache for security practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most security teams are already struggling with noise,” Blakley notes. “Any new database really needs to improve data quality, timeliness, or context and not just replicate identifiers under a different flag.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GCVE has cross-vulnerability referencing built in, with both automated and human-curated mechanisms, an approach most experts quizzed by CSO would minimise confusion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zbyněk Sopuch, CTO of data security vendor Safetica, was more upbeat arguing that GCVE is designed to be backwards compatible with CVE, so “existing data is preserved and independent entries are allowed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The gray areas arise in scope, ID formats, and fragmented tracking, and there are steps that the GSVE can take to ensure that critical data is shared and received,” says Sopuch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="coordinated-disclosure"&gt;Coordinated disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nik Kale, principal engineer and product architect at Cisco Systems, says GCVE’s main challenge comes from building a platform that the security community can rely on for coordinated disclosure and remediation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Viability depends far more on governance than on the data itself,” Kale says. “That includes clear attribution rules, transparent CNA processes, predictable decision-making, and an explicit commitment to synchronization rather than fragmentation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US-run NVD system is long established so any parallel system must either federate cleanly with that existing infrastructure or provide clear operational advantages that justify switching, according to Kale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Researchers will gravitate toward whichever system enables the fastest, most reliable coordinated disclosure,” says Kale. “Vendors, meanwhile, need confidence that vulnerability records will be handled consistently regardless of where they originate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Representatives of the GCVE project told CSO that CIRCL has both the relevant experience, &lt;a href="https://gcve.eu/process/"&gt;governance structures&lt;/a&gt;, and backing to make the database successful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CIRCL has been operating multiple services and open-source projects for more than 15 years, with sustained financial and in-kind support from the public sector, private sector, and EU and international organisations,” they explain. “GCVE.eu implements a level of governance that enables efficient operation, rapid delivery, and, most importantly, distributed allocation of identifiers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GCVE.eu has been fully functional and operational for several months. “We already deliver &lt;a href="https://www.vulnerability-lookup.org/"&gt;Vulnerability-Lookup&lt;/a&gt; as a complete open-source software and provide a reference database that facilitates the work of many organisations involved in vulnerability management,” GCVE tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="empowering-security-researchers"&gt;Empowering security researchers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fabian Gasser of cybersecurity consultancy Cyway says that GCVE brings benefits in removing the single point of failure inherent in reliance on the US-led CVE system while democratising vulnerability publishing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GCVE gives “more of a voice to independent security researchers, who can now also agree or disagree with vendor-self-assessments,” according to Gasser.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Daniel dos Santos, senior director and head of research at cybersecurity vendor Forescout, says that its &lt;a href="https://www.forescout.com/resources/exposing-the-exploited-a-quantitative-analysis-of-vulnerabilities-under-the-radar/"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; found a significant number of vulnerabilities without CVE IDs and even some that are exploited by threat actors. The GCVE has the potential to more quickly flag up exploited vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The GCVE DB has the advantage of aggregating several sources of vulnerability information and having a decentralized system of numbering authorities,” according to dos Santos.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="redundancy"&gt;Redundancy&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ferhat Dikbiyik, chief research and intelligence officer at cyber risk intelligence firm Black Kite, says the launch of GCVE is welcome following the funding scares of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For years, we treated the US-led CVE system as an immutable backbone,” Dr. Dikbiyik says. “When that backbone showed signs of stress due to budget politics, the world realized that relying on a single, centralized thread for vulnerability tracking was a strategic risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Localized vulnerability databases are already a reality in other regions, such as China.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Chinese platform is generally faster at indexing vendor disclosures and provides additional information compared to the US alternative,” says Martin Jartelius, AI product director at cybersecurity vendor Outpost24.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the GCVE to move from a regional project to a global standard, the focus must shift to integration with enterprise security tools, Dr. Dikbiyik argues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A database is only as valuable as the tools that use it,” says Dr. Dikbiyik. “To make this project viable, we need to see security vendors, scanner providers, and GRC platforms treat the GCVE not as an extra feature, but as a core data source.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The GCVE is less about competition and more about ensuring continuity, so that vulnerability disclosures don’t hinge on a single point of failure, according to Crystal Morin, senior cybersecurity strategist at Sysdig.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The success of the EU [vulnerability database] will be measured by how it complements existing efforts and supports faster triage, a smaller backlog, risk prioritization, and consistent access to quality data for the security community,” Morin says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123225/eus-answer-to-cve-solves-dependency-issue-adds-fragmentation-risks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reports of GDPR violations have risen sharply</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122281/reports-of-gdpr-violations-have-risen-sharply.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a recent &lt;a href="https://www.dlapiper.com/en/insights/publications/2026/01/dla-piper-gdpr-fines-and-data-breach-survey-january-2026"&gt;report by law firm DLA Piper&lt;/a&gt;, organizations are increasingly being reported for violations of the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562107/general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr-requirements-deadlines-and-facts.html"&gt;General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the study, the average number of daily reports has risen above 400 for the first time since the GDPR came into force across the EU on May 25, 2018. With 443 reports of violations per day, the number in 2025 was 22% higher than the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the data does not allow for any definitive conclusions about the causes of this increase, according to DLA Piper. The law firm believes that geopolitical tensions, the multitude of new technologies available to cyber threat actors, and a number of new laws mandating the reporting of security incidents are likely among the key factors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="e1-2-billion-in-gdpr-fines"&gt;€1.2 billion in GDPR fines&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to DLA Piper, the total amount of fines, at around €1.2 billion, was roughly the same as the previous year. However, this high sum also demonstrates that European data protection authorities remain willing to impose substantial fines. Since the GDPR came into effect, a total of €7.1 billion in fines has been levied.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Broken down by country, Ireland, where US tech giants like Apple, Google, and Meta have their EU headquarters, once again leads the enforcement statistics: The total fines imposed by the Irish Data Protection Commission have reached €4.04 billion since the GDPR came into force in May 2018.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This includes the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567531/the-biggest-data-breach-fines-penalties-and-settlements-so-far.html"&gt;highest fine ever imposed under the GDPR&lt;/a&gt;, amounting to €1.2 billion against Meta Platforms Ireland Ltd. Furthermore, in April 2025, TikTok Technology Ltd. was fined €530 million for transferring personal user data to China.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, DLA Piper points out that the risks of GDPR compliance are not limited to administrative fines. There is also the risk of subsequent claims for damages. Several landmark rulings by the CJEU and national European courts have addressed GDPR-related compensation claims — particularly regarding the requirements for claims for non-material damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122281/reports-of-gdpr-violations-have-risen-sharply.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA chief uploaded sensitive government files to public ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124320/cisa-chief-uploaded-sensitive-government-files-to-public-chatgpt.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acting director of the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency uploaded sensitive government contracting documents to a public version of ChatGPT last summer, triggering automated security alerts and raising questions about AI governance at the agency responsible for defending federal networks and critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Madhu Gottumukkala, who has led CISA since May 2025, uploaded at least four documents marked “for official use only” to OpenAI’s ChatGPT platform between mid-July and early August, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2026/01/27/cisa-madhu-gottumukkala-chatgpt-00749361" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Politico reported&lt;/a&gt;. The documents contained contracting information not intended for public release.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity sensors detected the activity in early August, generating several alerts in the first week alone, according to the report citing four Department of Homeland Security officials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident occurred despite Gottumukkala having personally requested special permission to use ChatGPT shortly after joining CISA. At the time, the AI tool was blocked for most DHS employees over concerns that sensitive information could be retained outside federal systems, the report added, citing the DHS officials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data entered into the public version of ChatGPT can be incorporated into the model’s training data and exposed to hundreds of millions of users. Unlike DHS-approved AI tools with controls preventing inputs from leaving federal networks, the public ChatGPT retains uploaded information on OpenAI servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprise-ai-governance-failures-exposed"&gt;Enterprise AI governance failures exposed&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident highlights systemic failures in how government agencies, and by extension, enterprises, manage AI tool exceptions for senior officials, security analysts said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“FOUO is not classified, but it is still sensitive government information,” said Arjun Chauhan, practice director at Everest Group. “Uploading it to a public AI tool creates real exposure: loss of data control, expanded exposure surface, secondary misuse risk, and policy boundary collapse.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The pattern mirrors early enterprise incidents where employees pasted confidential material into ChatGPT, Chauhan said. The critical difference is that controls reportedly existed at CISA, and the breach occurred through an exception pathway. “That highlights a core governance failure. Exceptions and senior access are often where AI controls break down.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Federal agencies now have &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/646291/if-you-dont-already-have-a-generative-ai-security-policy-theres-no-time-to-lose.html"&gt;AI policies&lt;/a&gt; and governance bodies, but the gap appears to be in execution rather than intent, according to Chauhan. Safe, approved AI tools are not always the default or most usable option, and enforcement varies by role and seniority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sunil Varkey, advisor at Beagle Security, said the incident reflects a broader organizational challenge. “Leadership teams may reference these tools positively for learning, productivity, and communication refinement, which unintentionally normalizes their use,” he said. “As a result, such platforms have rapidly become de facto productivity applications without being treated with the governance rigor typically applied to enterprise systems handling sensitive information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The tension between convenience and security often drives such incidents, Varkey added. Because “for official use only” data is not formally classified, users frequently underestimate its operational, contractual, or reputational impact.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaishiv Prakash, director analyst at Gartner, said the biggest risk when officials upload FOUO-marked documents to public AI platforms is losing control over the data. “You have no visibility into how long it’s retained, whether it can ever be deleted, or if it becomes exposed during legal holds or discovery.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations must provide employees with licensed, governed AI platforms featuring supplier-agreed data residency, strict no-training guarantees, and minimal retention, Prakash said. “Without that, people will continue turning to public AI tools out of convenience, putting sensitive information at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leadership-credibility-questioned"&gt;Leadership credibility questioned&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The uploads triggered an internal DHS assessment involving the department’s then-acting general counsel Joseph Mazzara and chief information officer Antoine McCord, along with CISA’s chief information officer Robert Costello and chief counsel Spencer Fisher, the report said. The outcome has not been disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the report, CISA spokesperson Marci McCarthy confirmed that Gottumukkala received approval to use ChatGPT under DHS safeguards and described the usage as “short-term and limited.” She said he last used the tool in mid-July 2025 under an authorized temporary exception and that CISA’s default policy blocks ChatGPT access unless an exception is granted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fact that automated alerts triggered shows controls can detect misuse, analysts said, but the incident occurring at the leadership level raises accountability questions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Because this involves the head of the civilian cybersecurity agency, the impact is largely reputational,” Chauhan said. “Leaders set behavioral norms. Deviations undermine compliance culture and weaken credibility when advising other agencies and critical infrastructure operators.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ChatGPT incident adds to mounting controversies surrounding Gottumukkala’s brief tenure. In December, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/12/21/cisa-acting-director-madhu-gottumukkala-polygraph-investigation-00701996" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Politico reported&lt;/a&gt; that he failed a counterintelligence polygraph test in late July and that DHS subsequently suspended six career staffers, characterizing the polygraph as “unsanctioned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829710/firing-of-130-cisa-staff-worries-cybersecurity-industry.html"&gt;lost a significant number of its workforce&lt;/a&gt; since the Trump administration took office, with personnel dropping from over 3,300 to around 2,200 through buyouts, early retirements, and layoffs. The agency faces proposed budget cuts of nearly $500 million for fiscal year 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gottumukkala previously served as South Dakota’s chief information officer under then-Governor Kristi Noem, now DHS secretary. CISA did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124320/cisa-chief-uploaded-sensitive-government-files-to-public-chatgpt.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-050)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-050</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-050</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–051)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-051</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-051</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-052)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-052</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-052</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-053)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-053</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-053</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-054)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-054</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-054</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-055)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-055</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-055</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-056)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-056</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-056</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-057)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-057</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-057</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNU security advisory (AV26-047) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmarterTools security advisory (AV25-866) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL security advisory (AV26-058)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-059) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-060)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-060</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-060</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719 - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-061)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-062)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-064)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-065)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-066)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-067)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-068)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Spot at RSAC 2026 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 2036411.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
