<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:26:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688) – Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding the next technical debt: Building AI governance before it breaks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101145/avoiding-the-next-technical-debt-building-ai-governance-before-it-breaks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The AI rush is repeating a familiar mistake. Early in my career, a risk executive I worked with used to say, “You didn’t invite me to drink the beer; now you want me to pay the bill?” whenever problems came up because a project moved ahead without enough oversight. If someone tried to avoid explaining the details, he’d add, “I don’t know if you’re showing me the monster’s head or just its toe.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, I’ve watched new products, business services and innovations launch without enough security or risk checks. Cloud computing, big data, BYOD, APIs, IoT, social media and low-code are just a few examples. We usually innovate first and worry about governance later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is following the same pattern. Leaders in many industries are excited about AI, just like they were with earlier technologies. But many still don’t have a clear way to track where AI is used, who owns the risks or how automated decisions could affect the business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ten years of fail fast have shown us the risks: more incidents, data breaches and bigger exposure. If organizations don’t build risk and accountability into AI now, they’ll face the same problems we saw with earlier innovations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-real-risk-isnt-ai-itself-its-how-we-use-it"&gt;The real risk isn’t AI itself, it’s how we use it&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even with detailed frameworks like the &lt;a href="https://airisk.mit.edu/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MIT AI Risk Repository&lt;/a&gt;, many organizations still struggle to connect AI risks to real business problems. Everyone wants new use cases, but few are tracking where risks begin — in the data, the models or the quick decisions machines make.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, AI risks aren’t just about the future — they’re already part of daily operations. These risks arise when algorithms affect business results without clear accountability, when tools collect sensitive data and when automated systems make decisions that people no longer check.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These governance gaps aren’t new. We saw the same issues with cloud, APIs, IoT and big data. The solution is also familiar: keep track, assess, control and monitor. The first step is knowing where AI is used, what data it handles and which processes it touches. With this visibility, governance becomes about managing what’s already in the business, not just fearing the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The next step is protection. We don’t need to reinvent the wheel or develop advanced new methods. Instead, we should start with the basics: with simple governance steps and then you can evolve your journey.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="borrow-what-already-works"&gt;Borrow what already works&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The good news is companies don’t have to start from scratch with AI governance. Guidelines for secure and compliant technology already exist in cybersecurity, cloud and privacy programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What’s needed is to apply traditional controls to this new context:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification and ownership.&lt;/strong&gt; Every model should have a clear owner, with limits on who can train, query or deploy it. Its relevance to the business should be clear by different criteria, such as regulatory, operational or revenue.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baseline security and non-negotiables.&lt;/strong&gt; Access control, multifactor authentication, network segmentation and audit logging are just as important for AI environments as they are for servers or clouds.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous monitoring.&lt;/strong&gt; Model behavior should be more than just accurate — it should be observable, traceable and accountable for any changes in purpose.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party due diligence.&lt;/strong&gt; Contracts with AI providers should clearly define rights over training data, generated content and how to respond to incidents.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing and validation.&lt;/strong&gt; Red-teaming, AI-specific penetration testing and scenario simulations should be regular practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These controls aren’t new, nor is the hope of avoiding another form of technical debt. Maybe this time we can apply the secure by design approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The same governance principles will be tested again soon; this time by a new wave of autonomous systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-rise-of-agent-ai-and-the-accountability-vacuum"&gt;The rise of agent AI and the accountability vacuum&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new generation of agent AI systems can act on their own across different platforms, doing tasks, making purchases or retrieving data without direct human input. This move from simple chatbots to self-directed agents creates an accountability gap that most organizations aren’t ready for.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without the right guardrails, an agent can access systems it shouldn’t, expose confidential data, create unreliable information, start unauthorized transactions, skip established workflows or even act against company policy or ethics. These risks are made worse by how fast and independently agent AI works, which can cause big problems before people notice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the rush to try new things, many companies launch these agents without basic access controls or oversight. The answer is to use proven controls like least privilege, segregation of duties, monitoring and accountability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Executives should be able to answer fundamental questions, drawn from frameworks such as NIST AI RMF, about any autonomous AI operating in their environment:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What governance processes are in place (policies, roles and responsibilities, oversight)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Which use cases and business applicability are being leveraged?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Who is accountable when it goes wrong?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Which risks does it represent? And which controls are applied?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-governance-into-the-business-not-around-it"&gt;Building governance into the business, not around it&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effective AI governance isn’t an IT function, any more than cybersecurity is. It’s a business function with shared accountability. Forward-looking organizations are now introducing three mechanisms that embed governance into operations:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI self-assessment frameworks&lt;/strong&gt; — simple checklists that help each business unit map their AI use cases, data sources and risks.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage governance committees&lt;/strong&gt; — cross-functional bodies with representation from risk, compliance, cybersecurity and business leaders.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corporate AI use policies&lt;/strong&gt; — defining approved tools, contractual standards and minimum safeguards for both internal and external AI usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These aren’t bureaucratic layers but foundations of sustainable innovation. When the business owns the inventory, risk teams can focus on assurance rather than discovery. Modern governance should enable adoption, not inhibit or slow it down, but help scale it safely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dont-build-another-debt"&gt;Don’t build another debt&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The similarities to cloud adoption are clear. Ten years ago, not having early controls led to exposed data, unmonitored systems and expensive fixes. AI is showing the same pattern, but it’s happening faster and with bigger consequences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Technical debt isn’t just about code anymore. It’s also about trusting your data, holding models accountable and protecting your brand’s reputation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The organizations that succeed with AI will be the ones that see governance as part of the design process, not as something that causes delays. They’ll move forward with clear plans and measure value and risk together.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They’ll see that real innovation isn’t just about building smarter systems but about making them safe, accountable and trusted from the start. For technology and business leaders, this isn’t just a security imperative. It’s a strategy for sustainable innovation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101145/avoiding-the-next-technical-debt-building-ai-governance-before-it-breaks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hardening browser security with zero-trust controls</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101173/hardening-browser-security-with-zero-trust-controls.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The shift from perimeter-based security to zero trust is now indispensable for combating modern threats. The obsolete “castle-and-moat” model, granting implicit trust to any device or user inside the network, collapsed with the rise of cloud, remote work and BYOD. Attackers now bypass traditional controls by targeting identity, exploiting AI-driven phishing, supply chain intrusions and advanced session hijacking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The browser is at this frontline, serving as the universal access point for SaaS, developer tools and sensitive AI resources. As data from diverse trust domains converge, each access request demands rigorous, real-time validation of identity, device posture and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIST SP 800-207 provides the model: decouple access from network location by using a policy engine, policy administrator and browser-based policy enforcement point to enforce dynamic, context-aware authorization. &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/207/a/final" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST SP 800-207A&lt;/a&gt; extends this to runtime control across multi-cloud and microservices. Simultaneously, &lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/resources/cisa-zero-trust-maturity-model-v2" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CISA’s Zero Trust Maturity Model v2&lt;/a&gt; maps a clear implementation path spanning five pillars and emphasizing automation, analytics and governance as essential enablers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This journal unites these leading standards with current enterprise practices, delivering a comprehensive browser-first ZTA framework that balances least-privileged access, SSO/MFA, device compliance and session isolation for secure, adaptable operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-imperative-for-browser-centric-zero-trust"&gt;The imperative for browser-centric zero trust&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As remote work and cloud adoption become the default operating model, the inability of implicit network trust and legacy VPNs to address the modern attack surface is undeniable. Adversaries now target the browser directly with attacks like cross-site scripting (XSS), session hijacking via stolen tokens and advanced phishing that bypasses traditional MFA. A browser-centric ZTA framework is the necessary response, built on the following six principles.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-identity-first-access-control"&gt;1. Identity-first access control&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Network proximity is now an inferior trust signal. Only federated, cryptographically verifiable identity tokens issued by centralized enterprise IdPs using OIDC or SAML are permitted as gates to corporate resources. This transition, well-documented by &lt;a href="https://fidoalliance.org/passkeys/"&gt;FIDO Alliance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/security/zero-trust/deploy/identity"&gt;Microsoft research&lt;/a&gt;, transfers the very concept of “inside” the organization from the network to the user’s validated persona. No session proceeds without a signed, short-lived identity claim.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-least-privileged-access-lpa"&gt;2. Least-privileged access (LPA)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Legacy roles that confer standing privileges are antithetical to zero trust. LPA decrees that entitlements are minimized, time-bounded and context-aware. The application of just-in-time access, JWT token scoping and dynamic risk assessment ensures users receive only what is necessary for their current task, never more. Device state, resource value and behavior all adjust privilege in flight: a noncompliant device or anomalous login instantly narrows the access window.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-continuous-verification-and-adaptive-policy"&gt;3. Continuous verification and adaptive policy&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust is not “authenticate once, trust forever.” It is a continuous cycle of verification. Adaptive policy rules, executed by the policy engine, must re-evaluate access in real-time based on new telemetry. This “posture drift” can be triggered by numerous signals:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behavioral:&lt;/strong&gt; If a user typically logs in from Texas at 9 am but suddenly authenticates from Eastern Europe at 3 am (“impossible travel”), adaptive rules flag the anomaly and restrict access.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Device:&lt;/strong&gt; An EDR agent detects a malicious process, changing the device’s health state from “compliant” to “at-risk.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network:&lt;/strong&gt; A user moves from a trusted corporate network to an untrusted public Wi-Fi hotspot. In response, the PE can automatically initiate a session revocation, force a step-up MFA challenge or reduce the session to read-only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-integrated-phishing-resistant-authentication"&gt;4. Integrated phishing-resistant authentication&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To secure the identity-first gate, the authentication method itself must be robust. Traditional MFA (like SMS or one-time passcodes) is phishable. The ZTA browser model mandates the adoption of phishing-resistant MFA, primarily through FIDO2/WebAuthn passkeys. As detailed by the &lt;a href="https://fidoalliance.org/passkeys/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;FIDO Alliance, passkeys are a W3C standard&lt;/a&gt; that replaces passwords with cryptographic key pairs. The private key never leaves the user’s device (e.g., a YubiKey, a phone’s secure enclave or a Windows Hello TPM), making it impossible to phish. The user authenticates with a simple biometric or PIN, providing unparalleled security with a superior user experience. By 2025, passkey adoption will have moved from emerging to mainstream, with deployments showing authentication times under two seconds and proven reductions in phishing-related losses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-device-health-gating"&gt;5. Device health gating&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A trusted user on a compromised device is a critical threat. The ZTA model must validate the &lt;em&gt;endpoint&lt;/em&gt; before issuing an access token. This “device health gating” is a cornerstone of modern IdP solutions. The conditional access policy engine queries the device for posture signals collected by an MDM (mobile device management) or EDR (endpoint detection and response) agent. As documented in &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/entra/identity/conditional-access/overview" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft’s conditional access framework&lt;/a&gt;, policies enforce compliance before token issuance. Key signals include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patch level:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the OS fully patched?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDR status:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the EDR agent (e.g., CrowdStrike, Defender) running and reporting no active threats?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disk encryption:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the primary drive encrypted (e.g., BitLocker, FileVault)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Device state:&lt;/strong&gt; Is the device jailbroken or rooted? Only devices that meet this baseline are considered “compliant” and eligible for access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-remote-browser-isolation-rbi"&gt;6. Remote browser isolation (RBI)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the highest-risk activities, we must assume the endpoint &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; be fully trusted and that web content &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; malicious. Remote browser isolation (RBI) addresses this by executing risky or privileged web sessions in isolated, disposable cloud containers. The user’s endpoint never interacts with active web code; it only receives a stream of pixels (pixel-streaming RBI) or a sanitized, reconstructed version of the page (DOM-reconstruction RBI). As demonstrated by &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/zero-trust/products/browser-isolation/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;zero trust solutions like Cloudflare RBI&lt;/a&gt;, this neutralizes all browser-based exploits, prevents malware from reaching the endpoint and can enforce data loss prevention (DLP) by disabling copy/paste or uploads from the isolated session.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="modern-workflows-and-policy-patterns-a-blueprint"&gt;Modern workflows and policy patterns: A blueprint&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A modern ZTA browser architecture is not a single product but an integrated system that operates on a continuous, per-request verification loop.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the foundational user-facing workflow for all access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request:&lt;/strong&gt; A user on a managed browser (e.g., Chrome Enterprise) attempts to access a protected app (e.g., test.company.com).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intercept &amp;amp; redirect:&lt;/strong&gt; An access proxy (ZTNA/PEP), like Cloudflare Access or Zscaler Private Access, intercepts the request. Seeing no valid session token, it redirects the browser to the enterprise IdP (e.g., Okta, Entra ID) to initiate an OIDC or SAML authentication flow.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP authenticates the user. Based on policy, it requires a phishing-resistant MFA step using a FIDO2/WebAuthn passkey. The user taps their YubiKey or uses Windows Hello.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextual evaluation:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP’s Conditional Access Policy Engine (PE) evaluates the request. It queries the Microsoft Intune or CrowdStrike ZTA integration for device posture. The policy is: ALLOW IF (user_group == ‘Sales’) AND (device_status == ‘Compliant’) AND (auth_method == ‘FIDO2’).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Token issuance:&lt;/strong&gt; Upon success, the IdP mints a signed JSON Web Token (JWT). This token contains critical &lt;em&gt;claims&lt;/em&gt;: the user’s ID (sub), their roles (groups), the authentication method (amr) and a short-lived expiration (exp).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access granted:&lt;/strong&gt; Browser supplies JWT to proxy, proxy grants direct, secure application access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="b-adaptive-session-management-and-least-privilege"&gt;B. Adaptive session management and least privilege&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This workflow demonstrates the “continuous verification” principle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario 1 — Posture drift:&lt;/strong&gt; The user is authenticated and working. Midway through the session, their EDR agent detects a high-priority threat (e.g., malware execution). The EDR agent instantly updates the device’s health state. The IdP’s conditional access, which leverages a continuous access evaluation protocol (CAEP), receives this signal and &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt; revokes all active session tokens for that device, forcing a logout and remediation.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario 2 — Step-up authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; A user with a valid session for a low-risk app (like a wiki) clicks a link to a high-risk app (like the SAP admin console). The ZTNA proxy (PEP) intercepts this new request, recognizes the “Tier 0” sensitivity of the application and re-challenges the user, forcing a new step-up authentication with a hardware passkey before proceeding, even though they already have an active SSO session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="c-privileged-and-sensitive-operations-via-isolation"&gt;C. Privileged and sensitive operations via isolation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This workflow is for protecting “Tier 0” assets like administrator consoles.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request:&lt;/strong&gt; An administrator attempts to access the Okta admin console or an internal Kubernetes dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy enforcement:&lt;/strong&gt; After successful FIDO2 authentication, the ZTNA policy (PEP) for this “Tier 0” application is configured not with an “Allow” action, but with an “Isolate” action.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isolation:&lt;/strong&gt; The user is transparently routed to an RBI service. The entire admin session is executed in a secure, disposable container in the cloud. Only benign pixels are streamed to the end-user’s browser.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DLP &amp;amp; threat neutralization:&lt;/strong&gt; This mitigates two critical risks:
&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endpoint Malware: If the admin’s workstation is compromised, keyloggers or token-stealing malware cannot access the privileged session, as it’s not running locally.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Data Exfiltration: Granular RBI policies are applied: copy/paste, file downloads and printing are disabled for this session, preventing accidental or malicious credential or data leakage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="d-forward-thinking-scim-provisioning"&gt;D. Forward-thinking SCIM provisioning&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This workflow is the automation backbone that makes LPA viable at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System for cross-domain identity management (SCIM) is an open standard (RFC 7643) for automating the exchange of user identity information between systems. &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc7643" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The SCIM protocol (RFC 7643)&lt;/a&gt; defines a REST API and schema for managing user and group resources.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Workflow (Joiner/Mover/Leaver):
&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source event:&lt;/strong&gt; A manager in the HRIS (e.g., Workday) changes an employee’s role from “Sales Rep” to “Sales Manager.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCIM push:&lt;/strong&gt; The HRIS (or an integration layer) automatically triggers a SCIM PATCH request to the IdP (Okta, Entra ID).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IdP update:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP updates the user’s attributes, removing them from the group:sales-rep and adding them to the group:sales-manager.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy propagation:&lt;/strong&gt; The IdP’s Policy Engine (PE) immediately uses this new attribute data.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re-evaluation:&lt;/strong&gt; The next time the user authenticates (or their token expires), their access is re-evaluated. Their old access to rep-level tools is gone, and their new access to manager dashboards is automatically granted. This “Just-in-Time” provisioning prevents “privilege creep” and ensures all access decisions are based on accurate, real-time identity data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="maturity-pathways-roadmap-to-optimal-state"&gt;Maturity pathways: Roadmap to optimal state&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This roadmap, aligned with the CISA ZTMM v2, allows organizations to make measurable, incremental progress.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial:&lt;/strong&gt; At this stage, the organization moves beyond the “Traditional” perimeter. All browser-accessed applications are federated with a central IdP and protected by an access proxy (ZTNA). SSO and passkey-based FIDO2/WebAuthn MFA are mandatory for all users. All access logs are centralized in a SIEM. This achieves the &lt;em&gt;Identity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Network&lt;/em&gt; pillar foundations.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced:&lt;/strong&gt; The organization builds on the initial foundation with richer context. Device compliance (via Intune/CrowdStrike integration) is enforced for all sessions. Policy decisions become adaptive, leveraging real-time telemetry from EDR and user behavior analytics (UBA). SCIM is fully implemented for automated provisioning from an identity source of truth (e.g., HRIS). This demonstrates maturity in the &lt;em&gt;Devices&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Automation&lt;/em&gt; capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimal:&lt;/strong&gt; At the highest level of maturity, access is determined on a per-request, least-privilege basis, fully aligning with NIST 800-207A. RBI is automatically and transparently enforced for all privileged, unmanaged or high-risk web sessions. The entire ecosystem is automated, with post-authentication security (like token theft detection and CAEP) fully integrated. This represents an optimal state across all CISA pillars, driven by robust automation and governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="operationalizing-zta-browser-security"&gt;Operationalizing ZTA browser security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implementing this architecture requires a shift in operational thinking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy design:&lt;/strong&gt; Move from network rules to a “who, what, where, when, why” logic model. Policies should be readable statements: GRANT access IF (user_group == ‘Finance’) AND (app == ‘SAP’) AND (device_status == ‘Compliant’) AND (auth_method == ‘FIDO2’). Start with a default “deny” and create explicit “allow” rules, creating a policy matrix that maps user personas to data and applications.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic access:&lt;/strong&gt; Token claims must be context-bound and short-lived. A token issued for a read-only wiki should not be valid for accessing a finance application. True phishing resistance &lt;em&gt;requires&lt;/em&gt; eliminating all phishable recovery methods. This means deprecating SMS, email links and security questions in favor of passkey-based recovery or in-person identity verification.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk automation:&lt;/strong&gt; Session adaptation (step-up, revocation) must be triggered by automated analytics. Integrate the IdP and ZTNA solution with your SIEM/SOAR platform. An EDR alert (e.g., “high-severity malware”) or a UBA alert (e.g., “impossible travel”) should automatically trigger a SOAR playbook that calls the IdP’s API to revoke the user’s session tokens.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governance-as-code:&lt;/strong&gt; Policies must not be managed via manual “click-ops” in a GUI. All ZTNA access rules, IdP Conditional Access policies and RBI configurations should be defined as code (e.g., using Terraform, HCL or JSON). This enables version control, peer review (via pull requests) and automated CI/CD pipelines, aligning with CISA’s cross-cutting controls for governance and automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="configuration-patterns-latest-2025"&gt;Configuration patterns (Latest, 2025)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chrome Enterprise:&lt;/strong&gt; Use Chrome Browser Cloud Management to enforce a secure baseline on all corporate browsers. Enforce policies like BrowserSignin (to force login to a managed profile), PasswordManagerEnabled (set to false to mandate use of an enterprise password manager), SafeBrowsingProtectionLevel (set to Enhanced) and BuiltInDnsClientEnabled (to enforce secure DNS). &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/a/answer/2657289" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google’s Chrome Enterprise policies&lt;/a&gt; provide the full list of controls to manage extensions, data leakage and security settings.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intune/conditional access:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a non-negotiable “baseline” policy: Require compliant device and Require phishing-resistant MFA for &lt;em&gt;all users&lt;/em&gt; accessing &lt;em&gt;all cloud apps&lt;/em&gt;. Then, create more granular policies. For example, block access entirely from high-risk countries or require a “Compliant + Hybrid Joined” device for access to legacy on-prem apps.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIDO2/WebAuthn passkeys:&lt;/strong&gt; Deploy passkeys (platform-based like Windows Hello and hardware-bound like YubiKeys) as the primary authenticator. Start with privileged users (admins) and high-value targets (executives, finance) first, then roll out to the general population.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare RBI/ZTNA:&lt;/strong&gt; Configure clientless ZTNA to secure third-party and BYOD access without requiring an agent. Use Service Auth policies (based on mTLS certificates or service tokens) to secure non-human (RPA bot) access to web applications. Configure a “default-isolate” policy that automatically sends all traffic to unclassified or high-risk domains through the RBI service.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCIM automation:&lt;/strong&gt; Connect your IdP (Okta, Entra ID) to your source of truth (e.g., Workday) via a pre-built SCIM connector. Map HR attributes (e.g., Department, Role, EmploymentStatus) to IdP attributes. Use these attributes to drive dynamic group membership, which in turn drives all application access and ZTNA policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-browser-is-now-both-sword-and-shield"&gt;The browser is now both sword and shield&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Browser security is the linchpin for zero trust and organizational resilience. By converging validated identity, rigorous device posture, adaptive access policies, automated provisioning and session isolation, we not only defend against the sophisticated threats of 2025 but also set a foundation for scalable, measurable governance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In moving from static perimeters to live, session-level policy enforcement, every click and credential is scrutinized, every privilege time-boxed, every access revocable by context and behavior not convenience or legacy. Teams must treat the browser not as an exposed window, but as the policy stronghold of the modern enterprise. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building toward this architecture is a journey: Begin with SSO and robust MFA, enforce device compliance, automate provisioning and integrate RBI where risk justifies isolation. Codify policy, automate telemetry and develop governance as code. Refuse the ‘trusted network’ myth. Zero trust is here, and the browser is now both sword and shield.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101173/hardening-browser-security-with-zero-trust-controls.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-779)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-780)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-781)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25-782)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-784)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-783)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-785)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-786)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-787)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insecure use of Signal app part of wider Department of Defense problem, suggests Senate report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101859/insecure-use-of-signal-app-part-of-wider-department-of-defense-problem-suggests-senate-report.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Signalgate scandal that enveloped US Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth in March appears to be symptomatic of a wider lax attitude towards the use of non-approved messaging apps by officials and employees, a Senate Committee has concluded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In March, the US Senate Committee on Armed Services set out to examine issues raised by the &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3854632/signalgate-theres-an-it-lesson-here.html" target="_blank"&gt;Signalgate incident&lt;/a&gt;: the need to clarify the existing rules on using “non-controlled” apps, and looking at whether Defense Secretary Hegseth adhered to them in his use of Signal, and whether his actions were evidence of a wider culture of insecure app usage within the Department of Defense (DoD).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This week’s dual reports have come back with a mixed assessment of these points. Broadly, what Hegseth was accused of doing – communicating sensitive information using a third-party messaging app – appears to have been happening at the DoD in less serious contexts since at least 2020.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This mirrors issues familiar to enterprises: unsanctioned or unmanaged messaging apps, including ones touting end-to-end encryption (E2EE) security, quickly become an IT backchannel that can invisibly undermine carefully-assembled security, compliance, and data retention policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="shadow-communications"&gt;Shadow communications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/Dec/04/2003834916/-1/-1/1/DODIG_2026_021.PDF" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;first report&lt;/a&gt;, an assessment of the Defense Secretary’s use of the Signal app to communicate with senior colleagues in advance of a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/March%E2%80%93May_2025_United_States_attacks_in_Yemen" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;military operation against Yemen on March 15&lt;/a&gt;, is used to illustrate the point. It confirms the widely reported fact that two hours before the raid, Hegseth revealed details of the operation to a Signal group of 19 people, including a journalist who had been added to it in error.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In doing so, the report agrees he violated security policies by sending sensitive information from a personal device, and using the non-approved Signal app in a way that revealed important operational details in advance of the strike. The report ducks the issue of whether this information was classified at the time it was sent, noting that Hegseth was senior enough to determine this for himself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/Dec/04/2003834921/-1/-1/1/DODIG_2026_022.PDF" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;second background report&lt;/a&gt; has uncovered evidence of a more general culture of shadow communications in the DoD, including widespread use of video-conferencing apps during the Covid 19 pandemic.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The evidence gathered is sparse and partly redacted, making it difficult to assess the seriousness of any breaches. Because the scope of its remit was limited to the evidence from previous audits, one of the committee’s recommendations is to undertake a more comprehensive assessment of unsanctioned app usage inside the DoD. There’s also a question mark around how old audits analyzed by a Senate committee could accurately measure something that, by its nature, is hidden and only recorded on personal devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the report says it is certain that Hegseth’s actions were not an isolated example, noting that staff had “used non-DoD-controlled electronic messaging systems for a variety of reasons. For example, some personnel used them because of the systems’ perceived appearance of security. As a result, DoD personnel increased the risk of exposing sensitive DoD information to our adversaries and did not comply with the legal obligation to retain and preserve official records.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In short, while there was no evidence that unsanctioned app use is routine or normalized, it is likely that enough staff are using them to make a serious breach possible at some point. The report concludes that one of the reasons staff have taken to these messaging apps was that they lack convenient alternatives. It recommends developing approved apps to remove this need, implementing a training program to ensure existing communication regulations are complied with, and limiting the authority to use messaging apps to senior staff, in specific circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What’s surprising about this is that it has taken a major political row at government level to raise an issue that enterprise CISOs have been grappling with for years: the effects of BYOD, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575457/shadow-it-is-increasing-and-so-are-the-associated-security-risks.html" target="_blank"&gt;shadow IT&lt;/a&gt; (and now &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/646835/is-genai-quietly-ushering-in-shadow-it-on-steroids.html" target="_blank"&gt;shadow AI&lt;/a&gt;), and unsanctioned apps that creep into organizations without anyone realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the last two decades, the rise of mobile devices, the cloud, and apps has radically de-centralized IT in ways that top-down management models struggle to control. Meanwhile, nothing has changed; the Signal app at the center of this scandal remains hugely popular on both sides of the political divide, despite the appearance of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3977385/company-behind-modified-signal-app-used-by-mike-walz-allegedly-hacked.html" target="_blank"&gt;additional issues&lt;/a&gt; with the technology. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101859/insecure-use-of-signal-app-part-of-wider-department-of-defense-problem-suggests-senate-report.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 21:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe tightens the net on sanctions evasion</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</link>
      <description>Europol is reinforcing its support to EU Member States in enforcing EU sanctions, as criminal networks develop ever more sophisticated methods to bypass restrictive measures linked to Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-788)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and partners shut down ‘Cryptomixer’</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partners-shut-down-cryptomixer</link>
      <description>From 24 to 28 November 2025, Europol supported an action week conducted by law enforcement authorities from Switzerland and Germany in Zurich, Switzerland. The operation focused on taking down the illegal cryptocurrency mixing service ‘Cryptomixer’, which is suspected of facilitating cybercrime and money laundering.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partners-shut-down-cryptomixer</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and Spanish National Police disrupt activities of far-right terrorist group 'The Base'</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</link>
      <description>Europol supported the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional) in disrupting activities of the far-right terrorist group 'The Base'. The operation took place over three days in Madrid and Valencia, resulting in significant seizures and the arrest of three suspected far-right extremists on 25 November 2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Submarine cable cybersecurity: protecting critical infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4099959/submarine-cable-cybersecurity-protecting-critical-infrastructure.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Between 95 and 99% of the world’s data traffic travels through submarine cables. An extensive network of more than 1.3 million kilometers, which travels across the seas and oceans, from shore to shore. According to &lt;a href="https://www2.telegeography.com/transport-networks?hsCtaAttrib=180200503225" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TeleGeography&lt;/a&gt;, there are 650 of these infrastructures in operation or in the pipeline, mainly operated by private companies. Whether we can connect to the internet, back up our computer files, make a bank transaction with our cell phone or communicate with other people depends to a large extent on whether nothing happens to the submarine cables that cross the world from one coast to another.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In recent times, numerous incidents where the breakage of a cable leaves a territory without connectivity are proof that despite their critical nature. They are not always properly protected: in the Baltic Sea alone, between 2022 and July 2025, ten cases of submarine cable breakage were &lt;a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/news/baltic-sea-undersea-cable-security/"&gt;recorded&lt;/a&gt;, seven between November 2024 and January 2025. In most of these incidents, international governments interests were suspected to be behind them, with Chinese or Russian involvement. In a complicated geopolitical context, these types of events, in which there remains some doubt as to whether they are accidental or intentional, put the focus on the need to ensure protection. Both at the physical and cybersecurity levels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US &lt;em&gt;think tank&lt;/em&gt; Atlantic Council &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/cyber-defense-across-the-ocean-floor-the-geopolitics-of-submarine-cable-security/"&gt;identifies&lt;/a&gt; several trends that threaten the security of submarine cables. On the one hand, linked to the geostrategic issue, the presence of authoritarian governments are reshaping the internet’s physical layout through companies that control internet infrastructure, to route data more favorably, interrupting the provision of services or taking advantage of infrastructures for espionage. In addition, network management centers have moved from locations close to cable entry points to remote ones, which adds new levels of risk. Finally, with the rise of technologies such as cloud computing, 5G or IoT, the volume of data transmitted over these cables has increased, but also their sensitivity, as more and more sectors depend on these tools for their performance. Once again, these are added factors for which cybersecurity and security policies for these critical infrastructures need to be reviewed. In fact, the European Union is taking action, with a &lt;a href="https://joint-research-centre.ec.europa.eu/jrc-explains/subsea-cables-how-vulnerable-are-they-and-can-we-protect-them_en"&gt;Cable Security Action Plan&lt;/a&gt; published in February 2025 that alludes not only to the physical challenges, but also to the need for cyber protection. But with the vast majority of cables in the hands of private companies, the approach they take is critical.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dealing-with-the-cybersecurity-of-submarine-cables"&gt;Dealing with the cybersecurity of submarine cables&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this new scenario, big technology companies are becoming major players thanks to their growing presence as a project developer: in a decade, Google, Meta, Amazon and Microsoft have gone from having 10% of international capacity to 71%. Asked how they address issues of infrastructure protection and cybersecurity, Google says they focus on the physical aspect. “Security is a key factor in all our infrastructure investments. Routes are deliberately chosen with many factors in mind, and methods such as shielding and cable burial are used to protect submarine cables.” Google says fishing boats and ship anchors as the greatest physical risk, and notes that “the best protection against these risks and any other physical damage is to build a network infrastructure that achieves resilience, in part, through multiple diverse network routes. Our philosophy is to create sufficient concurrent network paths at metropolitan, regional and global levels, along with a scalable software control plane, to support traffic redistribution and minimize network congestion. When physical damage occurs, redundant network paths can reroute traffic to minimize service disruption for customers and users.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the Spanish companies most involved in this global network is Telxius, a subsidiary of Telefónica. The company stresses that “submarine cables are more than just infrastructure; they are the backbone of the global digital ecosystem. In a hyperconnected world, submarine cables are essential and are part of a broader digital ecosystem that goes beyond the coast to key data centers,” the company says. Regarding the physical protection of this type of critical infrastructure, the company points to a significant improvement in recent times. “Physical accessibility is limited, so redundancy and resilience are still essential to guarantee continuity in the event of accidental damage caused by fishing, anchoring or natural phenomena such as earthquakes or landslides which, in the absence of redundancy, could affect service continuity”. In terms of cybersecurity, there is a twofold perspective. On the one hand, “it guarantees diversity and redundancy in all our terrestrial and submarine routes, which allows us to maintain service continuity with high availability even in the event of outages”. They exemplify this with the case of its transatlantic route, where Telxius offers what they call redundant connectivity through its two state-of-the-art submarine cables: Marea and Dunant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, from the Telefónica subsidiary they talk about protecting the infrastructure through a comprehensive security model. “In terms of cybersecurity, Telxius adopts, for its IT systems, networks and devices, a multi-layered approach and leverages artificial intelligence and machine learning for real-time threat detection.” This comprehensive model would thus combine different elements including physical measures and cybersecurity in the mooring stations, periodic audits and continuous evaluation, continuity and disaster recovery plans, periodic testing and clear protocols for crisis action, training and awareness to reduce social engineering risks and the use of AI and machine learning for proactive detection and risk mitigation. “And all this from regulatory compliance in key areas: business continuity, information security, environmental management and energy efficiency,” they summarize. A necessary framework to ensure the continuity of an infrastructure on which much of modern life depends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4099959/submarine-cable-cybersecurity-protecting-critical-infrastructure.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice &amp; Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 suspects arrested in two blows against human trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>France and Spain: disrupting a Chinese human trafficking networkConducted jointly by France and Spain, this operation targeted a Chinese organised crime group involved in trafficking human beings for sexual exploitation. The network, active for several years, coordinated sexual exploitation rings across France and multiple EU Member States. Members of the network rented apartments online for short terms, a modus operandi...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 arrests in Bulgaria in a large art trafficking investigation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</link>
      <description>On 19 November 2025, a coordinated effort led by Bulgarian authorities and supported by Europol, resulted in the dismantling of a criminal network involved in large-scale trafficking of cultural goods across Europe and beyond. This operation was conducted under the framework of a Europol operational taskforce. The action day involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Albania, France, Germany, Greece,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16.6 million packages of fake and harmful toys taken off EU markets</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</link>
      <description>Fake toys are poisoning, deafening and injuring children across Europe, while causing major losses to the EU economy. 26 countries, coordinated by Europol, co-led by France, Spain and Romania, and supported by the EUIPO and OLAF, have once again led initiatives to take down the producers and importers of counterfeit toys. With the global toy market valued at up to EUR 300 billion annually, it also remains the second-most counterfeited industry globally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-790)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-790</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-790</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-791)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-791</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-791</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-792)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-792</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-792</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25-793)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-793</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-793</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-794)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-794</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-794</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-795)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-795</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-795</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-796)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-796</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-796</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-797)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-797</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-797</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 20:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupang breach of 33.7 million accounts allegedly involved engineer insider</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101486/coupang-leaks-personal-information-of-33-7-million-accounts-suspected-of-poor-authentication-key-management.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A prolonged lack of management of valid authentication keys for signed access tokens issued to authenticators is believed to be the root cause of over 30 million accounts being exposed externally by ecommerce giant Coupang. Ongoing analysis suggests that these keys could have been exploited even after the responsible employee left the company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 29, Coupang &lt;a href="https://news.coupang.com/archives/58849/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;released a statement&lt;/a&gt; confirming the unauthorized exposure of personal information from approximately 4,500 accounts on Nov. 18. The company also noted that the breach had been reported to the National Police Agency, the Korea Internet &amp;amp; Security Agency, and the Personal Information Protection Commission. Subsequent investigations, however, revealed that the damage involved approximately 33.7 million accounts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Leaked information included names, email addresses, shipping address lists, and some order information. Coupang stated that payment information, credit card numbers, and login information were not included. It is believed that unauthorized access occurred via overseas servers starting on June 24, 2025. The company also stated that it is currently cooperating with relevant authorities to investigate the cause of the breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.msit.go.kr/bbs/view.do?sCode=user&amp;amp;mPid=208&amp;amp;mId=307&amp;amp;bbsSeqNo=94&amp;amp;nttSeqNo=3186554" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Ministry of Science and ICT, the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency, and other relevant agencies conducted&lt;/a&gt; an on-site investigation after receiving a report of a breach on Nov. 19 and a report of a personal information leak on Nov. 20. The investigation confirmed that the attacker exploited an authentication vulnerability in Coupang’s servers, bypassing the normal login process and leaking customer information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The government launched a joint public-private investigation team on Nov. 30, and the Personal Information Protection Commission is investigating whether Coupang violated its personal information protection safety measures — access control, access authority management, encryption, etc. As a service with such a high user base that it’s often called the “Amazon of Korea,” Coupang issued a public security notice on Nov. 29 to prevent secondary damage. Furthermore, a three-month period, starting Nov. 30, will be dedicated to strengthening the monitoring of personal information leaks and illegal distribution online.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Choi Min-hee, Chairwoman of the National Assembly Science, ICT, Broadcasting and Communications Committee, released the results of an analysis of the specific causes of the incident in a press release on Nov. 30. According to information received from Coupang, the company reportedly responded that “the token signing key validity period is often set to 5 to 10 years,” adding that “the rotation period is long and varies greatly depending on the key type.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chairman Choi’s side explained this incident using an analogy to an access control system. If the “token” required for login is a single-use access card, the “signature key” is like the authentication stamp used to issue the access card. While access is impossible without the authentication stamp, even with the access card, if the signature key is left unattended for an extended period, it can be subject to continued exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Rep. Choi Min-hee’s office, Coupang’s login system is designed to immediately discard tokens after they are created, but the signature information required for token creation was deleted or not updated when the employee in charge left the company, and was thus exploited by internal employees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a press release, Chairman Choi Min-hee stated, “Coupang did not follow the most basic internal security procedure of renewing the signing key,” and “Abandoning a long-term valid authentication key was not simply a deviation by an internal employee, but the result of organizational and structural problems at Coupang that neglected the authentication system.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Victims of this breach have been notified via email or text message. Related information can also be found on a separate &lt;a href="https://mc.coupang.com/ssr/desktop/faqlist" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;information page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Coupang CEO Park Dae-joon &lt;a href="https://news.coupang.com/archives/58857/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;issued a separate statement&lt;/a&gt; on Nov. 30, saying, “We sincerely apologize for causing great inconvenience and concern to the public,” and “Coupang will do its best to prevent further damage by closely cooperating with the joint public-private investigation team including the Ministry of Science and ICT, the Personal Information Protection Commission, the Korea Internet &amp;amp; Security Agency, and the National Police Agency.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;South Korean President Lee Jae Myung this week referenced the data breach at Coupang in &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/boards-policy-regulation/south-koreas-lee-calls-tougher-penalties-after-coupang-data-breach-2025-12-02/"&gt;calling for increased penalties for corporate negligence&lt;/a&gt; in such scenarios. The breach is believed to be the worst in South Korea in over a decade. Bloomberg reports that the breach may be a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-12-03/coupang-breach-is-poised-to-be-a-landmark-case-for-south-korea"&gt;landmark case for South Korea&lt;/a&gt;. It could result in a record fine, &lt;a href="https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20251204006900315"&gt;potentially up to 1.2 trillion won (US$814M)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10629826"&gt;prime suspect is a former Coupang engineer&lt;/a&gt; who had worked on authentication systems. The police are investigating whether the former employee acted alone or collaborated with others on the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101486/coupang-leaks-personal-information-of-33-7-million-accounts-suspected-of-poor-authentication-key-management.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN security advisory (AV25-798)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openvpn-security-advisory-av25-798</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openvpn-security-advisory-av25-798</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-799)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-799</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-799</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Struts security advisory (AV25-800)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-struts-security-advisory-av25-800</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-struts-security-advisory-av25-800</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-801)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-801</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-801</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-802)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV25-803)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-805)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-806)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-807)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-018 - Vulnerability affecting React Server Components - CVE-2025-55182</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV25-808)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-809)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-810)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-804) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GISEC GLOBAL 2026 – The Middle East &amp;amp; Africa’s Largest Cybersecurity Event</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 49672783403306536.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
