<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:34:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-819)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-820)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-822)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft warns MSMQ may fail after update, breaking apps</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108360/microsoft-warns-msmq-may-fail-after-update-breaking-apps-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A warning from Microsoft that a Windows patch issued last week may cause the Message Queuing (MSMQ) function in the operating system to malfunction could be behind multiple reports of internet of things (IoT) applications failing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ca.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian security awareness training provider Beauceron Security, says he saw a query on a Microsoft learning forum today asking if the MSMQ problem is behind the failure of a firm’s point of sale system to issue sales receipts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another person posted a query on a different Microsoft forum about a building in an unnamed city being without its fire alarm or smoke detector systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A link between these posts and the December 16 security update from Microsoft on the MSMQ issue couldn’t be confirmed. But Shipley said it is odd that Microsoft’s initial advice says that a workaround is available, but instead of detailing it, it &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/answers/questions/5666974/message-queuing-(msmq)-might-fail-with-the-decembe" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;urges admins to contact Microsoft Support For Businesses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The scariest words when it comes to a serious bug in Windows you’re trying to fix, that’s crashing your applications, is, ‘Call us,’” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MSMQ is a protocol for secure messaging between applications, Shipley noted, so if there is a problem, “it’s going to break stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/release-health/status-windows-10-22h2#3751msgdesc" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft post&lt;/a&gt; says that individuals using Windows Home or Pro editions on personal devices are “very unlikely to experience this issue. This issue primarily affects enterprise or managed IT environments,” including those running clustered MSMQ environments under load.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Symptoms include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSMQ becoming inactive;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Internet Information Services (IIS) sites failing with “Insufficient resources to perform operation” errors;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;applications unable to write to queues;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;errors such as “The message file ‘C:\Windows\System32\msmq\storage*.mq’ cannot be created” when creating message files;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;misleading log entries such as “There is insufficient disk space or memory”, despite sufficient disk space and memory being available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Affected are servers running Windows Server 2019 and 2016, Windows Server 2012 R2 and Windows Server 2012.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also affected are PCs running Windows 10 version 22H2, Windows 10 version 21H2, Windows 10 version 1809, and Windows 10 version 1607. Support for Windows 10 ended October 14, so the issue should only affect these systems if admins have paid for extended support and received the December update.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This issue is caused by a December Patch Tuesday security update (KB5071546) that introduced changes to the MSMQ security model and NTFS permissions on the &lt;em&gt;C:\Windows\System32\MSMQ\ &lt;/em&gt;storage folder. MSMQ users now require write access to this folder, which is normally restricted to administrators, says Microsoft. As a result, attempts to send messages via MSMQ APIs might fail with resource errors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A workaround is available for affected devices,” says the Microsoft update. “To apply the workaround and mitigate this issue in your organization, please contact &lt;a href="https://support.serviceshub.microsoft.com/supportforbusiness/onboarding" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Support for business&lt;/a&gt;. We are investigating this issue and will provide more information when it is available.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bicer/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jack Bicer&lt;/a&gt;, director of vulnerability research at Action1, suggested as a temporary workaround for MSMQ failures that Windows admins grant write access to the MSMQ directory &lt;em&gt;C:\Windows\System32\msmq. &lt;/em&gt;Once Microsoft provides the official update, revert the directory permissions to their original state and deploy the fix, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Danny Nguyen of Wicloud suggested on a Microsoft Learn forum that admins could either roll back the December security update (KB5071546) or adjust the permissions, as Bicer suggests. However, Nguyen urged admins to consult with their security team before making system-level permission changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A Microsoft spokesperson was asked for comment, but no response was received by press time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the first MSMQ problem in recent memory; &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-30080" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;last year Microsoft discovered a remote code execution vulnerability &lt;/a&gt;(CVE-2024-30008) that carried a criticality rating of 9.8. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this case, however, said Robert Beggs, head of Canadian incident response firm DigitalDefence, although the cause of the issue is a security patch, the impact and workaround are not strictly security issues. Therefore, he believes the fix is a workaround that does not involve security and security support, but regular support for a Windows system. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As for the company’s reason for asking admins to contact Microsoft Support for Business for the workaround, he suggested that Microsoft may want to spread the workload to ensure that security support is not overworked.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More broadly, warned Shipley, any update that leads to a business application failure is the kind of issue that turns admins off patching. December is the biggest month of the year for retail, and not the time for POS machines to go down because of the installation of a new patch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4108289/microsoft-warns-msmq-may-fail-after-update-breaking-apps.html" target="_blank"&gt;Computerworld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108360/microsoft-warns-msmq-may-fail-after-update-breaking-apps-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-823)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-824)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-825)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-826)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian APT group pivots to network edge device misconfigurations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107406/russian-apt-group-pivots-to-network-edge-device-misconfigurations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A Russian state-sponsored cyberespionage group has been targeting energy companies and critical infrastructure providers by exploiting misconfigurations in network-edge devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group has been operating since at least 2021 and has exploited device misconfigurations before but also known vulnerabilities such as CVE-2022-26318 in WatchGuard Firebox and XTM appliances, CVE-2021-26084 and CVE-2023-22518 in Confluence or CVE-2023-2753 in Veeam Backup.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/amazon-threat-intelligence-identifies-russian-cyber-threat-group-targeting-western-critical-infrastructure/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to&lt;/a&gt; telemetry collected by Amazon Threat Intelligence, the group has heavily focused on targeting misconfigurations this year, pivoting away from zero-day or N-day vulnerabilities. The main targets have been enterprise routers and routing infrastructure, VPN concentrators and remote access gateways, network management appliances, collaboration and wiki platforms and cloud-based project management systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This tactical adaptation enables the same operational outcomes, credential harvesting, and lateral movement into victim organizations’ online services and infrastructure, while reducing the actor’s exposure and resource expenditure,” the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="links-to-sandworm-and-curly-comrades"&gt;Links to Sandworm and Curly COMrades&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Amazon’s telemetry, the group’s infrastructure has overlaps with Sandworm, a group also known as APT44 and Seashell Blizzard that’s associated with Russia’s military intelligence agency, the GRU. There are also overlaps with a group whose activity was documented in the past by security firm Bitdefender, under the name &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4085272/russian-apt-abuses-windows-hyper-v-for-persistence-and-malware-execution.html" target="_blank"&gt;Curly COMrades&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, these could be subgroups within the GRU that work together, with the one tracked by Amazon handling initial access and lateral movement and Curly COMrades handling the host persistence through its CurlyShell and CurlCat custom malware implants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Amazon detected attacks against customer network edge appliances hosted on AWS EC2 instances with actor-controlled IP addresses achieving persistent connections that indicate interactive access to the compromised devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="credential-harvesting"&gt;Credential harvesting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers also observed credential replay attacks against victims’ other online services using stolen domain credentials following network edge device compromises. This indicates that the attackers are likely harvesting credentials by leveraging the traffic capturing and analysis capabilities of the compromised devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Time gap between device compromise and authentication attempts against victim services suggests passive collection rather than active credential theft,” the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Network traffic interception is consistent with Sandworm’s known tradecraft and the targeting of network edge devices specifically positions the attackers to intercept credentials in transit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-critical-infrastructure-providers-can-defend-against-this-threat"&gt;How critical infrastructure providers can defend against this threat&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group has a strong focus on the energy sector, with victims including electric utility companies, energy providers and even MSSPs with energy sector clients. However, it has also targeted technology and service cloud providers, as well as telecommunications companies across multiple regions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Amazon Threat Intelligence team advises organizations to audit their network edge devices for packet capture files or utilities that shouldn’t be present, to review their device configurations and isolate management interfaces, and implement multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies should also review authentication logs and monitor authentication attempts from unexpected geographic locations. Anomaly detection for authentication patterns should be implemented for all online services and the use of plain text protocols that could expose credentials in transit should be audited.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Amazon report includes indicators of compromise associated with this attack campaign as well as security recommendations specific to AWS environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107406/russian-apt-group-pivots-to-network-edge-device-misconfigurations.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-827)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-828)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-829)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco confirms zero-day exploitation of Secure Email products</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108496/cisco-confirms-zero-day-exploitation-of-secure-email-products.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco has warned that a China-linked hacking group is actively exploiting a previously unknown vulnerability in its Secure Email appliances to gain persistent access, forcing affected organizations to consider disruptive rebuilds of critical security infrastructure while patches remain unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco Talos said the campaign has been active since &lt;a href="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/uat-9686/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;at least late November&lt;/a&gt;, raising concerns for security leaders about unseen compromise and how far incident response efforts may need to extend beyond the affected devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ Related: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3523958/cisco-latest-news-and-insights.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Cisco news and insights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The vulnerability affects Cisco Secure Email Gateway, Cisco Secure Email, and Web Manager appliances running AsyncOS, but only in configurations where the Spam Quarantine feature is enabled and exposed to the internet, according to Cisco.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company said there is currently no patch available, and that rebuilding affected appliances is the only way to fully remove the attackers’ persistence mechanisms in confirmed compromise cases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprise-exposure-and-risk-scope"&gt;Enterprise exposure and risk scope&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cisco said that systems where the Spam Quarantine feature is not enabled are not affected, but analysts said this does not necessarily &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073996/the-expanding-ciso-role-from-security-operator-to-enterprise-risk-strategist.html"&gt;reduce enterprise risk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This vulnerability may remain a high-risk issue because affected appliances typically sit in privileged network positions, even though the feature is not enabled by default,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunilvarkey1/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sunil Varkey&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity analyst.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also not clear how many enterprises may have enabled the feature in production environments, said &lt;a href="https://confidis.co/about/our-leadership-team/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keith Prabhu&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CEO of Confidis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Spam Quarantine provides a way for administrators to review and release ‘false positives,’ i.e., legitimate email messages that the appliance has deemed to be spam,” Prabhu said. “In today’s remote support and 24×7 operations, it is entirely possible that this feature has been enabled by many enterprises.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hfsresearch.com/team/akshat-tyagi/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Akshat Tyagi&lt;/a&gt;, associate practice leader at HFS Research, said the bigger concern is the nature of the target. Unlike a user laptop or a standalone server, email security systems sit at the center of how organizations filter and trust email traffic, meaning attackers would be operating inside infrastructure designed to stop threats rather than receive them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The fact that there’s no patch yet elevates the risk further,” Tyagi said. “When the vendor’s guidance is to rebuild appliances rather than clean them in place, it tells you this is about persistence and control, not just a one-off exploit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Varkey added that exploitation may not require direct internet exposure and could also occur from internal or VPN-reachable networks, advising organizations to close or restrict access to affected management ports temporarily.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="rebuild-guidance-and-operational-tradeoffs"&gt;Rebuild guidance and operational tradeoffs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cisco has said that wiping and rebuilding appliances is currently required in cases where compromise has been confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“From a security standpoint, it is indeed the right call,” Tyagi said. “When there’s a risk that attackers have embedded themselves deep in a system, patching alone won’t solve the issue. Rebuilding is the only way to be confident the threat is fully removed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Varkey said that this may not be a viable option for many organizations, as it introduces business risks, including downtime, misconfiguration, and the potential reintroduction of persistence through contaminated backups.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises will need to balance remediation speed with business continuity while relying on compensating controls to limit exposure. “Cisco Secure Email Gateway, Cisco Secure Email, and Web Manager are critical components of the email infrastructure,” Prabhu said. “Organizations would need to plan this activity in a way that minimizes downtime, but at the same time reduces the time window of compromise. In the interim, they could use other security measures like blocking ports on the firewall to limit exposure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="more-cisco-news"&gt;More Cisco news:&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4107942/cisco-defines-ai-security-framework-for-enterprise-protection.html"&gt;Cisco defines AI security framework for enterprise protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4093950/cisco-initiative-targets-device-security.html"&gt;Cisco initiative targets device security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4089360/key-takeaways-from-cisco-partner-summit.html"&gt;Key takeaways from Cisco Partner Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4089036/ai-networking-demand-fueled-ciscos-upbeat-q1-financials.html"&gt;AI networking demand fueled Cisco’s upbeat Q1 financial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4085293/cisco-launches-ai-infrastructure-ai-practitioner-certifications.html"&gt;Cisco launches AI infrastructure, AI practitioner certifications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4084438/cisco-centralizes-customer-experience-around-ai.html"&gt;Cisco centralizes customer experience around AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4083476/cisco-unveils-integrated-edge-platform-for-ai.html"&gt;Cisco unveils integrated edge platform for AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108496/cisco-confirms-zero-day-exploitation-of-secure-email-products.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The devil of proposed SEC AI disclosure rule is in the details</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107317/the-devil-of-proposed-sec-ai-disclosure-rule-is-in-the-details.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A US Securities and Exchange Commission committee has recommended a new rule that would mandate companies to analyze and report all AI efforts — including decisions to &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;use AI for some purposes. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attorneys who have studied the proposal note that the AI rule — just like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1247504/how-us-sec-legal-actions-put-cisos-at-risk-and-what-to-do-about-it.html"&gt;the SEC’s cybersecurity rule&lt;/a&gt; from about two years ago — won’t technically require anything to be reported that wouldn’t have already required reporting. The new rule refers only to material AI efforts and ever since the creation of the SEC some 90 years ago, anything material has always required disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But they theorize that the SEC committee believes that many public-company boards and their senior executives don’t fully understand the scope and potential impact of their various AI efforts. The new rule would force those executives to create committees and to formally review all AI decisions, potentially unearthing material issues that would otherwise not have occurred to those executives. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, argues that this extra focus could make a significant difference for many enterprises. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It will help focus people. It puts it in front of everyone who needs to be thinking about AI,” Levine said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As for requiring companies to examine and disclose where they are either &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;using or where they might be underinvesting compared to rivals, Levine said that could help executives understand “that there is a risk that our implementation of AI may not keep up with stakeholders and competitors.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/files/sec-iac-artificial-intelligence-recommendation-111825.pdf"&gt;proposed rule&lt;/a&gt; comes from the SEC Investor Advisory Committee (IAC) and was discussed during the Dec. 4 IAC meeting. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="companies-can-write-their-own-definitions-of-ai"&gt;Companies can write their own definitions of AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another controversial aspect of the proposed rule is that it fails to define AI, instead instructing companies to write their own definitions. Some legal experts have suggested that the committee didn’t literally want companies to evaluate all uses of AI, given that the technology dates back to the 1950s and exists in some form in just about every piece of software that businesses use. They more likely intended for such evaluations to focus on relatively recent AI popularizations, especially generative AI and agentic AI. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Under the proposed rule, companies would “self-define what they mean by artificial intelligence and then rely on that definition throughout its disclosures in describing AI-related risks, their AI deployment strategy if any and capital expenses and R&amp;amp;D expenditures related to the implementation and deployment of AI, amongst other material information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jnylaw.com/our-staff/monica-j-washington-rothbaum/"&gt;Monica Washington Rothbaum&lt;/a&gt;, a senior attorney with J&amp;amp;Y Law, said that it would be “risky for a company to define AI differently” because it makes “apple to apple” investor comparisons difficult if not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Requiring companies to disclose AI-related risks is a smart move. But letting each company define AI however they see fit is a loophole waiting to be exploited. Without a consistent baseline, you risk turning disclosures into PR spin rather than meaningful accountability,” Rothbaum said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Rothbaum does find value in forcing companies to disclose where management has opted to not use AI or to use it less than they might have otherwise. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Under-disclosing material risks like reliance on flawed AI models can expose companies to liability when things go wrong. Failing to invest in AI responsibly could also lead to competitive disadvantages that shareholders deserve to know about,” Rothbaum said. “This isn’t theoretical. AI is already shaping the way we look at hiring, customer service, and security. These are core operations that can affect a company’s value. If you can’t clearly explain how your AI decisions are made and who’s accountable for making them, then you’re already behind. Transparency like that has to be the cost of doing business today.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://kennyhertzperry.com/attorneys/braden-perry"&gt;Braden Perry&lt;/a&gt;, a litigation, regulatory, and government investigations attorney with law firm Kennyhertz Perry, is not a fan of the proposed rule because he sees it unlikely to help investors make decisions. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked the probability that such a rule would deliver useful information to investors and potential investors, Perry said, “None. In terms of an overall understanding from a shareholder, there will likely be zero usable information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="will-filing-reveal-anything-useful"&gt;Will filing reveal anything useful?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This concern is partly based on the many SEC cybersecurity filings that have used boilerplate language — and use SEC exemptions to reveal nothing specific.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Perry, the key part of the AI definition portion is that the definition — once used — has to be used consistently throughout all filings. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Adopt a clear, enterprise-wide definition of AI and use it consistently across SEC filings, internal policies, and marketing, so you do not redefine the term to suit the story you want to tell in a given quarter,” Perry said. “The IAC recommendation explicitly contemplates requiring issuers to define what they mean by AI, in part because inconsistent definitions are already making disclosures hard for investors to compare. Allowing companies to define AI themselves is a double-edged sword, since it can either promote honest, business-specific clarity or invite opportunistic word games.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some attorneys suggested that companies should be careful about AI phrasing or face potential actions from the SEC and the US Federal Trade Commission (FTC). &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;Be very cautious about AI marketing. The SEC has already shown, through its AI washing enforcement actions, that it is willing to charge firms that exaggerate their AI capabilities or mislead investors about how embedded AI is in their products and processes,” Perry said. “A disclosure regime that asks companies to explain where AI is used, how it is governed, and how it affects operations will only make it easier for the SEC to test whether those claims are real.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lexireese/"&gt;Lexi Reese&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of AI vendor Lanai, also expressed concern about allowing companies to write their own AI definitions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Giving companies the freedom to define AI may reduce short-term compliance friction, but it creates exactly the kind of fragmented, incomparable disclosure environment that leaves investors guessing,” Reese said. “If one company calls an autonomous decision system AI and another calls the same thing a data-driven tool, their disclosures will look compliant while describing two different universes of risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI specialist &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/rob-lee"&gt;Rob Lee&lt;/a&gt;, chief of research for the cybersecurity training firm the SANS Institute, said the rule might prove helpful in raising board and C-level awareness about what companies are actually doing with AI. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But as with the earlier SEC cybersecurity rule, Lee said he was unhappy that the rule includes “a massive number of get-out-of-jail-free cards. Who is going to actually disclose anything? What are they disclosing? They don’t even mention shadow IT. How do you track unsanctioned AI use in your company?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not even all members of the IAC were happy with the rule’s phrasing. IAC member John Gulliver submitted &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/files/john-gulliver-written-statement-dissent-ai-20251204.pdf"&gt;an official dissent &lt;/a&gt;to the proposed rule, expressing particular concern with each company’s ability to write its own AI definition. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These definitions would likely change from year-to-year or quarter-to-quarter. I don’t see how this benefits investors,” Gulliver wrote. But he also said that he doubted the details required are realistic. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposed rule would “require public companies to provide highly specific disclosures of how their use of AI impacts employees at their company and the company’s customers. It’s good that this is only required when the use of AI is financially material to the company. But unfortunately, I think this is an impossible task,” Gulliver wrote. “Does the SEC really have the AI expertise necessary to determine what these line-item disclosures should be? And how is a company supposed to know the precise impact of AI on hiring or their customers? There are many macroeconomic and industry-specific factors that affect jobs and customers. In my view, accurately isolating AI-specific impacts would be a difficult guessing game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107317/the-devil-of-proposed-sec-ai-disclosure-rule-is-in-the-details.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CASB buyer’s guide: What to know about cloud access security brokers before you buy</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/557365/cloud-access-security-broker-buyers-guide.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-access-security-brokers-casbs-explained"&gt;Cloud access security brokers (CASBs) explained&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, a cloud access security broker (CASB) manages access between enterprise endpoints and cloud resources from a security perspective. CASBs can be deployed on-premises or in the cloud; as a hardware appliance or software-only, as a proxy, reverse proxy, or through specific APIs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises have untold numbers of endpoints, both managed (corporate-owned devices) and unmanaged (devices owned by employees or third-party contractors). Endpoints can be on-premises or remote. And endpoints can include internet of things (IoT) devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ Download our editors’ PDF &lt;a href="https://us.resources.csoonline.com/resources/download-our-cloud-access-security-broker-casb-enterprise-buyers-guide/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;cloud access security broker (CASB) enterprise buyer’s guide&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; today! ]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="in-this-buyers-guide"&gt;In this buyer’s guide:&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud access security brokers (CASBs) explained&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Why enterprises need cloud access security brokers (CASBs)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to look for in a cloud access security broker (CASB) tool&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Core cloud access security broker (CASB) services&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Leading cloud access security broker (CASB) vendors&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to ask before cloud access security broker (CASB) tool&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Essential reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a multicloud environment, each endpoint could connect to multiple cloud resources over the course of a single day — productivity apps (like Microsoft 365), SaaS apps (like Salesforce and Workday), collaboration apps (like Slack and Zoom), and cloud storage (like Amazon Web Services and Dropbox). Not to mention homegrown apps that have been migrated to the cloud, or apps that have been developed in the cloud (that is, cloud-native).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CASBs sit between an organization’s endpoints and cloud resources, acting as a gateway that monitors everything that goes in or out, providing visibility into what users are doing in the cloud, enforcing access control policies, and looking out for security threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some vendors have begun incorporating additional features into core CASB functionality, such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/569559/what-is-dlp-how-data-loss-prevention-software-works-and-why-you-need-it.html"&gt;data loss prevention (DLP)&lt;/a&gt;, secure web gateway (SWG), &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;cloud security posture management (CSPM)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/553329/user-entity-behavior-analytics-next-step-in-security-visibilty.html"&gt;user and entity behavior analytics (UEBA)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, it is important to note that CASBs are also a key component of a broader security strategy that goes by several names:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gartner calls that broader strategy &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/957252/10-questions-to-ask-about-secure-service-edge-sse.html"&gt;Secure Service Edge (SSE)&lt;/a&gt;, an integration of CASB, secure web gateway (SWG), and &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/971137/who-is-selling-zero-trust-network-access-ztna-and-what-do-you-get.html"&gt;zero trust network access (ZTNA)&lt;/a&gt;. According to Gartner, by 2026, 85% of organizations seeking to secure their web, SaaS, and private applications will obtain the security capabilities from a Security Service Edge (SSE) offering. The Gartner nomenclature has become the de facto standard. They and others have used a second acronym, Security Access Service Edge (SASE).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;IDC defines the category as network edge security as a service (NESaaS), with the same three core components: CASB, SWG, and ZTNA. “The network security market is in the process of a much-needed convergence trend. Security vendors have shifted from a focus on à la carte, individualized security services to a consolidated, cloud-delivered network security platform that treats individual services as optional modules,” IDC states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-enterprises-need-cloud-access-security-brokers-casbs"&gt;Why enterprises need cloud access security brokers (CASBs)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The original use case for CASBs was to address &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563803/shadow-it-its-not-what-you-think.html"&gt;shadow IT&lt;/a&gt;. When security execs deployed their first CASB tools, they were surprised to discover how many employees had their own personal cloud storage accounts, where they squirreled away corporate data. CASB tools can help security teams discover and monitor unauthorized or unmanaged cloud services being used by employees. This has grown to also include &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3964282/cisos-no-closer-to-containing-shadow-ais-skyrocketing-data-risks.html"&gt;shadow AI services&lt;/a&gt;, as more enterprise users pick various machine learning models and use personal accounts to access public-facing generative AI tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, CASBs encompass a variety of other use cases:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data protection&lt;/strong&gt;: The COVID-19 pandemic drove employees to remote work and applications to the cloud, where they could be more easily accessed. The pandemic has passed, and many employees have returned to the office, but those applications and that data are still in the cloud. Organizations must protect sensitive data as it moves across a hybrid cloud environment. Today’s CASB often integrates DLP functionality.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; Data privacy regulations continue to tighten. CASBs are an important tool in an organization’s overall regulatory compliance framework, enforcing data privacy policies.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote workforce&lt;/strong&gt;: Regardless of the location of employees, CASBs allow enterprises to implement more consistent security standards and secure remote access to cloud resources.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat detection&lt;/strong&gt;: CASBs can detect malicious activity, intrusion attempts, ransomware, and other types of security events. CASB tools can generate real-time alerts to enable quick response by security teams and feed these alerts into other security platforms to mitigate and resolve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-look-for-in-a-cloud-access-security-brokers-casb-tool"&gt;What to look for in a cloud access security brokers (CASB) tool&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From a purely functional perspective, there are four key features of a CASB tool:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visibility:&lt;/strong&gt; CASBs provide comprehensive visibility into cloud usage, user activities, and data flows.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control:&lt;/strong&gt; CASBs offer granular control over user permissions and data access.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data protection:&lt;/strong&gt; CASB solutions provide data protection capabilities to safeguard sensitive information across multiple cloud services.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; CASB tools help maintain compliance with data privacy regulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond those core features, organizations need to make sure the CASB tool well integrates with existing cloud services, applications, and security infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are three deployment modes: forward proxy, reverse proxy and API-based. Most experts say that API-based CASBs provide better functionality, but organizations need to make sure that the vendor’s list of application programming interface (API) connections matches up with the organization’s inventory of cloud apps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="core-casb-services"&gt;Core CASB services&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Take note about the use or requirements for deploying various agents with each product. This is where the CASB vendors often place their secret sauce, which could be an issue depending on how agent-friendly or agent-adverse your IT department is. For example, Skyhigh uses a single agent that functions across all three operational modes. Some of the other CASBs have multiple agents — such as for specific functional areas like antivirus, DLP, or VPN — that can get messy, not to mention tough to deal with unmanaged endpoints such as personal mobile phones and embedded devices such as internet of things controllers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The following three basic services that all CASBs offer are at the core of what CASBs do and why you would buy one:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor and control your most sensitive data flows&lt;/strong&gt;: CASBs were originally designed to stem the tide of shadow IT products and to control and make SaaS applications more secure. Now they have broadened their use and can fit into a variety of situations, including operating across multiple cloud providers and mixing SaaS, mobile, and on-premises applications, too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply uniform DLP policies across all servers and apps:&lt;/strong&gt; As your data appetite increases, you need better ways to ensure that you aren’t leaking customer- and business-sensitive information, either through a malicious insider or inadvertently through a bad combination of security loopholes. While DLP products have been around for years, having DLP-like features in your CASB can be a nice way to track these potential weak spots, especially as more of your data moves into the cloud and is accessed by unmanaged mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage cloud-native encryption keys:&lt;/strong&gt; Ideally, your CASB should automatically keep track of your encryption needs and keys so you don’t have to do this manually, and so you can encrypt more of your data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some CASB tools are better at some things than others. For example:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitglass has an Ajax virtual machine-like layer that handles near-real-time DLP on unmanaged devices. The only caveat is that these devices have to access data through their browsers.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Some CASBs, such as Fortra, has field-level encryption on some SaaS structured data services, which can be a handy mechanism for protecting sensitive information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond these basics, all CASBs offer the potential to operate in one (or more) of three different modes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forward proxy&lt;/strong&gt;, usually deployed with endpoint agents or VPN clients.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverse proxy&lt;/strong&gt;, which doesn’t require agents and can work better for unmanaged devices.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API control&lt;/strong&gt;, which provides visibility into data already stored in cloud repositories or data that is used in a cloud process that never enters a corporate network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="feature-sets-across-casb-operational-modes-vary"&gt;Feature sets across CASB operational modes vary&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Part of the CASB evaluation challenge is understanding how the feature set extends to each operational mode if indeed the product operates in more than one mode. Broadcom’s Symantec CASB, for example, has reverse proxies just for Microsoft 365 and no other application. Meanwhile, Cisco Systems and Palo Alto Networks both offer API-only CASB products. Such differences mean you need to understand the types of protection and not just which apps are supported but how they are supported, and what is the exact API portfolio that is covered by each product.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You really need the API support if you want to get granular with your CASB protection to understand the state of your public cloud security exposure and to stop any cloud-based malware too. API deployments also can trap cloud-to-cloud activities and to retrospectively inspect archived traffic flows. You will also need some level of proxying to handle application gateways and for implementing specific security policies. It pays to read the fine print and develop an appropriate test plan that will reveal the relevant features for each vendors’ product.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="nice-to-have-sets-of-casb-features"&gt;Nice-to-have sets of CASB features:&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conduct continuous risk assessments and compliance audits on demand:&lt;/strong&gt; A CASB can show in a single place where a corporation has the most risk and summarizes issues that a security team can quickly focus on for suspicious behavior that other products couldn’t easily do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forcepoint, Netskope, and Proofpoint all have nice risk summary dashboards that you can customize to display the things you need to understand how your environment is behaving and what needs immediate attention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply uniform adaptive authentication policies across all logins, servers, and apps&lt;/strong&gt;: This should include read-only access (Gartner suggests this would be a good situation for unsanctioned SaaS services that are nonetheless needed), step-up authentication, and more granular access rights management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity management and single sign-on (SSO) tools are the usual go-to reasons for these sorts of tasks, and one important trend is that more CASBs are integrating with traditional SSO products. The trick is to understand that the typical level of integration happens (usually) in reverse proxy mode only, and the SSO authentication is only passed to the CASB at the initial application login moment. This means that if you want a more complete adaptive authentication to trap when more risky behavior happens, you will probably have to stick with your dedicated SSO product.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As you can see, CASBs touch a lot of different existing security products across your enterprise. The challenge for successful integration is being able to understand these interactions and ensure that you overall security profile is enhanced rather than degraded with their use.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leading-cloud-access-security-broker-casb-vendors"&gt;Leading cloud access security broker (CASB) vendors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The list of leading CASB vendors (in alphabetical order) includes pure-play companies as well as traditional security vendors that have added CASB capabilities to their portfolios either by acquisition or through internal development. Most vendors would not share their pricing details, but we have found approximate clues on AWS and Azure marketplaces where we could.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/zero-trust/products/casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an add-on to their One SASE platform, using the same overall agent. There is a free version for under 50 users which allows two SaaS components, and prices start at $7/user/month above that level, with custom pricing for larger installations. The CASB product is now four years old and integrates with visibility and control of various AI services such as ChatGPT and Google Gemini. It doesn’t support reverse proxies, includes DLP and integrates with the risk scores and metadata sources available with Microsoft’s cloud services, such as with protecting Office 365 documents and emails.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cisco.com/site/us/en/products/security/cloudlock/index.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cisco Cloudlock:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cisco Systems has had a CASB since it acquired Cloudlock back in 2016. Cisco Cloudlock is a cloud-native CASB that protects users, data, and apps with an automated approach that uses APIs to manage the risks in the cloud app ecosystem. It integrates with Cisco’s SSE platform for its protective policies and a uniform dashboard. Cloudlock uses advanced machine learning algorithms to detect anomalies. It also provides DLP functionality and targets shadow IT with policy-based controls that can block dangerous activities, depending on permissions and risk levels. It uses machine learning to produce risk scores for more than 1,300 applications along with having tools to manage AI supply chains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.forcepoint.com/product/casb-cloud-access-security-broker"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forcepoint ONE CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Forcepoint bought Bitglass in 2021, one of the original standalone CASB vendors and a leader in Gartner’s Magic Quadrant for CASB. Forcepoint has integrated Bitglass technology with its own DLP capabilities to provide an SSE solution. Forcepoint excels in monitoring and reporting on shadow IT, and its user analytics feature is popular. The software also supports a zero-trust architecture, providing device and user authentication. Pricing is $120 per user per year on AWS Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fortra.com/products/cloud-access-security-broker"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fortra’s CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;is the result of acquiringendpoint protection vendor Lookout who previously acquired CASB innovator CipherCloud. Fortra now has a solid SSE platform that covers zero trust access controls, advanced DLP capabilities to automate the data discovery process, and supports a range of purpose-built integrations that covers identity access management and security orchestration, among others. It can provide visibility across managed and unmanaged cloud-based applications, users, endpoints, and data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.netskope.com/products/casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netskope CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the original pure-play CASB vendors, Netskope is a leader in CASBs as well as SSE. According to Forrester Research, Netskope has shown innovation across its technology stack, including significant investments in an impressive new private global network, artificial intelligence and generative AI security. Netskope merged SWG functionality into its CASB tool and sells separate in-line and API versions each for $35,000 per year for 100 users on AWS Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.paloaltonetworks.com/next-gen-casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palo Alto Networks Prisma CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;Palo Alto Networks touts its CASB as being “next-generation,” based on the proposition that it’s less a standalone product and more of a range of integrated solutions such as inline security, SSPM, and enterprise DLP. The Palo Alto Networks CASB is designed to secure apps and data across cloud and hybrid workforce environments, protects data in transit between users and SaaS providers, facilities regulatory compliance and minimizes risks from shadow IT.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proofpoint&lt;/strong&gt;’s CASB&lt;/a&gt; is focused on extending DLP and threat protection from email to cloud apps. Proofpoint takes a people-centric approach; it provides granular visibility into who creates sensitive data and who owns, downloads, uploads, shares and edits that data. It identifies users who have been successfully phished, and those who have been attacked the most by hackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.skyhighsecurity.com/products/cloud-access-security-broker.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skyhigh Security &lt;/strong&gt;CASB&lt;/a&gt; supports all deployment modes and enables real-time control over user access to sanctioned and unsanctioned cloud services. Skyhigh (a unit of Indian IT tech provider Musarubra that also owns Trellix) focuses on providing comprehensive multimode coverage that feeds security events into a machine learning system to provide sophisticated event correlation, helping security teams to focus on real threats rather than false alarms. CASB is just part of its overall SSE platform which integrates across SWG, ZTNA, DSPM and DLP, along with remote browser isolation. Protective policies are developed platform-wide and include management of AI usage and prevention of shadow AI and crafting user risk scores from all these metrics. Pricing is based on per protected service per user per year, the unlimited services is $88/user/year, with extra charges for shadow services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symantec&lt;/strong&gt;, a division of Broadcom, offers its &lt;a href="https://www.broadcom.com/products/cybersecurity/information-protection/data-loss-prevention-cloud/cloud-application-security-cloudsoc"&gt;CloudSOC CASB&lt;/a&gt; to monitor and control the use of sanctioned SaaS apps through extensive API integrations and in-line traffic analysis. The Symantec CASB provides full visibility and automatic detection of high-risk users, compromised accounts, and malicious insiders. Individualized behavioral-based user threat scores allow fast identification of risky user accounts. The tool automates the classification regulated data flowing in and out of apps, and it enforces controls that align with corporate policies. The tool includes DLP functionality and CSPM.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://versa-networks.com/products/casb/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versa’s CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; is part of its One Universal SSE Platform &lt;/strong&gt;that contains a unified dashboard and policy rule set for a variety of security services, including DLP, ZTNA, applications firewall, analytics and reporting. All its modules were entirely developed in-house, include various AI-based tools, and it supports all three modes of operation. &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Users can create protective policies using natural language queries of its embedded AI, as well as explore alerts and remediations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zscaler.com/products-and-solutions/cloud-access-security-broker-casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zscaler&lt;/strong&gt; CASB&lt;/a&gt; offers inline, real-time capabilities and out-of-band scanning functionality to protect data, block threats, provide visibility, and assure compliance. Key features include agentless cloud browser isolation to secure BYOD and third-party devices where software installations are infeasible, advanced threat protection to stop malware from reaching cloud resources in real time, cloud sandboxing to detect new ransomware and other zero-day infections, shadow IT discovery to automatically identify unsanctioned apps used by employees and create a risk score for each. It uses AI to classify and detect data leaks and will have additional AI-based tools in early 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-ask-before-buying-a-casb-tool"&gt;What to ask before buying a CASB tool&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Buying a CASB tool can be complex. There’s a laundry list of possible features that fall within the broad CASB definition (DLP, SWG, etc.) And CASB tools themselves are part of a larger trend toward SSE and SASE platforms that include features such as ZTNA or SD-WAN. Enterprises need to identify their specific pain points — whether that’s regulatory compliance or shadow IT — and select a vendor that meets their immediate needs and can also grow with the enterprise over time. Here are the key questions to ask yourself before buying a CASB tool:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I have a good handle on what cloud services my users are accessing, including employees, contractors, and other third-parties?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have a solid data classification system in place, so that I know what types of data are sensitive or mission critical?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have policies in place for access control across both on-prem and cloud environments, including SaaS applications?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have clear objectives? What are my priorities when shopping for a CASB?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How will a CASB tool integrate with my existing security infrastructure such as firewalls, endpoint protection and web gateways. Examine how it will protect my entire applications’ estate, including custom-written apps. What happens as I migrate apps from on-premises to the cloud or in reverse?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I get DLP and SWG as part of the CASB, or are those additional modules?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How will the purchase of a CASB tool play into my broader security roadmap that might include the adoption of SSE or SASE?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What is the initial cost, as well as the longer-term total cost of ownership?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have the budget for a new tool?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Can your product scale as my company grows?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Does your product cover all the geographic regions where I operate?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have the inhouse staff to deploy and manage the tool on-premises, or should I take the cloud-based, managed service route?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="essential-reading"&gt;Essential reading&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562793/how-do-you-secure-the-cloud-new-data-points-a-way.html"&gt;How do you secure the cloud? New data points a way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/969119/what-is-sase-a-cloud-service-that-marries-sd-wan-with-security.html"&gt;What is SASE? A cloud service that marries SD-WAN with security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/557365/cloud-access-security-broker-buyers-guide.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-830)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreePBX security advisory (AV25–831)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JumpCloud agent turns uninstall into a system shortcut</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107744/jumpcloud-agent-turns-uninstall-into-a-system-shortcut.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JumpCloud’s Remote Assist for Windows agent contained a critical local privilege escalation flaw, allowing full system compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Disclosed by XM Cyber, the vulnerability stems from insecure file operations during uninstall or update flows that execute with Windows NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM privileges. The bug could allow a low-privileged local user to elevate themselves to full system control or induce denial-of-service conditions on corporate machines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JumpCloud’s agent is widely used in enterprise environments as part of its cloud-based Directory-as-a-service platform, managing device access and remote support features across Windows endpoints. According to XM Cyber’s Hillel Pinto, attackers only need a local foothold to exploit the flaw, generally &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3970094/cybercriminals-switch-up-their-top-initial-access-vectors-of-choice.html"&gt;obtainable&lt;/a&gt; from phishing, remote support sessions, or developer machines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Systems running Remote Assist for Windows before version 0.317 are vulnerable and need to be updated immediately to mitigate risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="privileged-uninstall-in-a-untrusted-temp-space"&gt;Privileged uninstall in a untrusted temp space&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The flaw, tracked as &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-34352"&gt;CVE-2025-34352&lt;/a&gt; and rated at CVSS 8.5 out of 10, highlights risks from improper handling of privileged operations on Windows endpoints. During uninstall or update operations, the JumpCloud agent triggers the Remote Assist uninstaller with system-level privileges, the highest possible authority in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, that routine performs create, write, execute, and delete actions on files in a user-writable %TEMP% subdirectory without validating the trustworthiness of the path or resetting access control lists.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the uninstaller performs privileged file operations inside a user-controlled %TEMP% directory, a low-privileged attacker can abuse those operations to overwrite or delete protected system files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What we have is a JumpCloud process with NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM privileges that is deleting, writing, and executing a file with a predictable filename from an untrusted path,” Pinto said in a blog &lt;a href="https://xmcyber.com/blog/jumpshot-xm-cyber-uncovers-critical-local-privilege-escalation-cve-2025-34352-in-jumpcloud-agent/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;. “The core of the exploit involves Link Following, utilizing mount points and symbolic links to redirect the privileged I/O operation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="full-privilege-escalation-and-denial-of-service"&gt;Full privilege escalation and denial of service&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability opens two primary exploitation vectors with significant operational impact: full privilege escalation to system level, and denial of service (DoS).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By manipulating filesystem paths and leveraging race conditions, an attacker can redirect the uninstaller’s operations to delete or overwrite protected installer configuration targets, ultimately triggering techniques that give them a system-level command prompt. System access on an enterprise endpoint effectively grants control over policy enforcement, credential theft paths, and lateral movement capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, attackers can get the privileged process to write arbitrary data to sensitive system files (such as drivers), corrupting them and forcing blue screen of death (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2589942/blue-screen-of-death-strikes-crowd-of-crowdstrike-servers.html"&gt;BSOD&lt;/a&gt;) conditions. This not only knocks machines offline but can require substantial remediation effort, particularly across distributed fleets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pinto said that updating to JumpCloud Remote Assist for Windows version 0.317.0 or later will remediate this issue. “My team and I responsibly disclosed the vulnerability to JumpCloud, which confirmed the findings and promptly released a patch.” While &gt;NIST&lt;/span&gt;’s National Vulnerability Database (NVD) marks the flaw as fixed and references the JumpCloud Agent release notes for patching, there is currently no note dedicated to the flaw on the page or on JumpCloud’s support site. JumpCloud did not immediately respond to CSO’s request for comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107744/jumpcloud-agent-turns-uninstall-into-a-system-shortcut.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA Flags Critical ASUS Live Update Flaw After Evidence of Active Exploitation</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/12/cisa-flags-critical-asus-live-update.html</link>
      <description>The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) on Wednesday added a critical flaw impacting ASUS Live Update to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV) catalog, citing evidence of active exploitation.
The vulnerability, tracked as CVE-2025-59374 (CVSS score: 9.3), has been described as an "embedded malicious code vulnerability" introduced by means of a supply chain compromise</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2025/12/cisa-flags-critical-asus-live-update.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:31:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D&amp;O liability protection rising for security leaders — unless you’re a midtier CISO</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107332/do-liability-protection-rising-for-security-leaders-unless-youre-a-midtier-ciso.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Smaller firms are far less likely than multinationals to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2505459/how-cisos-can-protect-their-personal-liability.html"&gt;protect their CISOs from personal liability&lt;/a&gt; for security breaches, according to a study by RSAC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts quizzed by CSO said the finding was concerning because without protection &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3631759/personal-liability-sours-70-of-cisos-on-their-role.html"&gt;CISOs face legal and financial risk&lt;/a&gt; tied to decisions made in their role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vast majority (88%) of CISOs from Fortune 1000 firms are legally indemnified by their companies, but this figure drops to just 53% for CISOs from organizations with 500 or more employees, &lt;a href="https://www.rsaconference.com/library/research/rsac-cybersecurity-insights-futures-volume-3"&gt;according to the survey by RSAC&lt;/a&gt; (formerly RSA Conference).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2512968/if-youre-a-ciso-without-do-insurance-you-may-need-to-fight-for-it.html"&gt;Directors’ and officers’ (D&amp;amp;O) insurance&lt;/a&gt; is the most common indemnification vehicle for both groups, and 70% of the Fortune 1000 CISOs surveyed report being covered by it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cm.law/people/kelly-culhane/"&gt;Kelly Rittenberry Culhane&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of CM Law, told CSO the finding is a concern for security leaders and midsize employers alike, given that, midsize or multinational, organizations face similar risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While the complexity and scale of operations may differ in a midsize company, the cybersecurity risks — ransomware, data breaches, regulatory compliance failures — are equally severe,” Rittenberry Culhane says. “Without indemnification, CISOs risk personal liability, which can deter highly qualified professionals from accepting these roles.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, midsize organizations put themselves at greater risk by not offering to protect from personal liability the top security leader they employ.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="do-for-cisos-on-the-rise"&gt;D&amp;amp;O for CISOs on the rise&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs have the potential for more than one safety net, the first of which is a company’s indemnification provisions — rules typically embedded in the company’s articles of incorporation and bylaws.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The language of a company’s indemnification provisions must be properly worded — typically achieved by the general counsel and a board vote — to provide indemnification for a CISO equal to every other director or officer of a company,” explains &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-peterson-15330975/"&gt;John Peterson&lt;/a&gt; of World Insurance Associates, a provider of employment practice liability insurance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second safety net for a CISO is the D&amp;amp;O liability insurance policy procured by the CISO’s company through an insurance broker. Even when a company has D&amp;amp;O insurance in place, Peterson advises CISOs to review those policies to make sure they are covered as an “insured person.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://www.iansresearch.com/resources/press-releases/detail/new-report-from-ians-and-artico-search-shows-6.7--rise-in-ciso-compensation-in-2025-amid-economic-uncertainty-and-evolving-digital-risk"&gt;latest IANS Research + Artico Search’s CISO Compensation Report&lt;/a&gt;, inclusion of CISOs in D&amp;amp;O insurance policies is increasing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More than 50% of CISOs in the US and Canada received this insurance benefit as part of their compensation package, according to the 2025 edition of the study. This figure is up from the 40% who said they received this protection in last year’s edition of the CISO Compensation Report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One in 5 CISOs also reported to IANS Research that they have access to external counsel — typically for investigations or audits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-question-of-indemnity"&gt;A question of indemnity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href="https://mcgillpartners.com/team?member=1864"&gt;Ryan Griffin&lt;/a&gt;, US cyber leader at insurance broker McGill and Partners, points out that the difference between D&amp;amp;O insurance and a direct indemnification agreement is often misunderstood.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The most crucial tool for a CISO’s protection is the indemnification agreement with their employer,” Griffin explains. “The D&amp;amp;O policy is how the company pays to protect its officer, but the indemnification agreement is what actually legally guarantees that protection.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without a formal indemnification agreement, CISOs are at great risk, Griffin warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They would be responsible for covering their own legal defense costs, forcing them to rely on personal savings or a personal umbrella insurance policy,” Griffin tells CSO. “Beyond the financial hit, their career could be severely damaged.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Griffin adds: “An enforcement action, even if it’s ultimately dismissed, could result in penalties that bar them from serving as an officer for a public company for years, which seriously limits future job prospects.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="blame-game"&gt;Blame game&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Central to the issue as well is accountability, which almost always lands on the shoulders of the person perceived to be “in charge of security,” according to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenrickbagnall/?originalSubdomain=ca"&gt;Kenrick Bagnall&lt;/a&gt;, president and co-founder of RB-Cyber Assurance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Whether that’s the CISO of a Fortune 500 company or the sole IT director of a 100-person manufacturing firm, when things go wrong, someone has to answer for it,” says Bagnall, a former detective constable with the Toronto Police Service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The difference between a multinational and a midsize company isn’t the exposure, Bagnall says; it’s the resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While enterprise CISOs often have access to legal teams and crisis PR advisors to help shield them, a midrange firm often has one or two people — possibly more — wearing multiple hats, like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4050232/pressure-on-cisos-to-stay-silent-about-security-incidents-growing.html"&gt;compliance&lt;/a&gt;, IT, and security all rolled into one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This can become an issue because “regulators, customers, and even the courts won’t lower the expectations just because the company is smaller,” Bagnall says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Without legal protection, CISOs face significant personal and professional risk,” Bagnall said. “They can be blamed for systemic failures outside of their control — things like legacy systems that were never budgeted for replacement, or business units that refuse to adopt security controls because they’re ‘too disruptive.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="solarwinds-case-continues-to-cast-lingering-shadow"&gt;SolarWinds case continues to cast lingering shadow&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1302388/solarwinds-calls-sec-charges-unfounded-and-inexplicable-files-for-dismissal.html"&gt;SEC’s 2023 lawsuit against SolarWinds’ CISO Timothy Brown&lt;/a&gt; over allegations that he misled investors and failed to accurately report the vendor’s cybersecurity measures is far from an isolated case. Even though the ultimate dismissal of this high-profile lawsuit eased immediate fears that many &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/569923/uber-breach-case-a-watershed-moment-for-cisos-liability-risk.html"&gt;CISOs might be held personally liable for security incidents&lt;/a&gt; the issue has far from gone way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cybersecurity leaders are increasingly held accountable for breaches and their handling of incidents,” CM Law’s Rittenberry Culhane says. “Regulatory bodies, shareholders, and courts are naming CISOs in lawsuits — even when they acted in good faith.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Midsize companies tend to have more limited legal and compliance resources, making indemnity insurance even more important as a potential safety net for security professionals employed by midrange firms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“D&amp;amp;O insurance should always be obtained but that doesn’t always cover all the risk,” Rittenberry Culhane says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rittenberry Culhane, a former general counsel turned attorney whose practice specializes in advising corporations on risk management and insurance, offered CISOs a best practice checklist:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm CISO coverage under your D&amp;amp;O policy&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Review policy limits and exclusions for cyber-related claims&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Consider supplemental indemnification agreements for CISOs and security leaders&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Align indemnity provisions with incident response and disclosure policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more, see “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2092069/navigating-personal-liability-post-data-breach-recommendations-for-cisos.html"&gt;Navigating personal liability: post data-breach recommendations for CISOs&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="governance-structures-need-revamping"&gt;Governance structures need revamping&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO role has evolved faster than the governance structures that protect it, according to RB-Cyber Assurance’s Bagnall.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We now ask security leaders to be part strategist, part technologist, part crisis responder, and part scapegoat,” Bagnall says. “Until organizations, especially midsized ones, recognize that and build legal and contractual protections accordingly, we’ll continue to see talented leaders hesitate to take on these roles, resulting in organizations of all sizes not getting the proper tech and information security guidance they need.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The CISO isn’t just defending the network — they’re defending the business’s reputation, its trust, and its future,” Bagnall adds. “That responsibility deserves protection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107332/do-liability-protection-rising-for-security-leaders-unless-youre-a-midtier-ciso.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russlands Einfluss – Kritik an Lücken bei Cybersicherheit</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108430/russlands-einfluss-kritik-an-lucken-bei-cybersicherheit.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 8786w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2144734163.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Die Bundesregierung wirft Russland eine massive Cyberattacke sowie die Verbreitung von Falschinformationen im jüngsten Bundestagswahlkampf vor.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;PHOTOCREO Michal Bednarek – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Grünen sehen sich durch die jüngsten Erkenntnisse über russische Einflussoperationen im Bundestagswahlkampf in ihrer Einschätzung bestärkt, dass die aktuellen Maßnahmen zum Schutz der parlamentarischen Demokratie nicht ausreichen. “Dass unsere Demokratie und ihre Institutionen zunehmend hybriden Angriffen autoritärer Regime ausgesetzt sind, kann spätestens seit den jüngsten und deutlichen Warnungen der Spitzen unserer Nachrichtendienste und der Einbestellung des russischen Botschafters niemand mehr bestreiten”, sagt der stellvertretende Vorsitzende der Grünen-Bundestagsfraktion, Konstantin von Notz.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieser bedrohlichen Kombination aus “anhaltend großer Verwundbarkeit und zunehmender Gefahren” müsse die schwarz-rote Koalition endlich entschlossen entgegentreten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="vorgaben-nur-fur-bundestagsverwaltung-nicht-das-parlament-selbst"&gt;Vorgaben nur für Bundestagsverwaltung – nicht das Parlament selbst&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zwar hätten die Regierungsfraktionen den schlechten Entwurf der Bundesregierung zur &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4090107/bundestag-beschliest-nis2-umsetzung.html" target="_blank"&gt;Umsetzung der europäischen NIS-2-Richtlinie&lt;/a&gt; zum Schutz der kritischen Infrastruktur vor Cyberangriffen so überarbeitet, dass hiervon nun auch die Bundesverwaltung und die Verwaltung des Bundestages umfasst seien. Der Bundestag selbst, inklusive der Fraktionen und Abgeordneten mit ihren Wahlkreisbüros, gehöre aber nicht zum Geltungsbereich.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es sei “geradezu absurd”, dass der Bundestag als “Herzstück der Demokratie” bisher nicht als kritische Infrastruktur eingestuft sei, obwohl er seit Jahren immer wieder angegriffen werde, sagt der Grünen-Politiker, der dem Bundestagsgremium zur Kontrolle der Geheimdienste angehört.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nis-2-richtlinie-der-eu-umgesetzt"&gt;NIS-2-Richtlinie der EU umgesetzt&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Am 6. Dezember ist das Gesetz in Kraft getreten, mit dem die NIS-2-Richtlinie in deutsches Recht umgesetzt wird. Das Gesetz erhöht die Anforderungen an die Cybersicherheit der Bundesverwaltung sowie bestimmter Unternehmen, die als wichtig für das Gemeinwesen gelten. Dazu zählen etwa Telekommunikationsanbieter und Energieversorger.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für sie gelten jetzt strengere Vorgaben in puncto IT-Sicherheit sowie die Pflicht, erhebliche Sicherheitsvorfälle dem Bundesamt für Sicherheit in der Informationstechnik zu melden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cyberattacke-und-desinformation"&gt;Cyberattacke und Desinformation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Bundesregierung wirft Russland eine massive Cyberattacke sowie Falschinformationen im jüngsten Bundestagswahlkampf vor und hatte deshalb vergangene Woche Konsequenzen angedroht. Die “gezielte Informationsmanipulation” reihe sich in eine Serie von Aktivitäten ein, die das Ziel hätten, das Vertrauen in demokratische Institutionen und Prozesse in Deutschland zu untergraben, teilte das Auswärtige Amt mit. Der russische Botschafter wurde daher ins Ministerium einbestellt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Konkret gehen nach Überzeugung der Bundesregierung zwei hybride Angriffe auf das Konto des russischen Militärgeheimdienstes GRU.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="it-der-flugsicherung-betroffen"&gt;IT der Flugsicherung betroffen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zum einen könne ein Cyberangriff gegen die Deutsche Flugsicherung (DFS) im August 2024 klar der russischen Hackergruppe “Fancy Bear” und dem GRU zugeordnet werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zum anderen könne man nun verbindlich sagen, dass Russland mit der Kampagne “Storm 1516” versucht habe, “sowohl die letzte Bundestagswahl als auch fortlaufend die inneren Angelegenheiten der Bundesrepublik Deutschland zu beeinflussen und zu destabilisieren”. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Fokus standen vor der Bundestagswahl unter anderem der Grünen-Spitzenkandidat Robert Habeck und der damalige Unions-Kanzlerkandidat Friedrich Merz (CDU). Um sie in Misskredit zu bringen, wurden unter anderem falsche Zeugenaussagen produziert und ins Netz gestellt sowie Websites mit erfundenen Inhalten aufgesetzt. (dpa/jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id=""&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108430/russlands-einfluss-kritik-an-lucken-bei-cybersicherheit.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-832)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-833)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-834)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-835)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-836)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-837)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–838)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-839)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectWise security advisory (AV25-840)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-841)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-821) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-842)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-843)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-845) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-846)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-847)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-848) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
