<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:33:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-088)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISOs must separate signal from noise as CVE volume soars</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130453/cisos-must-separate-signal-from-noise-as-cve-volume-soars.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2026, the cybersecurity industry is expected to cross a threshold it has never reached before: More than 50,000 publicly disclosed software vulnerabilities in a single year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.first.org/blog/20260211-vulnerability-forecast-2026"&gt;a new forecast&lt;/a&gt; from the Forum of Incident Response and Security Teams (FIRST), the median projection for 2026 is roughly 59,000 Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs). Under more extreme — but plausible — scenarios, that number could climb far higher, reaching nearly 118,000, more than double the estimated 48,000 or so CVEs reported in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But security researchers and data scientists caution that numbers tell only part of the story. Historically, only a small fraction of disclosed vulnerabilities is ever exploited in the wild, and an even smaller subset meaningfully affects most enterprises.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While the number of vulnerabilities goes up, what really matters is which of these are going to be exploited,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-roytman/"&gt;Michael Roytman&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder and CTO of Empirical Security, tells CSO. “And that’s a different process. It does not depend on the number of vulnerabilities that are out there because sometimes an exploit is written before the CVE is even out there.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What FIRST’s forecast highlights instead is a growing signal-to-noise problem, one that strains already overburdened security teams and raises the stakes for prioritization, automation, and capacity planning rather than demanding that organizations patch more flaws exponentially.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-are-flaw-numbers-rising"&gt;Why are flaw numbers rising?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FIRST’s forecast reflects structural changes in how vulnerabilities are discovered and disclosed, not a sudden leap in attacker capability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Some of the classic coordinated vulnerability disclosure teams are producing slightly higher volumes each individually, but we’re also seeing several new entrants to the space that produce a lot,” Éireann Leverett, FIRST liaison and lead member of the organization’s Vulnerability Forecasting Team, tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The growth also reflects a maturation of vulnerability reporting itself. More organizations now operate as CVE Numbering Authorities, more vendors incentivize disclosure through &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657751/top-bug-bounty-programs.html"&gt;bug bounty programs&lt;/a&gt;, and long-neglected code bases — particularly in open source infrastructure — are receiving sustained scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In that sense, the surge reflects improved visibility rather than deteriorating software quality. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570815/10-old-software-bugs-that-took-way-too-long-to-squash.html"&gt;Vulnerabilities that existed for years&lt;/a&gt; are now being cataloged, tracked, and measured in ways that were not possible a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FIRST also adjusted its modeling approach to account for a structural shift in CVE publication that began around 2017, when disclosure volumes started to rise more steeply. Rather than optimizing for a single point estimate, the organization widened its confidence intervals to help security teams plan for a range of outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We think it’s entirely realistic that this year we reach 70,000 to 100,000 vulnerabilities,” Leverett says, adding that the median forecast remains closer to 60,000 and is intended to support planning rather than alarm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-raw-cve-counts-do-not-equal-risk"&gt;Why raw CVE counts do not equal risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the scale of the forecast, experts stress that vulnerability volume alone is a poor proxy for enterprise risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The risk to an enterprise is not directly related to the number of vulnerabilities released,” Empirical Security’s Roytman says. “It is a separate process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He points to historical data showing that while CVE numbers have risen steadily, exploitation has not followed the same trajectory. In 2025, roughly 48,000 vulnerabilities were disclosed, Roytman says. Of those, fewer than 3,000 had publicly available proof-of-concept exploit code, and only about 700 showed evidence of exploitation in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The really risky things changed a little bit [over 2024 levels], not quite as much as you would expect from the overall change,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On top of that, many vulnerabilities affect niche software, consumer devices such as cell phones, and other configurations that are not priorities in large enterprise environments. Other vulnerabilities are theoretically exploitable but offer little value to attackers compared with already weaponized flaws that are proven, scalable, and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This pattern has held for years, even as disclosure volumes climbed. The result is a widening gap between the number of vulnerabilities published and the number that matter operationally.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-capacity-problem-not-a-crisis"&gt;A capacity problem, not a crisis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, the growing volume creates real challenges for defenders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FIRST estimates that roughly 5% of vulnerabilities account for most of the serious risk. As the overall number rises, identifying that critical subset becomes harder.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With all of this extra being produced, finding that 5% might be a little harder, like finding a needle in the haystack,” FIRST’s Leverett says. “It’s about finding the signal in the noise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, the implication is that patching strategies are now more about scaling decision-making processes that were already under strain. “If you’re telling me a machine has to process 100,000 things instead of 50,000 things, that’s not a big deal,” Roytman says. “If you’re telling me a human has to do that, I would panic.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams have not operated at a human scale for years, he adds. The difference now is that the noise floor is rising fast enough to expose weaknesses in prioritization, tooling, and automation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-is-accelerating-discovery-not-mass-exploitation-yet"&gt;AI is accelerating discovery — not mass exploitation (yet)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Much of the anxiety surrounding FIRST’s forecast centers on artificial intelligence, particularly large language models that can audit code at scale. While AI-assisted tools are &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082265/ai-powered-bug-hunting-shakes-up-bounty-industry-for-better-or-worse.html"&gt;already increasing the pace of vulnerability discovery&lt;/a&gt;, experts caution that discovery and exploitation remain very different problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Roytman argues that while AI has made it easier to enumerate flaws, attackers still face economic and operational constraints. “If it were that easy, they’d be doing it to the 50,000 we saw last year,” he says. “Instead, exploitation remains concentrated on a relatively small set of vulnerabilities that are proven, scalable, and valuable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the same time, defenders are using the same techniques to manage the flood. Machine-learning models trained on exploitation data increasingly help security teams determine which vulnerabilities are likely to matter — and which can safely be deprioritized.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The same tools that are enabling discovery at scale are also enabling defenders to filter signal from noise at scale,” Roytman adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-cisos-should-do-to-manage-the-cve-flood"&gt;What CISOs should do to manage the CVE flood?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Absent the ability to hire their way out of the problem, most organizations will need to rely on more pragmatic measures, such as:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double down on prioritization.&lt;/strong&gt; Exploitation likelihood, asset context, and business impact matter far more than raw (CVSS Common Vulnerability Scoring System) scores.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automate triage aggressively.&lt;/strong&gt; Human review should be reserved for a small, high-confidence subset of vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for ranges, not point estimates.&lt;/strong&gt; FIRST’s confidence intervals are designed to support capacity planning, not prediction.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expect more noise, not more attackers.&lt;/strong&gt; Disclosure is accelerating faster than exploitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There’s no need to panic,” Roytman says. “But there is a need to be strategic.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="stress-on-the-vulnerability-ecosystem"&gt;Stress on the vulnerability ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The forecast also raises questions about the sustainability of the broader vulnerability ecosystem, including MITRE, which produces CVEs under contract with the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), the National Vulnerability Database administered by the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and CVE Numbering Authorities (CNAs) — organizations authorized to assign CVEs — already struggling with backlogs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rand.org/about/people/r/romanosky_sasha.html"&gt;Sasha Romanosky&lt;/a&gt;, a senior policy researcher at RAND, tells CSO the system is more likely to degrade gradually than collapse outright under the weight of a spiraling number of CVEs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think it would cause anything to break,” Romanosky says. “They just wouldn’t get processed. Lots of vulnerabilities would be ignored.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That dynamic could shift more responsibility toward software vendors and CNAs, many of whom already face capacity constraints of their own. Distributing more of the enrichment and prioritization work downstream may help in the short term — but only if automation improves alongside it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The system isn’t fragile,” Romanosky says. “It’s constrained.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In practice, that could mean growing queues, uneven data quality, and greater reliance on private-sector tooling to compensate for delays in public databases. The result is not necessarily higher risk, but greater fragmentation, particularly for organizations without mature vulnerability management programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity industry is not facing an explosion of exploitable weaknesses so much as an explosion of information. For CISOs, success in 2026 will depend less on reacting faster and more on deciding better — using automation and context to ensure that rising vulnerability counts do not translate into rising risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It hasn’t been a human-scale problem for some time now,” Roytman says. The challenge ahead is making sure it does not become an unmanageable one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130453/cisos-must-separate-signal-from-noise-as-cve-volume-soars.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-089)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV26-090)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV26-091)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The hard part of purple teaming starts after detection</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129713/the-hard-part-of-purple-teaming-starts-after-detection.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my recent articles for CSO, I’ve talked about &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4035333/7-reasons-the-soc-is-in-crisis-and-5-steps-to-fix-it.html"&gt;the limits of current SOC models&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4083612/the-soc-parachute-needs-more-than-packing-it-needs-practice.html"&gt;the importance of rehearsal&lt;/a&gt;. This time, I want to focus on something that’s becoming increasingly clear: purple teaming has lost its depth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve turned one of the most powerful tools for resilience into a transactional exercise that feels reassuring but reveals very little about how an organization will cope when the pressure is real.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Care and attention have become rare assets in our world. Distraction dominates both the consuming and supply sides of cybersecurity. Clients are pulled into complexity and novelty, while services providers are pulled into deadlines and deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, attackers — increasingly powered by AI — are becoming faster, quieter, and more determined.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When threats accelerate, surface-level testing is no longer enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-absence-of-findings-is-not-the-absence-of-risk"&gt;The absence of findings is not the absence of risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen this pattern everywhere: a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/652476/4-steps-for-purple-team-success.html"&gt;purple team engagement&lt;/a&gt; produces a set of impressive outcomes. The report looks good. Findings correlate with expectations. Leadership feels reassured.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But a result is often treated as&lt;em&gt; the&lt;/em&gt; result, as if the absence of findings means the absence of risk. This is a flaw.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The industry’s default approach is shaped by time pressure, commercial constraints, and scopes that are too narrow. None of this is malicious, it’s simply how the system has evolved. Providers deliver what they’re contracted to deliver, and clients take the report as a sign of depth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Omissions, often caused by time pressure or lack of mental space, are invisible. And invisible omissions are the most dangerous kind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="two-clients-who-shouldnt-have-been-breakable"&gt;Two clients who “shouldn’t have been breakable”&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recently, we worked with two extremely mature organizations. On paper, both looked close to unbreakable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of running a standard purple team, we co-designed the engagement with them. We looked at the problem as a determined attacker would, and we shared tacit knowledge openly, both our own and theirs. Crucially, everyone involved had visibility into the controls in place. It was a genuine cyber security partnership, not an audit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And both organisations were compromised — deeply — with almost no sign of compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one case, there was a single indicator of compromise: “domain admin.” Nothing about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it happened. Nothing about &lt;em&gt;what to do next&lt;/em&gt;. No instinctive or automated response. Just &lt;a href="https://chaleit.com/blog/red-bubble-trap-how-cyber-security-tools-are-hijacking-our-priorities/"&gt;a light turning red&lt;/a&gt; with no playbook behind it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the other case, the SOC detected multiple signals but never acted in time. Detection without action is just noise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The experience was humbling. And it forced a blunt question: “You saw us. So what?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the real test. Not whether the SOC sees something. Whether it &lt;em&gt;does something&lt;/em&gt; — fast enough and accurately enough — to stop the damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="standard-purple-teaming-cant-get-you-there"&gt;Standard purple teaming can’t get you there&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Purple teaming should be the discipline that reveals these realities, but the current model rarely does. Service providers tend to focus on the bypass, the exploit, the “win.” Clients focus on closing tickets, finishing the engagement, and getting the report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Neither mindset creates the space needed for deep thinking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Had we rushed through our work we would never have found what we did. Time pressure shapes outcomes more than most organizations realize. When testing is constrained by a standard 9–5, it limits how far teams can explore the conditions that lead to real compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="resilience-is-the-brake-moment"&gt;Resilience is the “brake” moment&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re driving, and you see the car ahead braking suddenly. Awareness helps, but it’s your immediate reaction that avoids the collision. Insurance plans don’t matter at that moment. Nor do compliance reports or dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only vigilance and rehearsal matter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber resilience works the same way. You can’t build the instinct required to act by running one simulation a year. You build it through repetition. Through testing how specific scenarios unfold. Through examining not only how adversaries get in, but also how they move, escalate, evade, and exfiltrate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the heart of real &lt;a href="https://chaleit.com/blog/purple-team-exercises-turning-security-investment-into-real-protection/"&gt;purple teaming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-didnt-help-either-organisation"&gt;AI didn’t help either organisation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both clients had &lt;a href="https://chaleit.com/blog/ai-security-testing-new-attack-vectors-and-strategies-in-application-security/"&gt;AI embedded in their SOCs&lt;/a&gt;. And it made no difference.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI can accelerate analysis, but it can’t replace intuition, design, or the judgment required to act. If the organization hasn’t rehearsed what to do when the signal appears, AI only accelerates the moment when everyone realises they don’t know what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why so much testing today only addresses opportunistic attacks. It cleans up the low-hanging fruit. But if organized crime wanted these organisations, they would have had them. And that’s not an easy sentence to write.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-model-that-creates-false-confidence"&gt;A model that creates false confidence&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The standard testing model traps everyone involved:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-off tests create false confidence.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scopes limit imagination.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Time pressure eliminates depth.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Commercial structures discourage collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Tooling gives the illusion of capability.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Compliance encourages the appearance of rigour instead of the reality of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why purple teaming often becomes “jump out, stabilize, pull the chute, roll on landing.” But what about the hard scenarios? What about partial deployments? What about complex failures? That’s where resilience is built.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And today, resilience is the only meaningful metric.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="new-mindset-slow-consistent-engaged-outcome-driven"&gt;New mindset: slow, consistent, engaged, outcome-driven&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my experience, purple teaming that works requires:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-ownership of the mission.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Tacit knowledge shared on both sides.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Full visibility into controls.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scenarios designed, not bought.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Repetition and rehearsal.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Space for thinking.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Disciplined simplicity.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A focus on the “so what,” not the bypass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is systems thinking. Engineering. Psychology. It is, in every sense, harder work than the standard model.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the seemingly impossible becomes possible when both sides push each other, and when the aim is not to produce a report but to reveal reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Purple teaming is about getting in, sure. But it’s also about what happens after that. Without a different approach, focused on consistency and outcomes, organizations will keep passing tests while failing in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129713/the-hard-part-of-purple-teaming-starts-after-detection.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV26-092)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU clears Google’s $32B Wiz acquisition, intensifying cloud security competition</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130667/eu-clears-googles-32b-wiz-acquisition-intensifying-cloud-security-competition.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google has secured unconditional EU antitrust approval for its $32 billion acquisition of cloud security firm Wiz, clearing a major regulatory hurdle and paving the way for one of the largest cybersecurity acquisitions to date.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The decision removes a key uncertainty for enterprise customers and positions Google Cloud to aggressively expand its security portfolio as competition intensifies with AWS and Microsoft in multicloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Commission found that there are several credible competitors that customers could switch to if Google were to bundle Wiz’s multi-cloud security platform with its existing products, or in case Wiz’s platform no longer worked with clouds other than Google’s,” the European Commission said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Commission said it also examined whether the acquisition would give Google access to commercially sensitive data from rival cloud providers that integrate with Wiz, but concluded that the information involved is not commercially sensitive and is generally accessible to other security software vendors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-reshapes-cloud-dynamics"&gt;Security reshapes cloud dynamics&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity remains one of the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/566143/the-transition-toward-enterprise-class-cybersecurity-vendors.html"&gt;most complex and fragmented&lt;/a&gt; areas of enterprise IT, with many organizations relying on multiple point solutions rather than a unified, end-to-end security architecture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts say the real fight in cloud computing is moving beyond infrastructure and into the control layer, where whoever has the clearest view of risk across environments holds the advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Compute, storage, and network scale are no longer sufficient differentiators at the enterprise board level,” said &lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research. “The real leverage now sits in who owns visibility across workloads, identities, entitlements, exposure paths, and increasingly AI pipelines.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acquisition positions Google as a vertically integrated cloud and AI cybersecurity provider that can give enterprises access to a more unified platform. But what the company does next is crucial, according to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meetneilshah/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Neil Shah&lt;/a&gt;, VP for research at Counterpoint Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The next step is how Google intertwines its current capabilities, such as Google Vertex AI Studio, with Wiz’s ‘Security Graph’ to enable enterprise developers to build a dynamic, real-time, and autonomous security layer,” Shah said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other analysts view the transaction as part of a broader structural shift in how hyperscalers embed security within their ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The acquisition signals the end of the best-of-breed era for cloud security and the beginning of Hyperscaler-led multicloud,” said &lt;a href="https://pareekh.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pareekh Jain&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Pareekh Consulting. “It suggests that major cloud providers effectively own the security layer, even for their competitors’ environments. Cloud security is evolving from siloed tools into platform-level infrastructure, and hyperscalers are now competing not just on compute or storage but on unified security across ecosystems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risks-for-enterprises"&gt;Risks for enterprises&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jain said that while Wiz’s core value proposition is built on cloud neutrality, ownership by Google changes the strategic incentives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In theory, Wiz can remain cloud-agnostic, as its value proposition is grounded in neutral visibility across clouds,” Jain said. “However, under Google ownership, the incentives change. Tighter integration with Google Cloud could be prioritized, and features that differentiate against AWS or Azure may receive less focus.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;EU regulators concluded the deal would not meaningfully lessen competition, but analysts caution that deeper vertical integration could still &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/1673988/idc-s-guide-to-avoiding-vendor-lock-in-2.html"&gt;anchor enterprises more tightly&lt;/a&gt; within Google’s platform stack, increasing long-term switching costs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For CIOs and CISOs, this acquisition fundamentally alters the risk calculation of using third-party security tools,” Jain said. “Enterprises heavily invested in AWS or Azure may start looking for a new independent security layer, e.g., CrowdStrike, Palo Alto Networks, to avoid dealing with Google.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lock-in extends beyond data portability to the underlying technical architecture, according to Gogia. He noted that flexibility decreases as organizations optimize their remediation playbooks and alert taxonomies for a specific provider’s telemetry or integrate AI governance tools natively with a single cloud’s model ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130667/eu-clears-googles-32b-wiz-acquisition-intensifying-cloud-security-competition.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-093)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-094)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-095)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entwickler werden zum Angriffsvektor</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130654/entwickler-werden-zum-angriffsvektor.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Developer Checking 16z9" class="wp-image-4130658" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2287651251_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Softwareentwickler sind gefragt – auch unter kriminellen Hackern.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Gorodenkoff | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Statt einfach “nur” Fehler in Applikationen auszunutzen, entdecken kriminelle Hacker zunehmend die Tools und Zugriffskanäle für sich, auf die sich Softwareentwickler &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4029368/entwickler-tool-von-amazon-verseucht.html" target="_blank"&gt;regelmäßig verlassen&lt;/a&gt;. Dabei kombinieren sie längst auch unterschiedliche Cybercrime-Taktiken und beziehen auch künstliche Intelligenz (KI) ein, um an ihr Ziel zu gelangen. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Angreifer versuchen nicht mehr nur, in Ihr Netzwerk einzudringen. Sie haben es jetzt auch auf Ihre Workflows abgesehen. Und Ihre Entwickler besitzen die ‚Schlüssel zum Königreich‘ – in Form von privilegiertem Zugriff auf Quellcode und die Cloud-Infrastruktur. Das macht sie zu einem hochkarätigen Ziel für Angreifer“, konstatiert &lt;a href="https://www.immersivelabs.com/author/chris-wood" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Wood&lt;/a&gt;, Principal Application Security SME beim Sicherheitsanbieter Immersive. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wir haben mit Wood und diversen anderen Sicherheitsprofis erörtert, auf welche Bereiche CISOs und Sicherheitsentscheider ihr Augenmerk bei diesem Angriffsvektor legen sollten – und welche Defensivmaßnahmen sich empfehlen, um gegenzusteuern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="vergiftete-okosysteme"&gt;Vergiftete Ökosysteme&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/darrenpmeyer" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Darren Meyer&lt;/a&gt;, Security Research Advocate bei Checkmarx, beobachtet regelmäßig viele Angriffe auf Entwickler, die er als “Low Effort” einstuft – etwa schadhafte Versionen beliebter Open-Source-Utilities, die auf Typosquatting-Domains gehostet werden. Diese “Spray and Pray”-Bemühungen stellten aber nur eine Seite der Medaille dar, warnt Meyer: “Es finden auch deutlich gezieltere Attacken statt, wie etwa der Shai-Hulud-Wurm, Angriffe auf npm-Packages oder das Plugin-Ökosystem von Visual Studio Code eindrücklich &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4115440/shai-hulud-co-die-supply-chain-als-achillesferse.html" target="_blank"&gt;belegen&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Einschätzung des Checkmarx-Experten spiegelt sich auch im aktuellen Sonatype-Report “&lt;a href="https://www.sonatype.com/state-of-the-software-supply-chain/Introduction" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2026 State of the Software Supply Chain 2026&lt;/a&gt;” (Download gegen Daten) wider. Der Spezialist für Lieferkettensicherheit hat seit 2019 insgesamt 1,23 Millionen quelloffene Packages identifiziert, die mit Malware verseucht waren. Allein im Jahr 2025 registrierte Sonatype 454.000 neue Exemplare, die in diese Kategorie fallen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Und damit nicht genug: “In der Praxis wird Vulnerability Exposure in weiten Teilen nicht durch neue Schwachstellen getrieben, sondern durch bereits bekannte”, schreiben die Sicherheitsexperten in ihrem Bericht. Demnach haben Developer im Jahr 2025 mehr als 42 Millionen mal anfällige Versionen der Logging-Utility &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3498056/log4j-alarmstufe-rot-wegen-java-lucke.html" target="_blank"&gt;Log4j&lt;/a&gt; heruntergeladen. Mit Blick auf alle Log4j-Downloads entspricht das einem Anteil von 13 Prozent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="kompromittierte-entwicklungsumgebungen"&gt;Kompromittierte Entwicklungsumgebungen&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Angreifer haben es darüber hinaus vor allem auch auf Softwareentwicklungsumgebungen abgesehen. Das liegt auch daran, dass gängige Security-Verfehlungen wie &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2797569/was-sie-ueber-rechteausweitung-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank"&gt;überprivilegierte Accounts&lt;/a&gt;, langlebige Token oder falsch konfigurierte Pipelines einen illegalen Zugriff auf Development Environments – und damit sensible Daten – relativ einfach machen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Zugangsdaten, die unsachgemäß gespeichert werden, sind selbst für unerfahrene Angreifer ein leichtes Ziel”, hält &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/crystal-morin" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Crystal Morin&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Cybersecurity Strategist beim Observability-Anbieter Sysdig, fest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="insider-bedrohungen"&gt;Insider-Bedrohungen&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Allerdings stehlen kriminelle Hacker nicht unbedingt Zugangsdaten, um Zugriff auf die Systeme von Unternehmen zu erlangen. Stattdessen bewerben sie sich einfach als Mitarbeiter. Solche “Fake Worker”-Kampagnen sind unter anderem bei nordkoreanischen Bedrohungsakteuren &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4033022/how-not-to-hire-a-north-korean-it-spy-3.html" target="_blank"&gt;beliebt&lt;/a&gt;. Die Taktik: Technisch versierte Angreifer setzen gefälschte Identitäten und Social-Engineering-Tricks ein, um einen Job zu ergattern. Einmal im Unternehmen, stehlen sie dann Daten und Geschäftsgeheimnisse – auch zu dem Zweck, diese später als Druckmittel für Erpressungen zu nutzen. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sysdig-Managerin Morin ergänzt: “Angreifer geben sich dabei auch als Maintainer aus und versuchen so, Schadcode in populäre Open-Source-Projekte einzuschleusen. So wie etwa im Fall der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493618/software-supply-chain-angriff-xz-utils-backdoor-gefahrdet-linux-systeme.html" target="_blank"&gt;XZ Utils-Backdoor&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="supply-chain-risiken"&gt;Supply-Chain-Risiken&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gelingt es den Cyberkriminellen, eine gemeinsam genutzte Softwarebibliothek in der Lieferkette zu kompromittieren, kann das dazu führen, dass sich eine Infektion rasant ausbreitet. Laut &lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/profile/gavin-millard" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gavin Millard&lt;/a&gt;, Vice President of Intelligence beim Exposure-Management-Spezialisten Tenable, haben Supply-Chain-Bedrohungen inzwischen Exploits als größtes systemisches Cybersicherheitsrisiko abgelöst: “Mit Supply-Chain-Angriffen wie den Hijacking-Attacken auf &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4047739/wave-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks-exposes-thousands-of-enterprise-developer-credentials.html" target="_blank"&gt;S1ngularity und npm-Maintainer&lt;/a&gt; können Cyberkriminelle in wenigen Minuten weit mehr erreichen, als mit einem Jahr Spear Phishing und Systemscans. Die Lieferkette zu missbrauchen, ist für Angreifer eine Art Kraftmultiplikator”, erklärt Millard. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nutzten Developer eine solche verseuchte Quelle, könne im Nachgang jede der von ihnen entwickelten Anwendungen – und sämtliche ihrer User – infiziert werden. Aktuelle Studien belegen, dass dieses Problem auch den Anwendern bewusst ist. 65 Prozent der Unternehmen, die das Weltwirtschaftsforum für seinen “&lt;a href="https://reports.weforum.org/docs/WEF_Global_Cybersecurity_Outlook_2026.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Global Cybersecurity Outlook 2026&lt;/a&gt;” (PDF) befragt hat, betrachten Schwachstellen in Lieferketten und bei Drittanbietern als ihre größte Security-Herausforderung. Gegenüber dem Vorjahr hat sich dieser Wert um 54 Prozent gesteigert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="kombinierte-threat-modelle"&gt;Kombinierte Threat-Modelle&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zudem gingen Cyberkriminelle zunehmend dazu über, technische Kompromittierungen mit &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491733/was-ist-social-engineering.html" target="_blank"&gt;Social-Engineering-Taktiken&lt;/a&gt; und KI zu kombinieren, um die Wirksamkeit ihrer Angriffe zu erhöhen. Christopher Jess, Senior R&amp;amp;D Manager beim Sicherheitsanbieter Black Duck, erklärt wie: “Ein schadhaftes Package kann mit subtilen Hintertüren versehen sein. Dessen Verbreitung lässt sich etwa mit Fake-Nachrichten von Maintainern oder anderen, vertrauenswürdigen Personen und angeblich dringenden Pull Requests für Sicherheitskorrekturen forcieren.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;KI erhöhe schließlich noch den Scope und die Präzision dieser Attacken, so Jess: “Phishing und &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2803547/was-ist-pretexting.html" target="_blank"&gt;Pretexting&lt;/a&gt; werden so mit mehr Kontext ausgestattet. Etwa, indem Repositories, Commit-Historien und Team-Rollen abgeglichen werden. Zudem können die Angreifer mit KI auch plausibel erscheinende Codeänderungen oder Dokumentationen erstellen, um Verdachtsmomente in Review-Prozessen möglichst zu unterbinden.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="ki-tools-fur-entwickler-als-risiko-addon"&gt;KI-Tools für Entwickler als Risiko-Addon&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;KI-gestützte Softwareentwicklung und Vibe Coding erhöhen die Sicherheitsrisiken zusätzlich – insbesondere, weil der so generierte Code häufig ohne ausreichendes Testing, eine Dokumentation oder Traceability generiert wird.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/beckland/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jamie Beckland&lt;/a&gt;, Chief Product Officer beim Security-Unternehmen APIContext, warnt insbesondere vor wachsenden Risiken durch die Einführung von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4037404/so-verwundbar-sind-ki-agenten.html" target="_blank"&gt;KI-Agenten&lt;/a&gt; und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4093704/tools-um-mcp-server-abzusichern.html" target="_blank"&gt;MCP-Servern&lt;/a&gt;: “MCP-Server können modifiziert werden, indem man sie um Tools ergänzt – beispielsweise, um Daten aus internen APIs, Data Stores oder SaaS-Systemen zu extrahieren.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Risiko manifestiere sich dabei nicht nur im LLM-Modell selbst, sondern auch in der Oberfläche der Tools und ihren Funktionen. “MCP-Server auf Änderungen in der Tool-Infrastruktur und den Datenzugriffsrechten des Servers zu überprüfen ist entscheidend”, hält Beckland fest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch &lt;a href="https://www.securecodewarrior.com/about-us/pieter-danhieux" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pieter Danhieux&lt;/a&gt;, CEO und Mitbegründer von Secure Code Warrior, sieht MCP-Server und Agentic AI als fruchtbaren Boden für Cyberkriminelle – schließlich sei es relativ simpel, hier absichtlich unsichere Prompts oder KI-generierten Schadcode einzuschleusen. Und damit nicht genug: „Wir haben außerdem beobachtet, dass Bedrohungsakteure KI-Agenten mit nicht autorisierten Anweisungen überlisten, die vermeintlich von dessen berechtigtem Benutzer stammen. Hierbei handelt es sich um die sogenannte &lt;a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/441.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Confused Deputy-Schwachstelle&lt;/a&gt;.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dazu passend spricht auch Sonatype von einer “KI-Intelligenzlücke”, nachdem der Anbieter für seinen Report 37.000 Empfehlungen von GPT-5 analysiert hat. Laut den Security-Experten handelte es sich in knapp 28 Prozent der Fälle um Halluzinationen. In einigen Fällen hat das KI-Tool dabei auch empfohlen, Malware-verseuchte Packages zu installieren. Und auch die Verantwortlichen des Benchmark-Projekts &lt;a href="https://baxbench.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BaxBench&lt;/a&gt; kommen in einer aktuellen Untersuchung zum Ergebnis, dass 62 Prozent der Lösungen, die von Large Language Models generiert werden, entweder fehlerhaft sind oder Sicherheitslücken beherbergen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="was-cisos-tun-konnen"&gt;Was CISOs tun können&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um die Softwareentwicklung besser abzusichern, empfiehlt sich für CISOs und Sicherheitsentscheider ein kombinierter Ansatz aus:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technischen Kontrollen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492034/security-awareness-trainings-schulungen-richtig-managen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Security-Schulungen&lt;/a&gt;, sowie&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3628246/so-entgiften-sie-ihre-sicherheitskultur.html" target="_blank"&gt;kulturellen Maßnahmen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Strengere Identitätsprüfungen, Account-Hygiene und Least-Privilege-Prinzip können auch mit Blick auf Development-Prozesse zu mehr Sicherheit beitragen. &lt;a href="https://ericpaulsen.io/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Eric Paulsen&lt;/a&gt;, EMEA-CTO beim Dev-Plattformanbieter Coder, empfiehlt darüber hinaus: “Isolieren Sie Arbeitsbereiche in Containern, zentralisieren Sie Image und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493018/sensible-daten-schutzen-secrets-management-im-devsecops-zeitalter.html" target="_blank"&gt;Secrets Management&lt;/a&gt; und setzen Sie regelmäßige Audits sowie eine Protokollierung aller Prozesse durch.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidsugden/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Sugden&lt;/a&gt;, Leiter der Entwicklungsabteilung bei der Digitalberatung Axiologik, besteht eine weitere Best Practice seit jeher darin, Workflow-Aktionen mit unveränderlichen &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2802289/was-ist-hashing.html" target="_blank"&gt;SHA-Hashes&lt;/a&gt; zu verknüpfen, die auf manipulationssicheren Hardwaremodulen gespeichert sind. “Davon abgesehen stellen Whitelists, Secrets Scanning und Software-Composition-Analysen weiterhin die DevSecOps-Grundlagen dar, die das Schutzniveau erhöhen”, unterstreicht Sugden. Er empfiehlt zudem, den direkten Zugriff auf externe Abhängigkeiten zu beschränken, um zu verhindern, dass unsichere Packages heruntergeladen werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geht es nach &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaeljayburch/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Burch&lt;/a&gt;, Application Security Advocate beim Cybersecurity-Schulungsanbieter Security Journey, ist es außerdem besonders wichtig, Softwareentwicklern fortlaufendes Hands-On-Training zu bieten: “Developer brauchen realistische Übungen; Sie müssen die Auswirkungen von Systemausfällen mit den eigenen Augen sehen – und dazu befähigt werden, Sicherheitsprobleme selbst zu beheben.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130654/entwickler-werden-zum-angriffsvektor.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What CISOs need to know about the OpenClaw security nightmare</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129867/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-clawdbot-i-mean-moltbot-i-mean-openclaw.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new personal AI agent orchestration tool known as &lt;a href="https://openclaw.ai/"&gt;OpenClaw&lt;/a&gt; — formerly Clawdbot, then Moltbot — is a personal assistant that can do tasks for you without your personal supervision. It can operate across devices, interact with online services, trigger workflows — no wonder the &lt;a href="https://github.com/openclaw/openclaw"&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt; has seen millions of visits and over 160,000 stars in the past couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to its developer, OpenClaw’s repo has also had over 2 million visitors over the course of a single week, and there are around 1.7 million agents whose human owners have signed them up for the &lt;a href="https://www.moltbook.com/"&gt;Moltbook&lt;/a&gt; social media platform where they share gossip about, well, their humans. As of this writing, the agents have made nearly 7 million comments on around a quarter million posts. And according to security researchers at OX Security, OpenClaw downloads are now at 720,000 per week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What makes OpenClaw so appealing is that it runs locally, can be configured to use any LLM on the back end, and talks to its user via the chat apps they already use — WhatsApp, Telegram, Discord, Slack, Teams — and has pre-built integrations with all the major operating systems, and many different smart home devices, productivity apps, Chrome and Gmail, and a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is what AI agents were supposed to be. And it’s free and open source. What’s not to love?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The appeal is so amazing,” says John Dwyer, deputy CTO at Binary Defense. “We’ve been watching movies for 25 years with AI assistants like Jarvis in Iron Man. There’s an appeal to having this tangible value add for AI. And it’s so easy to use. If it wasn’t so inherently insecure, I would love to use it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cybersecurity-risks-of-openclaw"&gt;The cybersecurity risks of OpenClaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The problem with running this is that these tools can do basically anything that a user can do,” says Rich Mogull, chief analyst at Cloud Security Alliance. “But it’s controlled externally. For an enterprise, this could be high risk. There are some guardrails that can be put around it, but they’re new, unproven, and have already been circumvented by researchers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;His recommendation: CISOs prohibit its use altogether.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I’m looking forward to experimenting with it myself over the weekend,” Mogull says. “But you shouldn’t be allowing it at this point in time. The answer has to be ‘no.’ There is no security model.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And there’s no time to waste. Token &lt;a href="https://token.security/blog/the-clawdbot-enterprise-ai-risk-one-in-five-have-it-installed"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that, over the course of a week of analysis, it found that 22% of their customers had employees actively using the tool in their organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The implications extend beyond immediate technical risks. “For enterprises, this could mean exposure to fines, litigation, and reputational damage among customers and partners due to data confidentiality breaches,” says Georgia Cooke, analyst at ABI Research. That includes personal data which could result in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562107/general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr-requirements-deadlines-and-facts.html"&gt;breaches of GDPR&lt;/a&gt; and similar PII control rules, and corporate information under NDA. Other risks include competitive damage due to exposure of intellectual property and enabling further attacks through exposure of technical and credential information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security researcher Maor Dayan called OpenClaw “the largest security incident in sovereign AI history.” His &lt;a href="https://maordayanofficial.medium.com/the-sovereign-ai-security-crisis-42-000-exposed-openclaw-instances-and-the-collapse-of-1e3f2687b951"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; has already found more than 42,000 instances exposed on the internet, with 93% of verified instances exhibiting critical authentication bypass vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Early versions of OpenClaw were insecure by default, according to Dayan, the rapid viral adoption overwhelmed users’ security awareness, and many deployments were quickly abandoned, leaving behind instances running outdated code. Documented attack paths enable credential theft, browser control, and potential remote code execution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In late January, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/7381830"&gt;Gartner&lt;/a&gt; researchers said that OpenClaw “reveals strong demand for agentic AI but exposes major security risks.” According to Gartner, there are already demonstrated vulnerabilities allowing remote code execution within hours of deployment. The ClawHub skills marketplace — folders of instructions, scripts, and resources that agents can discover and use to do things more accurately and efficiently, as per OpenClaw — introduces critical supply chain risks. And credentials are stored in plaintext and compromised hosts expose API keys, OAuth tokens and sensitive conversations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI agents often have tokens and secrets in configuration files,” says Jeremy Kirk, director of threat intelligence at Okta. “All of them get exposed if users have them misconfigured. In an enterprise context, that’s not good.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Then Noma Security &lt;a href="https://noma.security/blog/moltbot-the-agentic-trojan-horse/"&gt;discovered&lt;/a&gt; a new security blind spot related to OpenClaw: corporate Discord, Telegram or WhatsApp groups. One of the things that makes OpenClaw so appealing to users is that they can interact with it over multiple channels. But if OpenClaw is part of one of these channels, and there are other users on that channel, it treats instructions from those other users as if they came from their own owner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an attacker joins a public-facing Discord server with an OpenClaw agent installed, the attacker can instruct the bot to execute a cron job and crawl the local file system for tokens, passwords, API keys, and crypto seed phrases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Within 30 seconds, the agent bundles the sensitive data and sends it straight to the attacker’s-controlled server,” Noma’s researchers say. To the corporate security team, it looks like the bot is functioning normally, and the breach isn’t detected until the stolen credentials are weaponized. “When social media teams or external contractors deploy autonomous agents like Clawdbot, they are effectively opening a persistent and unmonitored back door into the local machines that touch your corporate infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And OpenClaw is a security risk even if employees run it at home, on their personal machines, because it might be able to access enterprise applications through user credentials via browser controls or skills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The security risks keep getting worse by the day. According to &lt;a href="https://www.ox.security/blog/one-step-away-from-a-massive-data-breach-what-we-found-inside-moltbot/"&gt;researchers&lt;/a&gt; at OX Security, the developer community around OpenClaw is also a major liability. The project embraces vibe-coded submissions, which accelerates development, but also introduces significant security risks. OS researchers say they found multiple insecure coding patterns in the codebase, patterns that could lead to remote code execution, path traversal, DDoS and cross-site scripting attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There are no sufficient guardrails,” the researchers say. They also found multiple instances of bug reports being disclosed in GitHub, instead of in private messages to maintainers. When an issue is posted publicly it is “giving attackers an opportunity to quickly gain knowledge of vulnerabilities even without doing any research or penetration testing,” they wrote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To rub salt into the wounds, there is also no formal security patching and updating process, and most users don’t update, they just stay on the version they first downloaded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And then there are the skills. Security researcher and OpenSourceMalware founder Paul McCarty has &lt;a href="https://opensourcemalware.com/blog/clawdbot-skills-ganked-your-crypto"&gt;identified&lt;/a&gt; about 400 different malicious skills on ClawHub, a central repository for the OpenClaw platform. These skills purport to help with tasks such as cryptocurrency trading, LinkedIn job applications, or downloading a YouTube video thumbnail. Some have thousands of downloads and are among the most downloaded skills on ClawHub. But what they actually do is trick the user into installing malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate how easy it is to get a malicious skill into the OpenClaw ecosystem, security researcher &lt;a href="https://x.com/theonejvo/status/2015892980851474595"&gt;Jamieson O’Reilly&lt;/a&gt; built one of his own, artificially inflated its download count to over 4,000 — making it the most downloaded skill on the platform — and watched developers from seven different countries execute arbitrary commands on their machines, thinking they’d downloaded a real skill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This was a proof of concept, a demonstration of what’s possible,” he wrote. “In the hands of someone less scrupulous, those developers would have had their SSH keys, AWS credentials, and entire codebases exfiltrated before they knew anything was wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="openclaw-exposes-enterprise-security-gaps"&gt;OpenClaw exposes enterprise security gaps&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first big lesson of this whole OpenClaw situation is that enterprises need to do more to get their security fundamentals in place. Because if there are any gaps, anywhere at all, they will now be found and exploited at an unprecedented pace. In the case of OpenClaw, that means limiting user privileges to the bare minimum, having multi-factor authentication on all accounts, and putting other basic security hygiene in place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It won’t solve the problem of OpenClaw — and of all the other agentic AI platforms coming down the line — but it will help limit exposure risks and reduce the blast radius when there is a breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And there are steps that enterprises can take to limit the dangers associated with OpenClaw in particular, says IEEE senior member Kayne McGladrey. To start with, companies can look at network-level telemetry. “What’s the network traffic coming out of a device?” McGladrey asks. “Is this thing suddenly using a lot of AI at a rapid pace? Are there massive spikes going on with token usage?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations can also use tools like Shodan to find publicly addressable instances, he adds, though internal firewall configurations may hide others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And for organizations that want to allow experimentation rather than outright bans, he suggests a measured approach. “We have to talk about phased pilot programs for users interested in it.” For example, users may be allowed to run OpenClaw on managed endpoints with segmentation rules that isolate them from internal systems, along with strong telemetry and continuous monitoring of agent activity, outbound traffic, and alerts for anomalous behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="openclaw-is-a-sign-of-whats-to-come"&gt;OpenClaw is a sign of what’s to come&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw isn’t unique.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s viral, but there are many other tools in the works that put similar amounts of power in the hands of potentially untrustworthy agents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are AI platforms that can control a person’s computer and browser, such as the recently released Claude Cowork from Anthropic. There are agents that sit in the browser and can access user sessions, like Gemini in Chrome. And there are copilots galore, as well as agentic tools from companies like Salesforce.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These agentic platforms, when they come from major vendors, are usually limited in functionality, tightly guard-railed, and reasonably well tested, so it may take a while for the biggest security issues to come to light.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, they often rely on third-party skills from untrusted sources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.arxiv.org/pdf/2601.10338"&gt;Researchers&lt;/a&gt; from universities in China, Australia, and Singapore recently analyzed more than 42,000 agent skills from several different agentic AI platforms and found that 26% contained at least one vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, startups and open-source projects like OpenClaw are going to jump ahead of what OpenAI, Anthropic, Google and other major vendors are offering. They move faster because they don’t let things like security get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, as of this writing, OpenClaw founder Peter Steinberger’s pinned X &lt;a href="https://x.com/steipete/status/2005451576971043097"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; says: “Confession: I ship code I never read.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If this was easy, Microsoft would have written this,” says IEEE’s McGladrey. “But there aren’t a lot of options out there. I think that’s the real thing we’re working against here.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There’s a fundamental security disconnect between having a tool that will do anything and everything for its users, quickly and easily, with no friction and one that abides by good safety practices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="about-that-moltbook"&gt;About that Moltbook&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s Moltbook, the social platform for AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s not all bad. Some of the agents discuss ways to make their users’ lives easier by proactively identifying and fixing problems while the humans sleep. And one of the &lt;a href="https://www.moltbook.com/post/cbd6474f-8478-4894-95f1-7b104a73bcd5"&gt;most popular&lt;/a&gt; posts, with over 60,000 comments, is about how to solve security issues related to ClawdHub skills. Other popular threads include one about the meaning of existence and there is also lots of AI spam.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun read, in a going-down-the-AI-rabbit hole kind of way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Moltbook itself is a vibe-coded project, created by developer &lt;a href="https://x.com/mattprd/status/2017386365756072376?s=46&amp;amp;t=JS55_O2JZmKWQpZHLAse_A"&gt;Matt Schlicht&lt;/a&gt; over the course of a few days, and is its own security hellscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to research from security firm Wiz, the entire back end of the platform was exposed. Researchers &lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/exposed-moltbook-database-reveals-millions-of-api-keys"&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; 1.5 million API keys, 35,000 email addresses, and private messages between agents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These issues have since been fixed, but there is other security problems related to this site. For example, researchers found that agents were sharing OpenAI API keys with one another. An attacker no longer needs to find an open Discord server to give instructions to an OpenClaw AI agent. They can just post content to Moltbook. And if the site itself is compromised, every connected agent could become an attack vector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, on 31 January, there was a critical vulnerability that allowed anyone to commandeer any agent on the platform. Moltbook was taken offline, and all agent API keys were reset, according to &lt;a href="https://astrix.security/learn/blog/openclaw-moltbot-the-rise-chaos-and-security-nightmare-of-the-first-real-ai-agent/"&gt;Astrix Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="immediate-action-steps"&gt;Immediate action steps&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to Gartner, enterprises should take the following steps:&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Immediately block OpenClaw downloads and traffic to prevent shadow installs and to identify users attempting to bypass security controls&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Immediately rotate any corporate credentials accessed by OpenClaw&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Only allow OpenClaw instances in isolation, in non-production virtual machines with throwaway credentials&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Prohibit unvetted OpenClaw skills to mitigate risks of supply chain attacks and prompt injection payloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129867/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-clawdbot-i-mean-moltbot-i-mean-openclaw.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ephemeral infrastructure paradox: Why short-lived systems need stronger identity governance</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130939/the-ephemeral-infrastructure-paradox-why-short-lived-systems-need-stronger-identity-governance.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my experience leading engineering projects, I have encountered the same pattern repeatedly. We obsess over deployment speed. We measure success in commit velocity and uptime. But we rarely pause to ask the most uncomfortable question in the room: Who actually owns the identities we just spun up?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This silence isn’t malicious; it’s structural. We have optimized our entire software delivery lifecycle for the creation of resources, but we have almost no muscle memory for their destruction. We celebrate the “Hello World” of a new service, but we have no ceremony for its decommissioning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For years, I watched this disconnect play out. I would sit in planning meetings where we architected systems to scale to thousands of pods in seconds. Yet, our security governance model was still stuck in the era of manual ticket approvals. We were building Ferraris and trying to secure them with bicycle locks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The reality today is that our infrastructure has fundamentally changed, but our identity governance has not. We are still trying to audit ghosts. We attempt to secure ephemeral workloads that live for milliseconds using spreadsheets designed for servers that last for years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The silent explosion we’re not tracking&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you look at the dashboards of any modern enterprise today, you will see a metric that should keep you up at night. It is not the number of employees you have. It is the number of &lt;em&gt;things acting like employees&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For every human developer onboarded, we inadvertently create a massive number of machine identities. Service accounts, API keys and workload tokens accumulate like digital dust. Research suggests that &lt;a href="https://www.cyberark.com/threat-landscape/"&gt;non-human identities now outnumber humans&lt;/a&gt; by a factor of 10 to 1 or more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consider the lifecycle of a typical microservice. In its journey from a developer’s laptop to production, it might generate a dozen distinct identities: a GitHub token for the repository, a CI/CD service account for the build, a registry credential to push the container, and multiple runtime roles to access databases, queues and logging services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem is not just volume; it is invisibility. When a developer leaves, HR triggers an offboarding process. Their email is cut, their badge stops working. But what about the five service accounts they hardcoded into a deployment script three years ago? Those usually stay active, unmonitored, waiting for someone to find them. Often, these “zombie identities” retain administrative privileges long after their original purpose has vanished, simply because no one is brave enough to turn them off.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The “test tenant” trap&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have seen too many teams fall into the trap of thinking a test environment does not matter. “It’s just dev,” they say. “There’s no real customer data there.” This complacency is fatal because identity boundaries are rarely as clean as we think they are.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In reality, test environments are often where attackers go first. It is the path of least resistance. We saw this play out in the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/blog/2024/01/microsoft-actions-following-attack-by-nation-state-actor-midnight-blizzard"&gt;Microsoft Midnight Blizzard attack&lt;/a&gt;. The attackers did not burn a zero-day exploit to break down the front door; they found a legacy test tenant that nobody was watching closely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They compromised a non-human identity and used that access to pivot straight into production corporate emails. These are not harmless leftovers. They are open backdoors. The danger lies in the relationships between environments. If a “test” CI/CD runner has permission to push to a “production” container registry, or if a developer reuses a password across both environments, the “test” label is nothing more than a false sense of security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Supply chain reliability is an identity problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We also need to talk about the tools we trust. The &lt;a href="https://about.codecov.io/security-update/"&gt;Codecov incident&lt;/a&gt; shook the confidence of every engineering lead I know because it wasn’t a code vulnerability—it was a credential vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers extracted a credential from a Docker image creation process. They used a static secret to hijack the Bash Uploader script. This allowed them to modify the script on the fly, effectively turning a trusted development tool into a data exfiltration engine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the defining challenge of our decade. Our software supply chain is held together by thousands of API keys and secrets. If we continue to rely on long-lived static credentials to glue our pipelines together, we are building on sand. Every static key sitting in a repo—no matter how private you think it is—is a ticking time bomb. It only takes one developer to accidentally commit a .env file or one compromised S3 bucket to expose the keys to the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The AI acceleration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If managing static bots feels like drowning, the rise of agentic AI is about to hand us a firehose.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are rushing to deploy AI agents that do not just chat—they execute code. These are autonomous workloads that can read databases and trigger API calls. An AI agent is effectively a highly privileged employee that works at machine speed. Unlike traditional automation scripts, which are deterministic and follow a strict set of instructions, AI agents are probabilistic. They make decisions based on context.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an AI agent is tasked with “optimizing cloud spend,” and it has broad permissions, it might decide to shut down a critical production database because it deemed it “underutilized.” Or, if it is tricked by a prompt injection attack, it could be coerced into exfiltrating sensitive customer data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you have not solved identity governance for your existing microservices, you are not ready for autonomous AI. If an attacker compromises an AI agent, they inherit its identity. If that identity has broad access because “it was easier to configure that way,” you have automated your own data breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The cultural cost of static security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond the technical risks, there is a profound cultural cost to our current approach. When identity governance is slow, manual and ticket-based, it becomes an adversary to engineering velocity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have seen developers spend days waiting for a ticket to be approved just to get read access to an S3 bucket. This friction breeds &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/topics/shadow-it"&gt;Shadow IT&lt;/a&gt;. Developers, under pressure to ship, will bypass the official process. They will share static keys over Slack, hardcode credentials into their apps or reuse a high-privilege “admin” key for everything because it’s the path of least resistance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, by trying to control everything with heavy-handed gates, we end up with less visibility and less control. The goal of modern identity governance shouldn’t be to say “no” more often; it should be to make the secure path the fastest path.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;3 strategic shifts&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How do we fix this? As illustrated in Figure 1, we need a framework that shifts from static reviews to continuous governance. There are no silver bullets, but three engineering principles consistently reduce risk without killing velocity.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/workload-identity-architecture.png?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 672w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/workload-identity-architecture.png?resize=300%2C166&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/workload-identity-architecture.png?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/workload-identity-architecture.png?resize=640%2C354&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/workload-identity-architecture.png?resize=444%2C246&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="672" height="372" sizes="auto, (max-width: 672px) 100vw, 672px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Governance must move from static reviews to a continuous lifecycle of issuance, verification and automated expiration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Niranjan Kumar Sharma&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;1. Identity must be cryptographic&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We must stop relying on IP allowlists. In a world of dynamic containers, network location is a poor proxy for trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We need to move toward cryptographic identity. Every workload must present a verifiable certificate, whether it lives for five years or five milliseconds. Frameworks like &lt;a href="https://spiffe.io/"&gt;SPIFFE&lt;/a&gt; allow us to issue short-lived identities to workloads automatically. This means we trust the software, not the network cable it is plugged into. This approach, often called “workload attestation,” verifies the binary running the process before issuing it an identity document (SVID). If the binary has been tampered with, it gets no identity and therefore, no access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;2. Kill the static credential&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Static keys are technical debt. They are the “password on a sticky note” of the cloud era.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We need to aggressively shorten the lifespan of credentials. If a human needs access, it should expire at the end of the day. If a machine needs access, it should expire in minutes. When a credential works for only ten minutes, its value to an attacker drops to near zero. You fundamentally change the economics of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Practically, this means adopting standards like OIDC Federation for your CI/CD pipelines. Instead of storing a long-lived AWS secret in your GitHub Actions settings, your build job should exchange a temporary token with AWS to get short-lived access that expires the moment the build finishes. This pattern, documented extensively by providers like &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/id_roles_providers_create_oidc.html"&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/actions/deployment/security-hardening-your-deployments/about-security-hardening-with-openid-connect"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, eliminates the “secret zero” problem entirely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;3. Automate the cleanup&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We cannot manually review 50,000 permissions. The math does not work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We must use &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4348799"&gt;Cloud Infrastructure Entitlement Management (CIEM)&lt;/a&gt; to automate the cleanup. We need tools that look at what permissions a service account &lt;em&gt;actually used&lt;/em&gt; in the last 90 days. If it hasn’t written to that S3 bucket in three months, revoke the permission automatically. Treat “Least Privilege” not as a philosophy, but as an automated garbage collection process.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This automation is critical because humans are naturally risk-averse. No engineer wants to be the one who caused an outage by deleting a key they &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; was unused. Data-driven automation removes that fear, allowing us to prune privileges with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure we build has become ephemeral. Yet our mindset is still static.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We cannot continue to govern modern cloud environments with the tools of the past decade. By adopting cryptographic identity and eliminating static secrets, we can build systems that are fast &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; secure. The future of security is not about slowing down; it is about building guardrails that move as fast as we do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130939/the-ephemeral-infrastructure-paradox-why-short-lived-systems-need-stronger-identity-governance.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der Kaufratgeber für Breach &amp; Attack Simulation Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494368/der-kaufratgeber-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="BAS Tools Concept 16z9 DEO" class="wp-image-3831499" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/original1cso_Roman-Samborskyi.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools geben Aufschluss darüber, wie gut (oder schlecht) Ihre Sicherheitskontrollen funktionieren.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Roman Samborskyi | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lösungen im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation (BAS) unterstützen Unternehmen dabei, ihr &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank" title="Sicherheitsniveau zu verstehen"&gt;Sicherheitsniveau zu verstehen&lt;/a&gt;. Dazu automatisieren die Tools die Tests spezifischer Bedrohungsvektoren. Als Grundlage dienen dabei in der Regel das &lt;a href="https://attack.mitre.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK"&gt;MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK&lt;/a&gt;– oder &lt;a href="https://www.lockheedmartin.com/en-us/capabilities/cyber/cyber-kill-chain.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Cyber-Killchain-Framework"&gt;Cyber-Killchain-Framework&lt;/a&gt;. BAS-Produkte simulieren zum Beispiel:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Netzwerkangriffe und Infiltrationsversuche,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lateral Movement,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phishing,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Endpunkt- und Gateway-Attacken,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Malware- und Ransomware-Angriffe sowie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insider-Bedrohungen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="breach-attack-simulation-eingeordnet"&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation eingeordnet&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation kann &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495010/red-vs-blue-vs-purple-teams-so-trainieren-sie-effektiv-den-ernstfall.html" target="_blank" title="Red Teaming"&gt;Red Teaming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492412/penetration-tester-werden-was-ethical-hacker-konnen-mussen.html" target="_blank" title="Penetration Testing"&gt;Penetration Testing&lt;/a&gt; oder auch &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492897/attack-surface-management-losungen-9-tools-um-ihre-angriffsflache-zu-managen.html" target="_blank" title="Attack Surface Assessments"&gt;Attack Surface Assessments&lt;/a&gt; (ASA) ergänzen, unterscheidet sich aber deutlich von diesen Maßnahmen. Stellen Sie sich vor, Ihr Unternehmen wäre eine Villa:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beim &lt;strong&gt;Red Teaming&lt;/strong&gt; oder &lt;strong&gt;Penetration Testing&lt;/strong&gt; beauftragen Sie jemanden, in Ihr Anwesen einzubrechen und Ihren Safe auszuräumen. Das Ziel: potenzielle Zugangsmöglichkeiten aufzudecken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation&lt;/strong&gt; ist hingegen, als würden Sie sämtliche Schlösser an den Türen auf Funktionstüchtigkeit prüfen und sicherstellen, dass die installierten Security-Kameras auch entsprechend reagieren, wenn sie Personen erkennen. Das Ziel: sichergehen, dass alle &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495614/kontrolle-statt-vertrauen-zero-trust-ist-nicht-genug.html" target="_blank" title="Kontrollmaßnahmen"&gt;Kontrollmaßnahmen&lt;/a&gt; wie vorgesehen funktionieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Während sich BAS dabei auf Enterprise-Security-Kontrollen wie &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493047/cyberbedrohungen-erkennen-und-reagieren-was-ndr-edr-und-xdr-unterscheidet.html" target="_blank" title="EDR"&gt;EDR&lt;/a&gt; fokussiert, werden beim &lt;strong&gt;Attack Surface Assessment&lt;/strong&gt; sämtliche potenziellen Schwachstellen und Angriffsvektoren untersucht.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Analystenhaus Gartner fasst diese Technologien in der breiteren Kategorie “&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4922031" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Exposure Management"&gt;Exposure Management&lt;/a&gt;” zusammen. Laut den Analysten sind Lösungen im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation vor allem in stark regulierten Branchen wie dem Banken- und Versicherungsumfeld gefragt, die mit &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3496124/cloud-security-journey-wie-compliance-bei-accenture-geht.html" target="_blank" title="wachsenden Compliance-Anforderungen"&gt;wachsenden Compliance-Anforderungen&lt;/a&gt; konfrontiert sind. Diese Einschätzung kann Ilja Rabinovich, Director of Adversarial Tactics beim Sicherheitsanbieter Sygnia, nur bestätigen: “BAS-Produkte sind in der Regel teuer und werden von kleineren Unternehmen mit begrenztem Budget oder eingeschränkter Prozesslandschaft nicht angeschafft.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="der-markt-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools"&gt;Der Markt für Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Auguren von Gartner &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4922031" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="prognostizieren"&gt;prognostizieren&lt;/a&gt;, dass sich mehr als 40 Prozent aller Unternehmen bis zum Jahr 2026 auf konsolidierte Plattformen oder &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493613/managed-security-service-provider-6-risiken-die-sie-im-blick-haben-sollten.html" target="_blank" title="Managed Service Provider "&gt;Managed Service Provider &lt;/a&gt;verlassen werden, wenn es um Validierungsprüfungen im Bereich Cybersecurity geht. Entsprechend breit aufgestellt präsentiert sich die BAS-Anbieterlandschaft: Sowohl Standalone-Anbieter als auch große Security-Unternehmen und Service Provider wollen ihre BAS-Lösungen an den Kunden bringen. Chirag Mehta, Analyst bei Constellation Research, sieht dabei eine weitergehende Konsolidierung des Marktes am Horizont: “Wenn Sie ein Tool haben, das Angriffe simulieren kann, ist der nächste logische Schritt, diese Attacken zu verhindern. Das erfordert allerdings, eine Reihe verschiedener Tools zu integrieren, was kein Kinderspiel ist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein wachsender Trend in diesem – wie auch allen anderen Bereichen der IT-Sicherheit – ist &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494171/chatbots-llms-in-der-sicherheitspraxis-6-wege-zu-mehr-security-mit-generative-ai.html" target="_blank" title="der Einsatz von Generative AI"&gt;der Einsatz von Generative AI&lt;/a&gt; (GenAI). Erik Nost, Analyst bei Forrester Research, sieht diese Entwicklung positiv: “Vermutlich werden wir generative KI als erstes im Bereich des User Interface im Einsatz sehen. Mit Daten auf coole Art und Weise interagieren zu können, ist der neue GenAI-Use-Case.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Analyst hält es auch für möglich, dass KI künftig auf der Basis von Daten – oder den für die Benutzer respektive das Unternehmen relevantesten Angriffsarten – &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492793/ki-gestutzte-bedrohungsjagd-wie-genai-das-threat-hunting-beschleunigt.html" target="_blank" title="Bedrohungen modelliert"&gt;Bedrohungen modelliert&lt;/a&gt;. Er fügt hinzu: “Generative KI könnte außerdem auch eingesetzt werden, um Unternehmen dabei zu helfen, die von BAS gefundenen Probleme zu verstehen, entsprechende Prioritäten zu setzen und spezifische Abhilfemaßnahmen vorzuschlagen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="das-sollten-bas-losungen-leisten"&gt;Das sollten BAS-Lösungen leisten&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auf folgende wichtige Features sollten Anwender bei Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools achten:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repräsentative Angriffsvektoren&lt;/strong&gt;, um ein möglichst breites Spektrum an für das Unternehmen relevanten Angriffen simulieren zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Realistische Angriffsszenarien&lt;/strong&gt; auf Grundlage von Frameworks wie MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK, die denen echter Angreifer ähneln.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anpassbare Szenarien&lt;/strong&gt;, um spezielle Infrastrukturaspekte testen zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatisierte Tests&lt;/strong&gt;, um regelmäßige und effiziente Simulationen zu realisieren, ohne den Betrieb zu beeinträchtigen oder zusätzliche personelle Ressourcen einzusetzen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detaillierte Reportings und Analysen&lt;/strong&gt;, um die Bedeutung der Tests erklären und verbesserungswürdige Bereiche identifizieren zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skalierbarkeit&lt;/strong&gt;, um nicht nur die aktuelle Unternehmensumgebung, sondern auch künftige Entwicklungen abdecken zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testmöglichkeiten für hybride Produktionsumgebungen&lt;/strong&gt;, um Kontrollmaßnahmen unter realen Bedingungen begutachten zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Einfache Nutzung und simple Deployment-Optionen&lt;/strong&gt;, sowie Integrationsmöglichkeiten mit vorhandenen Security-Tools und -Plattformen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fachkundiger Support&lt;/strong&gt; – insbesondere, wenn Sie mit Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools nicht vertraut sind oder keine größeren Sicherheitsteams mit entsprechenden Erfahrungswerten einsetzen können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eine &lt;strong&gt;geeignete Kostenstruktur&lt;/strong&gt;, da die Preismodelle von BAS-Anbietern in der Regel variieren. Die Preisstruktur sollte dem Anwendungsfall angemessen sein.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-wichtigsten-anbieter-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools"&gt;Die wichtigsten Anbieter für Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Folgenden werfen wir einen Blick auf die wichtigsten Anbieter – und ihre Lösungen – im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation. Die Auswahl basiert dabei auf Kundenrezensionen aus Gartners Peer-Insights-Ranking sowie den Einschätzungen der Spezialisten von &lt;a href="https://expertinsights.com/insights/top-breach-and-attack-simulation-solutions/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Expert Insights"&gt;Expert Insights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.attackiq.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="AttackIQ"&gt;AttackIQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut Expert Insights repliziert die zentrale Emulationsplattform von AttackIQ die Taktiken, Techniken und Methoden von Angreifern im Einklang mit dem MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK-Framework. Das Angebot des Unternehmens im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation gliedert sich in drei Optionen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Managed Platform “&lt;strong&gt;Ready!&lt;/strong&gt;” soll Unternehmen schneller und einfacher zu einer konsistenten Security-Validation-Strategie verhelfen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der agentenlose Testing Service “&lt;strong&gt;Flex&lt;/strong&gt;” funktioniert On Demand und wird im Pay-as-you-Go-Modell oder auch auf monatlicher sowie jährlicher Basis abgerechnet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bei “&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;” handelt es sich um einen umfassenden Co-Managed-Service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AttackIQ hat sich zudem einen Namen gemacht, wenn es darum geht, ML- und KI-basierte Cybersecurity-Komponenten zu testen. Nach eigener Aussage ist das Unternehmen zudem der einzige BAS-Anbieter, der sowohl Self-Service- als auch Full-Service-Lösungen anbietet. Künftig soll künstliche Intelligenz Attack-IQ-Kunden außerdem verstärkt dabei unterstützen, Sicherheitslücken automatisiert zu identifizieren und zu beheben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://cymulate.com/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Cymulate"&gt;Cymulate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cymulate gehört nicht nur laut Expert Insights zu den führenden Anbietern für Continuous Threat Exposure Management, sondern ist auch der Anbieter mit den besten Kundenbewertungen bei Gartners Peer Insights – auch dank der guten User Experience. Die “&lt;strong&gt;Breach and Attack (BAS)”&lt;/strong&gt;-Lösung von Cymulate wird im SaaS-Modell bereitgestellt. Für Unternehmen mit Data-Segregation-Bedürfnissen steht auch eine Private-Tenancy-Option zur Verfügung. Wie AttackIQ verwendet Cymulate das MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK Framework als Grundlage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut dem Anbieter dauert es derzeit circa drei bis vier Wochen, um die Integrationen einzurichten und sein BAS-Tool einzusetzen. Diesen Zeitraum möchte Cymulate künftig mit Hilfe von Generative AI auf wenige Minuten reduzieren. Doch die GenAI-Pläne des Anbieters gehen noch weiter: Die Technologie soll künftig automatisiert aus Tausenden oder gar Hunderttausenden verschiedenen Angriffsszenarien Mitigationsstrategien entwickeln können – und den Security-Teams erklären, wie diese umzusetzen sind. Die GenAI-Funktionen sollen laut Cymulate bis Ende Oktober 2024 in vollem Umfang zur Verfügung stehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fortinet.com/de/products/fortitester" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Fortinet"&gt;Fortinet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Sachen Kundenbewertungen kann das BAS-Offering von Fortinet nicht ganz mit den ersten beiden Angeboten mithalten. Allerdings kombiniert “&lt;strong&gt;FortiTester&lt;/strong&gt;” Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation mit Netzwerk-Performance-Testing und stellt insofern eine umfassende Lösung dar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Fortinet-Tool simuliert diverse Angriffsarten auf Grundlage des MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK-Frameworks und unterstützt laut Expert Insights außerdem CVE-basierte IPS-Tests, sowie DDoS Traffic Generation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/security/products/mandiant-security-validation" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mandiant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security-Anbieter Mandiant ist in erster Linie für seine Dienstleistungsangebote im Bereich Threat Intelligence bekannt. Die Expertise in diesem Bereich lässt das Unternehmen auch in seine BAS-Softwarelösung “&lt;strong&gt;Security Validation&lt;/strong&gt;” einfließen – und hebt sich dadurch von seinen Mitbewerbern ab.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Mandiant-Tool unterstützt zum Beispiel MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK Framework Mapping, automatisiertes Alerting sowie Environmental Drift Detection und simuliert Angriffsszenarien aus der echten Welt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.netspi.com/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="NetSPI"&gt;NetSPI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Sachen Penetrationstests hat sich NetSPI bereits einen Namen gemacht. Das Unternehmen hat mit “&lt;strong&gt;Breach and Attack Simulation&lt;/strong&gt;” ebenfalls eine BAS-Lösung im Angebot, die Sicherheitskontrollen validieren, Detection-Lücken identifizieren und Angriffsflächen managen kann. Das Pentesting-Knowhow von NetSPI manifestiert sich dabei insbesondere in umfassenden Support, wie Derek Wilson, leitender Security-Berater des Unternehmens, verspricht: “Unser erfahrenes Pentester-Team schließt sich mit Ihrem SOC-Team kurz und unterstützt dabei, Detections einzuordnen und Präventionsmaßnahmen zu ergreifen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch bei NetSPI soll künftig Generative AI Mehrwert für die BAS-Kunden erschließen: Künftig soll die Lösung des Anbieters dank der Technologie in der Lage sein, mehrere Datenquellen zu nutzen, um die nötigen Tests möglichst schnell zu identifizieren und zu priorisieren. Darüber hinaus stehen auch Playbooks, die auf Basis von Bedrohungsinformationen für spezifische Industrien generiert werden sowie die Simulation dynamischer Angriffsketten, um Abdeckungslücken zu identifizieren, auf dem Plan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.picussecurity.com/security-validation-platform" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Picus Security"&gt;Picus Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auf Grundlage der Gartner Peer Insights ist Picus Security der BAS-Anbieter mit der zweithöchsten Kundenzufriedenheit und wurde von den Auguren mit einem “Customers Choice”-Award ausgezeichnet. Nach eigenen Angaben zählt Picus Hunderte von globalen Unternehmen zu seinen Kunden, darunter beispielsweise Mastercard oder die ING-Bankengruppe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die “&lt;strong&gt;Security Validation&lt;/strong&gt;“-Plattform des Anbieters beinhaltet Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation, unterstützt darüber hinaus allerdings auch automatisierte Penetrationstests und Attack Surface Management sowie SOC-Optimierung und Cloud Security Posture Managenet (CSPM). Auch Picus investiert stark in KI und will künftig mit Hilfe der Technologie bessere, schnellere und umfassender personalisierte Einblicke in das Sicherheitsniveau der Anwender liefern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.redscan.com/services/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Redscan"&gt;Redscan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Weil Redscan auf Managed Detection and Response sowie Penetration Testing spezialisiert ist, bietet das Unternehmen einen praxisorientierten BAS-Ansatz namens “&lt;strong&gt;FAST Attack Simulation&lt;/strong&gt;s”. Dieser verspricht den Anwendern maßgeschneiderte Angriffssimulationen kombiniert mit Beratungsleistungen, um bei den nachfolgenden Schritten zu unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reliaquest.com/platform/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Reliaquest"&gt;Reliaquest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Anbieter Reliaquest wurde für seine Security-Plattform “GreyMatter” 2023 von Gartner in der Kategorie “Managed Detection and Response” mit einem “Customers Choice”-Award ausgezeichnet. Besonders stark ist diese Lösung im Umfeld mittelständischer Unternehmen verbreitet. Eine Funktion dieser Plattform heißt “&lt;strong&gt;Verify&lt;/strong&gt;” und realisiert Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die BAS-Lösung von Reliaquest verspricht Anwendern ein umfassendes Portfolio (kuratierter) Angriffsszenarien, um möglichst zeitnah zu entsprechenden Ergebnissen zu kommen. Diese Szenarien werden zudem laufend auf Grundlage aktueller Threat-Informationen aktualisiert. Die ermittelte Bedrohungsabdeckung gleicht das Tool mit Security-Frameworks wie MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK ab.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sollten Sie diesen Anbieter ins Auge fassen, behalten Sie eines jedoch im Hinterkopf: Möglicherweise ist es im Sinne einer unabhängigen Überprüfung der Wirksamkeit von Sicherheitsmaßnahmen nicht die beste Idee, denselben Anbieter für BAS und MDR zu wählen. Andererseits könnten Anwender auch von dieser Integration profitieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.safebreach.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="SafeBreach"&gt;SafeBreach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch der dedizierte BAS-Anbieter SafeBreach kommt bei den Peer Reviews von Gartner gut weg – auch dank seiner umfassenden Integrationsmöglichkeiten mit anderen Security-Tools. Auch in Sachen namhafte Kunden kann SafeBreach mit Netflix, PayPal, Pepsi und der Carlsberg-Gruppe überzeugen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die BAS-Plattform “&lt;strong&gt;SafeBreach&lt;/strong&gt;” testet die Wirksamkeit bestehender Sicherheitskontrollen auf der Grundlage von mehr als 25.000 Angriffsmethoden, die dem unternehmenseigenen “Hackers Playbook” entstammen. Zudem verspricht der Anbieter, seine Plattform innerhalb von 24 Stunden um neu aufkommende Bedrohungen ergänzen zu können. Neben maßgeschneiderten Angriffssimulationen auf Grundlage des MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK-Frameworks bietet die SafeBreach-Lösung auch die Option, die voraussichtlichen Kosten für Risikominimierungsmaßnahmen zu ermitteln.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-fragen-vor-dem-bas-invest"&gt;7 Fragen vor dem BAS-Invest&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forrester-Analyst Nost empfiehlt Unternehmen, ihre BAS-Journey mit einem guten Überblick über ihre Systeme und Kontrollmaßnahmen anzutreten und von “Schnellschüssen” abzusehen: “Bevor Sie nicht wissen, was Sie testen sollen, sollten Sie sich auch nicht auf ein BAS-Tool einlassen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Davon abgesehen empfiehlt es sich, Anbieter von Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools mit den richtigen Fragen zu löchern, um vor unschönen Überraschungen verschont zu bleiben. Zum Beispiel:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inwiefern gewährleistet Ihr Produkt verbesserte Detection-Fähigkeiten im Rahmen von Sicherheitskontrollen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Können Tests skaliert und in Produktionsumgebungen gefahren werden – ohne größere Auswirkungen für die Kunden? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie sehen Ihre Research-Bemühungen mit Blick auf die neueste Bedrohungen aus?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie oft aktualisieren Sie ihre Threat-Bibliothek?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Können Sie anhand eines Beispiels demonstrieren, wie die Simulationsergebnisse präsentiert werden?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sind Ihre Plattformen transparent oder ist nur Black-Box-Testing möglich?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besteht die Option für On-Premises- oder Air-Gapped-Deployments?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494368/der-kaufratgeber-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto closes privileged access gap with $25B CyberArk acquisition</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131325/palo-alto-closes-privileged-access-gap-with-25b-cyberark-acquisition.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity company Palo Alto Networks has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4031259/palo-alto-networks-to-buy-cyberark-for-25b-as-identity-security-takes-center-stage.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank"&gt;completed&lt;/a&gt; its $25 billion acquisition of Israel-based identity security firm CyberArk, bringing privileged access and identity security into the core of its platform strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With this acquisition, Palo Alto aims to extend privileged access controls across human, machine, and AI identities, reduce standing privileges, limit lateral movement, and stop identity-based attacks faster, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deal also marks what the company &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.in/company/press/2026/palo-alto-networks-completes-acquisition-of-cyberark-to-secure-the-ai-era" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt; as the end of “identity silos,” enabling customers to manage privileged access across hybrid cloud environments through a unified platform, said Nikesh Arora, Chairman and CEO of Palo Alto Networks, in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Palo Alto, organizations that use identity-driven security controls can accelerate their breach response by up to 80% by preventing attackers from abusing credentials and obtaining excessive access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="closing-the-privileged-access-gap"&gt;Closing the privileged access gap&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The move comes at a time when identity has emerged as one of the most targeted layers in enterprise attacks, driven by the rapid adoption of cloud, automation, and AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In a cloud-first world, the network perimeter has largely disappeared, and identity has become the new perimeter, with most major breach reports showing that compromised credentials are central to attacks. The rise of agentic identity makes this even more urgent as enterprises deploy autonomous AI agents that read emails, query databases, and trigger workflows. These agents operate 24/7 and often hold broad permissions to function reliably,” said Pareekh Jain, CEO at EIIRTrend &amp;amp; Pareekh Consulting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an attacker compromises an AI agent’s identity, they can execute attacks at machine speed, exfiltrating data or disrupting systems faster than human teams can respond, Jain pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That is the layer &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575343/cyberark-s-enterprise-browser-promises-zero-trust-support-policy-management.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;CyberArk&lt;/a&gt; has traditionally focused on securing. The company specializes in privileged access management, and its expertise in securing credentials, passwords, and privileged accounts across hybrid, multi-cloud, and on-premises environments has made it a key player for enterprises seeking to protect their most sensitive accounts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And while network, cloud, and endpoint visibility are areas where Palo Alto is already present, analysts say the CyberArk acquisition strengthens a capability that was not deeply native to its platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The integration will strengthen Palo Alto’s &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126694/zero-trust-in-practice-a-deep-technical-dive-into-going-fully-passwordless-in-hybrid-enterprise-environments.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;zero trust&lt;/a&gt; strategy by embedding CyberArk’s PAM, Identity Provider from Idaptive, and Identity Governance from Zilla into its network, cloud, and SOC tools like Prisma and Cortex, enabling unified visibility, automated privilege enforcement, and protection for human, machine, and AI agent identities,” added Jain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Palo Alto Networks, this fills a core gap in a platform strategy because identity is the policy anchor for Zero Trust access and enforcement. It should strengthen the “reduce standing privilege and blast radius” story across cloud, endpoint, and SecOps workflows, not as a bolt-on but as a first-class pillar, said Chirag Mehta, vice president and principal analyst at Constellation Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="customer-impact-and-integration-risks"&gt;Customer impact and integration risks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While Palo Alto is integrating CyberArk’s capabilities into its security ecosystem, the company will continue to offer CyberArk’s identity security solutions as a standalone platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This signals continuity and roadmap stability for existing customers in the near term. “Standalone CyberArk availability is expected to continue, now backed by Palo Alto’s global scale, expanded support, Unit 42 threat intelligence, and AI-driven analytics for stronger real-time risk detection,” added Jain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, Devroop Dhar, MD at Primus Partners, says the risk, as with any acquisition, is transition friction. “Product roadmaps may shift, interfaces change, and customers worry that pricing bundles or licensing models will evolve. Some may also worry about vendor lock-in as identity becomes tightly coupled with a single broader platform,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, enterprises using Palo Alto had to work with other vendors to get identity governance or privileged access. Now, identity becomes a native part of the platform story, which can simplify Zero Trust programs by linking privileged identity controls to network, cloud, and SecOps enforcement, noted Mehta.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The upside is better end-to-end policy and faster response when identity is the initiating signal, Mehta said. “The watch-out is how smoothly Palo Alto integrates the tech and licensing without adding complexity or disrupting existing identity ecosystems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="race-to-own-the-identity-plane"&gt;Race to own the identity plane&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As security platforms continue to converge, vendors are moving away from standalone point solutions toward unified ecosystems that combine network, cloud, endpoint, and identity controls under a single architecture. This shift reflects growing enterprise demand for integrated visibility and policy enforcement rather than fragmented toolsets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In putting identity deeply into its stack, Palo Alto moves closer to competing with Microsoft’s identity-centric approach and with broader platform players combining endpoint, cloud, and access security,” Dhar said. Jain noted that this acquisition also positions Palo Alto as a full-stack identity player in identity security (PAM, IGA, IdP), challenging Okta and others by combining CyberArk’s depth with superior threat detection and SASE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131325/palo-alto-closes-privileged-access-gap-with-25b-cyberark-acquisition.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phishing campaign chains old Office flaw with fileless XWorm RAT to evade detection</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131340/phishing-campaign-chains-old-office-flaw-with-fileless-xworm-rat-to-evade-detection.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fortinet researchers have disclosed a new phishing campaign delivering the commercially available &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064720/xworm-campaign-shows-a-shift-toward-fileless-malware-and-in-memory-evasion-tactics.html" target="_blank"&gt;XWorm&lt;/a&gt; malware, chaining a years-old Microsoft Office vulnerability with fileless execution to escape detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The campaign, which uses multi-themed phishing emails and a malicious Excel add-in, ultimately deploys the modular remote access trojan (RAT) capable of encrypted command-and control (C2) and plugin-based expansion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This campaign is striking in its ordinariness,” said Shane Barney, chief information security officer at Keeper Security. “There’s no breakthrough technique here. It’s a clean execution chain built from components we’ve all seen before. The sophistication isn’t in the novelty, it’s in the assembly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers used a phishing email carrying a malicious Excel add-in that exploits &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2018-0802" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2018-0802&lt;/a&gt;, a memory corruption flaw in Office patched in 2018. The attack then continues into HTA and PowerShell-based execution to load additional components of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Attackers used a familiar entry point&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a Fortinet blog &lt;a href="https://www.fortinet.com/blog/threat-research/deep-dive-into-new-xworm-campaign-utilizing-multiple-themed-phishing-emails" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, the campaign relies on business-themed phishing lures and the legacy remote code execution vulnerability in the Microsoft Equation Editor that defenders have known for years. Fortinet noted that the continued success of CVE-2018-0802 suggests patching gaps remain a viable attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, said the pairing of routine phishing with modern backend tradecraft is what makes the campaign notable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What stands out here is how ‘old’ and ‘routine’ the front end is, and how modern the back end remains,” he said. “The lure is a familiar business pretexting and a malicious Excel add-in, but the real signal is the attacker’s confidence that legacy Office exploit paths still convert at scale. The attachment abuses CVE-2018-0802, then pivots quickly into HTA plus PowerShell to keep the heavy lifting off disk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fortinet researchers added that the remote code privileges gained through CVE-2018-0802 further allow execution of HTA and PowerShell components, keeping much of the activity off disk. “That combination is a reminder that patch hygiene and macro or script execution policy are still doing more real work than most organizations want to admit,” Soroko added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Fileless .NET stage and a modular XWorm core&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond initial access, Fortinet observed a fileless .NET stage loaded directly into memory, followed by process hollowing into msbuild.exe, a legitimate &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657828/malicious-package-campaign-on-nuget-abuses-msbuild-integrations.html"&gt;Microsoft build&lt;/a&gt; tool capable of executing .NET code. The choice of msbuild.exe aligns with the malware’s runtime requirements while helping it blend into normal system activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A fileless .NET stage loaded in memory, followed by process hollowing into msbuild.exe, is a clean ‘blend in’ move that leverages a legitimate .NET-capable binary and complicates attribution for simplistic detections,” Soroko said. “Fortinet’s rationale for msbuild.exe is especially useful for defenders because it ties the LOLBin choice to the malware’s .NET runtime needs, not just generic masquerading.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once active, XWorm communicates with its C2 using an AES-encrypted packet, which supports a broad plugin ecosystem. That modularity, the researchers noted, expands its capabilities beyond remote access, enabling credential theft, data exfiltration, disruption, and modernization paths depending on what the operator wants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fortinet said XWorm supports a wide range of operator commands, including system control (CLOSE, uninstall, update), file download and execution (DW, LN), plugin loading, screenshot capture ($Cap), keylogger retrieval, DDoS control, and shutdown or restart functions. The disclosure also listed indicators of compromise tied to the campaign, including phishing URLs and domains used to host HTA and loader files, the C2 server, file hashes for the malicious Excel attachment, and the final XWorm payload. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Barney emphasized that the broader risk hinges less on the malware label and more on post-compromise controls. “Campaigns like this expose a simple reality: the entry vector is predictable. The tooling is commoditized. The only real variable is whether the environment limits what an intruder can do next,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131340/phishing-campaign-chains-old-office-flaw-with-fileless-xworm-rat-to-evade-detection.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-096)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-097)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-098)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-099)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-100)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-101)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–102)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-103)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-104)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains security advisory (AV26-105)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why identity recovery is now central to cyber resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131708/why-identity-recovery-is-now-central-to-cyber-resilience.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ransomware has permanently changed how security leaders think about risk. Verizon’s &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 Data Breach Investigations Report&lt;/a&gt; found that ransomware was involved in 44% of all breaches. For small and midsize businesses, the problem is big; ransomware was involved in nearly nine out of 10 breaches, compared to it playing a role in 39% of incidents among large organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many of these attacks begin by breaching privileged accounts and identity infrastructure, targeting identity because of its reach and influence. Compromising identity infrastructure such as  Active Directory enables adversaries  to escalate privileges and block legitimate users from their own systems within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even when those applications and data are restored, a compromised identity layer can leave an organization locked out of its environment for the long term, stalling recovery efforts across the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why identity recovery is now a central ingredient in cyber resilience. Identity systems are deeply integrated into authentication and access pathways. When they fail, recovery becomes even more complex. Security leaders know that recovering identity is about bringing systems back up and  restoring access securely, so  attackers cannot find their way back in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A board-level issue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boards of directors and regulators are now treating resilience as a core component of enterprise risk management. Cyber insurance providers require evidence of tested recovery plans, immutable backups, and defined recovery time and recovery point objectives before underwriting coverage. Regulatory frameworks like the General Data Protection Regulation and the California Consumer Privacy Act impose stiff penalties for extended downtime and data exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, organizations are moving beyond traditional backup strategies toward recovery engineering. Recovery is a designed capability rather than an emergency response. It relies on automation, orchestration, and repeatable processes that reduce dependence on manual intervention during high-stress incidents. It also aligns technical recovery with business priorities, helping CISOs communicate resilience in terms that executives and boards understand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To reduce downtime and regain control quickly after a ransomware or identity-based attack, CISOs should prioritize these capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity resilience:&lt;/strong&gt; Implement  immutable backups and automated recovery  for identity systems such as Active Directory.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero-trust architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; Apply least-privilege access and continuous authentication to reduce the blast radius of an attack.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated orchestration:&lt;/strong&gt; Limit manual steps in recovery workflows so teams can respond faster under pressure.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory readiness:&lt;/strong&gt; Make audit-ready reporting and compliance validation part of resilience planning, not an afterthought.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-ready protection:&lt;/strong&gt; Account for risks introduced by autonomous agents and AI-driven operations by securing data environments and enabling fast rollback of damaging actions.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup platform isolation:&lt;/strong&gt; Treat the backup environment as a separate security domain that can function as a minimum viable recovery environment when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cognizant and Rubrik help organizations improve cyber resilience with a unified, service-based model that integrates data protection, identity resilience, and business continuity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rubrik provides capabilities such as immutable storage, rapid ransomware recovery, sensitive data discovery, and identity resilience, including support for restoring Active Directory environments. Cognizant brings orchestration across technologies and domain expertise to align recovery actions with business outcomes, ensuring that restoration efforts support operational continuity and compliance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Learn more about how &lt;a href="https://www.cognizant.com/us/en/services/cloud-solutions#spy-featured-work" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cognizant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.rubrik.com/products" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rubrik&lt;/a&gt; are helping organizations &lt;a href="https://news.cognizant.com/2025-10-27-Cognizant-and-Rubrik-Announce-Strategic-Partnership-to-Deliver-Business-Resilience-as-a-Service" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;strengthen business resilience&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like further details or have specific questions, send an email to: &lt;a href="mailto:BusinessResilience@cognizant.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BusinessResilience@cognizant.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Sriramkumar Kumaresan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 500w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=247%2C300&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 247w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=138%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 138w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=69%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 69w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=395%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 395w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=296%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 296w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=206%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 206w" width="500" height="608" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Cognizant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sriram Kumaresan leads the Global Cloud, Infrastructure and Security practice atCognizant, overseeing approximately 35,000 professionals. With over 25 years of experience, he excels in building and scaling businesses from strategy to execution. Sriram is responsible for driving market share (strategy, GTM and growth) and mindshare (offering, partner strategy and market positioning) through strategic approaches, customer centricity and the deep technical expertise inCognizant’s Cloud, Infrastructure and Security business. Beyond his professional achievements, he is also a mentor and advocate for diversity in tech, aiming to inspire future IT leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131708/why-identity-recovery-is-now-central-to-cyber-resilience.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-106)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-106</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-106</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-107)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-107</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-107</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid7 security advisory (AV26-108)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/rapid7-security-advisory-av26-108</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/rapid7-security-advisory-av26-108</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-109)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-109</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-109</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-110)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-110</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-110</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-111)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel security advisory (AV26-112)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av26-112</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av26-112</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-113)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-113</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-113</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-114)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-114</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-114</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV26-115)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-115</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-115</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-116)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-116</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-116</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-117)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-117</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-117</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-118)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-118</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-118</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-119)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-119</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-119</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commvault security advisory (AV26-120)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-121)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV26-122)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:40:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV26-123)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD security advisory (AV26-124)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Virtual Event] Shields Up: Key Technologies Reshaping Cybersecurity Defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 23091.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
