<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:23:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-620)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-620</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-620</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-621)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-621</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-621</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-622)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-622</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-622</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foxit security advisory (AV25-623)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/foxit-security-advisory-av25-623</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/foxit-security-advisory-av25-623</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 18:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISOs rethink the security organization for the AI era</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066733/cisos-rethink-the-security-organization-for-the-ai-era.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ever-changing cybersecurity landscape has long kept CISOs on their toes and now AI is bringing new challenges in how security teams operate and innovate. In some cases, the technology is even changing how they are perceived.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI capabilities are increasingly being used in cybersecurity programs, according to &lt;a href="https://www.deloitte.com/us/en/services/consulting/articles/future-of-cyber-survey-2024.html"&gt;Deloitte’s Future of Cyber Survey&lt;/a&gt; of US cyber decision-makers, with 43% of respondents using AI in their cybersecurity programs to a large extent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is helping CISOs gain more influence among an increasingly cyber-savvy C-suite: Almost one-third of respondents noted CISO involvement in strategic conversations about tech investment, the Deloitte survey says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, the change is gradual, stresses &lt;a href="https://www.plantemoran.com/get-to-know/people/joe-oleksak"&gt;Joe Oleksak&lt;/a&gt;, a partner at Plante Moran, an accounting and wealth management consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“After almost 30 years of cybersecurity consulting, I can say with confidence that AI hasn’t revolutionized security organizations — but it is gradually reshaping how they operate,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The biggest change Oleksak has seen is the growing realization that speed has become the defining factor. Security teams cannot take their foot off the pedal though and think that AI is a magic bullet, he contends.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI accelerates everything, both attacks and defenses, which means the fundamentals matter more than ever,” Oleksak says. “Provisioning, permissions, network segmentation, even what information is stored in shared folders must be closely managed, because AI magnifies every mistake.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where discipline comes in. “Organizations that have invested in security over time are seeing efficiencies by layering AI-driven tools into their workflows,” Oleksak says. “But those who haven’t taken security seriously are still stuck with the same exposures they’ve always had. AI doesn’t magically catch them up.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, because attackers are &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4014238/cybercriminals-take-malicious-ai-to-the-next-level.html"&gt;using AI to make phishing, scanning, and deepfakes cheaper and faster&lt;/a&gt;, Oleksak adds, the gap between mature and unprepared organizations is widening.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here is a look at how CISOs are re-examining their security organizations to keep up with the pace and potential of AI as the technology becomes a more frequent part of their strategies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="shifting-c-suite-dynamics"&gt;Shifting C-suite dynamics&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/deneendefiore/"&gt;Deneen DeFiore&lt;/a&gt;, vice president and CISO at United Airlines, says that unequivocally AI has changed the nature of her relationship with the rest of the C-suite.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI has elevated cybersecurity into a strategic business conversation. I’m working more closely with other executives to ensure security is built into AI initiatives from the start,” she says. “It’s no longer just about protecting infrastructure — it’s about enabling innovation safely, building trust, and helping the business move faster with confidence.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The shift has also occurred, she says, because of the airline’s commitment to responsible AI. “We’re focused on deploying AI ethically and transparently, with cybersecurity playing a central role in ensuring accountability, fairness, and resilience. This shared responsibility across the C-suite is reshaping how we lead and how we innovate.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-full"&gt;&lt;img alt="Deneen DeFiore stylized" class="wp-image-507651" src="https://legacy-us-images.foundryco.app/images/idge/imported/imageapi/2023/05/25/10/deneen-defiore-stylized_1600x900px-100941429-orig.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all" width="400px" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;United Airlines&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Much of this shift has to do with organizations having already seen what happens when security is treated as an afterthought, Oleksak notes. This occurred across the industry during the rollout of the internet in the 1990s, and Oleksak believes AI can follow the same pattern if C-suite dynamics don’t change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We cannot afford to repeat those mistakes,” he says. “For AI to be deployed responsibly, the CISO must be at the center of strategy and execution. A security-first approach, led by the CISO, and sponsored by executive management, is the only way to ensure AI strengthens rather than undermines the enterprise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="reshaping-cyber-it-collaboration"&gt;Reshaping cyber-IT collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The advent of AI has also changed how IT works with the security organization, shifting the focus from reactive security to proactive, strategic collaboration, DeFiore says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’re now embedding cybersecurity into AI initiatives from the start, working closely across teams to ensure innovation is both safe and ethical,” she stresses. “Our commitment to responsible AI means every solution is designed with transparency, fairness, and accountability in mind.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasonlander/"&gt;Jason Lander&lt;/a&gt;, senior vice president of product management at Aya Healthcare, who manages security for the organization, is also seeing a change in the dynamics between cybersecurity and IT.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI is noticeably reshaping how security and IT departments collaborate, streamline workflows, blend responsibilities, make decisions and redefine trust dynamics,” he says. “Our IT operations have become more intelligent and proactive. Our security team is gaining operational support and better visibility.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While Plante Moran’s Oleksak doesn’t believe AI has significantly changed how most security organizations work with IT, the technology has begun to shift expectations incrementally, he’s seen. “IT teams increasingly assume security can move faster because AI accelerates analysis and detection, and boards are starting to see the CISO as a more strategic role,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Oleksak doesn’t think there is enough recognition that the CISO brings a fundamentally different perspective than IT.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“IT’s focus is on speed, efficiency, and enabling the business, while the CISO’s focus is on protecting the business. That distinction is often misunderstood,” he maintains. “As AI introduces powerful new risks, from deepfakes and AI-driven phishing to employees unintentionally exposing sensitive IP through AI queries, only the CISO is positioned to anticipate and mitigate these threats.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jillknesek/"&gt;Jill Knesek&lt;/a&gt;, CISO of BlackLine, reports to the financial software company’s CIO. As she sees it the teams have always worked closely, but AI has taken that relationship to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Now, we have to be aligned on everything we do,” says Knesek, who was previously an FBI agent in the Cyber Crimes Squad and CISO of Mattel. This is because AI tools add risk and allow for opportunities, she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="transforming-the-nature-of-work"&gt;Transforming the nature of work&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is enabling various improvements at Aya Healthcare, including the ability to streamline and automate repetitive tasks, Lander says, thereby evolving how security work gets done.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI tools help retrieve data faster and expedite decision-making, which frees up team members’ time to focus on more strategic challenges,” he says. “We continue to upskill and train employees on new AI processes and tools, streamline systems integrations, identify immediate threat detection quicker, improve processes, and ensure a greater focus on overall security, and data governance and access.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;United Airline’s DeFiore echoes that, saying AI now handles the noise by triaging alerts, surfacing anomalies, and automating repetitive tasks. This enables her security team to focus on strategic analysis, threat modeling, and resilience planning. “It’s made our operations faster, more focused, and more impactful.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lander says AI has even reshaped his daily work by placing an emphasis on process automation, prompting him to reassess past organizational choices and enhance strategic priorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It requires a deeper knowledge in governance and risk, aligning AI capabilities with business objectives and balancing innovation with risk management,” he explains. “All of the investments we’re making at Aya are 100% mission-driven. Our innovative technologies ensure hospitals and healthcare facilities have the very best clinician when and where they’re needed most, while giving them time to focus on what’s most-important: patient care.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;BlackLine’s Knesek is zeroing in on her security operations team as the biggest use case for AI because it requires a lot of overhead. Blackline has its own 24/7 security operations, and Knesek plans to put some security operations engineers in the company’s India office to get better coverage overnight and on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That’s one area where we’re going to leverage the AI capability so we don’t have to hire as many people to provide that level of coverage across the globe,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The adoption of AI tools at Plante Moran “reflects a simple reality: The best way to combat AI-enabled threats is often with AI-enabled defenses,” Oleksak says. But as with all cybersecurity initiatives, technology is only one part of the solution, he points out. A sound defense begins with training and culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’ve made a deliberate effort to educate all employees on both the capabilities and the risks of AI, so they understand why our security protocols and policies matter,” Oleksak says. “We don’t want employees to fear AI — it’s software, and like all software it has vulnerabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Like United Airline’s DeFiore, Oleksak says that what matters is how responsibly AI is used. AI tools can help employees move faster, but people need to remember the basics.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For example, with deepfake voice farming now able to mimic executives, simple ‘old-school’ security practices like confirming instructions by phone are more important than ever,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even though AI hasn’t changed the size or structure of security teams at the consultancy, it has changed the focus of their work: less on repetitive triage, more on judgment, communication, and reinforcing a culture of security, Oleksak says. “It’s made training, culture, and old-fashioned good judgment more important than ever.”&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="making-cybersecurity-a-more-expansive-effort"&gt;Making cybersecurity a more expansive effort&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the complexities AI has introduced is the need to validate the technology and service providers’ own cybersecurity preparedness and processes — which has become a more expansive effort due to AI, Oleksak says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Deepfakes present enterprises with very real dangers, and they will only grow more prevalent,” he explains. “We are no exception and implemented redundant, often manual protocols to address these risks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Aya Healthcare’s Lander, AI has introduced a host of new opportunities his teams are looking at. “We’re rethinking and redefining sensitive data. We’re also adopting better detection models and practices for distinguishing between human- and bot-generated behavior,” he says, adding that security professionals are also monitoring and planning for increased risk of security leaks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At United Airlines, teams are being reorganized “to bring together threat analysts, engineers, and data scientists in more agile, collaborative pods,” DeFiore says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’re hiring selectively for AI and machine learning expertise, but we’re also investing in our existing talent — training them to understand how AI works, how to validate models, and how to use these tools responsibly,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="feeling-the-pressure-to-work-fast"&gt;Feeling the pressure to work fast&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Knesek remains concerned about AI’s unknowns, yet she says companies are pushing security teams to quickly build out new capabilities so they can say they have AI embedded in their products. Security and IT are “kind of the transportation team to lay the roads and guardrails so things don’t spin out of control,” she says. “We’re working at breakneck speed in some areas and the reality is, we don’t know exactly what the threats are. So, we’re trying to make sure that we’ve got the strongest rules in place.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Jill Knesek, CISO, BlackLine" class="wp-image-4066740" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/jill-knesek-stylized-1600x900px.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jill Knesek, CISO, BlackLine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;BlackLine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Echoing Oleksak, Knesek says she feels strongly about utilizing traditional security and having the right controls in place. Getting foundational security right will get you a long way, she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Then, as you learn about more sophisticated attacks … we’ll have to pivot our tooling and capabilities to those risks.” For now, “the most important thing for us is just to stay aligned with where the business is driving us very quickly [and] make sure today [security] is doing what it needs to do from a foundational standpoint,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="questioning-the-output"&gt;Questioning the output&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As organizations rethink their approach to security, Oleksak advises CISOs to not get “dazzled by the hype,” and remember that AI is not a strategy but a tool. “Treat it like any other technology investment,” he says. “Start with your risk priorities, then decide where AI can realistically help.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That means remembering AI magnifies strengths and weaknesses. “If your asset inventory is incomplete, if your IAM controls are loose, or if your patching cadence is poor, AI will not fix those problems; it will accelerate the mess,” Oleksak says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to take a cautious approach to deployment. He advises piloting AI tools in narrow use cases — such as for alert triage, log analysis, and phishing detection — and measuring outcomes. “Focus on augmenting human judgment, not replacing it,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams will also build trust through transparency. “Train your teams to question AI output and educate your executives and employees on both the benefits and risks,” Oleksak says. “The CISO’s job is not just to deploy AI tools, but to ensure the organization understands how they fit into the bigger security picture.”&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-coalitions"&gt;Building coalitions&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI should be used where it helps reduce risk, improve speed, or strengthen resilience, says DeFiore. “Build partnerships early — especially with legal, data, and operations teams,” she says. “Invest in education across the organization and stay grounded in ethics. AI decisions have real-world consequences, so organizations should use AI with care and consider potential accountability implications related to how it’s used.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While AI is a powerful tool, DeFiore says it’s people who make it meaningful. “At United, safety is our foundation. AI helps us deliver on that promise with more precision and agility — but it’s the human judgment behind it that drives trust, impact and long-term value,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is not something to be feared, but its singular impact on security must be respected, says Oleksak.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lander emphasizes the need to recognize that AI isn’t just a new tool but also “a new domain that requires careful governance, thoughtful integration, strategic thinking, and continuous learning. By embedding security from day one, engaging cross-functional stakeholders, anticipating unique AI risks, and investing in people and adaptive frameworks, CISOs can guide their organizations to responsibly and confidently harness AI’s potential.” He recommends that CISOs should plan and prepare for the AI era by building coalitions, ensuring AI is not managed as a silo, but as a shared responsibility. “The next few years will require an open mind and a view that AI is like a new member of the team who makes everyone better,” Lander says. “The CISO of the future is not just securing systems, they’re securing AI-enabled business success.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066733/cisos-rethink-the-security-organization-for-the-ai-era.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 suspected human traffickers arrested in Albania and Colombia</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/17-suspected-human-traffickers-arrested-in-albania-and-colombia</link>
      <description>17 suspected human traffickers arrested in Albania and Colombia. The criminal network is believed to have sexually exploited over 50 victims in Albania and Croatia, trafficked from South America to Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/17-suspected-human-traffickers-arrested-in-albania-and-colombia</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol conference warns: cybercrime fight hinges on access to data</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</link>
      <description>Criminals are exploiting encryption, anonymisation and emerging technologies faster than regulators and law enforcement can respond – making access to data the decisive challenge in the fight against cybercrime. This was the warning sounded at Europol’s 4th Annual Cybercrime Conference this week.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s most innovative law enforcement projects honoured at Europol’s 2025 Excellence Awards</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-most-innovative-law-enforcement-projects-honoured-europol’s-2025-excellence-awards</link>
      <description>At the annual European Police Chiefs Convention (EPCC) in The Hague, Europol announced the winners of the 2025 Europol Excellence Awards in Innovation. These awards recognise outstanding projects that demonstrate how innovation can strengthen operational effectiveness, ethical policing, and cross-border cooperation in Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-most-innovative-law-enforcement-projects-honoured-europol’s-2025-excellence-awards</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luxury hybrid car thieves taken down in Belgium, Italy and Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</link>
      <description>A highly specialised organised crime network responsible for the theft of more than 100 luxury hybrid cars has been dismantled in an international operation led by the Italian Carabinieri with support from Europol and Eurojust. The estimated value of all stolen cars is of at least EUR 3 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-624)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-624</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-624</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-625)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-625</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-625</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-626)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-626</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-626</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–627)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-627</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-627</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-628)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-628</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-628</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-629)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-630)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step Into the Password Graveyard… If You Dare (and Join the Live Session)</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/10/step-into-password-graveyard-if-you.html</link>
      <description>Every year, weak passwords lead to millions in losses — and many of those breaches could have been stopped.
Attackers don’t need advanced tools; they just need one careless login.
For IT teams, that means endless resets, compliance struggles, and sleepless nights worrying about the next credential leak.
This Halloween, The Hacker News and Specops Software invite you to a live webinar: “</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2025/10/step-into-password-graveyard-if-you.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:38:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>51 children identified during international taskforce against child sexual exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/51-children-identified-during-international-taskforce-against-child-sexual-exploitation</link>
      <description>The experts participating in the task force analysed over 300 datasets depicting victims of child sexual exploitation (CSE). The analysts saw victims of both genders, from toddlers to teenagers, with a variety of ethnic backgrounds and of many different nationalities. Following the operation, national authorities were sent 213 leads for further investigation.Catherine De BolleEuropol Executive DirectorChild sexual abuse material may...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/51-children-identified-during-international-taskforce-against-child-sexual-exploitation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From crypto-enabled money laundering to online recruitment of minors: European Police Chiefs tackle criminal threats</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</link>
      <description>The annual event brought together the heads of national police organisations, customs administrations, representatives from the European Commission, and international partners to discuss the most pressing threats to security in Europe.Catherine De Bolle, Europol’s Executive Director, and Lene Steen, Deputy National Commissioner of the Danish Police, opened the conference. Keynote addresses were delivered by EU Commissioner for Internal Affairs and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Major blow to billion-euro glass eel trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>The latest iteration of Operation LAKE, which ran from October 2024 to June 2025, uncovered large-scale trafficking networks and disrupted the flow of live eels destined for illegal farms in Asia.The operation led to:16,131 inspections carried out across Europe26 arrests22 tonnes of glass eels seizedOrganised crime at the heart of traffickingInvestigations revealed that several organised crime groups were driving the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 arrests for smuggling over 600 migrants across the Western Balkans</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/4-arrests-for-smuggling-over-600-migrants-across-western-balkans</link>
      <description>A large investigation, involving law enforcement and judicial authorities from Bosnia and Herzegovina, Croatia and Slovenia, has led to the dismantling of criminal network smuggling migrants from Bosnia and Herzegovina to Croatia and towards other EU countries. The investigation into this network active across the Western Balkans route was conducted under Europol’s dedicated Operational Task Force (OTF). Further arrests already took place in previous operational actions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/4-arrests-for-smuggling-over-600-migrants-across-western-balkans</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfeit and substandard food worth EUR 95 million seized in global operation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</link>
      <description>Europol, OLAF, DG SANTE and 31 countries across Europe and beyond, together with food and beverage producers from the private sector, joined forces in the fourteenth edition of Operation OPSON. This yearly effort targets the criminals behind counterfeit and substandard food and beverages. Law enforcement, customs and food regulatory agencies seized 259 012 packages, 1 416 168 litres of beverages and 11 566 958 kilograms of food, including meat and seafood.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted four key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudo security advisory (AV25-631)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sudo-security-advisory-av25-631</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sudo-security-advisory-av25-631</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the CISO chair becoming a revolving door?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066101/is-the-ciso-chair-becoming-a-revolving-door.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISO tenures average three years these days, according to co-founder of cybersecurity recruitment firm Icebergs Tom Chapman and based on the candidates he has placed. In a profession where the stakes are sky-high and the fallout from a single mistake can be career-defining, it raises a critical question: are CISOs leaving faster than ever before, and why?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="fighting-the-three-year-itch"&gt;Fighting the three-year itch&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It does differ from industry to industry, according to Chapman who points out, for example, that a CISO at a startup, who most often wears multiple hats and oversees more than just security, tend to have a shorter stint of 18 months to two years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He says the reasons vary, but burnout is often a common denominator. “In the startup space, it is very fast paced,” Chapman says. “There’s also often not a lot of systems in place already for CISOs to work off, so they have to build from scratch, and usually not with the largest budgets in the world. Startups often go, ‘Oh, we can just hire one person to do everything’, and then we’ll be secure. But that’s obviously not the case.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By contrast, CISOs in larger organizations that have a few thousand employees globally, bigger budgets, and more resources tend to stay on longer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CISOs come into those organizations with a plan. Over two to three years they’ll implement their changes, hire people, set up new teams, and really build out security within the organization,” Chapman says. “But by year three … it reaches a stage of BAU and there’s none of that stuff that excites them … and they are looking around because they have achieved what they want to do. Then, they say they want to go and do that again for another organization.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the biggest organizations such as global investment banks, retailers, e-commerce companies, CISO tenures can extend further. “Those folks at the much larger firms have teams that are two or three hundred people strong. There’s a lot more going on, more responsibilities, so they tend to stay longer because there’s more to do,” Chapman says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="is-the-stress-worth-the-sacrifice"&gt;Is the stress worth the sacrifice?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For others in the CISO role, including Fullpath CISO Shahar Geiger Maor, the issue is less about boredom and more about the constant strain. “At any time there may be a breach. You live under the assumption that something is going to go wrong, and it’s very stressful,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geiger Maor also described the job as fundamentally adversarial, pointing out that beyond the technical risk that CISOs face, the soft skills needed in the role and company politics that CISOs often face can also weigh heavily.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A CISO is interacting with a lot of interfaces, and you need to have soft skills and communicate well with others. In many cases, you need to drive others to take action, and that’s super tedious. It’s very difficult to keep doing it over time,” Geiger Maor says. “In many cases, you’re in direct conflict with company goals and your goals. You’re like a salmon fish going upstream against everybody else. This makes it very difficult to keep a long tenure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even downtime is elusive. Geiger Maor says that even when he’s on vacation, he takes his laptop and never disconnects from the company’s Slack channels. “That’s so basic for me,” he says. “When you go on vacation you can’t really disconnect. You – or at least part of you – needs to be back at work at all times because something can go wrong. It’s difficult, but it’s part of the role.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="liability-risk-versus-reward"&gt;Liability risk versus reward&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That constant exposure to risk and blame is another reason some CISOs hesitate to take the role in the first place, according to Rona Spiegel, senior manager, security and trust, mergers and acquisitions at Autodesk and former cloud governance leader at Wells Fargo and Cisco.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The bad guys, especially now with AI and automation, they’re getting more sophisticated, and they only have to be right once, but the CISO has to be right all day every day. They only have to be wrong once, and they get blamed … you’re an operational cost centre no matter what because you’re not bringing in revenue, so if something goes wrong … all roads lead to the CISO,” Spiegel says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Spiegel highlights this is a residual risk that CISOs have long known about but are beginning to question, which is ultimately impacting on their tenure. A BlackFog &lt;a href="https://www.blackfog.com/personal-liability-cybersecurity-leaders/"&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; revealed that 70% of CISOs said that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3631759/personal-liability-sours-70-of-cisos-on-their-role.html"&gt;hearing &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3631759/personal-liability-sours-70-of-cisos-on-their-role.html"&gt;stories of CISOs&lt;/a&gt; being held personally liable for cybersecurity incidents has negatively affected their opinion of the role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What we do in cybersecurity is manage risk, so what CISOs do is share with the board, audit committee, the executive team, the likelihood and impact of an incident occurring and then recommend mitigating controls to offset that,” she says. “Then CISOs have to determine if the residual risk is something that they can accept because ultimately all the advice CISOs give is all forgotten when an incident occurs, even though it’s not intentional.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, as Chapman notes, CISOs also factor in whether their salary is sometimes worth the risky position they put themselves in. “In London in particular, salaries are good for CISOs but not compared to the US. And then you weigh up: is it really worth it? That comes down to the individual, their risk appetite, and what drives them,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="its-more-than-just-about-the-ciso-title"&gt;It’s more than just about the CISO title&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not everyone who leaves the CISO role does so because they are worn out though. For many, it’s a matter of fit, motivation, and career direction. “I don’t believe in being a CISO for too long in a single place, because you become dull, your instincts are not that sharp,” Geiger Maor says. “Leading under continuous threat keeps you sharper.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He also sees CISOs pivoting into related fields. “A career change can be that maybe you join a security vendor and be a salesperson or move into management roles. Others grow into larger CISO roles step by step. But I do see some colleagues that have just had enough. They’d rather earn less but live more.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chapman is also seeing a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3977845/the-rise-of-vciso-as-a-viable-cybersecurity-career-path.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;rise in fractional CISOs&lt;/a&gt;, brought in part-time to set up frameworks or oversee specific projects. “It really comes down to the individual,” he says. “Some want that top seat, speaking to the board, communicating risk. But I am also seeing some say, ‘It doesn’t have to be a CISO role.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Spiegel adds that for some, the secret is knowing when to move. “You need to get out when it’s not the right place to be. It’s just a matter of fit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-evolving-role-of-a-ciso"&gt;The evolving role of a CISO&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One trait that has emerged as a decisive factor in whether a CISO thrives or burns out in the role is communication. “It’s amazing how many clients tell me their biggest requirement is communication,” Chapman says. “Can this person communicate to the board, to other executives, to teams across the business? Communication is probably the number one trait they look for.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Spiegel argues that scars from incidents can be valuable. “Frankly, suffering a breach can be a badge of honour, and you learn a lot. If you’re hiring a CISO with a completely clean record, as far as you know, are they more experienced than those who have sat in the chair? Ultimately if you haven’t responded to a real incident, you’re not less valuable, but you’re not less valuable either of knowing how to respond.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the revolving door perception, Spiegel believes the profession is still maturing. “Working in this space, people are very supportive, and the competitive factor is relatively limited. People really want everyone and CISOs to be successful. We want to create some stability and standardisation around the space, so the industry, companies and customers we’re protecting know what they’re signing up for and can feel confident that it is a consistent and stable practice.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, are CISO tenures getting shorter? The answer is both yes and no. Across the board, CISOs face relentless responsibility, exposure to risk, and the sense that no amount of preparation can fully shield against blame. For some, that’s enough reason to walk away. For others, it’s fuel to take on the next challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066101/is-the-ciso-chair-becoming-a-revolving-door.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-632)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-632</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-632</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-633)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-633</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-633</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-634)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-634</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-634</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-635)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-635</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-635</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] SSL security advisory (AV25-636)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-ssl-security-advisory-av25-636</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-ssl-security-advisory-av25-636</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-637)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-637</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-637</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV25-638)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-638</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-638</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>it-sa 2025: Fast 1.000 Security-Anbieter am Start</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4068792/it-sa-2025-fast-1-000-security-anbieter-am-start.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Editorial Use ONly, Germany only, it-sa 2025, PK BSI, Bitkom, Teletrust, ECSO, 16:9" class="wp-image-4068796" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/IMG_3358_16-9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Weggefährten der it-sa auf der ersten Pressekonferenz (von links): Claudia Plattner, BSI-Präsidentin, Ralf Wintergerst, Präsident des Bitkom, Prof. Norbert Pohlmann, Vorsitzender des Bundesverbandes für IT-Sicherheit „TeleTrusT“ und Joanna Świątkowska von der European Cyber Security Organisation (ECSO).&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Horst Ellermann&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Seit Dienstag, 7. Oktober 2025, läuft die it-sa 2025. Zu Besucherzahlen äußert sich Thimo Holst, der Verantwortliche bei der Nürnberger Messe, noch vage: Er wird wohl am Veranstaltungsende (Donnerstagabend) einen neuen Rekord verkünden. Für die Aussteller lässt sich das jetzt schon sagen: 990 tummeln sich in den Nürnberger Hallen, 15 Prozent mehr als letztes Jahr.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Viele Vorschusslorbeeren lieferten vier Wegbegleiterinnen und -begleiter der it-sa bei der ersten Pressekonferenz: „Die it-sa zeigt, dass es viele Lösungen auch aus Deutschland gibt“, sagte Claudia Plattner, Präsidentin des Bundesamtes für Sicherheit in der Informationstechnik (BSI) anlässlich des dritten Messebesuchs ihrer Amtszeit: „Ich halte das für ein Wachstumsfeld, auf dem wir durchaus noch punkten können.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cyber-resilience-act-fur-deutschland"&gt;Cyber Resilience Act für Deutschland&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Plattner nutzte die erste Pressekonferenz der Messe auch dazu, eine echte News zu verbreiten (ganz so, wie es früher auf Messen immer gemacht wurde): Das BSI hat von der Europäischen Union den Auftrag erhalten, den Cyber Resillience Act in Deutschland umzusetzen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das heißt: Es kontrolliert in Zukunft, dass hierzulande nur solche Sicherheits-Produkte auf den Markt kommen, die tatsächlich halten, was sie versprechen. „Als Marktüberwachungsbehörde können wir sogar Bußgelder verhängen oder Produkte vom Markt nehmen“, erklärte Plattner. Das sei eine riesige Verantwortung.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-markt-wachst"&gt;Security-Markt wächst&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ralf Wintergerst, Präsident des Bitkom, betonte die Relevanz des Themas Sicherheit für seinen IT-Branchenverband: „Die Security-Anbieter sind 2024 um zehn Prozent gewachsen und werden dies 2025 um voraussichtlich elf Prozent tun.“ Zum Vergleich: Insgesamt sei der IT-Markt 2024 um fünf Prozent gewachsen – auf immerhin auch beachtliche 245 Milliarden Euro.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kehrseite der Medaille: Cyberkriminelle haben im letzten Jahr rund 290 Milliarden Euro Schäden verursacht, schätzen BSI und Bitkom. „Das sind zwei Prozent aller Unternehmensumsätze in Deutschland“, sagte Wintergerst: „Zwei Prozent, die nicht für Innovationen ausgegeben werden können.“ Oder anders formuliert: „Damit ist Cyber Security ein echter Business Case geworden“, deutete Wintergerst.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="forderung-nach-mehr-sicherheitsbudget"&gt;Forderung nach mehr Sicherheitsbudget&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Prof. Norbert Pohlmann, Vorsitzender des Bundesverbandes für IT-Sicherheit „TeleTrusT“, griff dieses Argument auf. „Mit gut elf Milliarden Euro in IT-Sicherheit investieren wir derzeit ein Achtzehntel dessen, was Cyberkriminelle an Schaden verursachen.“ Pohlmann forderte alle Unternehmenslenker dazu auf, einmal durchzurechnen, was eine Verdoppelung der Sicherheits-Ausgaben an Schadensbegrenzung in ihren Unternehmen bringen könne.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Joanna Świątkowska von der European Cyber Security Organisation (ECSO) lieferte eine letzte Vorschusslorbeere für die it-sa: Security-Startups bekämen in Nürnberg die Chance, sich heimische Märkte zu erobern. Professor Pohlmann hatte zuvor auf das Problem hingewiesen, dass wir es auf dem Security-Markt leider zu häufig mit Monopolisten zu tun haben – meist aus Amerika. Europäische Security-Startups hätten es schwer gegen diese Konkurrenz. 70 Prozent der Security-Startups in Europa würden es nicht in die zweite Finanzierungsrunde schaffen, mahnte Świątkowska.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die it-sa will dem mit der Verleihung des „Athene Startup Awards“ gegensteuern. 28 junge Security-Unternehmen haben sich auf den Preis beworben, der am Mittwoch, den 8. Oktober 2025, verliehen wird. (jd)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4068792/it-sa-2025-fast-1-000-security-anbieter-am-start.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-639)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-639</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-639</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle issues emergency patch for zero-day flaw exploited by Cl0p ransomware gang</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4068379/oracle-issues-emergency-patch-for-zero-day-flaw-exploited-by-cl0p-ransomware-gang.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s the bad news that many customers of Oracle E-Business Suite (EBS) have been dreading: reports of ransomware attacks targeting the software have turned out to be connected to a serious zero-day vulnerability that requires immediate patching.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first indications that something might be awry emerged last week from &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4067501/cl0p-linked-threat-actors-target-oracle-e-business-suite-in-extortion-campaign.html" target="_blank"&gt;Halcyon, Google’s Threat Intelligence Group (GTIG), and Mandiant&lt;/a&gt;, which issued alerts that one of the world’s most active extortion groups, &lt;a href="https://www.halcyon.ai/threat-group/cl0p" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cl0p&lt;/a&gt;, was probably behind recent email demands sent to Oracle customers running internet-facing EBS ERP portals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although there was some initial uncertainty about the scope, severity, and attribution of the attacks, these reports revealed worrying details, including unusually large ransom demands of up to $50 million backed by proof of compromise such as screenshots and file trees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are the Cl0p team. If you haven’t heard about us, you can Google about us on the Internet,” began one of the ransom notes, re-published by a &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/oracle-patches-ebs-zero-day-exploited-in-clop-data-theft-attacks/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;news site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The note went on to make the usual demand for payment, backed by threats to expose stolen data if ransom was not paid.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The worry was how the attackers were compromising victims. During 2025, Oracle has patched several important EBS security issues, including &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-30727" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-30727&lt;/a&gt; affecting the iSurvey Module, and &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-21541" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-21541&lt;/a&gt; affecting Admin Screens and Grants UI, neither known to have been exploited.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The flaw exploited as part of the latest attack remains in question. A blog last week by Oracle’s CSO, &lt;a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/authors/rob-duhart" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Duhart&lt;/a&gt;, indicated that multiple vulnerabilities from the &lt;a href="https://www.oracle.com/security-alerts/cpujul2025.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;July 2025 Oracle Critical Patch Update (CPU)&lt;/a&gt; might be involved. However, this was later updated to remove that reference.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A post by &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/charlescarmakal_oracle-security-alert-advisory-cve-2025-activity-7380595612443893760-JNd_/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Charles Carmakal of Mandiant&lt;/a&gt; still refers to multiple vulnerabilities, but the focus has now shifted to a new remote code execution (RCE) flaw, &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-61882" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-61882&lt;/a&gt;, as the main culprit. The fact that Oracle issued &lt;a href="https://www.oracle.com/security-alerts/alert-cve-2025-61882.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;an emergency patch&lt;/a&gt; for it during the weekend seems to confirm this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Initial access by Cl0p dates to August, which means that attackers have had plenty of time to steal large amounts of data. Extortion emails were sent to victims from September 29 onwards, but might not yet have reached all victims, Carmakal cautioned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Given the broad mass 0-day exploitation that has already occurred (and the n-day exploitation that will likely continue by other actors), irrespective of when the patch is applied, organizations should examine whether they were already compromised,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-alert-patch-now"&gt;Red alert: Patch now&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rated a ‘critical’ 9.8 on CVSS, CVE-2025-61882 is a vulnerability in the EBS BI Publisher Integration component of Oracle E-Business Suite affecting &lt;a href="https://www.oracle.com/security-alerts/alert-cve-2025-61882.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;versions 12.2.3 to 12.2.14&lt;/a&gt;, which is remotely exploitable without authentication.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Customers should apply the latest patch after first applying the &lt;a href="https://www.oracle.com/security-alerts/cpuoct2023.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;critical patch update from October 2023&lt;/a&gt; if they hadn’t already done so. Any versions of the software updated before October 4 should be considered at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Oracle strongly recommends that customers apply the updates provided by this Security Alert as soon as possible,” the company warned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Oracle also published a list of indicators of compromise (IoCs), including IP addresses, observed commands, and malware signatures, to aid in detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s likely that almost no one patched over the weekend. We’re waking up to a critical vulnerability with public exploit code and unpatched systems everywhere,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-knott-046939107/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Knott&lt;/a&gt;, principal security researcher at continuous security testing company, &lt;a href="https://watchtowr.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;watchTowr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We fully expect to see mass, indiscriminate exploitation from multiple groups within days. If you run Oracle EBS, this is your red alert. Patch immediately, hunt aggressively, and tighten your controls – fast.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zbyneksopuch/?originalSubdomain=cz" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zbyněk Sopuch&lt;/a&gt;, CTO of data security vendor, &lt;a href="https://www.safetica.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Safetica&lt;/a&gt;, enterprises should also note the evolving cyber criminal behavior signaled by recent ransomware attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The targeted systems-of-choice for thieves include ERP, finance, HR, and the typical points of entry are via admin credentials and third-party connectors, such as VPNs, middleware, and API service accounts, which tend to have open access privileges,” said Sopuch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He recommended that companies isolate critical applications as much as possible, while making protections such as multi-factor authentication (MFA) standard for admin logins and integration or API access points.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Conversely, give service and integration accounts minimum access or simple access-appropriate-to-role permissions, and routinely rotate keys,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero-day vulnerabilities seem to be particularly favored by Cl0p, with the 2023 attack against the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575481/clop-ransomware-gang-exploits-the-moveit-transfer-vulnerability-to-steal-data.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank"&gt;MOVEit file transfer customers&lt;/a&gt; exploiting CVE-2023-34362 a high-profile example. Other attacks with the same approach included those against Accellion in 2020, and SolarWinds in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The lesson is that organizations can detect incursions only if they are continuously monitoring all risk points in the attack surface, such as external access points and logins, said Sopuch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4068379/oracle-issues-emergency-patch-for-zero-day-flaw-exploited-by-cl0p-ransomware-gang.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security-KPIs und -KRIs: So messen Sie Cybersicherheit</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495619/security-kpis-und-kris-so-messen-sie-cybersicherheit.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cybersicherheit zu messen, ist kein Kinderspiel." src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3357513/1200x.jpg" title="Cybersicherheit zu messen, ist kein Kinderspiel." width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Cybersicherheit zu messen, ist kein Kinderspiel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Ultraskrip – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eine wichtige Säule jedes ausgereiften Cyberrisk-Programms ist die Fähigkeit, die Performance der IT-Security und registrierte Bedrohungen zu messen, zu analysieren und zu melden. Die Cybersecurity zu messen, ist allerdings kein leichtes Unterfangen: Einerseits, weil sich viele Führungskräfte ohne entsprechenden Background schwer tun, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3498091/verantwortung-ubernehmen-so-werden-chefs-zu-security-vorbildern.html" target="_blank" title="IT-Risiken zu verstehen"&gt;IT-Risiken zu verstehen&lt;/a&gt;. Andererseits verstricken sich Sicherheitsprofis auch zu oft in technische Details, die die Stakeholder verwirren und auf den falschen Weg führen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das ideale Szenario: Security-Experten messen und reporten die Cybersicherheit auf eine Art und Weise, die für Führungskräfte leicht verständlich und nützlich ist – was zu umsetzbaren Ergebnissen führt. Klingt gut? Dieser Artikel vermittelt Ihnen, wie Sie das anstellen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="messkategorien-der-it-sicherheit"&gt;Messkategorien der IT-Sicherheit&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die meisten &lt;a href="https://www.cio.de/a/so-identifizieren-sie-projektbeteiligte,3644693" target="_blank" title="Stakeholder"&gt;Stakeholder&lt;/a&gt; beschäftigen Fragen zu Risiken, Compliance oder Sicherheit. Diese lassen sich jedoch in der Regel nicht mit einem einzigen Datenpunkt beantworten. Doch es gibt eine Reihe von Dingen, die Security-Profis messen können, um auf die Fragen und Bedenken der Stakeholder einzugehen. Diese lassen sich (grob) in folgende Kategorien einordnen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kontrollen:&lt;/strong&gt; Maßnahmen, die ergriffen werden, um Bedrohungen abzuwehren und Risiken zu reduzieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assets:&lt;/strong&gt; Jeder Gegenstand, der für die Organisation einen Wert besitzt, beziehungsweise sich in ihrem Besitz befindet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerabilities:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495294/schwachstellen-managen-die-6-besten-vulnerability-management-tools.html" target="_blank" title="Schwachstellen"&gt;Schwachstellen&lt;/a&gt; in einem System, die ausgenutzt werden können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat Events:&lt;/strong&gt; Von einer Bedrohung ausgelöste Ereignisse, die Assets potenziell Schaden zufügen können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sicherheitsvorfälle:&lt;/strong&gt; Ereignisse, die “erfolgreich” Wirkung auf das Unternehmen entfaltet haben, etwa in Form von (System-)Ausfällen, Datenschutzverletzungen oder &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank" title="Cyberangriffen"&gt;Cyberangriffen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Kategorien lassen sich weiter nach verschiedenen Faktoren aufschlüsseln: Zahlen, Zeit oder Kosten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zahlen&lt;/strong&gt; könnten beispielsweise in Form des Prozentsatzes der ungepatchten Server gemessen werden. Eine weitere Möglichkeit: Sie messen die &lt;strong&gt;Zeit&lt;/strong&gt;, die benötigt wurde, um einen Sicherheitsvorfall zu identifizieren. Schließlich könnten &lt;strong&gt;Kosten&lt;/strong&gt; – zum Beispiel in Form von Wiederherstellungs- oder Ausfallkosten – Aufschluss über die finanziellen Auswirkungen von Security-Ereignissen geben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cybersicherheits-metriken-kpis-und-kris"&gt;Cybersicherheits-Metriken, -KPIs und -KRIs&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn Security-Profis oder -Entscheider an Business Teams berichten, sollten sie dazu möglichst relevante Messerwerte wählen. Dabei konzentrieren sich die meisten Sicherheitsteams auf Metriken, die Low-Level-Messungen bezüglich Assets, Schwachstellen und Threat Events abbilden. Auf Führungs- und Vorstandsebene sind hingegen vor allem &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2795253/die-wichtigste-security-kpi.html" target="_blank" title="KPIs"&gt;KPIs&lt;/a&gt; (Key Performance Indicators) und KRIs (Key Risk Indicators) entscheidend, weil diese dazu beitragen können, spezifische Fragen in Bezug auf IT-Risiko, -Status und -Vorbereitung zu beantworten. Beispielsweise: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sind wir sicher?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liefern die Sicherheitsinvestitionen dem Unternehmen Mehrwert?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erfüllen wir aus Sicherheitsperspektive alle regulatorischen Anforderungen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie gut sind wir auf Ransomware- oder Supply-Chain-Angriffe vorbereitet?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Deshalb sollten sich Security-Praktiker auch auf KPIs und KRIs konzentrieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio foundryde-block"&gt; &lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video"&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? Unser kostenloser Newsletter liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn btn-danger" href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;Jetzt CSO-Newsletter sichern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cybersecurity-messen-in-5-schritten"&gt;Cybersecurity messen in 5 Schritten&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Aufbau des richtigen Messrahmens ist ein schrittweiser, iterativer Prozess. Im Folgenden die fünf wichtigsten Schritte, um einen Security Measurement Cycle aufzubauen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Anforderungen definieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sprechen Sie mit relevanten Stakeholdern, um deren Bedürfnisse zu definieren und zu verstehen. Diese haben zu diesem Zeitpunkt möglicherweise noch kein umfassendes Verständnis über IT-Risiken – oder ihre eigenen Anforderungen. Deshalb ist für Security-Praktiker ein Bottom-Up-Ansatz empfehlenswert, bei dem sie selbst die Initiative ergreifen und Fragen zu stellen, um die Anforderungen definieren zu können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Key Indicators auswählen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sobald die Anforderungen der Stakeholder definiert sind, sollten Sicherheitsexperten diejenigen Key Indicators auswählen, die auf diese einzahlen. Dabei sollten die Stakeholder konsultiert und über die beabsichtigten, späteren Messungen informiert werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn die Stakeholder die Key Indicators kennen, können sie Maßnahmen ergreifen oder Entscheidungen treffen. Die Schlüsselindikatoren sollten auf hoher Ebene angesiedelt sein – und ihre Anzahl überschaubar bleiben. Das Ziel besteht schließlich darin, die Entscheidungsfindung zu erleichtern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Metriken identifizieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nachdem Ziele und Key Indicators festgelegt sind, gilt es für die Sicherheitsteams, die Low-Level-Messgrößen zu fokussieren, die dabei unterstützen, die Indikatoren zu reporten. Das kann – je nach Art des Indikators – bedeuten, dass Dutzende von Metriken aus den verschiedenen oben beschriebenen Messkategorien erforderlich sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Metriken sammeln und analysieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Da die Anforderungen nun feststehen, die Schlüsselindikatoren ausgewählt und die Messgrößen festgelegt sind, können die Praktiker nun damit beginnen, Daten auf dieser Grundlage zu sammeln und zu analysieren. Metriken dürfen dabei nur aus Daten abgeleitet werden, die akkurat, aktuell, relevant und vertrauenswürdig sind. Anderenfalls kann es zu Entscheidungen kommen, die schwerwiegende Folgen für die Sicherheitslage des Unternehmens nach sich ziehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es ist die Aufgabe der Security-Teams, Wege zu finden, Daten kontinuierlich zu sammeln (die meisten Messungen erfordern einen Überblick über Trends im Zeitverlauf) und den Prozess vorzugsweise so weit wie möglich zu automatisieren (ein manueller Prozess kann ermüdend und zeitaufwändig sein).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Key Indicators reporten&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Key Indicators müssen zeitnah an die Entscheidungsträger reported werden. Dabei sollten sich Security-Profis und Stakeholder auf einen zeitlichen Rhythmus einigen – ebenso wie über die Art der Berichterstattung: Sind Dashboards erforderlich oder reichen Powerpoint-Präsentationen aus? Die Schlüsselindikatoren sollten deutlich sichtbar und leicht verständlich sein, um zu Entscheidungen oder Maßnahmen zu führen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus ist es wichtig, nach jedem Berichtszyklus die Key Indicators zu überprüfen und sie (unter Einbeziehung der Stakeholder) neu zu bewerten. Haben sich die geschäftlichen Anforderungen tatsächlich geändert, müssen die Anforderungen erneut definiert und ein anderer Satz von Indikatoren und Messgrößen erarbeitet werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unternehmen, Stakeholder und Sicherheitsexperten sollten keine Angst vor Rückwärts- oder Vorwärtsschritten haben: Die Fähigkeit, nach einem schnellen Fail direkt weiterzumachen, zu improvisieren oder sich neu auszurichten sind entscheidende Fähigkeiten, wenn es darum geht, Cybersicherheit erfolgreich zu messen. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio foundryde-block"&gt; &lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video"&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.csoonline.com/article/3687733/measuring-cybersecurity-the-what-why-and-how.html" target="_blank" title="Dieser Beitrag basiert auf einem Artikel unserer US-Schwesterpublikation CSO Online."&gt;Dieser Beitrag basiert auf einem Artikel unserer US-Schwesterpublikation CSO Online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495619/security-kpis-und-kris-so-messen-sie-cybersicherheit.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous AI hacking and the future of cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069075/autonomous-ai-hacking-and-the-future-of-cybersecurity.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI agents are now hacking computers. They’re getting better at all phases of cyberattacks, faster than most of us expected. They can chain together different aspects of a cyber operation, and hack autonomously, at computer speeds and scale. This is going to change everything.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the summer, hackers proved the concept, industry institutionalized it, and criminals operationalized it. In June, AI company XBOW took the &lt;a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/news-ai-xbow-tops-hackerone-us-leaderboad"&gt;top spot&lt;/a&gt; on HackerOne’s US leaderboard after submitting over 1,000 new vulnerabilities in just a few months. In August, the seven teams competing in DARPA’s AI Cyber Challenge &lt;a href="https://www.darpa.mil/news/2025/aixcc-results"&gt;collectively found&lt;/a&gt; 54 new vulnerabilities in a target system, in four hours (of compute). Also in August, Google &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/08/04/google-says-its-ai-based-bug-hunter-found-20-security-vulnerabilities/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that its Big Sleep AI found dozens of new vulnerabilities in open-source projects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It gets worse. In July Ukraine’s CERT &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4025139/novel-malware-from-russias-apt28-prompts-llms-to-create-malicious-windows-commands.html"&gt;discovered&lt;/a&gt; a piece of Russian malware that used an LLM to automate the cyberattack process, generating both system reconnaissance and data theft commands in real-time. In August, Anthropic reported that they disrupted a threat actor that used Claude, Anthropic’s AI model, to &lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/detecting-countering-misuse-aug-2025"&gt;automate&lt;/a&gt; the entire cyberattack process. It was an impressive use of the AI, which performed network reconnaissance, penetrated networks, and harvested victims’ credentials. The AI was able to figure out which data to steal, how much money to extort out of the victims, and how to best write extortion emails.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another hacker used Claude to create and market his own ransomware, complete with “advanced evasion capabilities, encryption, and anti-recovery mechanisms.” And in September, Checkpoint &lt;a href="https://blog.checkpoint.com/executive-insights/hexstrike-ai-when-llms-meet-zero-day-exploitation/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; on hackers using HexStrike-AI to create autonomous agents that can scan, exploit, and persist inside target networks. Also in September, a research team &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.01835"&gt;showed&lt;/a&gt; how they can quickly and easily reproduce hundreds of vulnerabilities from public information. These tools are increasingly free for anyone to use. &lt;a href="https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/chinese-ai-villager-pen-testing/"&gt;Villager&lt;/a&gt;, a recently released AI pentesting tool from Chinese company Cyberspike, uses the Deepseek model to completely automate attack chains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is all well beyond AIs capabilities in 2016, at DARPA’s &lt;a href="https://www.darpa.mil/news/2016/cyber-grand-challenge-winners"&gt;Cyber Grand Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The annual Chinese AI hacking challenge, &lt;a href="https://www.schneier.com/essays/archives/2022/01/robot-hacking-games.html"&gt;Robot Hacking Games&lt;/a&gt;, might be on this level, but little is known outside of China.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tipping-point-on-the-horizon"&gt;Tipping point on the horizon&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI agents now rival and sometimes surpass even elite human hackers in sophistication. They automate operations at machine speed and global scale. The scope of their capabilities allows these AI agents to completely automate a criminal’s command to maximize profit, or structure advanced attacks to a government’s precise specifications, such as to avoid detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/09/20/ai-hacking-cybersecurity-cyberthreats/?pwapi_token=eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJyZWFzb24iOiJnaWZ0IiwibmJmIjoxNzU4MzQwODAwLCJpc3MiOiJzdWJzY3JpcHRpb25zIiwiZXhwIjoxNzU5NzIzMTk5LCJpYXQiOjE3NTgzNDA4MDAsImp0aSI6IjEzZGE1Njk0LTMxOTItNDdkNi1hNTU3LTRkOWEzNDI5ODM0OCIsInVybCI6Imh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS90ZWNobm9sb2d5LzIwMjUvMDkvMjAvYWktaGFja2luZy1jeWJlcnNlY3VyaXR5LWN5YmVydGhyZWF0cy8ifQ.N_h4ygZ86XPjbtpR253UIbbArH7e0Tu3tN0iapl5v2k"&gt;In this future&lt;/a&gt;, attack capabilities could accelerate beyond our individual and collective capability to handle. We have long taken it for granted that we have time to patch systems after vulnerabilities become known, or that withholding vulnerability details prevents attackers from exploiting them. This is &lt;a href="https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/ai-vulnerability-detection-patching-threats-mandiant-summit/760746/"&gt;no longer&lt;/a&gt; the case.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cyberattack/cyberdefense balance has long skewed towards the attackers; these developments threaten to &lt;a href="https://www.schneier.com/essays/archives/2018/03/artificial_intellige.html"&gt;tip the scales&lt;/a&gt; completely. We’re &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/the-era-of-ai-generated-ransomware-has-arrived/"&gt;potentially&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4048415/the-ai-powered-cyberattack-era-is-here.html"&gt;looking&lt;/a&gt; at a singularity event for cyber attackers. Key parts of the attack chain are becoming automated and integrated: persistence, obfuscation, command-and-control, and endpoint evasion. Vulnerability research could potentially be carried out during operations instead of months in advance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The most skilled will likely retain an edge for now. But AI agents don’t have to be better at a human task in order to be useful. They just have to excel in one of &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/will-ai-take-your-job-the-answer-could-hinge-on-the-4-ss-of-the-technologys-advantages-over-humans-258469"&gt;four dimensions&lt;/a&gt;: speed, scale, scope, or sophistication. But there is every indication that they will eventually excel at all four. By reducing the skill, cost, and time required to find and exploit flaws, AI can turn rare expertise into commodity capabilities and gives average criminals an outsized advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-ai-assisted-evolution-of-cyberdefense"&gt;The AI-assisted evolution of cyberdefense&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI technologies can benefit defenders as well. We don’t know how the different technologies of cyber-offense and cyber-defense will be amenable to AI enhancement, but we can extrapolate a possible series of overlapping developments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phrase One: The Transformation of the Vulnerability Researcher.&lt;/strong&gt; AI-based hacking benefits defenders as well as attackers. In this scenario, AI empowers defenders to do more. It simplifies capabilities, providing &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3632268/gen-ai-is-transforming-the-cyber-threat-landscape-by-democratizing-vulnerability-hunting.html"&gt;far more people the ability&lt;/a&gt; to perform previously complex tasks, and empowers researchers previously busy with these tasks to accelerate or move beyond them, freeing time to work on problems that require human creativity. History suggests a pattern. Reverse engineering was a laborious manual process until tools such as IDA Pro made the capability available to many. AI vulnerability discovery could follow a similar trajectory, evolving through scriptable interfaces, automated workflows, and automated research before reaching broad accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase Two: The Emergence of VulnOps.&lt;/strong&gt; Between research breakthroughs and enterprise adoption, a new discipline might emerge: VulnOps. Large research teams are already building operational pipelines around their tooling. Their evolution could mirror how DevOps professionalized software delivery. In this scenario, specialized research tools become developer products. These products may emerge as a SaaS platform, or some internal operational framework, or something entirely different. Think of it as AI-assisted vulnerability research available to everyone, at scale, repeatable, and integrated into enterprise operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase Three: The Disruption of the Enterprise Software Model.&lt;/strong&gt; If enterprises adopt AI-powered security the way they adopted continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD), several paths open up. AI vulnerability discovery could become a built-in stage in delivery pipelines. We can &lt;a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2024/11/ais-discovering-vulnerabilities.html"&gt;envision a world&lt;/a&gt; where AI vulnerability discovery becomes an integral part of the software development process, where vulnerabilities are automatically patched even before reaching production — a shift we might call continuous discovery/continuous repair (CD/CR). Third-party risk management (TPRM) offers a natural adoption route, lower-risk vendor testing, integration into procurement and certification gates, and a proving ground before wider rollout.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase Four: The Self-Healing Network.&lt;/strong&gt; If organizations can independently discover and patch vulnerabilities in running software, they will not have to wait for vendors to issue fixes. Building in-house research teams is costly, but AI agents could perform such discovery and generate patches for many kinds of code, including third-party and vendor products. Organizations may develop independent capabilities that create and deploy third-party patches on vendor timelines, extending the current trend of independent open-source patching. This would increase security, but having customers patch software without vendor approval raises questions about patch correctness, compatibility, liability, right-to-repair, and long-term vendor relationships.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These are all speculations. Maybe AI-enhanced cyberattacks won’t evolve the ways we fear. Maybe AI-enhanced cyberdefense will give us capabilities we can’t yet anticipate. What will surprise us most might not be the paths we can see, but the ones we can’t imagine yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069075/autonomous-ai-hacking-and-the-future-of-cybersecurity.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce AI agents set to assist enterprises with security and compliance</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069285/salesforce-ai-agents-set-to-assist-enterprises-with-security-and-compliance.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salesforce has announced two new AI agents operating on its Agentforce platform: one agent that monitors activity, detects anomalies, and accelerates investigations and remediations in the Salesforce Security Center; and one that streamlines compliance tasks in the Privacy Center.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The things that our customers are already doing today, we’re just helping them to do that more efficiently, effectively, more quickly,” says Marla Hay, Salesforce SVP of product management for security, privacy, and data protection. “And we’re helping them to really think about how they want to take on that agentic transformation in a way that feels secure, safe and compliant.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These two new agents access Salesforce security and compliance information and will soon expand to external data, such as feeds from a customer’s other security systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Our customers have security, privacy and compliance teams who aren’t necessarily Salesforce experts,” says Hay. “And Salesforce experts who are not necessarily security and compliance experts. We want to bridge those two things together.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salesforce has already announced a &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4066640/salesforce-trusted-ai-foundation-provides-scaffolding-for-the-agentic-enterprise.html"&gt;partnership with CrowdStrike&lt;/a&gt; as one example of such a capability. These partnerships are part of a move towards even more integrations that will extend agentic capabilities in the Salesforce Security Center via its AgentExchange marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="more-than-chatbots"&gt;More than chatbots&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The agents are more than just rebranded chatbots who only answer questions. The company says that they can detect events and then take relevant actions. “It is not waiting for a human to initiate the interaction — it is running independently,” Hay says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The security agent can analyze event logs to identify unauthorized or unusual actions, guide step-by-step incident response, and autonomously freeze users exhibiting suspicious behavior, according to Salesforce. The privacy agent scans Salesforce metadata and data privacy policies against regulatory frameworks like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562107/general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr-requirements-deadlines-and-facts.html"&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/565923/california-consumer-privacy-act-what-you-need-to-know-to-be-compliant.html"&gt;CCPA&lt;/a&gt; to surface sensitive data exposure and non-compliance risks and can autonomously re-classify sensitive data or implement right-to-be-forgotten policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Constellation Research analyst Chirag Mehta recommends that enterprises take a measured approach to their adoption of these agents instead of jumping straight into fully autonomous agents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They have an agentic workflow that runs behind the scenes,” he explains. “If someone logs in from, say, North Korea, it checks the systems accessed. And, say, they touched these five systems and it doesn’t seem right.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The agent would then alert a human security analyst about the event, provide all the context about what’s going on, and then present a remediation plan. “And you can accept the plan,” Mehta says. “Or you as a human, as a security analyst, can say, ‘I don’t agree with this plan.’ Or you might want to double-check before you execute on this plan.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the past the analyst would simply get an alert and then have to go and figure out who logged in, and what systems they have access to, and what else might be infected, and whether it’s even a real incident or a false positive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Machines are much better at sifting through all that, he says, as well as being much faster.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With security, every second, every minute counts,” Mehta says. “The negative impact amplifies. You don’t just have systems down, but the adversaries could get access to even more stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises that aren’t currently using the Security Center add-on should consider it, he says. And those who are, should enable the AI agent functionality. “Customers should absolutely use it,” he says. “See how useful it is, what the remediation plans looks like, then, once they build trust, they should start automating one thing at a time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-agentforce"&gt;Salesforce Agentforce&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agentforce is a relatively new platform but has already evolved at an extremely rapid pace. It was &lt;a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/press-releases/2024/09/12/agentforce-announcement/"&gt;first unveiled&lt;/a&gt; in September 2024, became generally available the following month, added testing and agent lifecycle management tools in November, announced integration with Slack and other platforms in December, added autonomous agents that can take action on their own this past March, and also launched an agent marketplace at the same time with more than 200 partners. Then Salesforce added native &lt;a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/press-releases/2025/06/23/agentforce-3-announcement/"&gt;MCP support&lt;/a&gt; in June as well as an array of new MCP integration partners including AWS, Box, Cisco, Google Cloud, IBM, Notion, PayPal and Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As of September, Salesforce said it had closed more than 12,500 new deals since Agentforce was launched.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Salesforce wants to be the agentic center of the universe,” says Peter Nebel, chief strategy officer at AllCloud, a cloud consultancy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the same month, a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4063044/vulnerability-in-salesforce-ai-could-be-tricked-into-leaking-crm-data.html"&gt;critical vulnerability in Salesforce’s Agentforce&lt;/a&gt; was disclosed. The vulnerability could trick the AI agent into leaking sensitive CRM data through indirect prompt injection. It has since been patched.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The basic security and compliance agents are available today. CrowdStrike integration is expected later this year. In early 2026, Salesforce will add autonomous threat detection and triaging, access to agents via Slack, and custom data compliance policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069285/salesforce-ai-agents-set-to-assist-enterprises-with-security-and-compliance.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-source monitor turns into an off-the-shelf attack beacon</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069515/open-source-monitor-turns-into-an-off-the-shelf-attack-beacon.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;China-affiliated hackers have quietly turned a once-benign open-source network monitoring tool into a remote access beacon.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to new findings from cybersecurity firm Huntress, the attackers used log poisoning and a web shell to install Nezha, a legitimate remote monitoring/management tool (RMM), as a foothold to deploy Ghost RAT for deeper persistence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To our knowledge, this is the first public reporting of Nezha being used to facilitate web compromises,” Huntress researchers Jai Minton, James Northey, and Alden Schmidt, said in a blog post shared with CSO ahead of its publication on Wednesday. “Analysis of the intrusion revealed the threat actor had likely compromised more than 100 victim machines.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The campaign, first detected in August 2025, primarily targeted victims from Taiwan, Japan, South Korea, and Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sneaking in through log poisoning&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The adversary’s entry began through an exposed “phpMyAdmin” interface that lacked authentication. A DNS change months earlier had inadvertently made it publicly accessible, the researchers &lt;a href="https://staging.huntress.com/blog/nezha-china-nexus-threat-actor-tool" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;added&lt;/a&gt;. Once inside, they switched the interface language to Simplified Chinese and immediately began issuing SQL commands via the query interface.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They then abused MariaDB’s general query logging, reconfiguring it to write logs into a .php file within the web directory. In effect, they turned the log file itself into a web shell: SQL queries containing PHP code were recorded and then executed when accessed via HTTP POST. The PHP code reflected a basic evaluation web shell, commonly referred to as the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572879/zero-day-flaw-in-atlassian-confluence-exploited-in-the-wild-since-may.html?utm=hybrid_search#:~:text=the-,China%20Chopper%20webshell,-to"&gt;China Chopper&lt;/a&gt; web shell.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This “Log Poisoning” technique allowed the attackers to hide the backdoor among normal traffic. After validating the shell, they switched to a different IP address, likely to compartmentalize their operations, and moved to issue commands via AntSword’s virtual terminal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AntSword is an open-source Chinese web shell management framework (essentially a graphical control panel) for hackers to manage compromised web servers. In this case, it worked as a command station to interact with the planted backdoor China Chopper.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Riding Nezha to Ghost RAT&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With the web shell in place, the attackers used AntSword to download two components: “live.exe” (the &lt;a href="https://github.com/nezhahq/nezha" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nezha&lt;/a&gt; agent) and a “config.yml” that pointed to the attacker-controlled domain. The Nezha agent connected back to a management server whose dashboard was running in Russian, presumably to throw off attribution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once Nezha was active, the attackers ran an interactive PowerShell session to create Windows Defender exclusions on key system folders. This allowed them to drop and run a Ghost RAT variant from  “C:\Windows\Cursors”. The RAT executable also installed a persistence mechanism and used a domain generation algorithm (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4055796/why-domain-based-attacks-will-continue-to-wreak-havoc.html?utm=hybrid_search#:~:text=domain%20generation%20algorithms%20(-,DGAs,-)%20to%20automatically%20create"&gt;DGA&lt;/a&gt;) for command &amp;amp; control (C2).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress’ analysis showed the Ghost RAT implant had a multi-stage loader, dynamic API resolution, and command blocks consistent with China-nexus APT activities. The team was able to contain the August 2025 incident before attackers could cause significant damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Fortunately, Huntress was able to isolate the system and remediate the incident by removing the web shell, Nezha agent, and malware before the attacker could carry out any further objectives,” the researchers added. Huntress published a set of indicators of compromise (IOCs) tied to the intrusion, including the file name and path for the web shell, Nezha agent, and the Ghost RAT Payload. This incident fits a broader 2025 pattern of threat actors abusing legitimate admin and monitoring tools for persistence on networks. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Symantec (Broadcom) &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4006743/fog-ransomware-gang-abuses-employee-monitoring-tool-in-unusual-multi-stage-attack.html"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; Fog ransomware operators using employee monitoring software Syteca alongside other open-source pen-testing tools like GC2 and Adaptix. Last month, researchers also &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4057785/cobaltstrikes-ai-native-successor-villager-makes-hacking-too-easy.html"&gt;flagged&lt;/a&gt; a red-teaming tool, “Villager,” from a shadowy Chinese firm that they said was ripe for hackers to abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069515/open-source-monitor-turns-into-an-off-the-shelf-attack-beacon.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory (AV25-640)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-641)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-641</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-641</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-642)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-642</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-642</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-643)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-643</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-643</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–644)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-644</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-644</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-645)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-645</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-645</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redis security advisory (AV25-646)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/redis-security-advisory-av25-646</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/redis-security-advisory-av25-646</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-013 – Vulnerability impacting Oracle E-Business Suite - CVE-2025-61882</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.06</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-647)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-648)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-649)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
