<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:17:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-013 – Vulnerability impacting Oracle E-Business Suite - CVE-2025-61882</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-647)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-648)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol welcomes the European Investment Bank to its secure information exchange network</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</link>
      <description>The European Investment Bank (EIB) has today joined Europol’s Secure Information Exchange Network Application (SIENA), marking a new step in the cooperation between the two institutions to protect the EU’s financial interests and combat serious crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-649)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coming AI regulations have IT leaders worried about hefty compliance fines</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4072396</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More than seven in 10 IT leaders are worried about their organizations’ ability to keep up with regulatory requirements as they deploy generative AI, with many concerned about a potential patchwork of regulations on the way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More than 70% of IT leaders named regulatory compliance as one of their top three challenges related to gen AI deployment, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-10-06-gartner-predicts-ai-regulatory-violations-will-result-in-a-30-percent-increase-in-legal-disputes-for-tech-companies-by-2028"&gt;recent survey from Gartner&lt;/a&gt;. Less than a quarter of those IT leaders are very confident that their organizations can manage security and governance issues, including regulatory compliance, when using gen AI, the survey says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders appear to be worried about complying with the potential for a growing number of AI regulations, including some that may conflict with one another, says &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/lydia-cloughertyjones"&gt;Lydia Clougherty Jones&lt;/a&gt;, a senior director analyst at Gartner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The number of legal nuances, especially for a global organization, can be overwhelming, because the frameworks that are being announced by the different countries vary widely,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner predicts that AI regulatory violations will create a 30% increase in legal disputes for tech companies by 2028. By mid-2026, new categories of illegal AI-informed decision-making will cost more than $10 billion in remediation costs across AI vendors and users, the analyst firm also projects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="just-the-start"&gt;Just the start&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Government efforts to regulate AI are likely in their infancy, with the &lt;a href="https://commission.europa.eu/news-and-media/news/ai-act-enters-force-2024-08-01_en"&gt;EU AI Act&lt;/a&gt;, which went into effect in August 2024, one of the first major pieces of legislation targeting the use of AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the US Congress has so far taken a hands-off approach, a handful of US states have passed AI regulations, with the 2024 &lt;a href="https://leg.colorado.gov/sites/default/files/images/fpf_legislation_policy_brief_the_colorado_ai_act_final.pdf"&gt;Colorado AI Act&lt;/a&gt; requiring AI users to maintain risk management programs and conduct impact assessments and requiring both vendors and users to protect consumers from algorithmic discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Texas has also passed its own AI law, which goes into effect in January 2026. The Texas &lt;a href="https://www.dlapiper.com/en/insights/publications/2025/06/texas-adopts-the-responsible-ai-governance-act"&gt;Responsible Artificial Intelligence Governance Act&lt;/a&gt; (TRAIGA) requires government entities to inform individuals when they are interacting with an AI. The law also prohibits using AI to manipulate human behavior, such as inciting self-harm, or engaging in illegal activities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Texas law includes &lt;a href="https://natlawreview.com/article/traiga-key-provisions-texas-new-artificial-intelligence-governance-act"&gt;civil penalties&lt;/a&gt; of up to $200,000 per violation or $40,000 per day for ongoing violations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Then, in late September, California Governor Gavin Newsom signed the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.ca.gov/2025/09/29/governor-newsom-signs-sb-53-advancing-californias-world-leading-artificial-intelligence-industry/"&gt;Transparency in Frontier Artificial Intelligence Act&lt;/a&gt;, which requires large AI developers to publish descriptions on how they have incorporated national standards, international standards, and industry-consensus best practices into their AI frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The California law, which also goes into effect in January 2026, also mandates that AI companies report critical safety incidents, including cyberattacks, within 15 days, and provides provisions to protect whistleblowers who report violations of the law.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that fail to comply with the disclosure and reporting requirements face fines of up to $1 million per violation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;California IT regulations have an outsize impact on global practices because the state’s population of about 39 million gives it a huge number of potential AI customers protected under the law.  California’s population is larger than more than 135 countries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;California also is the AI capital of the world, containing the headquarters of &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/lists/ai50/"&gt;32 of the top 50&lt;/a&gt; AI companies worldwide, including OpenAI, Databricks, Anthropic, and Perplexity AI. All AI providers doing business in California will be subject to the regulations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cios-on-the-forefront"&gt;CIOs on the forefront&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With US states and more countries potentially passing AI regulations, CIOs are understandably nervous about compliance as they deploy the technology, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhinchcliffe"&gt;Dion Hinchcliffe&lt;/a&gt;, vice president and practice lead for digital leadership and CIOs, at market intelligence firm Futurum Equities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The CIO is on the hook to make it actually work, so they’re the ones really paying very close attention to what is possible,” he says. “They’re asking, ‘How accurate are these things? How much can data be trusted?’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While some AI regulatory and governance compliance solutions exist, some CIOs fear that those tools won’t keep up with the ever-changing regulatory and AI functionality landscape, Hinchcliffe says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s not clear that we have tools that will constantly and reliably manage the governance and the regulatory compliance issues, and it’ll maybe get worse, because regulations haven’t even arrived yet,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI regulatory compliance will be especially difficult because of the nature of the technology, he adds. “AI is so slippery,” Hinchcliffe says. “The technology is not deterministic; it’s probabilistic. AI works to solve all these problems that traditionally coded systems can’t because the coders never thought about that scenario.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tina-joros-0ab53413/"&gt;Tina Joros&lt;/a&gt;, chairwoman of the Electronic Health Record Association AI Task Force, also sees concerns over compliance because of a fragmented regulatory landscape. The various regulations being passed could widen an already large digital divide between large health systems and their smaller and rural counterparts that are struggling to keep pace with AI adoption, she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The various laws being enacted by states like California, Colorado, and Texas are creating a regulatory maze that’s challenging for health IT leaders and could have a chilling effect on the future development and use of generative AI,” she adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even bills that don’t make it into law require careful analysis, because they could shape future regulatory expectations, Joros adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Confusion also arises because the relevant definitions included in those laws and regulations, such as ‘developer,’ ‘deployer,’ and ‘high risk,’ are frequently different, resulting in a level of industry uncertainty,” she says. “This understandably leads many software developers to sometimes pause or second-guess projects, as developers and healthcare providers want to ensure the tools they’re building now are compliant in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://contractpodai.com/news/leadership-team-expansion-leah-innovation/"&gt;James Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, chief AI officer at contract software provider ContractPodAi, agrees that the inconsistency and overlap between AI regulations creates problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For global enterprises, that fragmentation alone creates operational headaches — not because they’re unwilling to comply, but because each regulation defines concepts like transparency, usage, explainability, and accountability in slightly different ways,” he says. “What works in North America doesn’t always work across the EU.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="look-to-governance-tools"&gt;Look to governance tools&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thomas recommends that organizations adopt a suite of governance controls and systems as they deploy AI. In many cases, a major problem is that AI adoption has been driven by individual employees using personal productivity tools, creating a fragmented deployment approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While powerful for specific tasks, these tools were never designed for the complexities of regulated, enterprise-wide deployment,” he says. “They lack centralized governance, operate in silos, and make it nearly impossible to ensure consistency, track data provenance, or manage risk at scale.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As IT leaders struggle with regulatory compliance, Gartner also recommends that the focus on training AI models to self-correct, create rigorous use-case review procedures, increase model testing and sandboxing, and deploy content moderation techniques such as buttons to report abuse AI warning labels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders need to be able to defend their AI results, requiring a deep understanding of how the models work, says Gartner’s Clougherty Jones. In certain risk scenarios, this may mean using an external auditor to test the AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You have to defend the data, you have to defend the model development, the model behavior, and then you have to defend the output,” she says. “A lot of times we use internal systems to audit output, but if something’s really high risk, why not get a neutral party to be able to audit it? If you’re defending the model and you’re the one who did the testing yourself, that’s defensible only so far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cio.com/article/4072396</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol conference warns: cybercrime fight hinges on access to data</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</link>
      <description>Criminals are exploiting encryption, anonymisation and emerging technologies faster than regulators and law enforcement can respond – making access to data the decisive challenge in the fight against cybercrime. This was the warning sounded at Europol’s 4th Annual Cybercrime Conference this week.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-650)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 19:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s no such thing as quantum incident response – and that changes everything</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073058/theres-no-such-thing-as-quantum-incident-response-and-that-changes-everything.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the key elements to detecting cyberattacks is the concept of observability. We can literally see the packets of data being thrown towards a website when a DoS attack is taking place. The “boom” of the attack is visible and observable. But when a cryptographically relevant quantum computer is utilized to break into encrypted traffic flows, the attacker “snoops” the traffic and stores a copy somewhere else where it can be processed later with impunity, which makes the act both not observed and not observable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is what I call the “silent boom,” and it will most definitely be a plate tectonic shift in the world of secrets and privacy, disrupting the balance of power for every nation, every industry and every individual.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The evidence isn’t theoretical. According to network security firm Qrator Labs, &lt;a href="https://qrator.net/blog/details/q2-2024-ddos-bots-and-bgp-incidents-statistics-and" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;there were approximately 13,626 BGP hijack attacks&lt;/a&gt; in the second quarter of 2024 and 13,438 in the third quarter. Not all are malicious, but enough create that “scenic route” through Chinese-owned or Russian-owned IP addresses that makes security professionals nervous about store-now-decrypt-later attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At Marvel, we had secrets that, if disclosed ahead of the planned time, would cause significant damage to the brand and potentially also to projected revenues. The actors who attend the red carpet premiere have no idea what they’re going to see on screen. The scripts they were given had false scenes in them as a means of forensic watermarking that helps identify leaks. When you’re protecting 10-year story arcs and plans for what comes after phase 6 of the Multiverse Saga, you develop an appreciation for what needs long-term protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="this-is-a-developer-problem-not-a-ciso-shopping-problem"&gt;This is a developer problem, not a CISO shopping problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs are directing attention to have quantum security risks added to the corporate risk register. It belongs there. But the problem to be solved is not a quick fix, despite what some snake oil salesmen might be pushing. There is no simple configuration checkbox on AWS or Azure or GCP where you “turn on” post-quantum cryptography (PQC) and then you’re good to go. This is a shared responsibility problem. Just as migrating to the cloud doesn’t magically make your infrastructure more secure, quantum vendors cannot solve this without significant developer engagement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here’s why this lands on developers: The majority of all internet traffic is not human-generated traffic from laptops to servers and back. It’s API traffic. Your company most likely delivers services using a host of third-party solutions, all accessed via APIs. So your API client needs to learn how to speak PQC algorithms just as much as that remote API endpoint needs to learn how to speak PQC algorithms. Otherwise, the connection will negotiate down to a common protocol that both can speak and it won’t be TLSv1.3 with PQC algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without significant engagement from developers, QA teams and product owners, the quantum decryption risk will remain in play. You cannot transfer this risk by adding more cyber insurance policy coverage. The entire cyber insurance industry itself is in a bit of an existential doubt situation regarding whether cybersecurity can reasonably be insured against, given the systemic impacts of supply chain attacks that cascade across entire industries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What can developers actually do? Three concrete steps this quarter:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step one&lt;/strong&gt;: Inventory your algorithms and data with a view towards which sensitive data ought to be protected with PQC. This is a data classification exercise where you need to add a column to track whether the datastore or application qualifies for PQC.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step two&lt;/strong&gt;: Check your internet-facing assets to see which, if any, are already capable of supporting TLSv1.3 with PQC algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step three&lt;/strong&gt;: Create internal capability to test new ciphers so that once NIST is able to “bless” another set of candidates (two of the first set of four algorithms have already been broken), you’ll be positioned to implement them without a five- to 10-year lag time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-fearmongering-critics-are-missing-the-point"&gt;The fearmongering critics are missing the point&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Critics say this is fearmongering and that we’ll have warning signs before quantum becomes a real threat. They’re wrong on the timeline. In my discussions with colleagues on the quantum security working group for the World Economic Forum, we see that financial services, healthcare and manufacturing are making plans now because they understand something crucial: It took us at least 10 years to get financial services to move to SHA-256 for encryption and for PCI compliance requirements to deprecate SSLv3 after TLS came into play in 1999. The insecure protocols weren’t formally deprecated until PCI DSS version 3.1 in 2015. That’s the current speed of “crypto agility” in financial services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cryptographically relevant quantum computer risk, being about five to 10 years away, is essentially a now risk, given the rate of adoption of new cryptography standards. The most dangerous myth seems to be that it can be put off to tomorrow and that nothing needs to be done today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen recent kerfuffles over &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/chinese-did-crack-rsa-quantum-yet-marin-ivezic-kew0c/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;factoring 22-bit RSA keys in research papers published in China&lt;/a&gt;, which is just a trivial academic milestone that doesn’t purport the demise of RSA-2048 encryption. But we will continue to see advancements in hybrid classical-quantum approaches to factoring integers. The writing is on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I’ve seen some pretty insane LinkedIn assertions from organizations making statements about computers with 4,000 qubits. For RSA-2048 to be broken, according to Shor’s algorithm, we would need around 20 million qubit quantum computers. So we are still orders of magnitude away. (The marketing teams will make sweeping generalizations about achievements and write them off as “good enough,” often comparing physical qubits and logical qubits as if they’re the same thing, but that is a classic apples-and-oranges fallacy.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="monday-morning-action-items"&gt;Monday morning action items&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The moment when a cryptographically relevant quantum computer comes into existence won’t arrive with fanfare or bombast. Hence, the idea of the silent boom. But by then, it will be too late for incident response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What you should do Monday morning: Start that data classification exercise. Figure out what needs protecting for the long term versus what has a shorter shelf life. In the world of DNS, we have Time To Live (TTL) that declares how long a resolver can cache a response. Think of a “PQC TTL” for your sensitive data, because not everything needs 30-year protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just as the HTTPS-everywhere movement took time to gain traction, so too will the PQC-everywhere efforts. The difference is we can’t wait for the attack to happen before we start preparing. There’s no such thing as quantum incident response — only quantum readiness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073058/theres-no-such-thing-as-quantum-incident-response-and-that-changes-everything.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luxury hybrid car thieves taken down in Belgium, Italy and Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</link>
      <description>A highly specialised organised crime network responsible for the theft of more than 100 luxury hybrid cars has been dismantled in an international operation led by the Italian Carabinieri with support from Europol and Eurojust. The estimated value of all stolen cars is of at least EUR 3 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV25-651)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-603) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esri security advisory (AV25-652)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Major blow to billion-euro glass eel trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>The latest iteration of Operation LAKE, which ran from October 2024 to June 2025, uncovered large-scale trafficking networks and disrupted the flow of live eels destined for illegal farms in Asia.The operation led to:16,131 inspections carried out across Europe26 arrests22 tonnes of glass eels seizedOrganised crime at the heart of traffickingInvestigations revealed that several organised crime groups were driving the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The expanding CISO role: From security operator to enterprise risk strategist</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073996/the-expanding-ciso-role-from-security-operator-to-enterprise-risk-strategist.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO job has outgrown its old definition. What started as a technical role has become a test of strategy, stamina, and leadership — and the scope keeps widening. According to Foundry’s 2025 Security Priorities Study, a majority of security leaders say their roles have expanded in the past year, and more than half now brief their boards multiple times a month. The CISO’s reach has extended well beyond cybersecurity operations to encompass enterprise risk, compliance, privacy, and AI oversight — a shift that’s redefining what leadership looks like at the top of the security organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The expanding scope reflects how integral security has become to every aspect of business. Today’s CISOs are taking on ever more responsibilities and functional roles, with many overseeing not just cybersecurity but also risk management, compliance, and even operational domains such as business continuity, data governance, and AI oversight. Some security leaders have added ESG or physical security to their remit — an acknowledgment that cyber risk is inseparable from business resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That expansion has elevated the CISO’s standing. In many enterprises, security leaders are now core members of executive decision-making teams, often helping to shape M&amp;amp;A strategy, product direction, and corporate governance. “CISOs of the present and the future need to get out of being just technologists and build their influence and communication muscle,” said Bread Financial’s Gaurav Kapil in a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4002753/cisos-reposition-their-roles-for-business-leadership.html"&gt;recent CSOonline article&lt;/a&gt; on CISO leadership. “It’s not transactional but more of a value-based conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO 95 percent board engagement" class="wp-image-4073993" height="271" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/cso-board-engagement-stat.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But greater influence comes with greater strain. Nearly one in four CISOs say they’re considering leaving the profession due to stress. Role creep has become a real issue, as some organizations consolidate additional duties — from physical security to sustainability — under the same leader. The expectation to oversee everything from ransomware readiness to ESG metrics has created &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3851735/cisos-are-taking-on-ever-more-responsibilities-and-functional-roles-has-it-gone-too-far.html"&gt;what some describe&lt;/a&gt; as a “hodgepodge” of responsibilities that can be unsustainable without the right support structure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those tensions — between rising expectations and personal bandwidth — are front and center at this year’s &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/"&gt;CSO Conference&lt;/a&gt; panel, “Navigating Through Uncertainty: Staying Alert and Staying Sane.” Moderated by Bob Bragdon, the discussion brings together Jonathan Chow (Genesys), Frank DePaola (Enpro), and Marcus Johnston (Precisely) to explore how top security executives are balancing expanded mandates with mental resilience and sustainable leadership.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The takeaway: The CISO role has evolved from technologist to strategist, from security operator to business risk steward. The influence is real — so is the pressure. As boards turn to security leaders for guidance on everything from AI policy to operational resilience, CISOs are proving indispensable to the enterprise. The challenge now is making the job sustainable for those tasked with defending not just networks, but the business itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CSO Security Priorities study for 2025 will be presented during a discussion at the annual CSO Conference &amp;amp; Awards, October 20–22 at the Grand Hyatt Indian Wells. Join leading CISOs as they share strategies for managing growing responsibilities, sustaining resilience, and leading effectively amid constant uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more information about the agenda and speakers, please visit: &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/agenda/"&gt;https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/agenda/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4073996/the-expanding-ciso-role-from-security-operator-to-enterprise-risk-strategist.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-653)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-654)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV25-655)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfeit and substandard food worth EUR 95 million seized in global operation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</link>
      <description>Europol, OLAF, DG SANTE and 31 countries across Europe and beyond, together with food and beverage producers from the private sector, joined forces in the fourteenth edition of Operation OPSON. This yearly effort targets the criminals behind counterfeit and substandard food and beverages. Law enforcement, customs and food regulatory agencies seized 259 012 packages, 1 416 168 litres of beverages and 11 566 958 kilograms of food, including meat and seafood.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted five key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISOs face quantum leap in prioritizing quantum resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074154/cisos-face-quantum-leap-in-prioritizing-quantum-resilience.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite recognizing the severity of the threat, enterprises continue to respond slowly to warnings that existing systems must be updated to address the risks of the approaching advent of quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers threaten the security of existing public-key cryptography systems. Government agencies such as the US National Institute of Standards and Technology and the UK’s National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) are advising to adopt &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/654887/11-notable-post-quantum-cryptography-initiatives-launched-in-2023.html"&gt;post-quantum cryptography (PQC)&lt;/a&gt; before a 2030 deadline, in time for the expected depreciation of vulnerable cryptographic algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, five years from this deadline, &lt;a href="https://www.pwc.com/us/en/services/consulting/cybersecurity-risk-regulatory/library/global-digital-trust-insights.html"&gt;PwC’s Global Digital Trust Insights report&lt;/a&gt; paints a picture of a general lack of preparedness for rolling out quantum resistant cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Although quantum computing ranks among the top five threats organisations are least prepared to address, fewer than 10% prioritise it in budgets and only 3% have implemented all [the] leading quantum resistant measures surveyed,” the report states.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Some organisations are making initial progress, with 29% in piloting and testing stages. However, only 22% have moved beyond piloting, and almost half (49%) haven’t considered or started implementing any quantum-resistant security measures,” it adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry readiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The majority of independent experts quizzed by CSO say the PwC report’s findings reflect a real gap between industry awareness and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4002749/cisos-urged-to-push-vendors-for-roadmaps-on-post-quantum-cryptography-readiness.html"&gt;operational readiness for PQC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sectigo.com/about/leadership/jason-soroko"&gt;Jason Soroko&lt;/a&gt;, senior fellow at automated certificate lifecycle management firm Sectigo, tells CSO that sectors of the economy that are already cryptographically mature are pushing ahead with PQC projects, leaving other sectors even further behind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Uptake is not confined to banking, yet financial services tend to lead because they are highly regulated, risk averse, and exposed to long-lived data risks,” Soroko explains. “Many banks and payment networks have larger cryptographic inventories, established key management and compliance drivers, which push them to move earlier.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Other sectors with long data lifetimes and wide device estates such as government, telecom, cloud, and critical infrastructure are also active,” Soroko adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Financial services and professional services are furthest ahead, but manufacturing, oil and gas, mining, and healthcare remain significantly behind, in some cases with PQC adoption as low as 2%, according to cybersecurity vendor Forescout.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrishickman613/?originalSubdomain=ca"&gt;Chris Hickman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; CSO at digital identity management firm Keyfactor, says that most organizations are waiting “either for the risk to feel more immediate or for others to make the first move.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That delay will be costly,” Hickman predicts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obstacles to widespread adoption range from a lack of skilled personnel, limited time and competing priorities, and the slow adoption of existing standards, Hickman says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="state-of-migration"&gt;State of migration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Encryption underpins the security of everything from healthcare records to government data and e-commerce transactions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But just 8.5% of SSH servers currently support quantum-safe encryption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;TLS 1.3 adoption — currently at 19% — also trails older, quantum-vulnerable versions, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.forescout.com/blog/q-day-countdown-new-data-on-post-quantum-cryptography-adoption-across-devices-and-industries/"&gt;recent study by Forescout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other experts paint a more optimistic picture of PQC deployment since &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3486075/nist-finally-settles-on-quantum-safe-crypto-standards.html"&gt;NIST finalized the first post-quantum cryptographic standards&lt;/a&gt; in August 2024.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Google, Apple, Signal, and Zoom have implemented PQC,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/duncanjones/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Duncan Jones&lt;/a&gt;, head of cybersecurity at integrated quantum computing firm Quantinuum. “Government mandates like &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/May/30/2003728741/-1/-1/0/CSA_CNSA_2.0_ALGORITHMS.PDF"&gt;CNSA 2.0&lt;/a&gt; set hard deadlines. Financial services are moving — &lt;a href="https://x9.org/"&gt;ASC X9&lt;/a&gt;’s 2025 readiness assessment outlines concrete steps from cryptographic inventory through migration planning.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obstacles to adoption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The main obstacles to widespread PQC adoption including cost, standards uncertainty, and organizational inertia. This last issue is significant given that preparing for the quantum threat requires a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4030898/prepping-for-the-quantum-threat-requires-a-phased-approach-to-crypto-agility.html"&gt;phased approach to crypto agility&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The obstacles to widespread adoption are very real,” Keyfactor’s Hickman says. “A lack of skilled personnel, limited time and competing priorities, and the slow adoption of the existing standards are the top challenges slowing progress.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hickman continues: “Additionally, risk perception varies, especially between security teams and executive leadership, making it harder to align strategies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kevin Hilscher, senior director of product management at DigiCert, says the time horizon is playing a significant role in the PQC preparation gap. “Companies are prioritizing other projects because, let’s face it, 2030 is still more than four years away and other projects take precedence,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, security teams find themselves &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4032035/ransomware-up-179-credential-theft-up-800-2025s-cyber-onslaught-intensifies.html"&gt;increasingly under fire from escalating threats&lt;/a&gt; in the here and now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Organizations often lack the expertise or resources to prioritize PQC while dealing with day-to-day threats,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/katrinarosseini/"&gt;Dr. Katrina Rosseini&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity expert at Ascendant Group. “Standards are still evolving, and deploying quantum-resistant algorithms requires careful testing to avoid breaking critical systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, delays in PQC adoption not only leave organizations vulnerable to future quantum threats but also amplify the vulnerabilities already being targeted by attackers, Dr. Rosseini warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Uncertainty, complexity, and the difficulties in mapping cryptographic assets are also putting a brake on PQC rollouts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Budgets compete with nearer-term threats and not all people are yet aware of the 2030 deprecation of RSA/ECC by NIST, so planning and investment are delayed,” says Sectigo’s Soroko. “Standards and vendor support are still being operationalized, and some algorithms introduce performance overhead or compatibility issues for legacy systems and constrained devices.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Soroko adds: “Skills are scarce and dependencies run through supply chains and cloud services, so end-to-end migration planning and governance slow adoption.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dr. Rosseini also notes that legacy systems and infrastructure can make rolling out new algorithms difficult.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/benjamin-mourad-1678a5/"&gt;Benjamin Mourad&lt;/a&gt;, senior director and solution architect at DMI, sees the main obstacles to widespread adoption being education about quantum computing risks — such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4030898/prepping-for-the-quantum-threat-requires-a-phased-approach-to-crypto-agility.html"&gt;the threat from “harvest now, decrypt later” attacks&lt;/a&gt; — and funding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Conversely, improvements in technology over the past year have made implementing and scaling up cryptographic systems more straightforward, Mourad contends.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Technological improvements over the past 12 months have improved capabilities and lowered the costs to migrate to PQC at scale with containerized, lightweight applications that did not exist over a year ago,” Mourad explains. “The decreasing need for significant investments in hardware and software will make PQC more scalable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="navigating-quantum-uncertainty"&gt;Navigating quantum uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts predict quantum computers capable of breaking current encryption anywhere from five to 20 years away.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This uncertainty can be distracting, Dr. Rosseini says. “The focus has to be on &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552701/the-cisos-guide-to-establishing-quantum-resilience.html"&gt;preparedness and resilience&lt;/a&gt;,” she advises. “Organizations need to inventory sensitive assets, assess system readiness, run pilot programs, and secure key management.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The PwC report should act as a wake-up call, Dr Rosseini adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Organizations that treat PQC as a strategic security initiative now will be positioned to reduce risk and strengthen resilience,” she says. “Those who wait risk leaving themselves exposed to both present and future threats.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074154/cisos-face-quantum-leap-in-prioritizing-quantum-resilience.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government considered destroying its data hub after decade-long intrusion</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074876/government-considered-destroying-its-data-hub-after-decade-long-intrusion.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A Chinese-sponsored cyber attack was so damaging that it was briefly proposed that an entire data hub be destroyed, according to &lt;a href="https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/here-be-dragons-the-truth-about-chinese-espionage/"&gt;British news magazine The Spectator&lt;/a&gt;. It observed that the attack accessing confidential UK government data was just one manifestation of a continuing series of threats to British IT infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That breach is but one example of the risks faced not only by the UK, but by governments and organizations everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-15/china-accessed-classified-uk-systems-for-a-decade-officials-say"&gt;news service Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;, two former senior security officials and other government officials familiar with the matter revealed that China has routinely accessed low- and medium-level classification information on UK government servers for at least a decade. This included information marked “official-sensitive” and “secret,” in addition to some material on the government’s secure IT networks, although no information designated “top secret” was compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chinese threats to the UK infrastructure are very much at the forefront of government thinking right now, given the &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgd5jgzdweo"&gt;collapse of the trial&lt;/a&gt; of two Britons accused of passing secret documents to Chinese authorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack on the data hub, through which classified government information was exchanged, came about following the sale of the company controlling it to a Chinese entity. While the destruction of the data hub was considered, the government found alternative ways to protect the data, according to Bloomberg. However, the breach was serious enough for then British Prime Minister Boris Johnson to commission a report on threats, including digital surveillance and cyber attacks, posed by China. That report was never publicly released and, The Spectator said, technical details of the attack on the hub remain classified.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-hub-attack-particularly-critical"&gt;Data hub attack ‘particularly critical’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack on the data hub is seen as particularly critical. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jakemooreuk/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Jake Moore&lt;/a&gt;, global cybersecurity advisor with software company ESET said,  “The fact that ministers once considered destroying a data hub holding sensitive government data after it was sold to a China-aligned entity shows how seriously the UK views control over critical infrastructure. Physically destroying the site would have stopped services and wiped forensic evidence, yet it underscores the depth of concern about potential foreign control of national assets”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/grjk83/"&gt;Gavin Knapp&lt;/a&gt;, cyber threat intelligence lead at &lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Bridewell, a supplier to the UK government critical network infrastructure, endorsed the severity of this approach. He said, “it’s like when a device is compromised, the only way to truly be sure there are no remnants, or unidentified backdoors is to restore the asset to a known good state. In the physical realm, in particular a data centre, to sweep and verify there is no enduring threat actor / spy presence is much more difficult, and at a state secrets level the required effort to treat or terminate the risk requires a huge amount of effort and cost to bring risks down to an acceptable level.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While it’s not clear exactly how the data hub had been compromised, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/martinariley/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Martin Riley&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at Bridewell, said, “The main point of entry may have been a VPN, as is common with Chinese actors, but if they have already moved across the environment and escalated privileges, then the impact would be wider.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Riley noted that when the government said it had discovered another way to protect the data, it was likely that it had patched a vulnerability “after performing incident response to understand the breadth of the breach and how it was initially accessed.”                                                                                                                    &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="organizations-cant-ignore-the-supply-chain"&gt;Organizations can’t ignore the supply chain&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because of the constant threat from state-backed attackers, organizations everywhere need to be on constant alert, said Knapp, adding, “CISOs across government must assume they’re already being targeted, particularly by state-linked advanced persistent threats (APTs). These groups are difficult to detect because they prioritize stealth and long-term access over disruption. This raises key questions around how well organizations detect insider threats and hunt for compromises on edge devices, especially where vendors manage the hardware, making forensics more complex.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Knapp warned that it was not sufficient to make government infrastructure more secure while ignoring the supply chain. “Even the most secure networks can be breached when attackers exploit users, contractors, or third-party systems to gain a foothold. They often compromise edge devices or exploit misconfigurations to move laterally within environments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Remember, state-backed attackers play a long game, embedding themselves within critical networks for months or years,” he said. “Techniques such as &lt;a href="https://www.team-cymru.com/post/an-introduction-to-operational-relay-box-orb-networks-unpatched-forgotten-and-obscured" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Operational Relay Boxes&lt;/a&gt; (ORBs) allow them to mask their activity and bypass endpoint detection tools, making attribution extremely difficult.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074876/government-considered-destroying-its-data-hub-after-decade-long-intrusion.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 23:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-656)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-657)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-658)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-659)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–660)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-661)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-662)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-663)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-664)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-665)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory - October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-666)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-667)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-668)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV25-669)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-670)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-671)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-672)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-014 Security Incident impacting F5</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-673)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-674)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-675)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-676)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-677)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-616) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zimbra security advisory (AV25-678)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
