<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:25:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and Spanish National Police disrupt activities of far-right terrorist group 'The Base'</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</link>
      <description>Europol supported the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional) in disrupting activities of the far-right terrorist group 'The Base'. The operation took place over three days in Madrid and Valencia, resulting in significant seizures and the arrest of three suspected far-right extremists on 25 November 2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-spanish-national-police-disrupt-activities-of-far-right-terrorist-group-base</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New report explores use of robotics and unmanned systems in the fight against crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</link>
      <description>Europol has today published The Unmanned Future(s): The Impact of Robotics and Unmanned Systems on Law Enforcement. The report, produced by the Europol Innovation Lab, provides an in-depth analysis of how unmanned systems could change society, crime and law enforcement, and discusses the challenges and opportunities they present.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN security advisory (AV25-798)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openvpn-security-advisory-av25-798</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openvpn-security-advisory-av25-798</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-799)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-799</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-799</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIS2 umsetzen – ohne im Papierkrieg zu enden</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103179/nis2-umsetzen-ohne-im-papierkrieg-zu-enden.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 6173w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2082667993.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Die EU-Richtline NIS2 ist in Deutschland am 06. Dezember 2025 in Kraft getreten. Dieser Beitrag zeigt, wie sich mit DevSecOps ein Großteil der Pflichtarbeit automatisieren lässt.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Vadi Fuoco – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4090107/bundestag-beschliest-nis2-umsetzung.html"&gt;NIS2&lt;/a&gt; ist symbolisch für das Kernproblem europäischer Richtlinien und Verordnungen: Sie erzeugen unnötigen Papierkrieg und entfalten ihre Wirkung zu selten. Sei es das Lieferkettengesetz, die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088083/eu-kommission-will-dsgvo-fur-ki-und-cookie-tracking-lockern.html"&gt;DSGVO&lt;/a&gt;‑Folgenabschätzungen oder das IT‑Sicherheitsgesetz – sie haben gemeinsam, dass Unternehmen gigantische Dokumentationsberge produzieren müssen. Diese erhöhen weder die tatsächliche Sicherheit, noch sind sie realistisch prüfbar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compliant ist in der Regel derjenige, der eine umfangreiche Dokumentation aller Prozesse und regelmäßigen Prüfungen vorlegen kann. Diese sind zumeist so ausführlich, dass ihre Erstellung bereits nahezu unzumutbare Aufwände verursacht und ihre manuelle Prüfung praktisch unmöglich wird. Selbst wenn man sie prüfen würde, wären die Informationen nicht präzise genug, um echte Sicherheit zu belegen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="sicherheit-gehort-in-die-planung"&gt;Sicherheit gehört in die Planung&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In vielen Unternehmen entsteht dadurch eine absurde Praxis: Das technische Team baut funktionierende Infrastruktur und losgelöst davon schreibt ein Compliance‑Beauftragter im Nachhinein eine seitenlange Rechtfertigung, warum die Lösung angeblich sicher sei.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das ist ungefähr so, als würde Volkswagen ein Auto bauen und erst danach verfasst jemand 40 Seiten darüber, warum dieses Auto den Sicherheitsstandards entsprechen sollte. In der realen Industrie läuft es natürlich anders: Sicherheitsanforderungen fließen bereits in die Planung ein, technologische Mindeststandards sind definiert, und Qualitätsprozesse überwachen die Umsetzung automatisch. Compliance ergibt sich aus Technik – nicht aus Leitz‑Ordnern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In anderen Bereichen, wie der Steuerprüfung, hat man dieses Problem längst erkannt und die Automatisierung relevanter Prozesse gesetzlich vorgeschrieben (Stichwort: elektronische Registrierkasse, revisionssichere Buchhaltungssoftware). Das erspart ehrlichen Unternehmern nicht nur enorme manuelle Arbeit, sondern reduziert vor allem das Missbrauchsrisiko.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Leider werden in Deutschland nur wenige Dinge so konsequent umgesetzt wie das Eintreiben unserer Steuern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anders als beim Thema Steuerlast sollten Unternehmen jedoch ein intrinsisches Interesse daran haben, ihre IT‑Sicherheit korrekt zu implementieren. Das Bußgeld für einen NIS2‑Verstoß kann bis zu zehn Millionen Euro oder zwei Prozent des weltweiten Jahresumsatzes betragen. Die wirtschaftlichen Schäden erfolgreicher Cyberangriffe sind oft existenzbedrohend und summieren sich bereits heute auf dreistellige Milliardenbeträge pro Jahr.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch wenn es nicht ausdrücklich gesetzlich vorgeschrieben ist, gibt es mittlerweile – nicht zuletzt durch AI‑gestützte Werkzeuge – die Möglichkeit, Sicherheitsprozesse und ihre vollständige Dokumentation so weit zu automatisieren, dass sich Security, Compliance und Auditierbarkeit in einem einzigen technischen Prozess vereinen lassen. Das spart nicht nur Ressourcen, sondern erhöht auch die tatsächliche Sicherheit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie dies im Detail aussehen kann, zeigt ein Beispiel einer SaaS‑Applikation in der Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id=""&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="it-im-wandel-von-textdokumenten-zu-deklarativer-technik"&gt;IT im Wandel: von Textdokumenten zu deklarativer Technik&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 verlangt im Kern drei Dinge: konkrete Sicherheitsmaßnahmen, Prozesse und Richtlinien zur Steuerung dieser Maßnahmen sowie belastbare Nachweise, dass sie im Alltag funktionieren. Die Prozessdokumentation – also Policies, Zuständigkeiten und Abläufe – ist für die meisten größeren Unternehmen nichts grundsätzlich Neues. &lt;a href="https://www.bsi.bund.de/DE/Themen/Unternehmen-und-Organisationen/Standards-und-Zertifizierung/Zertifizierung-und-Anerkennung/Zertifizierung-von-Managementsystemen/ISO-27001-Basis-IT-Grundschutz/iso-27001-basis-it-grundschutz_node.html"&gt;ISO‑27001&lt;/a&gt;‑basierte Informationssicherheits-Managementsysteme (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495826/iso-und-isms-darum-gehen-security-zertifizierungen-schief.html"&gt;ISMS&lt;/a&gt;), HR‑Prozesse und Management‑Handbücher existieren oft seit Jahren. Entscheidend für NIS2 sind deshalb vor allem zwei Ebenen: die technischen Maßnahmen und die Evidenz, dass sie wirksam sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Genau hier zeigt sich der Umbruch der letzten Jahre. Früher wurden Konzepte, Maßnahmen und Spezifikationen von Software‑ und IT‑Infrastrukturen überwiegend in Textform dokumentiert. Programmcode war zu komplex, Konfigurationen lagen verstreut in Dateien, Ticketsystemen oder im Kopf einzelner Administratoren. Im Nachgang hat man Dokumente geschrieben – häufig durch fachfremde Kollegen. Dieses Vorgehen war vor allem aus zwei Gründen problematisch: Es skaliert nicht in wachsenden, verteilten Umgebungen, und es passt nicht zu dem Ziel, technische Prozesse konsequent zu automatisieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In modernen Systemen setzt man deshalb auf Verfahren wie Test‑ oder Behaviour‑driven Development und Infrastructure as Code (IaC), die – konsequent angewendet – textuelle Dokumentation weitgehend ersetzen. Die von NIS2 geforderten technischen Spezifikationen können direkt auf diese Artefakte referenzieren: IaC‑Definitionen legen Verschlüsselung, Netzsegmente oder Backup‑Szenarien fest, und CI/CD‑Pipelines spielen sie revisionssicher in die Produktion aus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Änderungen sind damit nicht nur technisch exakt beschrieben, sondern über Commits und Deployments auch zeitlich nachvollziehbar. Die Evidenz für Aspekte, die sich nicht vollständig deklarativ fassen lassen – etwa die Sicherheit der Software‑Supply‑Chain oder des Anwendungscodes – kann über Security‑Checks in der CI/CD‑Pipeline und eine laufende Bewertung durch SIEM‑ und CNAPP‑Systeme abgebildet werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie das konkret aussehen kann, zeigt sich besonders deutlich in folgenden Bereichen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity &amp;amp; Access Management,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Schwachstellenmanagement in der Software‑Supply‑Chain sowie im Monitoring,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Incident Handling&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;und Meldepflichten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id=""&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="identity-access-management-policies-as-code-statt-rollen%e2%80%91excel"&gt;Identity &amp;amp; Access Management: Policies as Code statt Rollen‑Excel&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity &amp;amp; Access Management ist eine der zentralen Säulen von NIS2. Gefordert sind nicht nur „irgendwelche“ Rollen, sondern ein Zugriffskonzept nach Need‑to‑know, Least Privilege und Separation of Duties. In der Praxis lässt sich das gut in drei Ebenen denken: bewusste Vergabe von Rechten, ein realistischer Lebenszyklus dieser Rechte – und eine Architektur, die Lateral Movement so weit wie möglich verhindert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Statt Berechtigungen in Excel, Admin‑UIs und verstreuten Wikis zu pflegen, werden Rollen und Zugriffsrechte als Policies as Code, beziehungsweise Infrastructure as Code definiert – etwa als Terraform‑Module oder JSON/YAML‑Policies in einem Git‑Repository. Alle Änderungen laufen ausschließlich über Merge Requests und werden über eine CI/CD‑Pipeline ausgerollt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Damit ist klar nachvollziehbar, wer welche Rechte geändert hat, wer das freigegeben hat und wann die Änderung produktiv gegangen ist. Die Dokumentations‑ und Nachweispflichten von NIS2 ergeben sich so direkt aus Git‑History und Pipeline‑Logs, ohne dass jemand zusätzliche Word‑Konzepte schreiben muss.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Rollenmodell allein ist noch kein Least Privilege. NIS2 verlangt, dass Rechte regelmäßig überprüft und überflüssige Berechtigungen entfernt werden. In Cloud‑Umgebungen mit hunderten Accounts, Services, Pods und Functions ist das manuell kaum noch handhabbar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hier setzen Cloud‑Identity‑Entitlement‑Management‑Systeme (CIEM) an. Sie lesen alle effektiven Berechtigungen aus der Umgebung aus, korrelieren sie mit Audit‑Logs und zeigen, welche Rechte tatsächlich genutzt werden und wo Überprivilegierung besteht. Besonders bei Non‑Human Identities (Service‑Accounts, Workloads) ist das entscheidend, weil genau hier oft sehr breite Rechte vergeben werden, die Angreifern später als Sprungbrett dienen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Einige Start-Ups bieten mittlerweile sogar CIEM-Systeme, welche mit Hilfe von AI automatisch IAM-Policies für die entsprechenden Rollen generieren können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id=""&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="schwachstellenmanagement-software%e2%80%91supply%e2%80%91chain-sbom-statt-scanner%e2%80%91pdf"&gt;Schwachstellenmanagement &amp;amp; Software‑Supply‑Chain: SBOM statt Scanner‑PDF&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der zweite Block, den NIS2 und die neue Durchführungsverordnung 2024/2690 für digitale Dienste scharf stellen, ist das Schwachstellenmanagement im eigenen Code und in der Lieferkette. Gefordert sind regelmäßige Vulnerability‑Scans, Verfahren zur Bewertung und Priorisierung, fristgerechte Behandlung kritischer Schwachstellen sowie ein geregeltes Vulnerability‑Handling und – wo nötig – Coordinated Vulnerability Disclosure. Für Cloud‑ und SaaS‑Provider kommen Supply‑Chain‑Pflichten hinzu, etwa gegenüber Cloud‑, CI/CD‑ und Registry‑Dienstleistern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im klassischen Schwachstellenmanagement werden SCA‑, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493611/dynamic-static-application-security-testing-die-besten-dast-sast-tools.html"&gt;SAST‑ und DAST&lt;/a&gt;‑Scanner einfach „über alles drüber geworfen“. Das Ergebnis sind endlose Listen an Findings, von denen ein Großteil Fehlalarme oder für das konkrete System nicht relevant ist. Diese Daten landen dann in Excel‑Tabellen oder einer Schwachstellendatenbank, in der Teams versuchen, Prioritäten zu vergeben. Gerade bei Zero‑Day‑Lücken führt das zu hektischen Ad‑hoc‑Analysen: Welche unserer Komponenten sind betroffen? Ist die Schwachstelle in unserer Architektur überhaupt ausnutzbar? Was tun wir, solange es noch keinen Patch gibt?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der moderne Ansatz ist, alle &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493657/security-by-design-devsecops-so-gelingt-sichere-softwareentwicklung.html"&gt;DevSecOps&lt;/a&gt;‑Findings in einem zentralen System zu konsolidieren. Dort fließen Ergebnisse aus SCA, SAST und DAST zusammen, werden mit Kontext aus Software Bill of Materials (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491814/sbom-erklart-was-ist-eine-software-bill-of-materials.html"&gt;SBOMs&lt;/a&gt;), Architektur und Exponiertheit angereichert und mit Hilfe von AI vorgefiltert. False Positives lassen sich so drastisch reduzieren, und übrig bleibt eine deutlich kleinere Menge an tatsächlich relevanten Schwachstellen, inklusive einer Einschätzung, wie kritisch sie im konkreten Setup sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese verdichteten Findings können direkt in Ticketsysteme und ins &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495240/security-operations-services-das-mussen-soc-analysten-uber-ihr-unternehmen-wissen.html"&gt;SOC&lt;/a&gt; weitergegeben werden, wo sie wie Incidents behandelt, nachverfolgt und für NIS2‑Reports ausgewertet werden. Aus einem wuchernden Scanner‑Output wird so ein steuerbarer Prozess, der sowohl die gesetzlichen Anforderungen als auch die Realität im Betrieb abbildet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id=""&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="monitoring-incident%e2%80%91handling-und-meldestelle"&gt;Monitoring, Incident‑Handling und Meldestelle&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der dritte Bereich, in dem NIS2 schnell zum Papiertiger wird, ist die Kombination aus Monitoring, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3842982/6-wichtige-punkte-fur-ihren-incident-response-plan.html"&gt;Incident Response&lt;/a&gt; und den neuen Meldepflichten. Die Richtlinie gibt klare Deadlines vor: Frühwarnung innerhalb von 24 Stunden, eine strukturierte Meldung nach 72 Stunden, ein Abschlussbericht nach spätestens einem Monat. Viele Organisationen reagieren darauf, indem sie neue Templates, Excel‑Listen und Meldehandbücher bauen – oft weitgehend losgelöst vom bestehenden SOC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Ernstfall bedeutet das: Das SOC bekämpft den Vorfall, während parallel eine „NIS2‑Taskforce“ versucht, Informationen aus Tickets, Mails und Ad‑hoc‑Chats so aufzubereiten, dass sie in ein Formular passen. Die Folge sind doppelte Arbeit, Informationsverluste und Berichte, die zwar Seiten füllen, aber wenig darüber sagen, wie gut Detection und Response tatsächlich funktionieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In einer Cloud‑SaaS‑Umgebung bietet sich ein anderer Weg an: Statt NIS2‑Reporting als eigenes Dokumentenprojekt zu verstehen, wird ein modernes DevSecOps‑basiertes SOC aufgebaut, so dass alle sicherheitsrelevanten Signale von vornherein an einem Ort zusammenlaufen: Cloud‑Infrastruktur, CI/CD‑Pipelines, Anwendungen, IdP und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495114/identity-access-managementdie-9-besten-iam-tools.html"&gt;IAM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Regeln, nach denen diese Daten korreliert, angereichert und in Incidents überführt werden, sind als Code definiert und versioniert. T Detection‑Logik (Threat Detection and Response), Schwellenwerte und Playbooks liegen im Repository und werden wie Anwendungscode über Pipelines ausgerollt. Große Teile der klassischen SOC‑Arbeit lassen sich damit automatisieren: Aus Roh‑Logs werden konsistente Incidents mit Kontext, ohne dass jemand manuell Textbausteine zusammenkopieren muss. &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/de-at/security/business/security-101/what-is-cnapp"&gt;CNAPP&lt;/a&gt; (Cloud-Native Application Protection Platform ) und ähnliche Plattformen übernehmen gleichzeitig Speicherung und Archivierung der Daten, sodass der Nachweis der Überwachungstätigkeit im System mitläuft, statt in gesonderten Doku‑Schleifen erzeugt zu werden. Machine‑Learning‑ und AI‑Komponenten helfen zusätzlich, False Positives zu reduzieren, ähnliche Ereignisse zu clustern und auffällige Muster hervorzuheben – das SOC konzentriert sich auf die wenigen Vorfälle, die wirklich Aufmerksamkeit brauchen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auf Prozessebene bleiben Playbooks und Meldewege wichtig – aber schlank. Ein IR‑Playbook definiert Incident‑Klassen, Eskalationspfade und Kommunikationsregeln, inklusive der Kriterien, ab wann ein Vorfall als „NIS2‑signifikant“ gilt. Ein Meldeprozess regelt, wer die Informationen aus SOC und Fachbereichen konsolidiert und über die BSI‑Meldestelle einreicht.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die eigentliche Dokumentation entsteht auch hier im Wesentlichen automatisch: Incident‑Tickets enthalten Timeline, betroffene Services, Impact, Ursache und Maßnahmen; ein Kennzeichen „NIS2‑relevant“ und ein Meldestatus verknüpfen sie mit den externen Berichten. Aus &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492608/was-ist-siem.html"&gt;SIEM&lt;/a&gt;‑ und IR‑Daten lassen sich Kennzahlen wie MTTD, MTTR oder die Zeit zwischen Detection und Erstmeldung direkt berechnen – genau die Größen, an denen sich ablesen lässt, ob NIS2 gelebter Prozess ist oder nur eine neue Schublade im Dokumentenschrank.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nis2-als-architektur%e2%80%91test-nicht-nur-als-doku%e2%80%91ubung"&gt;NIS2 als Architektur‑Test, nicht nur als Doku‑Übung&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 zwingt Unternehmen, ihre Sicherheitsmaßnahmen, Prozesse und Nachweise explizit zu machen. Das ist unbequem – gerade für Organisationen, die bisher stark ad hoc gearbeitet haben. Ob daraus ein Papiertiger oder ein echter Sicherheitsgewinn wird, entscheidet sich aber nicht im Gesetzestext, sondern in der Architektur.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wer versucht, die Richtlinie vor allem mit Word, PowerPoint und Excel „wegzudokumentieren“, wird viel Aufwand und wenig Resilienz produzieren. Werden hingegen IdP und IAM, CI/CD‑Pipelines, SBOM‑ und Vulnerability‑Tools, SIEM und IR‑Plattform so aufgesetzt, dass sie die geforderten Controls und Nachweise quasi nebenbei liefern, bekommt man NIS2‑Compliance als Nebeneffekt einer modernen Security‑Landschaft. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103179/nis2-umsetzen-ohne-im-papierkrieg-zu-enden.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Struts security advisory (AV25-800)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-struts-security-advisory-av25-800</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-struts-security-advisory-av25-800</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-801)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-801</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-801</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racks, sprawl and the myth of redundancy: Why your failover isn’t as safe as you think</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4102530/racks-sprawl-and-the-myth-of-redundancy-why-your-failover-isnt-as-safe-as-you-think.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-physical-roots-of-resilience"&gt;The physical roots of resilience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, at 2 a.m., I stood in a data center aisle watching a core switch lose a power supply. The room was cold, the fans loud and the alert light blinked amber. Within four seconds, the backup unit took over. Not a single packet dropped. That seamless, silent shift captured the essence of networking redundancy at its best: automatic, invisible and flawless. It was the kind of moment engineers live for — a quiet victory in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, that same principle faces relentless pressure. Networks have outgrown physical racks and now span hybrid clouds, edge nodes, SD-WAN overlays, API gateways and micro-segmented virtual fabrics. Redundancy no longer means just extra hardware or twin fiber links. It demands survival against misconfigured routing policies, regional DNS outages, zero-day exploits in router firmware and cascading failures triggered by human error or supply chain compromise. The landscape has evolved dramatically, but the core lessons — built on discipline, foresight and trust — endure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My journey began with physical infrastructure, back when reliability was measured in cables and chassis. Every server connected through dual paths, with link aggregation bundles split across two top-of-rack switches, each uplinked to separate core routers over distinct fiber routes. I once spent an entire weekend labeling cables with color-coded heat shrink: red for primary, blue for backup. It was meticulous, almost meditative work. When a technician accidentally kicked a patch cord loose during a floor tile replacement, traffic shifted in under 200 milliseconds. No alarms triggered. No user complaints. The monitoring dashboard stayed green. That reliability felt like muscle memory: predictable, testable and deeply tangible. It was redundancy you could touch, trace and trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-complexity-and-policy-traps"&gt;Cloud complexity and policy traps&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Networks, however, no longer stay confined to racks. They live in routing tables, BGP sessions, cloud control planes and software-defined overlays. Many organizations rush to multi-region cloud setups, believing geographic distance alone guarantees resilience. It does not. Last year, I oversaw a global e-commerce platform with active-passive failover across two regions. Health checks withdrew prefixes from the primary if latency crossed 80 ms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During a routine maintenance window, a junior engineer mistyped a BGP community tag. Instead of marking one subnet, the change blocked the entire backup path with a no-export rule. Traffic surged onto an already saturated primary link, pushing packet loss to 11 percent. The backup route was healthy, advertising correctly and fully reachable — yet policy prevented its use. We corrected the error in six minutes, but customers felt the impact for nearly 40. The takeaway was stark: redundancy without aligned policies is mere decoration, expensive and useless when it matters most. This mirrors the &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-1111-incident-on-june-27-2024/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2024 Cloudflare 1.1.1.1 hijack incident&lt;/a&gt; caused by a leaked border gateway (BGP) route.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As cloud environments grow, consistency becomes harder to maintain. A small template tweak in one availability zone can cascade across regions if copied unchecked, turning intended protection into widespread failure. Teams now manage configurations like code, with versioning, peer reviews, staged testing and automation to enforce uniformity. Tools like infrastructure-as-code pipelines, policy engines and drift detection systems are no longer optional — they are the new standard for scalable resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SD-WAN extends these challenges to branch locations, linking multiple internet paths for fluid failover and intelligent, application-aware routing. It promises simplicity and agility. Yet a single carrier firmware update can degrade performance everywhere, even when links remain active. I’ve seen MTU mismatches, encryption mismatches and path preference bugs ripple through hundreds of sites in minutes. Phased rollouts, strict change policies and gradual deployment rings prevent blanket disruption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The same discipline applies at the edge, where devices in retail stores, warehouses or remote clinics depend on local backups for speed and continuity. A rushed firmware push can erase that safety net across all units, forcing field teams to restore from USB drives or mobile hotspots. Careful staging, rollback plans and on-site recovery kits are now part of every deployment checklist.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Routing mistakes and DNS breakdowns lurk as quiet, persistent risks. One errant rule can dead-end traffic and even solid backups stay idle if policies block them. Robust prefix filters, route validation and RPKI enforcement keep paths safe. Likewise, DNS backups must operate independently — free of shared anycast IPs, providers or control planes — to avoid joint collapse. Security checks, DNSSEC and diverse resolver strategies strengthen failover. These are not add-ons; they are foundational to modern network hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="anticipating-the-inevitable-pre-mortem-and-defense-in-depth"&gt;Anticipating the inevitable: Pre-mortem and defense in depth&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The next outage is already taking shape, hidden until the first alert. It might hide in a supply chain flaw inside a trusted IOS-XR patch, quietly altering routes worldwide. Or it could stem from a single flawed intent policy in an ACI fabric, isolating entire application layers with surgical precision. External forces like wildfires, floods or geopolitical events can force data center evacuations, knocking out power grids and delaying generators for hours. The &lt;a href="https://www.fastly.com/blog/summary-of-june-8-outage" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2021 Fastly global outage&lt;/a&gt; — triggered by one valid config change exposing a hidden bug — shows how fast a CDN can collapse. These scenarios are not speculation; they are probabilities waiting to strike, each with its own failure signature.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experience reframes the question. Failure is inevitable in infrastructure work. What matters is how it unfolds, how precisely and whether the design anticipates that exact failure mode. Resilience now means shaping failure’s impact, not stopping it. This mindset demands a new ritual: the pre-mortem. In every design review, we assume total failure at peak load. We trace dependencies — transit providers, certificate authorities, undersea cables, even physical access roads. We hunt for shared fate: two “diverse” carriers in the same conduit, a single control plane for multi-region DNS or a vendor update applied globally without validation. Each discovery triggers action: a new peer, a policy rewrite, a satellite link or a dark fiber lease. &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/wellarchitected/latest/reliability-pillar/welcome.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AWS recommends pre-mortems in its Reliability Pillar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I sat in a dim network operations center at 3 a.m., cold coffee forgotten, as one BGP update spread chaos via a global transit provider. A peer leaked a default route with lower preference, sucking outbound traffic into oblivion. The backup path was fully functional, yet our policy still favored the tainted route. For 17 minutes, half the internet vanished for users. Customers raged. Executives demanded answers. A swift prefix filter fixed it, but the lesson lingered: redundancy requires not just a second path, but intelligence to choose it wisely and reject the wrong one. That night, I rewrote our change process: no routing policy touches production without simulation, peer review and automated testing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Observability unifies the picture. A consolidated view of logs, traffic flows, performance metrics and control plane health spots weakening paths before collapse, enabling fixes before users notice. Cost tensions persist. Leaders crave full redundancy yet settle for cheaper, correlated links that fail together. Genuine resilience needs true separation, geographic distance and sometimes higher budgets, all justified by the disruptions avoided. A $50,000 cross-connect can prevent a $2 million outage. The math is simple.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Automation now manages routine failovers, sensing issues and shifting traffic instantly so engineers tackle root causes, not manual switches. The next disruption looms from software bugs, policy slips, physical cuts or zero-day attacks. Effective planning means expecting breakdown, mapping vulnerabilities and scripting clear recovery. In a recent breach, an attacker tried hijacking core routing via a compromised jump host. Layered defenses — RPKI, prefix filters and automated session resets — contained it. Users saw only a 40 ms blip. Redundancy had matured from spare cables into a dynamic blend of security, automation and vigilance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The foundational principles hold: remove single points of failure, secure real separation, automate responses and monitor relentlessly. The scale has ballooned — from patch panels to cloud regions, from local switches to global routes — but the mission stays constant: keep data moving regardless of obstacles. Outages will come. They always do. But with redundancy woven into a tested, trusted and adaptable network, their sting will fade and the packets will keep flowing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4102530/racks-sprawl-and-the-myth-of-redundancy-why-your-failover-isnt-as-safe-as-you-think.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice &amp; Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-802)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-802</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV25-803)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av25-803</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-805)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-805</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-806)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-806</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-807)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-807</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-018 - Vulnerability affecting React Server Components - CVE-2025-55182</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-018-vulnerability-affecting-react-server-components-cve-2025-55182</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Action Secrets aren’t secret anymore: exposed PATs now a direct path into cloud environments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103717/github-action-secrets-arent-secret-anymore-exposed-pats-now-a-direct-path-into-cloud-environments-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many enterprises use GitHub Action Secrets to store and protect sensitive information such as credentials, API keys, and tokens used in CI/CD workflows. These private repositories are widely assumed to be safe and locked down.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But attackers are now exploiting that blind trust, according to &lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/github-attacks-pat-control-plane" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; from the Wiz Customer Incident Response Team. They found that threat actors are using exposed GitHub Personal Access Tokens (PATs) to access GitHub Action Secrets and sneak into cloud environments, then run amok.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The root cause issue is the presence of these secrets in repos,” said &lt;a href="https://www.beauceronsecurity.com/blog/tag/David+Shipley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt; of Beauceron Security. “Cloud service provider access keys are gold, they can be extraordinarily long lived, and that’s what [attackers are] sniffing around for.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="github-action-secrets-arent-secrets-anymore"&gt;GitHub Action Secrets aren’t secrets anymore&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz estimates that 73% of organizations using private GitHub Action Secrets repositories store cloud service provider (CSP) credentials within them. When PATs, which allow developers and automation bots to interact with GitHub repositories and workflows, are exploited, attackers can easily move laterally to CSP control planes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PATs can become a “powerful springboard” that allows attackers to impersonate developers and carry out a range of activities, explained &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/erik-avakian" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Erik Avakian&lt;/a&gt;, technical counselor at Info-Tech Research Group. It’s like having a backstage pass into a company’s cloud environments, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Once they’re holding that valid PAT, they can do all sorts of things in GitHub that lead directly back into a company’s AWS, Azure, GCP, or other types of cloud services, because GitHub treats that PAT like the real developer,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With that access, threat actors can “poke around” various repositories and workflows and look for anything that hints at cloud access, configuration items, scripts, and hidden secrets, he noted. If they get access to real cloud credentials, they “have the keys to the company’s AWS bucket, Azure subscriptions, and other workflows.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They can then spin up cloud resources, access databases, steal source code, install malicious files such as crypto miners, sneak in malicious workflows, or even pivot to other cloud services, while setting up persistence mechanisms so they can return whenever they want.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“At that point, basically anything you can do in the cloud, so can they,” said Avakian.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="easily-evading-detection"&gt;Easily evading detection&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz found that a threat actor with basic read permissions via a PAT can use GitHub’s API code search to discover secret names embedded directly in a workflow’s yaml code, accessed via “&lt;em&gt;${{ secrets.SECRET_NAME }}&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The danger is that this secret discovery method is difficult to monitor because search API calls are not logged. Further, GitHub-hosted Actions run from GitHub-managed resources that use legitimate, shared IP addresses not flagged as malicious. Attackers can abuse secrets, impersonate workflow origins to exploit trust, and potentially access other resources if code is misconfigured or reused elsewhere in the workflows. They can also persistently access the system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, if the exploited PAT has write permissions, attackers can execute malicious code and remove workflow logs and runs, pull requests, and ‘created branches’ (isolated copies of codebases for dev experimentation). Because workflow logs are rarely streamed into security incident and event management (SIEM) platforms, attackers can easily evade detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also, notably, a developer’s PAT with access to a GitHub organization makes private repositories vulnerable; Wiz research found that 45% of organizations have plain-text cloud keys stored privately, while only 8% are in public repositories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley noted: “In some developers’ minds, a private repo equals safe, but it’s clearly not safe.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-enterprise-leaders-can-respond"&gt;How enterprise leaders can respond&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To protect themselves against these threats, enterprises should treat PATs as they would any other privileged credentials, Avakian noted. Cloud infrastructure and cloud development environments should be properly locked down, essentially “zero trustifying” them through micro segmentation and privileged user management to contain them and prevent lateral pivoting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Like any other credentials, tokens are best secured when they have reasonable expiration dates,” said Avakian. “Making tokens expire, rotating them, and using short-lived credentials will help thwart these types of risks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Least privilege everything and give accounts only the rights they need, rather than an ‘admin everything’ approach, Avakian advised. More importantly, move cloud secrets out of GitHub workflows and ensure that the proper amount of monitoring and log review processes are in place to flag surprise or unexpected workflow or cloud creation events.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beauceron’s Shipley agreed, saying that enterprises need a multi-pronged strategy, good monitoring, instant response plans, and developer training processes that are reinforced with “meaningful consequences” for non-compliance. Developers must be motivated to follow secure coding best practices; building a strong security culture in developer teams is huge. “You can’t buy a blinky box for that part of the problem,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Criminals have stepped up their game,” said Shipley. “Organizations don’t have a choice. They have to invest in these areas, or they will pay.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also, stop blindly trusting GitHub repos, he added. “The nature of repos is that they live forever. If you don’t know if you have cloud secrets inside your repos, you need to go and find them. If they’re there, you need to change them yesterday, and you need to stop adding new ones.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If there is an upside, he noted, it’s that enterprises are “victims of their own success” as they’ve raised the bar with multi-factor authentication (MFA). Gains in general security awareness makes it more difficult for criminals to obtain access and identities and compromise systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In some ways, this is a good sign,” said Shipley. “In a hilarious kind of way, it means [the criminals] are now moving into deeper levels requiring more effort.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4103696/github-action-secrets-arent-secret-anymore-exposed-pats-now-a-direct-path-into-cloud-environments.html" target="_blank"&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103717/github-action-secrets-arent-secret-anymore-exposed-pats-now-a-direct-path-into-cloud-environments-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV25-808)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-808</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools, um MCP-Server abzusichern</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4093704/tools-um-mcp-server-abzusichern.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 7200w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Gorodenkoff_shutterstock_2324952347_16z9.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Unabhängig davon, welche MCP-Server Unternehmen wofür einsetzen – “Unsicherheiten” sollten dabei außenvorbleiben.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Gorodenkoff | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Model Context Protocol (&lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/4031227/was-ist-model-context-protocol.html" target="_blank"&gt;MCP&lt;/a&gt;) verbindet KI-Agenten mit Datenquellen und erfreut sich im Unternehmensumfeld wachsender Beliebtheit. Allerdings ist auch MCP &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4032065/wie-model-context-protocol-gehackt-wird.html" target="_blank"&gt;nicht frei von Sicherheitslücken&lt;/a&gt;, wie entsprechende Entdeckungen, etwa beim SaaS-Anbieter &lt;a href="https://www.upguard.com/blog/asana-discloses-data-exposure-bug-in-mcp-server" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt; oder dem IT-Riesen &lt;a href="https://www.catonetworks.com/blog/cato-ctrl-poc-attack-targeting-atlassians-mcp/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Atlassian&lt;/a&gt; gezeigt haben. Inzwischen hat sich jedoch einiges in Sachen MCP-Sicherheit getan. Einerseits wurden mit Blick auf das Kernprotokoll etliche Fortschritte erzielt. Beispielsweise in Form von Support für OAuth sowie für Authentifizierungs-Server von Drittanbietern und Identity-Management-Systeme. Darüber hinaus wurde inzwischen auch eine &lt;a href="https://modelcontextprotocol.info/tools/registry/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;offizielle MCP Registry&lt;/a&gt; geschaffen, die einen Überblick über sichere, öffentlich verfügbare MCP-Server bietet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dennoch bestehen weiterhin Sicherheitslücken, die sich für diverse Cyberschandtaten ausnutzen lassen – &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/4044551/wenn-der-ki-agent-im-fakeshop-kauft.html" target="_blank"&gt;Prompt Injection&lt;/a&gt;, Tool Poisoning, Token-Diebstahl, Server-übergreifende Attacken oder manipulierte Messages sind nur einige von vielen Beispielen. Mit anderen Worten: Unternehmen, die sich beim &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/4049237/3-tipps-um-agentic-ai-systeme-in-der-cloud-zu-entwickeln.html" target="_blank"&gt;Aufbau von Agentic-AI-Systemen&lt;/a&gt; einen Wettbewerbsvorteil verschaffen wollen, müssen erhebliche Anstrengungen unternehmen, um zu gewährleisten, dass sensible Daten nicht nach außen dringen. Glücklicherweise gibt es diverse Tools, die dabei Unterstützung versprechen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In diesem Artikel lesen Sie:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was Security-Tools für MCP leisten sollten, und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;welche Angebote in diesem Bereich interessant sind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="das-sollten-mcp-sicherheitslosungen-konnen"&gt;Das sollten MCP-Sicherheitslösungen können&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Gefahr von Datenlecks, Prompt Injections und weiteren Sicherheitsbedrohungen besteht unabhängig davon, ob Unternehmen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ihre eigenen KI-Agenten mit MCP-Servern von Drittanbietern,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ihre eigenen MCP-Server mit Drittanbieter-Agenten, oder&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ihre eigenen Server mit den eigenen Agenten verbinden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Soll heißen: Unternehmen müssen in jedem Fall Autorisierungen und Berechtigungen überprüfen, detaillierte Zugriffskontrollen implementieren und alles protokollieren. Daraus ergeben sich auch die Anforderungen für MCP-Sicherheitslösungen. Diese sollten bieten:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCP-Servererkennung.&lt;/strong&gt; Für Mitarbeiter eines Unternehmens ist es einfach, MCP-Server herunterzuladen und zu nutzen. Mit Scan-Services für MCP-Server können Unternehmen sämtliche Instanzen von Schatten-MCP-Servern in ihrer Umgebung finden.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laufzeitschutz.&lt;/strong&gt; KI-Agenten kommunizieren mit MCP-Servern in natürlicher Sprache. MCP-Sicherheits-Tools sollten deshalb in der Lage sein, diese Kommunikation auf Sicherheitsprobleme wie Prompt Injections hin zu überwachen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentifizierungs- und Zugriffskontrollen.&lt;/strong&gt; Das MCP-Protokoll unterstützt inzwischen OAuth, aber das ist nur ein erster Schritt. Für zusätzliche Sicherheit empfehlen sich Tools mit integrierten Kontroll-Frameworks für Zero Trust und Least Privilege.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logging und Observability.&lt;/strong&gt; Tools und Plattformen sollten zudem die Möglichkeit bieten, MCP-Protokolle zu sammeln, Sicherheitsteams über Richtlinienverstöße zu informieren, Compliance-Daten zu erfassen oder Protokolle in die bestehende Sicherheitsinfrastruktur einzuspeisen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="mcp-security-angebote"&gt;MCP-Security-Angebote&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Folgenden haben wir die Anbieter von MCP-Security-Tools in drei Kategorien aufgeteilt. Diese Aufstellung erhebt keinen Anspruch auf Vollständigkeit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyperscaler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für Unternehmen, die sich vollständig auf eine bestimmte Cloud-Plattform verlassen, bieten die MCP-Tools des jeweiligen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492887/aws-google-und-azure-im-vergleich-welcher-hyperscaler-ist-der-sicherste.html" target="_blank"&gt;Hyperscalers&lt;/a&gt; einen einfachen Einstieg.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;/strong&gt; hat Mitte 2025 seine eigene agentenbasierte KI-Plattform eingeführt. &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/de/bedrock/agentcore/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Bedrock AgentCore&lt;/a&gt; umfasst ein Gateway, das mehrere Protokolle unterstützt (darunter auch MCP), ein Identity-Management-System sowie Observability.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt; bietet einen grundlegenden &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/de-de/azure/developer/azure-mcp-server/overview" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Azure-MCP-Server&lt;/a&gt; an, inklusive Support für Azure Key Vault. Darüber hinaus unterstützen auch Azure AI Foundry Agent Service und Azure API Management das Model Context Protocol. Zudem bietet Microsoft mit dem &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/de-de/agent-framework/overview/agent-framework-overview" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Agent Framework&lt;/a&gt; auch ein Open-Source-Entwicklungskit, das sowohl MCP als auch Agent2Agent unterstützt und beispielsweise Schutz vor Prompt Injections verspricht.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; kündigte Anfang 2025 seine &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/ai-machine-learning/mcp-toolbox-for-databases-now-supports-model-context-protocol?hl=en" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MCP Toolbox für Datenbanken&lt;/a&gt; an – inklusive integrierter Authentifizierung und Observability. Außerdem hat der Hyperscaler auch &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/identity-security/how-to-secure-your-remote-mcp-server-on-google-cloud?hl=en" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;eine Referenzarchitektur&lt;/a&gt; veröffentlicht, um MCP-Server auf seiner Cloud-Plattform abzusichern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Große Plattformanbieter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Der IT-Dienstleister &lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/strong&gt; hat mit &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/zero-trust-mcp-server-portals/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MCP Server Portals&lt;/a&gt; ein Tool veröffentlicht, mit dem Unternehmen MCP-Verbindungen zentralisiert absichern und überwachen können. Die Funktion ist Bestandteil der Cloudflare-One-Plattform.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palo Alto Networks&lt;/strong&gt; hat mit Blick auf MCP-Sicherheit mehrere Eisen im Feuer. Mit &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/blog/2025/06/securing-ai-agent-innovation-prisma-airs-mcp-server/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Prisma AIRS&lt;/a&gt; hat das Unternehmen einen eigenen, intermediären MCP-Server veröffentlicht. Dieser sitzt zwischen den KI-Agenten und dem eigentlichen MCP-Server und erkennt schadhafte Inhalte und Daten. Das Tool &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/blog/2025/06/cloud-security-model-context-protocol-mcp-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MCP Security&lt;/a&gt; ist hingegen Bestandteil von Cortex Cloud WAAS und überprüft die MCP-Kommunikation an der Netzwerkgrenze auf bösartige Aktivitäten.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SentinelOne&lt;/strong&gt; gewährt mit seiner &lt;a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/avoiding-mcp-mania-how-to-secure-the-next-frontier-of-ai/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Singularity Platform&lt;/a&gt; ebenfalls Einblick in die MCP-Interaktionskette und bietet zum Beispiel Warnmeldungen und automatisierte Incident Response für MCP-Server auf lokaler oder Remote-Ebene.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Daneben hat auch &lt;strong&gt;Broadcom&lt;/strong&gt; MCP-Sicherheitsfunktionen für VMware Cloud Foundation &lt;a href="https://www.broadcom.com/company/news/product-releases/63401" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;angekündigt&lt;/a&gt;, die künftig mehr Sicherheit für agentenbasierte Workflows gewährleisten sollen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Startups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Die &lt;a href="https://acuvity.ai/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Plattform&lt;/a&gt; von &lt;strong&gt;Acuvity&lt;/strong&gt; verspricht, MCP-Server umfassend abzusichern. Dafür sorgt laut dem Anbieter eine Kombination aus Least-Privilege-Execution, unveränderlichen Laufzeiten, kontinuierlichen Schwachstellenscans, Authentifizierung und Bedrohungserkennung.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Das API-Security-Startup &lt;strong&gt;Akto&lt;/strong&gt; hat eine &lt;a href="https://www.akto.io/mcp-security" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MCP-Security-Plattform&lt;/a&gt; im Angebot. Sie umfasst ein Discovery Tool, um MCP-Server in Unternehmensumgebungen zu identifizieren, Security-Testing-Werkzeuge sowie Monitoring- und Threat-Detection-Funktionen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invariant Labs&lt;/strong&gt; bietet mit &lt;a href="https://github.com/invariantlabs-ai/mcp-scan" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MCP-Scan&lt;/a&gt; ein quelloffenes Tool, das die statische Analyse und Echtzeitüberwachung von MCP-Servern ermöglicht. Mit &lt;a href="https://invariantlabs.ai/blog/guardrails" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Guardrails&lt;/a&gt; hat das Startup auch ein kommerzielles Produkt im Angebot. Dabei handelt es sich um einen Proxy. Der zwischen KI-Agenten und MCP-Servern sitzt und vor Security-Risiken schützen soll. Das Tool befähigt Anwender außerdem dazu, Richtlinien aufzusetzen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Die &lt;a href="https://www.getjavelin.com/ai-security" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AI Security Fabric-Plattform&lt;/a&gt; von &lt;strong&gt;Javelin&lt;/strong&gt; addressiert ebenfalls das Thema MCP-Sicherheit. Etwa mit Funktionen wie MCP-Server auf Risiken zu scannen oder Datenanfragen zu überprüfen.  &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lasso Security&lt;/strong&gt; stellt ein Open-Source-&lt;a href="https://github.com/lasso-security/mcp-gateway" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MCP-Gateway&lt;/a&gt; zur Verfügung, das die Konfiguration und das Lebenszyklusmanagement von MCP-Servern ermöglicht und Messages um sensible Informationen bereinigt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4093704/tools-um-mcp-server-abzusichern.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key cybersecurity takeaways from the 2026 NDAA</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103754/key-cybersecurity-takeaways-from-the-2026-ndaa.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On Dec. 7, the House and Senate Homeland Security Committees released their &lt;a href="https://armedservices.house.gov/uploadedfiles/fy26_ndaa_conference_text_legislative_summary.pdf"&gt;compromise version&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href="https://armedservices.house.gov/uploadedfiles/rcp_text_of_house_amendment_to_s._1071.pdf"&gt;2026 National Defense and Authorization Act (NDAA)&lt;/a&gt;, a nearly 3,100-page piece of legislation that contains a host of provisions to fund several Department of Defense cybersecurity efforts in fiscal year 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although cybersecurity is referenced hundreds of times across the NDAA, the legislation contains provisions that, once the law becomes effective, will mark significant shifts in how the US military manages major cybersecurity tasks, particularly in the timely arena of protecting mobile communications of top brass and AI deployments, as well as more understated, but potentially high-impact, infosec duties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although numbers chronically vary widely for NDAA cyber expenses, depending on the source or the year, according to a July &lt;a href="https://comptroller.war.gov/Portals/45/Documents/defbudget/FY2026/FY2026_Budget_Request_Overview_Book.pdf"&gt;budget request&lt;/a&gt; from the CFO for the Defense Department, the cyber activities in the NDAA request for FY2026 are approximately $15.1 billion, or 4.1% more than the previous year’s request. This cyber budget bump stands in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4019109/trump-seeks-unprecedented-1-23-billion-cut-to-federal-cyber-budget.html"&gt;stark contrast&lt;/a&gt; to proposed double-digit cuts for civilian agencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Around $9.1 billion of that amount goes to pure cybersecurity efforts, with the rest allocated to not clearly defined “cyberspace operations” of US Cyber Command, the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Defense Threat Reduction Agency, the National Security Agency, and the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense, Research and Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Around $611.9 million of the total was allocated to DoD cyber research for the “deployment and modernization of existing capabilities and technologies that advance next generation cybersecurity and cyberspace operations programs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="securing-mobile-phones-for-top-officials"&gt;Securing mobile phones for top officials&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Few cyber risks are as operationally consequential as insecure mobile communications, and the NDAA directly targets this gap with new mandates for how the Pentagon procures and protects devices for top officials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill requires that, no later than 90 days after enactment, the DoD will ensure that each wireless mobile phone and all related telecommunications the department provides to senior military officials or any other employee who performs sensitive national security functions are acquired under contracts or other agreements that require enhanced cybersecurity protections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Under the bill, enhanced cybersecurity protections mean encrypted data, capabilities to mitigate or obfuscate persistent device identifiers, including periodic rotation of network or hardware identifiers to reduce the risk of inappropriate tracking of the activity or location of the wireless mobile phones, and the capability to monitor the wireless mobile phones continuously.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Under the legislation, 180 days after the bill’s enactment, the Secretary of Defense must submit to the relevant congressional defense committees a report detailing the mobile telecommunications contracts the Pentagon has entered pursuant to these provisions, how it determined which employees these mobile provisions apply to, and the total costs of wireless mobile phones and telecommunication services involved.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is likely no coincidence that these provisions follow the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101859/insecure-use-of-signal-app-part-of-wider-department-of-defense-problem-suggests-senate-report.html"&gt;so-called Signalgate incidents from earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. During those incidents, the current DoD head Pete Hegseth shared over Signal via his private mobile device “nonpublic” information that identified “the quantity and strike times of manned US aircraft over hostile territory over an unapproved, unsecure network approximately two to four hours before the execution of those strikes,” according to a &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/Dec/04/2003834916/-1/-1/1/DODIG_2026_021.PDF"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; released on Dec. 2 by the department’s inspector general.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-and-machine-learning-security-and-procurement-requirements"&gt;AI and machine learning security and procurement requirements&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recognizing that AI now underpins everything from battlefield planning to intelligence analysis, the bill introduces sweeping requirements to safeguard these systems from emerging digital threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NDAA spells out a spate of policy and procurement practices that the military should meet regarding artificial intelligence and machine learning (ML). First, the DoD, in consultation with other Federal agencies, has 180 days after the date of enactment to develop and implement a department-wide policy for the cybersecurity and associated governance of AI and ML systems and applications, as well as the models for AI and ML used in national defense applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The policy must protect against security threats to AI and machine learning, including model serialization attacks, model tampering, data leakage, adversarial prompt injection, model extraction, model jailbreaks, and supply chain attacks. It also must employ cybersecurity measures throughout the life cycle of systems using artificial intelligence or machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the policy must reflect the adoption of industry-recognized frameworks to guide the development and implementation of AI and ML security best practices. Likewise, it must follow standards for governance, testing, auditing, and monitoring of systems using artificial intelligence and machine learning to ensure the integrity and resilience of such systems against corruption and unauthorized manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, the AI and machine learning policy must accommodate training requirements for the department’s workforce to ensure personnel are prepared to identify and mitigate vulnerabilities specific to AI and ML.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill further spells out physical and cybersecurity procurement requirements for AI and machine learning systems. It specifies that the defense secretary must develop a framework for the implementation of cybersecurity and physical security standards and best practices relating to AI and ML technologies to mitigate risks to the department from the use of such technologies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NDAA specifies that the framework must cover all relevant aspects of the security of AI and ML systems, including the risk posed to and by the DoD workforce, including insider threat risks, training and workforce development requirements regarding artificial intelligence security awareness, artificial intelligence-specific threats and vulnerabilities, professional development and education, supply chain threats (including counterfeits), tampering risks, unintended exposure or theft of AI systems or data, security management practices and more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It also requires the framework to draw on existing frameworks, including the NIST Special Publication 800 series and existing DoD frameworks, including the Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification framework.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, under the legislation, the framework must prioritize the most highly capable AI systems that may be of highest interest to cyber threat actors, based on risk assessments and threat reporting, and impose requirements for security on contractors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other AI provisions under the NDAA require the DoD to revise the mandatory training on cybersecurity for members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the department to include content related to the unique cybersecurity challenges posed by artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bill further says that by April 1, 2026, the DoD needs to establish a task force on AI sandbox environments to identify, coordinate, and advance department-wide efforts to develop and deploy AI sandbox environments necessary to support experimentation, training, familiarization, and development across the military.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="other-noteworthy-cyber-related-ndaa-provisions"&gt;Other noteworthy cyber-related NDAA provisions&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond mobile security and AI governance, the NDAA includes a broad array of cyber measures with strategic implications across defense, intelligence, and international partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The following are among the more noteworthy cybersecurity provisions in the compromise bill:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commercial spyware: &lt;/strong&gt;The bill contains a “sense of Congress” statement that there is a national security need for the legitimate and responsible procurement and application of cyber intrusion capabilities, including efforts related to counterterrorism, counternarcotics, and countertrafficking. It expresses the view that the proliferation of commercial spyware presents significant and growing risks to national security, including to the safety and security of government personnel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It suggests that the US should oppose the misuse of commercial spyware “to target individuals, including journalists, defenders of internationally recognized human rights, and members of civil society groups, members of ethnic or religious minority groups, and others for exercising their internationally recognized human rights and fundamental freedoms, or the family members of these targeted individuals.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It also further stipulates that the US should coordinate with allies and partners to prevent the export of commercial spyware tools to end-users likely to use them for malicious activities, and to share information on this issue with allies robustly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation of national security risks posed by foreign adversary acquisition of American multiomic data: &lt;/strong&gt;The bill stipulates that not later than 270 days after its enactment, the director of national intelligence, in consultation with the secretary of defense, the US attorney general the secretary of health and humans services, the secretary of commerce, the secretary of homeland security, the secretary of state, and the national cyber director, shall complete an assessment of risks to national security posed by human multiomic data from US citizens that is collected or stored by a foreign adversary from the provision of biotechnology equipment or services. Multiomic data combines different types of biological data, such as genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics, to provide a complete picture of a biological system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biological data for artificial intelligence:&lt;/strong&gt; The legislation calls for tiered levels of cybersecurity safeguards and access controls for the storage of biological data and contains requirements for the protection of the privacy of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cybersecurity regulatory harmonization: &lt;/strong&gt;By June 1, 2026, the DoD must harmonize the cybersecurity requirements applicable to the defense industrial base, reduce the number of such requirements that are unique to a specific contract or other agreement, and submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the actions taken to carry out the harmonization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cybersecurity and resilience annex in Strategic Rail Corridor Network assessments: &lt;/strong&gt;The legislation says the defense secretary, in coordination with the transportation secretary and the homeland security secretary, should conduct a periodic evaluation of the Strategic Rail Corridor Network. The assessment must include an annex containing a review of the cybersecurity and the resilience of the physical infrastructure of the Strategic Rail Corridor. The Strategic Rail Corridor is the interconnected network of rail corridors important to national defense and military mobility, as defined by the Department of Defense and the Federal Railroad Administration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber workforce recruitment and retention: &lt;/strong&gt;The billrequires the defense secretary to fix the rates of basic pay for military employees working on cyber with a pay rate on par with comparable employees elsewhere in the government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supporting cybersecurity and cyber resilience in the Western Balkans: &lt;/strong&gt;The NDAA contains a “sense of Congress” statement that the United States support for cybersecurity, cyber resilience, and secure ICT infrastructure in Western Balkans countries will strengthen the region’s ability to defend itself from and respond to malicious cyber activity conducted by nonstate and foreign actors, including foreign governments, that seek to influence the region.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demonstration of real-time monitoring capabilities to enhance weapon system platforms&lt;/strong&gt;: If funds are available&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;the secretary of defense, in coordinationwith the undersecretary of defense for acquisition andsustainment and the service acquisition executives, will carry out a demonstration to equip selected weapon systemplatforms with onboard, near real-time, end-to-end serialbus and radio frequency monitoring capabilities to detectcyber threats and improve maintenance efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103754/key-cybersecurity-takeaways-from-the-2026-ndaa.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-809)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-809</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-810)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-810</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-804) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisories-av25-804</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum meets AI: The next cybersecurity battleground</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103288/quantum-meets-ai-the-next-cybersecurity-battleground.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In recent years, artificial intelligence (AI) has been spreading its tentacles across the global technological landscape, as evidenced by the increase in autonomous and automated technologies and their deployment across industries and sectors. While the world is still recovering from the global impact of AI, quantum computing is gradually emerging. In quantum computing, the principles of quantum mechanics are used to perform calculations, enabling the solution of complex problems faster than classical computers. Some have described the recent AI boom and the soon-to-be fully emerged quantum as the ‘mind’ and ‘muscle’ respectively. If this analogy is true, one can only imagine the resultant effect when the ‘mind’ meets the ‘muscle’, and that is where we are heading.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The collision of these two technologies promised to be the next major technological battleground capable of shaping computing, cybersecurity and even geopolitical power structures. With these two forces, not only will the way we compute be redefined in the 21st century, but also how power, privacy and innovation will be distributed. This is because, while AI algorithms are known to recognize patterns and learning from data that was fed into them, quantum computers are capable of exploring multiple paths simultaneously, making it easy to unlock a computing revolution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="quantum-logic-reshaping-the-internet"&gt;Quantum logic reshaping the internet&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At its core of invention, quantum computing goes beyond being just faster computers, but is uniquely designed to create an entirely different universe of processing. Instead of using bits (0s and 1s) as it’s applicable in AI, quantum computers use qubits, which can exist in multiple states simultaneously through the principles of superposition and entanglement. By implication, a well and thoroughly designed quantum system can solve problems in microseconds, compared to classical computers, which could take years to solve the same and similar problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This could enable ultra-secure communication through what is known as &lt;a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/whitepaper/quantum-networking-technologies" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;quantum key distribution&lt;/a&gt; (QKD). Consequently, data interception would be made nearly impossible, which could reshape global connectivity, providing faster power and more secure digital infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-ai-meets-quantum-power"&gt;When AI meets quantum power&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The concept of AI systems greatly depends on data input into the AI algorithm, which means the more data that is fed into the Algorithm, the better the output. Most AI systems are commonly faced with hardware limitations, and some of the largest AI systems, like ChatGPT and DeepMind’s AlphaFold, among others, are known to be confronted with these challenges. However, with quantum, these limitations are not present. This is because quantum machine learning (QML) is leveraged to perform tasks such as pattern recognition, optimisation and simulation. Additionally, with the concept of QML training, the need to train data in real time with massive data centres will no longer be necessary. In practical terms, the impact of quantum capacity and its application would be felt more than training billions of AI model parameters for minutes, as the expected output will now be achieved in microseconds. For instance, realizing global climate systems in real-time and simulating financial markets can now be achieved in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-darker-side-of-quantum-ai-synergy"&gt;The darker side of quantum-AI synergy&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As good as this collision is, a dark undercurrent could emerge, where these very brilliant technologies that promise to transform our way of doing things could also be weaponised by state actors or cybercriminals. The malicious attackers can utilize the combination of AI and quantum to actualize quantum-enhanced cyber threats. Researchers are also of the view of the possibilities that cybercriminals will be able to decrypt modern encryptions like elliptic curve cryptography (ECC), advanced encryption standard (AES) and Rivest-Shamir-Adleman (RSA), among others.  For instance, RSA and ECC are practical encryption methods used in financial institutions to protect online transactions. When these are compromised, they render the confidentiality of scrambled data exposed, hence allowing unauthorized access to such information. The day that this happened is already tagged ‘&lt;a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2024/07/01/pqc-standardization/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Q-Day’&lt;/a&gt;, that is, when quantum computers become powerful enough to break today’s encryption standards. Additionally, other security breaches like password cracking, forging digital certificates or even deepfaking (that is, impersonating AI systems) are among others that can be triggered by cybercriminals with the advent of quantum and AI.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="preparing-for-q-day-the-cybersecurity-paradox"&gt;Preparing for Q-Day: The cybersecurity paradox&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As most systems now employ cryptographic keys to provide confidentiality to their data, Q-Day, the moment when quantum computers become powerful enough to break existing encryption, would render some of these efforts useless. So, organization and government institutions alike are bracing ahead of Q-Day since the internet, government databases, corporate organizations’ databases and even financial systems could easily be cracked. For instance, while the UK’s National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) has outlined a phased approach with a 2035 target set for complete migration across all systems, the US is mandating a similar transition for its National Security Systems by 2,030. These efforts are a proactive defence approach that focuses on developing &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/post-quantum-cryptography" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;quantum-resistant encryption models&lt;/a&gt;, ensuring the security of cryptographic keys and adaptive cybersecurity policies to withstand the coming quantum age.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="trust-the-new-currency-of-innovation"&gt;Trust: The new currency of innovation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of quantum systems is that they operate based on probabilities, and not certainties. Similarly, the output of AI systems can easily be marred by inappropriate data quality, data bias, lack of explainability and transparency, adversarial threats, ethical concerns and governance concerns. The real battles that the developer of this innovation should concentrate on should not only revolve around their speed, efficiency or building the most potent combination of quantum and AI systems, but trust. Trust is essential as the ultimate expectation of any built system is to generate the expected outcome. Therefore, if AI represents intelligence, and quantum represents uncertainty, then ‘ How do we trust outcomes from systems we cannot fully explain?’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Therefore, trust would need to be built through cybersecurity frameworks and regulations to enhance security, transparency and governance. This would help in addressing the post-quantum cryptography, AI auditing, explainability and ethical oversight, which will form the foundation of resilient digital ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-road-ahead"&gt;The road ahead&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although AI and quantum computing will not replace human intelligence, their fingerprints will be seen all over the place in the not-too-distant future. While it is evident today that AI is already transforming the industries, the future holds that both AI and quantum will further provide innovations beyond what humans can imagine in various sectors such as energy, healthcare, finance and national defence, among others. However, the real question is whether society can adapt to the pace at which these technologies are moving before they control us.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="looking-beyond-innovation"&gt;Looking beyond innovation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is now clear that the convergence of artificial intelligence and quantum computing not only provides technological breakthroughs but also cybersecurity challenges. Putting them together, computation, problem-solving and data analysis will be more effective and efficient at unimaginable scales. Despite positive capabilities, the tendency for them to be threatened and undermine the very foundations of digital trust and privacy that modern societies depend upon is very high. Therefore, as quantum computing is gradually coming up with Q-Day approaching, the urgency to prepare for a post-quantum world becomes increasingly clear.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consequently, organizations, governments and cybersecurity experts should now start looking beyond innovation and the technological advancement that these technologies deliver and start focusing on resilience. This would involve a massive investment in advancing ethical AI governance, developing regulatory frameworks and regulations, and building post-quantum cryptographic standards in existing systems to maintain security and public confidence. Therefore, the race should not only be focused on developing advanced technologies, but also on creating secure technologies that are not easily prone to attacks by cybercriminals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103288/quantum-meets-ai-the-next-cybersecurity-battleground.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can staff+ security engineers force-multiply their impact?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103311/how-can-staff-security-engineers-force-multiply-their-impact.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://leaddev.com/career-development/what-do-we-mean-staff" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Staff+ engineers&lt;/a&gt; play a critical role in designing, scaling and influencing the security posture of an organization. Their key areas of expertise include developing security strategy and governance, incident response leadership, automation, compliance/risk management and cross-org collaboration to shape security culture. Together, these capabilities are essential to enhance application security and the effectiveness of their organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, in our experience, we have seen that many staff+ security engineers face scaling challenges. Instead of leveraging their expertise to drive broad, cross-stack impact, they tend to concentrate on specific incidents or focus areas, which limits their ability to extend their influence and strategic reach. Such a scaling problem has consequences on the organization and its personal goals. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also, leadership considers staff+ engineers as trusted advisors, helping them make high-judgment decisions. However, when engineers tend to get stuck on specific tactical incidents or solutions, leaders are left without their strategic insights. Conversely, staff+ engineers who are too busy in the weeds, miss to proactively look out for their “leaders’ problems.” Leaders perceive these engineers as too busy and hesitate to increase their scope and loop them in broader discussions, which ultimately leads to missed opportunities for the staff+ security engineers. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of practices that staff+ engineers can adopt to enable them to scale and &lt;a href="https://www.theengineeringmanager.com/growth/force-multipliers/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;force-multiply&lt;/a&gt; their impact across their organization. Remember, you, as a staff+ security engineer, are ultimately an enabler, not a bottleneck!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="practical-ideas-to-help-you-scale"&gt;Practical ideas to help you scale&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the most common ideas in people management, “scaling through others,” is well-applicable to staff+ security engineers. It basically means amplifying your impact not by doing more work yourself, but by enabling many others to work more effectively and productively with your influence. In other words, you’ll not do best by being a hero, but by creating “mini you’s” across the organization. When applied with discipline, scaling through others’ work well in practical settings. Here are some ideas you can consider: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="create-mechanisms-that-allow-you-to-scale"&gt;Create mechanisms that allow you to scale&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mechanisms enforce or reinforce a behavior automatically. Also, they are not one-size-fits-all, but with some trial and error, we have observed that strong mechanisms consistently support desired behavior. For example, a &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/cyberpedia/what-is-policy-as-code" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;policy-as-code&lt;/a&gt; framework integrated into CI/CD pipelines automatically enforces security and compliance policies, reducing manual checks and human error. While this is an example of a technical mechanism (which we will talk more about in the next section), mechanisms can also be people-oriented, say, mentorship programs or mentorship trees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="determine-where-to-dive-deeper-and-where-to-delegate"&gt;Determine where to dive deeper and where to delegate&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Being an expert in the area, staff+ engineers can pretty much dive in anywhere from critical incidents to strategic initiatives. They may be drawn in by urgent team needs, their own curiosity or something else. But it is crucial for them to carefully evaluate where to make and avoid costly commitments. Asking a set of targeted questions can provide valuable insight: “What is the potential impact on security posture or risk to the organization?”; “Is there an established process or tooling (‘paved path’) to address this?”; and “Is this a one-time incident or a recurring security challenge that requires a scalable, strategic solution?” Often, true learning comes from failure. If the risk is manageable, allow others to step up and learn from their own failures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="create-a-trusted-group"&gt;Create a trusted group&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To scale through others, you will need a group to rely on. Some organizations solve this problem via job levels, where staff+ engineer roles are defined to scale through other roles like senior security engineers. In other cases, you might need to define your selection criteria and training path. Just creating this group is not enough; an action plan and thorough execution are critical. In practice, such working groups run brown-bag sessions, create mentorship and recognition programs and discuss/review solutions that help lift the organization’s security KPIs. Additionally, mentorship sessions and office hours from staff+ engineers help build working relationships that last.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="employ-non-security-engineers-to-the-cause"&gt;Employ non-security engineers to the cause&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Involving application engineers in the security cause is an often-overlooked “hack” that works well in industrial settings. This “shift-left” approach involves embedding security practices directly into the software development pipeline, enabling development teams to take ownership of security controls and assessments early in the lifecycle. Programs such as &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-project-security-culture/v10/4-Security_Champions/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;security champions&lt;/a&gt; or security reviewers empower application engineers to integrate standard security and compliance practices as part of their regular workflows, reducing bottlenecks and fostering a security-first mindset. Staff+ security engineers should look for opportunities to drive the creation of these programs, enable cross-functional collaboration and scale through application engineers to increase their impact. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="eliminate-anti-patterns"&gt;Eliminate anti-patterns&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we would recommend staff+ security engineers to inspect and eliminate anti-patterns in their (and peer) organizations. These anti-patterns work against scaling and make them and their organizations bottlenecks, instead of enablers. One example we have commonly seen is when security engineers act as permanent gatekeepers. This “block by default” approach is expensive and needs significant time investment for staff+ engineers and slows down business. Similarly, policies without exceptions are a time drain for both security and application teams. We highly recommend staff+ security engineers to proactively identify such patterns and replace them with mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="technical-mechanisms-to-consider"&gt;Technical mechanisms to consider&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To effectively scale their impact, staff+ security engineers should champion a comprehensive technical approach that integrates secure practices into every layer of the organization, technology and culture. This ultimately acts as a mechanism or guardrails for their organizations, ensuring their guidance is automatically enforced and allowing them time for strategic influence. Key elements include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incorporate focused action areas in the organization-wide security strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; While staff+ security engineers are responsible for developing a clear, actionable security strategy, we recommend they encompass policy-as-code enforcement, risk gates and continuous monitoring. Leverage the trusted group to assign ownership by appointing area leaders who drive accountability and progress within their domains. Review their findings and tune the strategy periodically. This helps staff+ engineers avoid the need to inspect every aspect of a large organization’s security strategy.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adopt reference architectures and &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/information/secure-default" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;secure-by-default&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; reusable modules:&lt;/strong&gt; We recommend staff+ security engineers to build and provide trusted, opinionated blueprints, golden images, baseline policies and reusable components that make secure design the path of least resistance for development teams. Building such “paved paths” enables seamless and secure development for teams without developer whiplash. Finally, using trusted groups to drive adoption, they can effectively influence teams’ technical direction.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/en-us/cybersecurity-101/cloud-security/shift-left-security/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shift-left&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; security practices:&lt;/strong&gt; Briefly discussed before, integrating security early in the development lifecycle is the central theme of modern-day &lt;a href="https://www.devsecops.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DevSecOps&lt;/a&gt; practices. Embedding automated controls, threat modeling and validation tools into pull requests, CI/CD pipelines and infrastructure-as-code (IaC) plans enables developers to catch and fix issues before deployment without workflow disruption. Consequently, this allows staff+ engineers (and their organizations) to reduce security bugs that reach production.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage AI-driven scanning tools and automation cautiously:&lt;/strong&gt; The rapid development of GenAI has unlocked significant capabilities in security tooling. AI tools are now available that strengthen security practices through adaptive learning, risk prioritization and context-aware detection. Staff+ security engineers should champion the adoption of these tools to enhance vulnerability detection and streamline workflows. Supplementing these tools with expert reviews helps mitigate false positives and assess the impact of security vulnerabilities effectively.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardrails over Gates:&lt;/strong&gt; We recommend staff+ security engineers to build checks that enforce blocking only on high confidence and high impact security signals, while warning or logging lower risk issues to maintain velocity. Using compensating controls like monitoring, automated remediation and risk scoring to manage risks without blocking progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The overall guiding principle we recommend for all staff+ security engineers is to make the secure way the easiest and most intuitive path for all engineers; this helps security to scale sustainably alongside business growth. We believe this guiding principle, along with the above technical framework, enables staff+ security engineers to force-multiply their impact by embedding robust security foundations, fostering a culture of shared ownership and automating enforcement. The result is a resilient, scalable and developer-friendly security posture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="incident-influence"&gt;Incident influence&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, how can staff+ security engineers force-multiply their impact during active security incidents? The most critical tool that the engineer has in such a scenario is their mindset: “You’re the stabilizer, not the savior.” Take the role of an orchestrator: If you get too deep into the logs, other areas that need support will suffer. Look to assign tactical work to different individual contributors and focus on leading the incident, coordinating across roles and managing leadership communications. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Next, it is critical to identify inflection points. You will be expected to make high-velocity, high-judgement decisions that decide the course of &lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/trust/security/security-incident-management" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;incident management&lt;/a&gt;. Determine thresholds beyond which upper leadership involvement or additional support is essential. Utilize the inflection points to guide you when to move from containment to recovery to retrospective. Once the situation is in control, switch to an influencer role and scale through others, in line with your standard engagement mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="act-as-a-bridge-between-leadership-and-teams"&gt;Act as a bridge between leadership and teams&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lastly, note that you are a link between management/leadership and engineers on the ground. Managers may not fully understand the details of execution or delays in identifying/remediating vulnerabilities in the software. Teams will rely on you to identify and bridge process gaps or represent them to leadership for decision-making. For example, in our case, our team was hesitating to adopt a powerful static analysis tool. While the team identified it as a critical need, it had high licensing costs, leading to multiple back-and-forth discussions. When our principal staff engineer learned about it, she promptly created a one-page document with the pros and cons and aligned leaders on funding it due to the high return-on-investment. She resolved a two-week team debate and analysis in just one afternoon. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Conversely, you are also the leadership’s representative on the ground, shepherding the team along the leadership’s direction. Consider influencing the teams in building and reviewing deep visibility dashboards that accurately capture key security insights. This provides leaders with a strong feedback loop and real-time visibility on the consequences of their decisions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="final-thoughts"&gt;Final thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The journey of a staff+ security engineer is about transitioning from individual contributions to a force multiplier. This is especially important as AI and automation redefine scale; the leaders who design for empowerment will define the next era of cybersecurity engineering. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103311/how-can-staff-security-engineers-force-multiply-their-impact.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making cybercrime illegal won’t stop it; making cybersec research legal may</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104382/security-researchers-given-new-boost.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hacking into computer systems is illegal in many countries — even if you’re a cybersecurity researcher figuring out how to better defend systems. But Portugal has just introduced an exemption for researchers, and the UK is thinking of doing so too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last week, British security minister &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/people/dan-jarvis" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dan Jarvis&lt;/a&gt; set out &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/keynote-address-to-ft-cyber-resilience-summit-2025" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a new approach to combatting computer crime&lt;/a&gt;, highlighting the damage that security breaches have done to the UK economy and emphasizing the importance of computer security researchers. The next day, &lt;a href="https://diariodarepublica.pt/dr/detalhe/decreto-lei/125-2025-962603401" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Portuguese parliament passed an act&lt;/a&gt; giving more protection to the same group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In his speech, Jarvis explained how the UK’s &lt;a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1990/18/contents" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1990 Computer Misuse Act&lt;/a&gt; had outlived its usefulness, stating, “it can leave many cyber security experts feeling constrained in the activity that they can undertake. These researchers play an important role in increasing the resilience of UK systems, and securing them from unknown vulnerabilities. We shouldn’t be shutting these people out, we should be welcoming them and their work.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He went on to say that the government is looking to upgrade current legislation. “We are looking at a legal change to the Computer Misuse Act. This would create a ‘statutory defense’ for these researchers to spot and share vulnerabilities, which would protect them from prosecution, as long as they meet certain safeguards.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Portuguese legislation also offers a degree of protection to security researchers, provided that they don’t seek to gain financial advantage and don’t breach data protection laws.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These updated approaches from the UK and Portugal are in line with other countries’ statutory protection for researchers; the Netherlands, France and Belgium have all introduced similar guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jarvis’s proposals have been warmly received by the security industry. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/charlotte-m-wilson/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Charlotte Wilson&lt;/a&gt;, head of enterprise business, UK and Ireland at Check Point Software, said that the Computer Misuse Act was outdated and not fit for purpose. “As it stands, it treats security researchers in much the same way as cybercriminals, even when they are acting in good faith to strengthen defenses rather than undermine them,” she pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, she added, “the solution is relatively simple: create a legal safe space that allows researchers to test systems and report vulnerabilities responsibly, without fear of prosecution. Portugal has recently taken this important step by introducing clear rules for good-faith testing and a framework for responsible disclosure. It’s a pragmatic model that recognizes the essential role researchers play in identifying and fixing security weaknesses and something the UK should seriously consider adopting.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wilson stressed, however, that organizations should not be entirely dependent on government action; businesses could also take steps to help researchers. “They should publish a clear vulnerability disclosure policy that outlines how researchers can safely report issues; respond swiftly to vulnerabilities and define boundaries by being transparent about what testing is permitted, how to report findings, and what the process entails.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Her views were echoed by &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/drayagha/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dray Agha&lt;/a&gt;, senior manager of security operations at Huntress. “Organizations can support the process by rewarding responsible disclosure, avoiding knee-jerk legal threats, participating in community initiatives, and advocating for reforms that strike the right balance between preventing abuse and enabling legitimate research,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He added that the government should ensure that researchers are fully protected, calling for an independent oversight body to validate and support responsible research. “This could provide rapid advisory opinions, mediate disclosure disputes, and issue assurance letters so researchers are not left exposed when organizations are slow or uncooperative.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, he noted, companies are often slow to disclose security breaches, something which needs to change. “User organizations should be legally obliged to maintain a disclosure channel, acknowledge reports promptly, and work within a set remediation window. This lifts the burden from researchers and reduces the grey zone where they feel legally at risk,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This will be music to the ears of Dan Jarvis, who, in his speech, stressed the need for co-operation. “This work is not the responsibility of the government alone,” he said. “We need a whole of society approach. We can only create a proper deterrence through partnership, which is why the government and business are working together to improve our security. For too long, businesses and politicians have been under the misapprehension that cyber investment is a drag on growth. But this is a mistake. Cyber security keeps us safe – and is a key enabler of growth.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jarvis’s speech is only a precursor to any legislation, but it is clear that the UK is set to go down the path that other countries have taken, finally giving security researchers their day in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104382/security-researchers-given-new-boost.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to justify your security investments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104472/how-to-justify-your-security-investments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In modern corporate environments, investments in security technologies are no longer judged solely on technical maturity. Funding increasingly depends on the extent to which they can generate revenue, mitigate risks, and create shareholder value.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, CISOs are expected to present their strategies not as mere technical upgrades, but as enablers of revenue growth. The challenge lies not only in making the right investment decisions, but also in justifying them at the board level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs often find themselves on the defensive when they present solutions before the challenge has been clearly defined. This approach creates disconnect &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3955001/decision-making-101-how-to-get-consensus-right.html"&gt;instead of consensus&lt;/a&gt;. Executives want to understand what their organization can achieve with a new solution, which pitfalls can be avoided, and why cybersecurity investments cannot be postponed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Therefore, when presenting a cybersecurity strategy, for example, zero trust, the focus of communication with the board should be on how the company’s cyber risk profile can be changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="linking-security-technology-with-strategic-priorities"&gt;Linking security technology with strategic priorities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To be credible in the boardroom, CISOs must define their planned expenditures in line with the company’s objectives. The board focuses on priorities such as entering new markets, improving margins, increasing resilience, and ensuring compliance. A well-thought-out proposal directly addresses these concerns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When a security platform reduces incident response time, the result is operational stability and therefore &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2111061/cyber-resilience-a-business-imperative-cisos-must-get-right.html"&gt;greater resilience&lt;/a&gt;. When it &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2515727/6-tips-for-consolidating-your-it-security-tool-set.html"&gt;consolidates tools&lt;/a&gt;, it ensures cost efficiency. When it enables secure expansion into new regions, revenue growth follows. Such a line of reasoning builds credibility and helps secure investment approvals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-language-of-risks-and-returns"&gt;The language of risks and returns&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boards of directors make decisions considering concepts such as risk and return. These include financial risks, operational risks, and reputational risks for the company. Board members assess the probability, exposure, and impact of incidents in each of these areas. Accordingly, the CISO’s role is to clarify how a proposed investment reduces vulnerabilities, limits the impact of incidents, or increases infrastructure resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These discussions should outline cost models, scenarios for potential security breaches, recovery timelines after a cyberattack, and the business benefits. The goal should be to avoid downtime while speaking the language of the board of directors, without compromising technical integrity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="consider-shareholder-value"&gt;Consider shareholder value&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The maturity level and mindsets of boards regarding cybersecurity vary considerably. Some supervisory boards react only after a major cyber incident or a failed audit. Others are much more proactive in their approach and require cybersecurity assessments as part of their market expansion or M&amp;amp;A activities. Still others incorporate cybersecurity into simulations and ask forward-looking questions about resilience in the face of potential attack scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Understanding this level of maturity helps in adapting the communication strategy. A reactive board may need a clear explanation of the negative consequences. An informed board is more likely to expect quantifiable results and a roadmap. The best board discussions occur when the CISO adapts to the board’s understanding of technology while carefully broadening its perspective.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="positioning-operational-excellence-as-an-outcome"&gt;Positioning operational excellence as an outcome&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the most effective arguments in discussions with the board regarding cybersecurity is operational excellence. When companies operate in different regions and industries, they must work agilely, securely, and with control. An IT architecture should:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Address global requirements&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Support employees who work from anywhere&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Integrate third parties&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Meet a number of regulatory requirements&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Protect intellectual property&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such a comprehensive set of requirements can very quickly lead to complex implementation and, consequently, inefficiencies. CISOs, with a strong technology strategy, focus on a simplified infrastructure, enabling secure global data flows and shortening time to market. This positioning elevates the discussion from system selection to a strategic level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="focus-on-future-risks"&gt;Focus on future risks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A board of directors is expected to focus not only on current risks but also on future scenarios. These include, for example, &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3984527/how-to-establish-an-effective-ai-grc-framework.html"&gt;regulating the ethical use of AI&lt;/a&gt;, understanding the impact of data misuse, and preparing for the effects of quantum computing. The board will be responsible and even held liable for the secure and regulated handling of data. These are no longer abstract issues. Therefore, they should already be on the CISO’s agenda as future technological challenges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The use of AI has increased in companies, and executives are now responsible for data usage. While quantum computing is still in its early stages, the risks this future technology poses to today’s encryption methods already make it a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552701/the-cisos-guide-to-establishing-quantum-resilience.html"&gt;necessary component of any long-term planning&lt;/a&gt;. Many CISOs are already seizing the opportunity to raise the issue with the board and explain what measures will be necessary to protect data in the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-power-of-numbers"&gt;The power of numbers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The financial structure is just as important as the strategic approach. As companies continue to move from hardware-intensive architectures to cloud-native SaaS models, the economics of security are changing. Costs are shifting from capital expenditures to operating expenses. While this may initially lead to a decrease in EBITDA (Earnings Before Interest, Taxes, Depreciation, and Amortization), it also eliminates hardware replacement cycles, improves forecast accuracy, and reduces long-term total cost of ownership.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Per-user billing models for cloud services ensure predictability and greater flexibility in responding to changes. Further savings potential lies in consolidating tools onto a few platform providers. Additionally, process automation can reduce the burden on the service desk and improve productivity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, CISOs should demonstrate how potential investments in new technologies will improve cash flow, safeguard margins, and scale with business growth. CFOs and audit committees want to know how each proposal will impact financial results. They also want to understand what can be capitalized, what offsetting effects to expect, and how the investments will align with demand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, justifying security investments isn’t about persuasion, &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4026386/how-to-win-allies-and-influence-boards.html"&gt;but about exerting influence&lt;/a&gt;. It’s about &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080670/what-does-aligning-security-to-the-business-really-mean.html"&gt;aligning business priorities with secure&lt;/a&gt;, scalable, and cost-effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, CISOs must present a strategy that reduces risks, improves agility, and positions the company for long-term success. When IT leadership speaks the language of added value in their solutions, their proposals no longer sound like technical requirements, but like business necessities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104472/how-to-justify-your-security-investments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-811)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-811</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-811</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-812)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-812</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-812</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-813)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-813</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-813</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-814)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-814</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-814</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–815)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-815</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-815</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-816)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-816</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-816</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the breaches: Case studies that reveal adversary motives and modus operandi</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103300/behind-the-breaches-case-studies-that-reveal-adversary-motives-and-modus-operandi.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In today’s threat landscape, it’s no longer enough to focus solely on &lt;a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/what-is-a-malware-file-signature-and-how-does-it-work/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;malware signatures&lt;/a&gt; and IP addresses. Defenders must understand how adversaries think, organize and operate, because attacker intent and methodology are now just as critical as technical artifacts. Recent developments have provided rare visibility into the internal processes of modern threat groups, how they coordinate, communicate, exploit vulnerabilities and adapt their tooling in real time. This kind of behind-the-scenes insight is becoming indispensable as cyber threats grow more sophisticated, more specialized and more tightly aligned with financial or strategic objectives. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve analyzed a series of recent real-world incidents to better understand evolving &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/think/topics/threat-actor" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;threat actor&lt;/a&gt; behavior. Let’s take a closer look at what these cases reveal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-blackbasta-chat-leak"&gt;The BlackBasta chat leak&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vi.loginsoft.com/threat-profiles/BlackBasta-Ransomware-Campaign" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BlackBasta&lt;/a&gt; is often viewed as a tightly run ransomware operation, but internal leaks tell a very different story. The &lt;a href="https://www.trellix.com/blogs/research/analysis-of-black-basta-ransomware-chat-leaks/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BlackBasta chat leak&lt;/a&gt; exposes the group’s behind-the-scenes reality, revealing not a polished, corporate-style criminal enterprise but a fragmented ecosystem marked by hierarchy issues, operational stress, shifting loyalties and deep-seated mistrust among members.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the top of the structure sits &lt;strong&gt;Oleg&lt;/strong&gt; (aka &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tramp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), acting as the de facto operations director. The chats depict him as the ultimate decision-maker on campaigns, revenue distribution and targeting rules, including strategic exclusions such as avoiding Russian financial institutions. His leadership, however, is portrayed as opaque and self-interested, with several members openly questioning whether their earnings and workloads reflect fair compensation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio&lt;/strong&gt; functions as the operation’s central technical architect, managing everything from infrastructure stability to access orchestration. His background under the alias “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pumba&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” in the Conti collective reinforces the well-known pattern of talent migrating across ransomware-as-a-service ecosystems. Despite his skill set, the chats show Bio repeatedly expressing paranoia about state surveillance, especially following his release from detention, underscoring the constant psychological pressure faced by operators.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lara&lt;/strong&gt; handles administrative tasks under heavy workload and stress, reportedly receiving less compensation than others despite being central to operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The presence of actors like Cortes, with ties to &lt;a href="https://vi.loginsoft.com/threat-profiles/Qakbot-Malware-Campaign" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Qakbot&lt;/a&gt;, demonstrates how ransomware crews frequently outsource expertise, rely on external access brokers or pull in operators with malware-specific experience as needed. This kind of crossover, visible only when internal dialogues spill out, shows how interconnected the cybercriminal ecosystem truly is.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The chats further reveal operational inefficiencies that contradict the polished image these groups try to project. Members complain about slow decision-making, unclear leadership directives and disorganized workflows. Disputes over profit sharing, workload assignment and campaign prioritization point toward a group struggling to maintain cohesion. Even discussions around infrastructure updates, task delegation and encryption deployments show signs of technical debt and inconsistent coordination.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the &lt;a href="https://www.loginsoft.com/post/black-basta-exposed-anatomy-of-a-relentless-ransomware-threat" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BlackBasta&lt;/a&gt; chat leak demystifies the myth of ransomware groups as disciplined, unified machines. Instead, it exposes a loose federation of operators bound together by profit but pulled apart by mistrust, emotional strain, resource imbalance and competing for personal agendas. For defenders, these insights offer not only a rare psychological snapshot of threat actor behavior but also a reminder that even the most feared cybercriminal groups are vulnerable to the same organizational weaknesses that plague legitimate enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-dual-life-of-encrypthub"&gt;The dual life of EncryptHub&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What if the same threat actor breaching networks turned around and got a “Thank-you” note for reporting the flaws they once exploited? In a curious twist, Microsoft credited “&lt;a href="https://outpost24.com/blog/unmasking-encrypthub-chatgpt-partner-crime/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EncryptHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“, a persona long tied to malware campaigns, credential theft and access brokering, for responsibly disclosing two Windows vulnerabilities in March 2025. Better known by aliases like &lt;strong&gt;SkorikARI&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a href="https://vi.loginsoft.com/threat-profiles/Water-Gamayun-Threat-Actor-Campaign" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LARVA-208&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, this actor demonstrates a striking contradiction: simultaneously engaging in cybercrime while positioning themselves as a security researcher. When adversaries start submitting bug reports, the boundary between black-hat activity and legitimate vulnerability disclosure becomes increasingly blurred.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both vulnerabilities patched in Microsoft’s March Patch Tuesday were attributed to an individual with a documented history of malicious operations, including distributing malware through spoofed WinRAR websites and compromising hundreds of high-value targets across Europe and Asia. Unlike hierarchical ransomware groups, EncryptHub functions as a solo operator, shifting fluidly between freelance development, ad-hoc bug bounty submissions and illicit intrusion campaigns. Reports also indicate the use of ChatGPT to automate code generation, reconnaissance scripting and communication, reducing workload while enabling faster operational tempo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This case highlights a growing trend in the threat landscape: actors who no longer fit into fixed categories. Instead of being exclusively criminal or exclusively “researcher,” many now oscillate between both based on financial incentives, operational pressure and perceived risk. The acknowledgment from Microsoft underscores the uncomfortable reality that modern threat actors are increasingly hybrid strategic, opportunistic and adaptive. Understanding this duality is essential for evaluating their psychology, long-term intent and the evolving gray zone where legitimate security research and cybercrime increasingly intersect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="blacklocks-open-recruitment-tactics"&gt;BlackLock’s open recruitment tactics&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What happens when ransomware operators start posting job ads? &lt;a href="https://vi.loginsoft.com/threat-profiles/BlackLock-Ransomware-Campaign" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BlackLock’s&lt;/a&gt; recent recruitment campaigns reveal an increasingly brazen and industrialized cybercrime ecosystem, one where threat actors no longer rely solely on stealth but openly solicit personnel to scale their operations. The group has been aggressively searching for “&lt;a href="https://reliaquest.com/blog/threat-spotlight-inside-the-worlds-fastest-rising-ransomware-operator-blacklock/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;traffers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,” a role dedicated to funneling compromised traffic and delivering ready-to-exploit victims. These recruitment efforts, found across Russian-language underground forums such as RAMP as well as gated Telegram channels, highlight a maturing supply-chain model in ransomware operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This traffer-driven workflow is designed to offload the riskiest phase of the attack chain – initial access to external contractors. By outsourcing victim acquisition, &lt;a href="https://www.loginsoft.com/post/the-blacklock-breakdown-tools-tactics-and-the-rivalry-that-brought-it-down" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BlackLock&lt;/a&gt; minimizes its operational exposure while ensuring a consistent inflow of compromised endpoints, credentials and exploitable network footholds. The model mirrors legitimate gig-economy structures but operates with criminal specialization, where &lt;em&gt;traffers&lt;/em&gt; focus exclusively on harvesting access through phishing, malware loaders or traffic distribution systems, while the core BlackLock operators handle encryption, negotiation mechanics and monetization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This level of open recruitment signals growing confidence within the ransomware underground. It further reflects the shift toward modular cybercrime-as-a-service ecosystems, where roles are distributed, attack components are interchangeable and entry barriers for aspiring threat actors continue to fall. Understanding this recruitment strategy is crucial, as the &lt;em&gt;traffer&lt;/em&gt; economy significantly accelerates ransomware proliferation and underscores how deeply commoditized initial access has become.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="understanding-foresight-anticipation"&gt;Understanding, foresight, anticipation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Through this analysis, we’ve explored not just isolated incidents, but the broader behavioral patterns, operational workflows and strategic decision-making that define modern threat actors. By understanding how these adversaries adapt, coordinate and exploit emerging opportunities, we gain the foresight needed to anticipate their next moves and continuously refine our defense strategies. As threat actor behaviors evolve, we’ll continue to publish deeper insights and actionable intelligence to help the cybersecurity community stay informed, resilient and one step ahead.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103300/behind-the-breaches-case-studies-that-reveal-adversary-motives-and-modus-operandi.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-817)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-817</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-817</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-818)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-818</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-818</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-819)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-820)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-821)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-822)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-823)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-824)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-825)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-826)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GISEC GLOBAL 2026 – The Middle East &amp;amp; Africa’s Largest Cybersecurity Event</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/gisec-global</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 21368602095890668.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
