<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:35:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Commvault security advisory (AV26-120)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-121)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From in-house CISO to consultant. What you need to know before making the leap</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4132950/from-in-house-ciso-to-consultant-what-you-need-to-know-before-making-the-leap.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href="https://mandos.io/about/"&gt;Nikoloz Kokhreidze&lt;/a&gt;, the move into cybersecurity consulting came gradually through a series of small steps. “I accumulated enough experience across different industries, I started my newsletter, and I realized there’s a community of people interested in what I have to say,” he explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What ultimately crystallized the decision was the thought that his impact didn’t have to stop at the edge of one organization. “I was solving the same problems repeatedly in one company,” he says, “when I could solve them for multiple companies simultaneously, multiplying my impact and helping more businesses grow through pragmatic security leadership.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In August 2025, Kokhreidze launched his consulting business, Mandos. But he’s careful not to romanticize the move. “It’s important to stay realistic,” he says. Going solo takes time and patience. It means figuring out where you can be most useful. And being willing to stay flexible. “You have to be ready to pivot when you have new ideas, or when things don’t work out,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Like Kokhreidze, a growing number of CISOs are either moving into consulting roles or seriously considering it. The appeal is easy to see: more flexibility and quicker learning, alongside steady demand for experienced security leaders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some of these professionals &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3977845/the-rise-of-vciso-as-a-viable-cybersecurity-career-path.html"&gt;work as virtual CISOs (vCISOs)&lt;/a&gt;, advising companies from a distance. Others operate as fractional CISOs, embedding into the organization one or two days a week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Consulting gives me more autonomy and control over how I work, while still letting me apply the same strategic approach to improving resilience, governance, and practical security execution,” says &lt;a href="https://www.acyber.io/about-acyber"&gt;Antanas Kedys&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CEO at ACyber. He made the shift from an in-house CISO role to consulting in 2022, because he wanted to grow and work across different environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When a CISO transitions into consulting, their role changes in ways that aren’t always obvious at first. The new job means sharpening some skills, building entirely new ones and, perhaps hardest of all, learning to let go of control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As a CISO, you can mandate; as a consultant, you can only influence,” says Nigel Gibbons, director and senior advisor at NCC Group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-prepare-to-make-the-leap-from-security-leader-to-consultant"&gt;How to prepare to make the leap from security leader to consultant&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Long before stepping away from a full-time role, Kokhreidze and other security leaders tried to quietly plan ahead. They tested ideas, built visibility, reconnected with old contacts, and began mapping out who their potential clients might be. The list of potential should be a long one, because few conversations tend to turn into actual work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If someone is not asking you right now to consult for them, it can take 12-18 months before you land your first client,” says Carlota Sage. She held a part-time CISO role at a nonprofit before transitioning into vCISO work. Later, she went on to found Pocket CISO, which provides cybersecurity services to early-stage startups and small organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kokhreidze agrees with her. For a smoother transition, he suggests CISOs line up their first clients while they’re still employed. Otherwise, he says, it can take a long time to build momentum. And the pressure to make it work can quickly turn into panic. In that moment, security professionals may start “underpricing themselves because they need money immediately,” he says. Once rates are set out of desperation, they’re often hard to reset without straining the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other CISOs-turned-consultants also emphasize preparation. Kedys, for instance, stresses the need for a go-to-market focus. “Decide who you want to advise (industry, company size, maturity), what problems you’ll solve, and why you’re credible for that,” he says. “The combination of strong soft skills and a clear focus — who, how, and why — is the best starting point for a successful transition.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gibbons adds that consulting should grow out of a CISO’s existing experience. He suggests treating that experience as a set of real-world case studies worth talking about, capturing the decisions, the trade-offs, what went wrong and what worked. He also stresses the importance of building relationships beyond the security function, including legal teams, auditors, regulators and investors. “Consulting is ultimately a trust-based profession not a technical one,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="skills-that-carry-over-into-consulting"&gt;Skills that carry over into consulting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many of the skills CISOs honed inside large organizations translate directly to the new consulting job, while others suddenly matter more than they ever did before. In addition to technical skills, it is often the practical ones that prove most valuable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ability to prioritize — sharpened over years in a CISO role — becomes especially important in consulting. “It matters more than anything else,” Gibbons argues, because in consulting environments resources are often limited. Consultants are paid not to know everything, but to know what matters most, which risks to tackle first, and which problems can safely wait.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Crisis management is another essential skill. Paired with hands-on knowledge of cybersecurity processes and best practices, it gives former CISOs a real advantage as they move into consulting. Kedys highlights stress management: the ability to stay calm, focused and keep execution moving under pressure, which is just as valuable outside the enterprise as it ever was inside.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But if there’s one translatable skill that everyone talks about, that skill is communication. “All of your security and compliance knowledge is wasted if you cannot communicate to a business audience,” Sage says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kokhreidze agrees. Instead of leading with controls, tools or technical details, he focuses on what CTOs and other business leaders actually care about: outcomes. He talks about how security protects revenue, supports resilience, or builds confidence with regulators.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="new-skills-needed-in-the-toolkit"&gt;New skills needed in the toolkit&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As CISOs move into consulting, they quickly discover they need new skills as well, some of which they may have deliberately avoided in their in-house roles. Chief among them is sales. “Eighty percent of your work is actually selling yourself,” says Kokhreidze. “You are first a business, and CISO second.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And being a business is time-consuming. Consultants must juggle personal branding, marketing, accounting, and writing. Writing and online presence, in particular, matter because done well, they signal credibility and give current and future clients a sense of how a CISO thinks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The multiple roles consultants have to play — switching between delivery, sales, marketing and admin while juggling several clients — come with a real mental toll. For many former in-house executives, adjusting to that constant context switching is one of the hardest parts of leaving a structured organization behind. “If you’re running your own consulting firm, context switching can be a struggle,” Sage says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In time, many consultants learn that discipline matters, and that saying no is part of the job. “You must become comfortable saying no to work that dilutes your positioning or turns you back into an outsourced operator rather than a trusted advisor,” Gibbons says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="setting-the-right-price"&gt;Setting the right price&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many CISOs know their value inside an enterprise but translating that value into a consulting price is a different challenge altogether. It requires a shift from thinking like an employee to thinking like a business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Skills are not different from a product,” Kedys says. “You just need to find the right product (in this case, the skill) and wrap it in a way a market will be most likely to take it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That understanding, he adds, comes from market analysis: observing how executives buy, what they value, and what comparable services cost.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sage agrees with the idea of analyzing the market but says that CISOs coming from large enterprises and targeting small and mid-sized organizations often need to recalibrate their expectations. What feels like a modest rate to a global organization can be misaligned with the realities of smaller clients, particularly those buying advisory services for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When thinking about pricing, Kokhreidze took a two-way approach. He looked at the market and assessed his value. Then he set a realistic income goal and worked backwards, factoring in how many clients he could serve well. The result was a pricing model that favored quality over volume, a trade-off he knew the clients he wanted to work with would resonate with.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“B2B companies closing enterprise deals understand that professional security leadership costs far less than losing a single €10M+ contract to failed security reviews,” Kokhreidze says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When setting prices, one of the most common mistakes is charging for time rather than for the value the consultant brings to the table. Early in his career, Gibbons priced his work by the day instead of by the consequences it helped clients avoid. Over time, he moved toward outcome-based engagements, such as board assurance, regulatory readiness and post-incident recovery, so clients can understand more easily what they’re paying for.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Clients are buying judgment, not hours,” Gibbons says. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This approach, however, is not universal. Some more traditional organizations remain firmly attached to day rates. In those environments, shifting negotiations can be difficult regardless of the expertise being offered.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="potential-mistakes-to-avoid"&gt;Potential mistakes to avoid&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ask experienced consultants what mistakes newcomers tend to make, and the answers tend to be consistent. The biggest mistakes are rarely about security skills. They tend to cluster around mindset, money, and figuring out how to show up in the market.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The hardest lesson was realizing that being a great CISO doesn’t guarantee clients at all,” Kokhreidze says. “I quickly learned that professional expertise means nothing without strong sales and qualification skills, because you’ll waste months chasing companies that either don’t have the problem you’re trying to solve or aren’t ready to invest in fixing it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gibbons sees a related issue: consultants trying to recreate an in-house role from the outside. They take on operational responsibility, running programs or becoming embedded indefinitely. “That erodes margins and credibility,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another common misstep he points to is leading with tools, frameworks or certifications rather than judgment and experience. “Clients do not hire former CISOs for policy templates,” he argues. “They hire them to help make hard decisions with incomplete information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even CISOs who plan carefully before making the leap often discover that the freedom of consulting comes with hidden costs. As Sage puts it, “Most CISOs consulting for the first time underestimate how much time and effort go into just managing your own business.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4132950/from-in-house-ciso-to-consultant-what-you-need-to-know-before-making-the-leap.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersicherheit braucht Reife und keine Checklisten</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4133975/cybersicherheit-braucht-reife-und-keine-checklisten.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CISOs &amp;amp; Strategie" class="wp-image-4134352" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/shutterstock_2634856915_642f7c.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Wenn CISOs stärkere Programme, bessere Widerstandsfähigkeit und eine sicherere Zukunft wollen, müssen sie ihren Ansatz weiterentwickeln.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Overearth – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersicherheit wird oft wie ein Spiel behandelt. Unternehmen jagen schnellen Erfolgen hinterher, haken Compliance-Listen ab oder klopfen sich nach einem einzigen erfolgreichen Audit selbst auf die Schulter. Auf dem Papier mag das produktiv aussehen, aber in Wirklichkeit schafft es ein falsches Gefühl der Sicherheit. Der CISO stellt in diesem Bild den Quarterback dar, auf dem die ganze Verantwortung lastet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity ist jedoch kein Spiel. Sie erfordert eine ausgereifte Führung, langfristiges Denken und klare Verantwortlichkeiten. Alles andere setzt Unternehmen unnötigen Risiken aus. CISOs wissen um diesen Umstand, müssen ihn aber immer wieder in ihren Organisationen zur Sprache bringen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zu viele Sicherheitsteams verlassen sich auf Aktivitäten, die wie Fortschritte aussehen und dargestellt werden, aber das Risiko nicht wesentlich verringern. Dinge wie gelegentliche simulierte Phishing-Tests, auffällige neue Sicherheitstools oder die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494023/cybersicherheitsvorschriften-so-erfullen-sie-ihre-compliance-anforderungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Erfüllung grundlegender Compliance-Anforderungen&lt;/a&gt; können ein beruhigendes Gefühl vermitteln. Das Problem ist, dass diese Aktivitäten oft nur die Symptome bekämpfen, nicht aber die Ursachen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Häufige Beispiele hierfür sind:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance als Errungenschaft statt als Ausgangspunkt betrachten.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Vorfälle als isolierte Ereignisse statt als Indikatoren für systemische Probleme behandeln.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Kennzahlen verfolgen, die gut aussehen, aber nicht die tatsächliche Widerstandsfähigkeit messen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Glauben, dass Technologie Lücken schließen kann, die durch schwache Governance oder unklare Prozesse entstanden sind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das alles ist nur Scheinsicherheit. Es schafft Sichtbarkeit, aber keinen echten Schutz. CISOs sollten Risiken als real und gegenwärtig behandeln. Sie müssen Sicherheitsprogramme entwickeln, die wechselnden Bedrohungen, Personalfluktuation und unerfahrenen Teams standhalten können. Starke Führung ist nicht reaktiv. Sie ist stattdessen bewusst und informiert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Erfolgreiche CISOs konzentrieren sich auf:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Menschen und Prozesse und priorisieren diese vor technischen Hilfsmitteln&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Kulturelle Erwartungen und Verantwortlichkeiten&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Klare Zuständigkeiten&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Entscheidungsfindung auf der Grundlage von Cyberrisiken und ihren Datenanalysen&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Langfristige Resilienz anstatt kurzfristiger Erfolg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Das ist der Unterschied zwischen einem Sicherheitsprogramm, das wirklich funktioniert, und einem, das nur Checklisten abhakt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="der-wandel-vom-spiel-zum-echten-programm"&gt;Der Wandel vom Spiel zum echten Programm&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Übergang von einem reaktiven Ansatz zu einem ausgereiften Sicherheitsprogramm beginnt mit einer Änderung der Denkweise. CISOs müssen sich dafür entscheiden, aus dem „Spielmodus“ auszusteigen. Das Ziel besteht bislang darin, mögliche Probleme für ein weiteres Quartal zu vermeiden. Stattdessen müssen sie sich dazu verpflichten, Programme zu entwickeln, die echten Bedrohungen standhalten können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zu den wichtigsten Grundsätzen eines solchen Programmes gehören:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance ist die Mindestanforderung, nicht das Endziel.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Sicherheitsmetriken sollten reale Ergebnisse messen, wie die Zeit bis zur Erkennung und Reaktion.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Jeder Vorfall sollte Erkenntnisse liefern, die das Programm verbessern.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Die Planung der Ausfallsicherheit sollte genauso wichtig sein wie die Prävention.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Die Verantwortlichkeit sollte geteilt, sichtbar und messbar sein.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dies sind die Grundlagen eines ausgereiften Sicherheitsprogramms. Denn die Notwendigkeit wird jeden Tag sichtbar, die Bedrohungslandschaft entwickelt sich mit einer Geschwindigkeit weiter, die jeden Checklistenansatz übertrifft. Hochprofessionelle Angreifer gehen zielgerichtet vor. Sie arbeiten zusammen, automatisieren und innovieren. Sie spielen kein Spiel, verlassen sich nicht auf Checklisten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn Unternehmen Sicherheit weiterhin als eine Reihe von Aufgaben und nicht als strategische Disziplin behandeln, werden sie ins Hintertreffen geraten. Sicherheitsvorfälle sind keine Zufälle. Sie sind das vorhersehbare Ergebnis einer unreifen Führung.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495028/chief-information-security-officer-ein-neues-berufsbild-fur-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;CISOs&lt;/a&gt; müssen daher die Ernsthaftigkeit vorleben, die diese Aufgabe erfordert. Sicherheit ist kein Spiel. Es gibt keine Auszeiten und keine einfachen Neustarts. Was Unternehmen heute aufbauen, wird darüber entscheiden, ob sie den Bedrohungen von morgen standhalten können. Eine Führung mit entsprechender Reife macht den Unterschied zwischen scheinbarer Sicherheit und tatsächlicher Sicherheit aus. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072083/vom-ciso-zum-chief-risk-architect.html" target="_blank"&gt;Vom CISO zum Chief Risk Architect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4133975/cybersicherheit-braucht-reife-und-keine-checklisten.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drug trafficking network supplying cocaine to Iceland dismantled</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/drug-trafficking-network-supplying-cocaine-to-iceland-dismantled</link>
      <description>A criminal network involved in cocaine trafficking from South America to Europe has been dismantled following a coordinated investigation by authorities in Iceland, Lithuania and Spain, with the support of Europol and Eurojust. The group is believed to have generated EUR 4 million in criminal profits through the large-scale trafficking of illicit substances.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/drug-trafficking-network-supplying-cocaine-to-iceland-dismantled</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV26-123)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD security advisory (AV26-124)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers can turn Grok, Copilot into covert command-and-control channels, researchers warn</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134419/hackers-can-turn-grok-copilot-into-covert-command-and-control-channels-researchers-warn.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprise security teams racing to enable generative AI tools may be overlooking a new risk: attackers can abuse web-based AI assistants such as Grok and Microsoft Copilot to quietly relay malware communications through domains that are often exempt from deeper inspection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The technique, &lt;a href="https://research.checkpoint.com/2026/ai-in-the-middle-turning-web-based-ai-services-into-c2-proxies-the-future-of-ai-driven-attacks/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;outlined&lt;/a&gt; by Check Point Research (CPR), exploits the web-browsing and URL-fetch capabilities of these platforms to create a bidirectional command-and-control channel that blends into routine AI traffic and requires neither an API key nor an authenticated account.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Our proposed attack scenario is quite simple: an attacker infects a machine and installs a piece of malware,” CPR said. The malware then communicates with the AI assistant through the web interface, prompting it to fetch content from an attacker-controlled URL and return embedded instructions to the implant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because many organizations allow outbound access to AI services by default and apply limited inspection to that traffic, the approach effectively turns trusted AI domains into covert egress infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security analysts said the findings expose a growing blind spot in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4132860/why-2025s-agentic-ai-boom-is-a-cisos-worst-nightmare.html"&gt;enterprise AI governance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises that allow unrestricted outbound access to public AI web services without inspection, identity controls, or strong logging are more exposed than many realize,” said &lt;a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=PRF005665" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sakshi Grover&lt;/a&gt;, senior research manager for IDC Asia Pacific Cybersecurity Services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These platforms can effectively function as trusted external endpoints, meaning malicious activity can be concealed within normal network traffic, including routine HTTPS sessions to widely used AI domains,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunilvarkey1/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sunil Varkey&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity analyst, said the technique echoes past evasion strategies such as steganography and “living off the land” attacks, where adversaries abuse legitimate tools and trusted infrastructure to avoid detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CPR said using AI platforms as C2 relays is only one potential abuse case. The same interfaces could be prompted to generate operational commands on demand, from locating files and enumerating systems to producing PowerShell scripts for lateral movement, allowing malware to determine its next steps without direct human control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a more advanced scenario, an implant could transmit a brief profile of the infected host and rely on the model to determine how the attack should progress.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-structural-shift-in-detection"&gt;A structural shift in detection&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The research also points to a broader shift in how malware may evolve as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131078/companies-are-using-summarize-with-ai-to-manipulate-enterprise-chatbots-3.html"&gt;AI becomes embedded&lt;/a&gt; in runtime operations rather than just development workflows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When AI moves from assisting development to actively guiding malware behavior at runtime, detection can no longer rely solely on static signatures or known infrastructure indicators,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/krutikpoojara/"&gt;Krutik Poojara&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity practitioner. “Instead of hardcoded logic, you are dealing with adaptive, polymorphic, context-aware behavior that can change without modifying the malware itself.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Grover said this makes attacks harder to fingerprint, forcing defenders to rely more on behavioral detection and tighter correlation across endpoint, network, identity, and SaaS telemetry.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More significantly, this changes the tempo of defense. If attackers can dynamically adjust commands and execution paths based on the environment they encounter, security teams are no longer responding to a fixed playbook but to a continuously evolving interaction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This compresses the window between intrusion and impact and increases the importance of real-time detection, automated response, and tighter feedback loops between threat intelligence and SOC operations,” Grover said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="steps-to-take"&gt;Steps to take&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security leaders should not respond by blocking AI outright, analysts said, but by applying the same governance discipline used for other high-risk SaaS platforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Varkey recommended starting with a comprehensive inventory of all AI tools in use and establishing a clear policy framework for approving and enabling them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations should also implement AI-specific traffic monitoring and sequence-based detection rules to identify abnormal automation patterns. Other options to consider include rolling out phased awareness programs. “From an architectural standpoint, organizations should also invest in platforms that provide unified visibility across network, cloud, identity, and application layers, enabling security teams to correlate signals and trace activity across domains rather than treating AI usage as isolated web traffic,” Grover said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134419/hackers-can-turn-grok-copilot-into-covert-command-and-control-channels-researchers-warn.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol report: evolving tactics in maritime cocaine trafficking operations</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</link>
      <description>A new Europol report published today provides a comprehensive analysis of the evolving tactics employed by criminal networks to traffic cocaine into Europe via maritime routes. The report, 'Diversification in Maritime Cocaine Trafficking Modi Operandi', provides an in-depth analysis of the shifting tactics employed by organised crime networks, which continue to exploit vulnerabilities and evade detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fact Check: Europol’s support to Ukraine and entries into the Schengen Information System</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fact-check-europol-support-to-ukraine-and-entries-schengen-information-system</link>
      <description>The clarification below provides information to help accurately understand a recent media article on Europol’s support to Ukraine.Case at hand:A recent media article headlined: Separated by war — and by Schengen described how data and alerts in the EU’s Schengen Information System (SIS), originally designed to keep Europe safe from security threats, is now trapping Ukrainian refugees, including those who...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fact-check-europol-support-to-ukraine-and-entries-schengen-information-system</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol supports French investigation into alleged criminal activity linked to platform X</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</link>
      <description>The investigation is conducted by the Paris Public Prosecutor’s Office with the support of the French Gendarmerie’s cybercrime unit (UNCyber) and Europol.On the action day, French authorities carried out investigative measures in the offices of the platform in France. Europol supported the investigation through its European Cybercrime Centre (EC3), providing specialised cybercrime expertise and deploying an analyst on the ground...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication of a vacancy notice for the position of Europol Executive Director</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/publication-of-vacancy-notice-for-position-of-europol-executive-director</link>
      <description>Catherine De Bolle has served as Europol’s Executive Director since 1 May 2018, her mandate will conclude on 1 May 2026. The incoming Executive Director will have the opportunity to shape Europol's future and strengthen its role in safeguarding the European Union’s internal security.About EuropolEuropol, based in The Hague, the Netherlands, supports and strengthens action by and cooperation of the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/publication-of-vacancy-notice-for-position-of-europol-executive-director</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL security advisory (AV26-125)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/postgresql-security-advisory-av26-125</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/postgresql-security-advisory-av26-125</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-126)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-126</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-126</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-127)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-127</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-127</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-111) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV26-122) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV26-128)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-128</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-128</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-129)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-129</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-129</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US dominance of agentic AI at the heart of new NIST initiative</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134743/us-dominance-of-agentic-ai-at-the-heart-of-new-nist-initiative.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This week, the US National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) announced a new listening exercise, the &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/caisi/ai-agent-standards-initiative" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AI Agent Standards Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, which it hopes will provide a roadmap for addressing agentic AI hurdles and, it said, ensure that the technology “is widely adopted with confidence.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI agents, which have now ascended to the status of enterprise tools, are designed to be autonomous and powerful: ambiguous but ominous concepts where boundaries and limits are not always easy to define or understand. The risk this poses in terms of misuse, error, and unintended consequences is striking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, working under the direction of the Center for AI Standards and Innovation (CAISI), &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4027604/white-house-ai-plan-heavy-on-cyber-light-on-implementation.html" target="_blank"&gt;set up within NIST&lt;/a&gt; last June to replace the Biden administration’s US AI Safety Institute, the AI Agent Standards Initiative’s remit will be broader than security alone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although appearing to be a re-naming of the existing initiative, CAISI’s mandate is now wider, and more overtly political. Bluntly, “CAISI aims to foster the emerging ecosystem of industry-led AI standards and protocols while cementing US dominance at the technological frontier,” said NIST’s press release.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This will mean fostering the US’s leadership in international standards bodies, open-source AI agent development, and advancing research into AI agent security and use cases. Interoperability – the ability of agents from different companies to work together – will also be a priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Absent confidence in the reliability of AI agents and interoperability among agents and digital resources, innovators may face a fragmented ecosystem and stunted adoption,” NIST said. “To address this concern, NIST, including CAISI, aims to foster industry-led technical standards and protocols that build public trust in AI agents, catalyze an interoperable agent ecosystem, and diffuse their benefits to all Americans and across the world.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="more-concerns"&gt;More concerns&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stories of agentic AI missteps have been hard to miss recently, from the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4005965/first-ever-zero-click-attack-targets-microsoft-365-copilot.html" target="_blank"&gt;2025 ‘EchoLeak’ vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; in which Microsoft 365 Copilot was used to exfiltrate data, to the sudden &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129867/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-clawdbot-i-mean-moltbot-i-mean-openclaw.html" target="_blank"&gt;popularity of OpenClaw&lt;/a&gt; (formerly known as Moltbot and Clawdbot), a helpful agent which also opens a door for attackers to roam unseen around a user’s applications and data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And in November, the Information Technology Industry Council, a global trade association, identified a wide range of &lt;a href="https://www.executivegov.com/articles/iti-agentic-ai-risks-policy-recommendations" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;agentic security and accountability risks&lt;/a&gt; including ‘jagged intelligence,’ the tendency of AI models to complete complex tasks while failing at much simpler ones. These errors could expose enterprises to unpredictable failures in automated environments, it said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="moving-too-slowly"&gt;Moving too slowly&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gary-w-phipps/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gary Phipps&lt;/a&gt;, head of customer success at agentic AI security startup Helmet Security, a problem with NIST is that its initiatives are being outpaced by real-world developments. “History says that anything NIST comes up with will likely not emerge fast enough to address agentic AI,” said Phipps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“From the time NIST announced it was working on the AI Risk Management Framework to the day it published the final version was roughly two years,” he noted. “In that same window, the entire generative AI landscape was born, scaled, and began reshaping enterprise security. Now we’re doing it again with agentic AI, and NIST’s answer is more RFIs, more listening sessions, more convening.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIST has issued a &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2026/01/caisi-issues-request-information-about-securing-ai-agent-systems" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;request for information&lt;/a&gt; (RFI) on agentic AI threats, safeguards, and assessment methods; input is due by March 9. In addition, CAISI will hold “listening sessions” in April on sector-specific barriers to AI adoption, NIST said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIST’s statement about “cementing US dominance at the technological frontier” is, Phipps said, “a bold thing to say about an initiative whose first concrete deliverable is a listening session in April.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He pointed out, “Standards don’t create dominance: they follow it. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123196/nists-ai-guidance-pushes-cybersecurity-boundaries.html" target="_blank"&gt;The AI Risk Management Framework (RMF)&lt;/a&gt; is proof. It took two years to produce, and by the time it was final, the industry had largely already formed its own views on AI risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134743/us-dominance-of-agentic-ai-at-the-heart-of-new-nist-initiative.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 21:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>103 arrests and 36 labs dismantled in strike against synthetic drug network</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/103-arrests-and-36-labs-dismantled-in-strike-against-synthetic-drug-network</link>
      <description>Between 12 and 17 February 2026, Europol supported law enforcement authorities in Ukraine, Poland, and Moldova in a joint operation against an international criminal network involved in the production and trafficking of synthetic drugs, primarily synthetic cathinones such as alpha-PVP. The action day saw the Ukrainian National Police and the Polish Police Central Bureau of Investigation conducting coordinated checks at approximately 510 locations. Law enforcement officers dismantled 36 illicit production sites and 74 storage facilities for ready-to-distribute drugs. A total of 129 persons faced criminal charges, 103 persons were taken into custody.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/103-arrests-and-36-labs-dismantled-in-strike-against-synthetic-drug-network</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PayPal launches latest struggle to get rid of SMS for MFA</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134258/paypal-launches-latest-struggle-to-get-rid-of-sms-for-mfa.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When PayPal started emailing customers this month that it was backing off unencrypted SMS for multifactor authentication (MFA) at login, it came with the typical approach-avoidance asterisk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The financial services giant signaled that it was turning the page on the much-maligned authentication method while simultaneously offering no timeline and assuring customers SMS wouldn’t entirely go away — a curious strategy that could help smooth over customer loss.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SMS has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/566075/why-sms-banking-is-still-a-bad-idea.html"&gt;a long history&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567203/why-unauthenticated-sms-is-a-security-risk.html"&gt;opposition from security executives&lt;/a&gt;, mostly pointing to how easily it can be sniffed and subject to man-in-the-middle attacks, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4070281/clayrat-spyware-turns-phones-into-distribution-hubs-via-sms-and-telegram.html"&gt;among others&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, &lt;a href="https://www.bitdefender.com/en-us/blog/hotforsecurity/google-drops-sms-gmail"&gt;Google has backed off SMS&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;a href="https://www.vissensa.com/blog/microsoft-mfa-microsoft-to-remove-sms-multi-factor-authentication/"&gt;has Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://documentation.meraki.com/Platform_Management/Product_Information/Privacy%2C_Security%2C_Compliance/Overview_and_FAQ%3A_Cisco_Meraki_SMS_MFA_Deprecation"&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt;, and even the &lt;a href="https://www.bankinfosecurity.com/uae-central-bank-tells-fis-to-drop-sms-otp-authentication-a-28589"&gt;United Arab Emirates Central Bank&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“SMS as an authentication factor is devil spawn and should be banned by an act of Congress,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gwlongsine/"&gt;Gary Longsine&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at IllumineX, encapsulating the frustration of many security specialists.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, SMS remains, largely due to convenience, given that many business executives fear any change to MFA processes will be viewed as friction that could lead to customer loss or reduced engagement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They don’t want to lose users who won’t do anything other than SMS as a second factor,” says cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov. “Although app-based MFA is generally considered more secure than SMS-based MFA, not all users are willing to take the time to set up app-based MFA, so making it an absolute requirement tends to result in fewer conversions.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youattest.com/our-team/"&gt;Garret Grajek&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of access certification firm YouAttest, has experienced this business unit pushback directly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We designed a very strong authentication and the CISO loved it, but the security teams did not want to push back against user requests” for unencrypted SMS, he says, adding that a business unit executive argued that the security boost “is going to cost us money.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I feel sorry for PayPal because they [are a victim of] the battles that go on in business units versus security. And security doesn’t always win,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="muddled-effort-mixed-messages"&gt;Muddled effort, mixed messages&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fvillanustre/"&gt;Flavio Villanustre&lt;/a&gt;, CISO for the LexisNexis Risk Solutions Group, says he’s “always found it odd” that PayPal still supports SMS as its primary secondary authentication factor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Everyone in financial services and government has abandoned it for not being sufficiently secure and are moving to even phishing-resistant authentication, such as passkeys, Yubikeys,” he explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s shift was announced via email sent to some customers earlier this month. “Starting March 2026, we’ll start removing SMS codes [for login MFA] but they’ll still be available as part of our standard security checks,” PayPal’s email said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s reference to standard security checks refers to when its system, leveraging behavioral analytics, flags a customer interaction as potentially fraudulent based on factors such as transaction size or deviation from historic patterns. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, Grajek finds PayPal’s decision to keep SMS in use for fraud checks to be odd. When the system flags a potential problem, he says, “you want to do a higher level [of authentication]. Why would you de-escalate [to a lower level of authentication]?” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s customer email said the company would “start removing” SMS in March, but how long that process will take is unclear. Logistics is one factor, as these communications are going to a global customer base of roughly 439 million people and businesses. PayPal will batch those messages over an extended time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal will likely also assess customer reaction, giving itself flexibility by not committing to a firm end date. PayPal declined to comment on the record for this story.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s email suggested that customers switch their MFA method to an authenticator app or a onetime-password-issuing fob such as those compliant with FIDO2 security keys. Strangely, the email instructed security key users to “Put the device into your USB slot and you’re all set,” despite the fact that mobile devices communicate with keys via NFC or mobile connectors, not via USB slots, and most users transact with PayPal via mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The PayPal email also instructed customers to “update your verification method at paypal.com. Log in to your account and use the gear icon to go to security settings and update your 2-step verification.” The problem? When the email was received, that security page offered no direct way to make the change. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Customer service suggested to customers that they could deactivate MFA entirely and then reactivate it. That less-than-secure option did work and the user was then able to make the change. Further testing revealed that a user could click the “add a new device” button, even if they had no intention of adding a new device. That also presented a screen where the customer could change their MFA method. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://moorinsightsstrategy.com/team/melody-brue/"&gt;Melody Brue&lt;/a&gt;, principal analyst for Moor Insights &amp;amp; Strategy, says using SMS can still be valuable for some isolated situations, but that PayPal appears to be trying to have it both ways.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It sounds to me that they are trying to soften the blow of saying ‘SMS isn’t safe enough.’ They are saying that you can’t use it to verify who you are unless we are worried that you are not you,” Brue says. “They are clearly actively inching away from SMS. They have to do that. They have to align with new standards. In financial services you don’t even want to mess around with” SMS.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="financial-cost-of-sms-may-be-final-straw"&gt;Financial cost of SMS may be final straw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Brue also referred to another reason PayPal may be stepping back from SMS authentication: cost reduction. Sending SMS messages involves hard costs for PayPal, whereas telling customers to authenticate with a FIDO2 key or an authenticator app is free for the company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cost of individual SMS messages is low — for example, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sns/sms-pricing/"&gt;AWS charges a fraction of a penny&lt;/a&gt; for each message. But given that PayPal handles about 25 billion transactions a year, those fractions quickly add up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also, attackers test PayPal systems routinely “and they can trigger millions of SMS codes,” Brue adds. “For a company &lt;a href="https://247wallst.com/investing/2026/02/13/paypal-stock-falls-31-as-new-ceo-inherits-execution-crisis/"&gt;under new leadership and especially margin sensitive right now&lt;/a&gt;, sending millions of codes to bots that are not needed? That is an easy line to cut and it’s an OPEX win.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://acceligence.com/talent/profiles/justin-greis/"&gt;Justin Greis&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of consulting firm Acceligence and former head of the North American cybersecurity practice at McKinsey, says his main concern with SMS authentication is “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4022848/7-obsolete-security-practices-that-should-be-terminated-immediately.html"&gt;SIM swapping, SIM jacking&lt;/a&gt; — we have seen that go up.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“PayPal is one of the most spoofed and spammed emails out there,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/steveneric/"&gt;Steven Eric Fisher&lt;/a&gt;, an independent cybersecurity and risk advisor who served as the director of cybersecurity, risk, and compliance for Walmart until August 2025, agrees about SMS’s many authentication drawbacks, dubbing SMS “a very low bar of protection.” But he is less enthusiastic than most about authenticator apps. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Authenticator apps “are only marginally better than SMS. Each has its own faults,” Fisher says. “FIDO2 is the best option from a security standpoint but end user adoption” may slow down because the customer has to pay for each FIDO2 device “as well as [experience] the difficulty placed on the user for the enrollment and use.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134258/paypal-launches-latest-struggle-to-get-rid-of-sms-for-mfa.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.06</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-097) - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-003 - Vulnerability affecting BeyondTrust - CVE-2026-1731</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-003-vulnerability-affecting-beyondtrust-cve-2026-1731</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-003-vulnerability-affecting-beyondtrust-cve-2026-1731</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-131)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-131</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-131</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-132)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-132</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-132</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-133)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-133</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-133</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26-134)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-134</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-134</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-135)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-135</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-135</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-136)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-136</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-136</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-137)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-137</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-137</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-130) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-130</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-130</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compromised npm package silently installs OpenClaw on developer machines</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4135449/compromised-npm-package-silently-installs-openclaw-on-developer-machines.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new security bypass has users installing AI agent OpenClaw — whether they intended to or not.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have discovered that a compromised npm publish token pushed an update for the widely-used Cline command line interface (CLI) containing a malicious postinstall script. That script installs the wildly popular, but increasingly condemned, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129867/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-clawdbot-i-mean-moltbot-i-mean-openclaw.html" target="_blank"&gt;agentic application OpenClaw&lt;/a&gt; on the unsuspecting user’s machine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This can be extremely dangerous, as OpenClaw has broad system access and deep integrations with messaging platforms including WhatsApp, Telegram, Slack, Discord, iMessage, Teams, and others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to research by security platform Socket, the script was live for eight hours on the registry.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It should be emphasized that, in this case, OpenClaw wasn’t inherently malicious. However, it does represent yet another chapter in OpenClaw’s shaky security saga, and situations like this could earn it ‘potentially unwanted application’ (PUA) status.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I mean, they effectively turned OpenClaw into malware that EDR [endpoint detection and response ] isn’t going to stop,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt; of Beauceron Security. It is “deviously, terrifyingly brilliant.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="users-love-openclaw-attackers-do-too"&gt;Users love OpenClaw; attackers do, too&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw (formerly Clawdbot and Moltbot) is a free, open-source, autonomous AI agent that &lt;a href="https://openclaw.ai/blog/introducing-openclaw" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;launched on January 29&lt;/a&gt; and almost immediately went viral. According to its developer, Peter Steinberger, its repo had more than 2 million visitors over the course of a single week, and it’s estimated that it has been &lt;a href="http://www.ox.security/blog/how-to-uninstall-openclaw-remove-data-revoke-access/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;downloaded 720,000 times a week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw runs locally on a user’s hardware rather than in the cloud, and can perform autonomous, real-world actions on their behalf, such as reading emails, browsing web pages, running apps, or managing calendars.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, almost immediately after release, it raised &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4125939/by-whatever-name-moltbolt-clawd-openclaw-this-uber-ai-assistant-is-a-security-nightmare.html" target="_blank"&gt;serious security issues&lt;/a&gt;: It is prone to prompt injection attacks, authentication bypasses, and server-side request forgery (SSRF), among other &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134540/six-flaws-found-hiding-in-openclaws-plumbing.html" target="_blank"&gt;attacks&lt;/a&gt;. Many enterprises have responded by severely restricting, or outright banning, the AI agent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While, in the Cline situation, it was merely installed, but not inherently malicious, “the attacker had the ability to install anything,” &lt;a href="https://socket.dev/blog/cline-cli-npm-package-compromised-via-suspected-cache-poisoning-attack" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Socket’s Sarah Gooding&lt;/a&gt; wrote. “This time it was OpenClaw. Next time it might be something malicious.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Cline CLI is widely-used across the developer ecosystem, with about 90,000 weekly downloads from npm. The compromised token pushed cline@2.3.0, which contained a modified package.json with a postinstall script that installed the latest version of OpenClaw, to the npm registry. The addition of that script was the only modification to the package; otherwise the CLI binary and other contents were identical to the legitimate prior release, Gooding noted, making it easy to miss.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The compromised package was pushed on February 17, although the underlying problem had been &lt;a href="https://adnanthekhan.com/posts/clinejection/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;discovered six weeks prior&lt;/a&gt; by security researcher Adnan Khan. The package sat live on the registry for an estimated eight hours before it was deprecated and Cline published a corrected version (2.4.0).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Khan had initially published his research about the vulnerable workflow on February 9, after unsuccessful attempts to get a response to his reports from Cline, and Cline fixed it within 30 minutes. However, while the patch closed the entry point, the token could have been stolen during an attacker’s initial reconnaissance, meaning the fix came too late to prevent the February 17 publish (which, ultimately, was the day it was exploited).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cline had no prior install scripts, so a new one appearing was an anomalous signal worth investigating,” Gooding noted, adding that Socket has marked the unauthorized publish as malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For devs who installed or updated the Cline CLI in the roughly eight-hour window on February 17, Socket advises:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update to the latest version: npm install “-g cline@latest.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;If on version 2.3.0, update to 2.4.0 or higher.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Check for and immediately remove OpenClaw if it hadn’t been intentionally installed (“npm uninstall -g openclaw”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gooding noted, “nothing ran automatically beyond the install,” but added there was still a risk: “OpenClaw is a capable agentic tool with broad system permissions, not a trivial package to have silently dropped onto a developer’s machine.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-no-win-scenario"&gt;A no-win scenario&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;EDR, managed detection and response (MDR), and other security providers are going to be forced to declare OpenClaw as either a PUA or “flat out as malware, which, honestly, it can be,” said Shipley, or these kinds of attack win.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I hate to give it to attackers, but you kind of have to on this one,” he said. “This is why agentic AI is going to get so many people pwned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it’s a no-win scenario, Shipley noted, particularly if any organization was “so foolish” as to have allowed OpenClaw into their enterprise environment and built business-reliant work processes on it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As he put it: “Attackers combined the two biggest dumpster fires in 2026 cybersecurity into a city-scale landfill fire by chaining supply chain hacks via npm and the smoking-hot-vibe-coded AI agent disaster of OpenClaw.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4135449/compromised-npm-package-silently-installs-openclaw-on-developer-machines.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 02:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-139)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-139</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-139</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-140)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-140</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-140</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV26-141)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-141</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-141</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV26-142)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av26-142</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av26-142</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-143)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-143</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-143</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-138) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-138</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-138</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV26-144)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-144</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-144</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-145)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-145</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-145</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV26-146)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-146</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-146</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-147)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-147</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-147</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IceWarp security advisory (AV26-148)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/icewarp-security-advisory-av26-148</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/icewarp-security-advisory-av26-148</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-149)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-149</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-149</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-150)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-150</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-150</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roundcube security advisory (AV25-309) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/roundcube-security-advisory-av25-309</link>
      <description>On June 1, 2025, Roundcube published security advisories to address vulnerabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/roundcube-security-advisory-av25-309</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Virtual Event] Shields Up: Key Technologies Reshaping Cybersecurity Defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 2845.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
