<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 19:16:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–699)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-700)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>654 war crimes suspects tied to Russian paramilitary</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/654-war-crimes-suspects-tied-to-russian-paramilitary</link>
      <description>Europol’s Core International Crimes Team supported Moldova and Ukraine in a second phase of war crimes investigation against members of Wagner and Redut mercenary groups.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/654-war-crimes-suspects-tied-to-russian-paramilitary</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-701)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Tomcat security advisory (AV25-702)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV25-703)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-704)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business continuity and cybersecurity: Two sides of the same coin</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086135/business-continuity-and-cybersecurity-two-sides-of-the-same-coin.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As someone who has spent over six years in the trenches of IT operations at Amazon, managing critical infrastructure that cannot afford downtime, I’ve witnessed firsthand how the convergence of cyberthreats and business continuity has fundamentally changed the game for executives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 3 am call that every CISO and CIO dreads isn’t just about a server crash anymore. It’s about sophisticated threat actors who understand that disrupting your operations can be more profitable than stealing your data. After managing IT infrastructure for one of the world’s largest companies and responding to countless incidents, I can tell you that the traditional approach to business continuity planning is dangerously outdated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-5-4-million-question-every-executive-must-answer"&gt;The $5.4 million question every executive must answer&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to IBM’s 2024 Cost of a Data Breach report, the &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/reports/data-breach" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;average cost of a data breach has reached $4.88 million globally&lt;/a&gt;, with business disruption accounting for the largest portion of these costs. But here’s what keeps me up at night: These figures don’t capture the full picture of what happens when cybercriminals specifically target your business continuity infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During my tenure as an IT support engineer at Amazon, I’ve seen how quickly operational disruptions cascade through interconnected systems. When attackers target your disaster recovery sites, backup systems and the very tools you rely on to restore operations, the financial impact multiplies exponentially. The question isn’t whether your organization will face a cyber-induced business disruption; it’s whether you’ll survive it with your reputation and market position intact.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-traditional-business-continuity-plans-fail-against-modern-threats"&gt;Why traditional business continuity plans fail against modern threats&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’ve implemented change management processes in environments requiring 99.99% uptime and I can tell you that most business continuity plans were designed for a different era. They assume that your backup systems, communication channels and recovery procedures will be available when you need them. Today’s threat actors specifically target these assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2023 Veeam Ransomware Trends Report revealed that &lt;a href="https://www.veeam.com/ransomware-trends-report-2023?ad=in-text-link" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;93% of ransomware attacks target backup repositories&lt;/a&gt;. This isn’t coincidental. Cybercriminals understand that by compromising your recovery infrastructure, they maximize their leverage and your desperation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From my experience managing IT assets and coordinating incident responses, I’ve learned that the most dangerous assumption executives make is that cybersecurity and business continuity are separate disciplines. They’re not. They’re two sides of the same operational coin and treating them separately creates the vulnerabilities that sophisticated attackers exploit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-human-factor-your-biggest-asset-and-greatest-risk"&gt;The human factor: Your biggest asset and greatest risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Having trained numerous engineers and served as an escalation point for complex technical challenges, I’ve observed a critical pattern: human behavior under pressure consistently undermines even the most sophisticated technical controls. When your primary systems are down and executives are demanding immediate restoration, your team will take shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They’ll use personal devices to access company systems. They’ll share credentials to speed up recovery processes. They’ll bypass security protocols to restore operations quickly. This isn’t a training problem; it’s a human nature problem that requires systematic solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2024 Verizon Data Breach Investigations Report confirms that &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;68% of breaches involve a human element&lt;/a&gt;. During crisis situations, this percentage increases dramatically as stress and urgency override security awareness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-resilient-infrastructure-lessons-from-high-availability-environments"&gt;Building resilient infrastructure: Lessons from high-availability environments&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implementing network security protocols and backup solutions in Amazon’s demanding environment has taught me that resilience requires a fundamental shift in thinking. You cannot simply add cybersecurity measures to existing business continuity plans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You must architect your entire continuity strategy around the assumption that your primary systems will be compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This means implementing network segmentation that isolates critical business functions from general corporate networks. When attackers gain access to email systems or file shares, they shouldn’t automatically have pathways to manufacturing controls or financial systems. &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/publications/zero-trust-architecture" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST’s Zero Trust Architecture guidelines&lt;/a&gt; provide a framework, but implementation requires deep understanding of your operational dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Your backup and recovery systems need their own security considerations. I’ve seen organizations invest millions in backup infrastructure only to discover that attackers had persistent access to their recovery environments for months. This requires implementing offline backup strategies, maintaining air-gapped recovery environments and regularly testing restoration procedures under simulated attack conditions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cloud-paradox-opportunity-and-vulnerability"&gt;The cloud paradox: Opportunity and vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud services present both opportunities and challenges for business continuity planning. While platforms like AWS, Azure and Google Cloud offer geographic redundancy and professional security management, they also create dependencies on external providers and internet connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2023 Uptime Institute Global Data Center Survey found that &lt;a href="https://uptimeinstitute.com/resources/research-and-reports/uptime-institute-global-data-center-survey-results-2023" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;80% of data center outages could have been prevented through better processes and training&lt;/a&gt;. In cloud environments, you’re dependent on your provider’s processes and training, which creates a different risk profile that many executives underestimate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="integration-where-most-organizations-fail"&gt;Integration: Where most organizations fail&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effective business continuity planning must integrate cybersecurity incident response from the very beginning. This means having communication protocols that work even when primary networks are compromised, decision-making processes that account for ongoing security threats and recovery procedures that don’t inadvertently reintroduce vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The traditional approach of focusing on restoring operations first and investigating security issues later is no longer viable. Organizations need to be able to conduct forensic analysis while simultaneously working to restore services. This requires specialized tools, trained personnel and procedures that balance the urgency of business recovery with the need to preserve evidence and prevent further compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="testing-the-reality-check-most-executives-avoid"&gt;Testing: The reality check most executives avoid&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regular testing becomes even more critical when cybersecurity threats are factored into the equation. Organizations need to conduct exercises that simulate not just technical failures, but active attacks on their recovery infrastructure. These tests should include scenarios where primary communication channels are compromised, key personnel are unavailable and recovery systems themselves are under attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/white-papers/sans-2024-detection-response-survey" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SANS 2024 Detection and Response Survey&lt;/a&gt; revealed that organizations that conduct regular tabletop exercises recover 50% faster from actual incidents. But tabletop exercises aren’t enough. You need red team exercises where security professionals attempt to disrupt business continuity procedures using the same tactics that real attackers might employ.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-executive-imperative-act-before-the-crisis"&gt;The executive imperative: Act before the crisis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The integration of cybersecurity and business continuity planning will only become more important as organizations become increasingly dependent on digital infrastructure. Emerging technologies like artificial intelligence and internet of things devices create new attack surfaces that must be considered in continuity planning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The key to success lies in recognizing that cybersecurity and business continuity are not separate disciplines that occasionally overlap. They are fundamentally interconnected aspects of organizational resilience that must be planned, implemented and managed as a unified strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As executives, you have a choice: Invest in integrated cyber-resilient business continuity now or explain to your board, customers and shareholders why your organization couldn’t maintain operations when it mattered most. The threat actors are already making their choice. The question is, what’s yours?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086135/business-continuity-and-cybersecurity-two-sides-of-the-same-coin.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-705)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-705</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-705</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-706)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-016 Internet-accessible industrial control systems (ICS) abused by hacktivists</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-707)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker security advisory (AV25–708)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV25-693) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-709)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-710)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-629) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-711)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress security advisory (AV25-712)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-713)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global experts advance the joint fight against crypto-enabled crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</link>
      <description>The criminal use of cryptocurrency is becoming increasingly professionalised, but so too is the global response. Participants at the 9th Global Conference on Criminal Finances and Cryptoassets emphasised three priorities: developing common standards, deepening cooperation and investing in capacity. These are essential if authorities and industry are to keep pace with evolving threats and recover illicit cryptoassets at scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and UEFA united for fair and safe football</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</link>
      <description>Today, 5 November 2025, Europol and UEFA have renewed and extended their Memorandum of Understanding, focused on preventing and combating crime while protecting the integrity of European football. The memorandum was signed at UEFA headquarters in Nyon by the Executive Director of Europol, Catherine De Bolle, and by the President of UEFA, Aleksander Čeferin. Europol and UEFA committed to cooperate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden hosts naval exercise with 200 special tactics operators</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</link>
      <description>Preparing to fight terrorism on land and seaThe exercise scenario focused on the deployment of special intervention units and naval assets during day- and night-time, simulating terrorist and hostage incidents on board of cruise liners and ferries. Day after day, the participants faced new challenges on the water and on some of the archipelago’s many islands, slowly preparing them for...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake number, real damage: Europol urges action against caller ID spoofing</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</link>
      <description>Europol is calling for a coordinated European response to tackle caller ID spoofing, an in increasingly common tool, used for online fraud and social engineering scams. Caller ID spoofing occurs when criminals falsify the information displayed on phones, making numbers appear legitimate to deceive victims. This practice is driving substantial financial and societal harm, with an estimated EUR 850 million lost worldwide each year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drilling Down on Uncle Sam’s Proposed TP-Link Ban</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/</link>
      <description>The U.S. government is reportedly preparing to ban the sale of wireless routers and other networking gear from TP-Link Systems, a tech company that currently enjoys an estimated 50% market share among home users and small businesses. Experts say while the proposed ban may have more to do with TP-Link's ties to China than any specific technical threats, much of the rest of the industry serving this market also sources hardware from China and ships products that are insecure fresh out of the box.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 18:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-714)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-714</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-714</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-715)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-715</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-715</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-716)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-716</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-716</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-717)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-717</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-717</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–718)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-718</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-718</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-719)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-720)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-720</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-720</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquiti security advisory (AV25-721)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubiquiti-security-advisory-av25-721</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubiquiti-security-advisory-av25-721</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nikkei’s Slack breach leaks sensitive data from more than 17,000 users</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086100/nikkeis-slack-breach-leaks-sensitive-data-from-more-than-17000-users.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Japanese media company Nikkei has confirmed that a security breach of its Slack accounts has potentially leaked highly sensitive information from more than 17,000 of its users. Consultants point to the incident as yet another reminder of the dangers when non-corporate devices are allowed to access confidential corporate data. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“An employee’s personal computer was infected with a virus, leading to the leakage of Slack authentication credentials. It is believed that this information was used to gain unauthorized access to employee accounts,” Nikkei said in &lt;a href="https://www.nikkei.co.jp/nikkeiinfo/en/news/announcements/1394.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a published statement&lt;/a&gt;. “The incident was identified in September and countermeasures such as changing passwords were implemented. Potentially leaked information includes the names, email addresses, and chat histories for 17,368 individuals registered on Slack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Nikkei statement added “Considering the incident’s significance and to ensure transparency, we voluntarily reported it to [Japan’s] &lt;a href="https://www.ppc.go.jp/en/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Personal Information Protection Commission&lt;/a&gt;. No leakage of information related to sources or reporting activities has been confirmed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, a directory of former government and military specialists, stressed that this is part of an ongoing trend of Slack breaches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There is often increased risk when employees or contractors access company resources from non-company-managed devices. Recent attacks against Okta, MGM Resorts, and others have been linked to such unmanaged access,” Levine said, adding that last year, “an attacker exfiltrated more than [1 terabyte] of internal data from Disney’s Slack environment when a contractor had accessed Slack from an unmanaged device, bypassing monitoring tools.”  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/erik-avakian" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Erik Avakian&lt;/a&gt;, technical counselor at Info-Tech Research Group, noted that one of the most concerning things about attacks similar to the Nikkei breach is that the attackers are often able to easily bypass MFA defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“An employee’s computer gets hit by malware designed to steal credentials. The malware grabs Slack session tokens and cookies, then sends them to attacker command and control servers,” Avakian said. “With those stolen and likely active tokens, the attacker is able to log into Slack from their own device and access private channels and chat history without even triggering a multi-factor authentication prompt, since they reused an already-authenticated session.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Avakian said that the nature of these attacks suggests that enterprise CISOs should consider procedural changes. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This kind of attack would give threat actors “broad access to channels and integrations, which made the impact worse. Weaknesses around this incident shine a light on unmanaged or poorly protected devices, long-lived tokens, and not enough logging or alerts for suspicious sessions,” Avakian said. “Organizations can learn from these types of incident, and those using Slack, or any other widely used communications platform similar to Slack, should maintain a policy for revoking active sessions and refreshing tokens for affected users routinely, forcing password resets and rotating API tokens.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffreyeman/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jeff Man&lt;/a&gt;, a senior information security consultant with Online Business Systems, pointed out, “the larger discussion should be on the failings of the Nikkei IT/IS program to protect against some sort of attack that targeted its employees. Why are employees allowed to use Slack on personal devices?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“So this is really an issue of risk management,” Man said. “In the case of Nikkei, it appears the exploitation was elsewhere [on the system]. The initial access allowed the miscreants to use credentials to gain access to Slack. That’s not a compromise of Slack itself, that’s a compromise of employee account authentication.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://thecyberdr.com/#about" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Stephen Boyce&lt;/a&gt;, security consultant and CEO of The Cyber Dr., said the Nikkei incident represents “what happens when someone uses a personal device to get into work systems. Once that device gets hit with malware, it’s game over for the credentials. The part that worries me is this could happen anywhere. People forget how much sensitive stuff ends up in Slack: messages, files, links, sometimes even credentials. Once someone has that, they can poke around pretty freely.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To me, it’s just another reminder that zero trust has to go all the way out to the edge, not just the network. You’ve got to know the device, use MFA tied to managed hardware, and control what data lives in those SaaS tools,” Boyce said. “You may be also asking ‘Well, do we do away with BYOD all together?’ And the short answer is ‘no’ but we do need to look at ways we can secure the workforce beyond company issued assets.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086100/nikkeis-slack-breach-leaks-sensitive-data-from-more-than-17000-users.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Chargeback: 4.3 million cardholders affected, EUR 300 million in damages</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</link>
      <description>On 4 November 2025, an international coordinated action day targeted three major fraud and money laundering networks as part of Operation “Chargeback.” Led by the Cybercrime Department (Landeszentralstelle Cybercrime) of the General Prosecutor's Office (Generalstaatsanwaltschaft) in Koblenz, Germany, and the German Federal Criminal Police Office (Bundeskriminalamt), the operation has been investigating these networks since December 2020. More than 60 house searches were conducted and a total of 18 arrest warrants executed. The criminal networks are suspected of misusing credit card data from over 4.3 million cardholders across 193 countries. In total, the estimated damage from the fraud scheme exceeds EUR 300 million, with attempted damages amounting to over EUR 750 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>54 individuals arrested in action against labour exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</link>
      <description>Over the last weeks, law enforcement, border guards and labour and tax authorities across Europe joined forces to identify and tackle labour exploitation. This recent edition of the EMPACT Joint Action Days targeted trafficking in human beings for labour exploitation purposes, with a special emphasis on the agricultural sector, gastronomy, and temporary work agencies. In particular, the involved authorities also took measures against the exploitation of non-EU nationals and refugees. Led by France and the Netherlands, and carried out by authorities from 32 countries with support from Europol and the European Labour Authority (ELA), the action days resulted in the arrest of 54 individuals and identification of 404 potential victims of human trafficking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-722)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-722</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-722</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-723)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-723</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-723</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-725)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-724) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-726)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-619) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-727)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-728)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-729)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-730)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-731)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
