<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:29:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-020 – Vulnerability Impacting WatchGuard Fireware OS - CVE-2025-14733</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-020-vulnerability-impacting-watchguard-fireware-os-cve-2025-14733</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-020-vulnerability-impacting-watchguard-fireware-os-cve-2025-14733</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.06</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-858)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-858</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-858</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-859)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-859</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-859</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-860)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-860</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-860</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV25-861)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-861</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av25-861</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Security for Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.securityweek.com/rethinking-security-for-agentic-ai/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When software can think and act on its own, security strategies must shift from static policy enforcement to real-time behavioral governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com/rethinking-security-for-agentic-ai/"&gt;Rethinking Security for Agentic AI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com"&gt;SecurityWeek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.securityweek.com/rethinking-security-for-agentic-ai/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical RCE flaw allows full takeover of n8n AI workflow platform</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113980/critical-rce-flaw-allows-full-takeover-of-n8n-ai-workflow-platform.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have released details about a critical vulnerability that was silently patched in n8n, a platform used by many companies to build LLM-powered agents and automated workflows. The flaw can allow unauthenticated attackers to completely take over local n8n deployments, execute commands on the underlying system, and extract sensitive corporate data workflows typically have access to.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The blast radius of a compromised n8n is massive,” researchers from data security company Cyera, who found the vulnerability, noted in their &lt;a href="https://www.cyera.com/research-labs/ni8mare-unauthenticated-remote-code-execution-in-n8n-cve-2026-21858"&gt;report on the vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;. “N8n is connecting countless systems, your organizational Google Drive, OpenAI API keys, Salesforce data, IAM systems, payment processors, customer databases, CI/CD pipelines, and more. It’s the central nervous system of your automation infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The n8n developers &lt;a href="https://github.com/n8n-io/n8n/security/advisories/GHSA-v4pr-fm98-w9pg"&gt;patched this issue in version 1.121.0&lt;/a&gt; released on Nov. 18, but the release notes did not mention security fixes at the time, which seems to be standard procedure as n8n security advisories are intentionally released with a delay. The project has patched other critical RCE vulnerabilities since then, such as &lt;a href="https://github.com/n8n-io/n8n/security/advisories/GHSA-v98v-ff95-f3cp"&gt;CVE-2025-68613&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/n8n-io/n8n/security/advisories/GHSA-62r4-hw23-cc8v"&gt;CVE-2025-68668&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/n8n-io/n8n/security/advisories/GHSA-v364-rw7m-3263"&gt;CVE-2026-21877&lt;/a&gt;, so users should ensure they always update to the latest available version.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="content-type-confusion-leads-to-arbitrary-file-reads"&gt;Content-Type confusion leads to arbitrary file reads&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability, tracked as CVE-2026-21858, has a severity rating of 10.0 (critical) and enables a two-part attack. First, it allows unauthenticated attackers who have access to n8n web forms to leak internal files from the n8n server. This is because the &lt;code&gt;formWebhook&lt;/code&gt; function used by n8n Form nodes to receive data doesn’t validate whether the &lt;code&gt;Content-Type&lt;/code&gt; field of the POST request submitted by the user is set to &lt;code&gt;multipart/form-data&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Imagine a very common use case in which n8n has been used to build a chat interface that allows users to upload files to the system — for example, a customer support portal that accepts error screenshots or logs, an HR system for submitting CVs, or a knowledge base where employees can upload documents to index for later querying through an LLM-powered chatbot.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the normal flow, when the content type is &lt;code&gt;multipart/form-data&lt;/code&gt; and the request body has a &lt;code&gt;files:&lt;/code&gt; definition, n8n will parse the request with its &lt;code&gt;parseFormData()&lt;/code&gt; function, which uses Node.js library Formidable to handle file uploads securely by storing the file in a temp directory with a random path before populating the &lt;code&gt;req.body.files&lt;/code&gt; global variable with the filename and location.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, if a request has a different content type, for example &lt;code&gt;application/json&lt;/code&gt;, n8n will parse the request body using another function called &lt;code&gt;parseBody()&lt;/code&gt;, which behaves differently. This function extracts the request’s data section to populate the &lt;code&gt;req.body.data&lt;/code&gt; global variable, but it also extracts any other section from the request to populate the corresponding &lt;code&gt;req.body.[section name]&lt;/code&gt; variables with their content.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;code&gt;formWebhook&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t validate whether a request with a &lt;code&gt;files&lt;/code&gt; section is actually &lt;code&gt;multipart/form-data&lt;/code&gt;, it will call the wrong parsing function on its body, resulting in the population of the &lt;code&gt;req.body.files&lt;/code&gt; variable with user-controlled values like filenames and paths. It will then call a function called &lt;code&gt;copyBinaryFile()&lt;/code&gt; to copy any files from the &lt;code&gt;req.body.files&lt;/code&gt; variable — which are supposed to be temp random paths — to persistent storage locations to be consumed by other nodes/workflows, leading to potential path traversal attacks, in which legitimate files on the system can be overwritten or loaded elsewhere in a workflow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To exploit this vulnerability, an attacker can submit a request as &lt;code&gt;application/json&lt;/code&gt; with a &lt;code&gt;files&lt;/code&gt; section that specifies known file paths from the local system, including n8n configuration files that contain sensitive credentials and tokens. If these files are added into the context of an LLM-powered chatbot node, the attacker can then use the chat interface to ask questions about those files and leak their contents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-arbitrary-file-read-to-admin-privileges"&gt;From arbitrary file read to admin privileges&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second part of the attack enabled by this vulnerability opens the “blast radius” considerably, as the ability to read any local file has serious implications due to the way n8n tracks authenticated sessions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Session cookies are strings stored in the user’s browser to maintain their authenticated status for a period of time. Attackers regularly steal session cookies from compromised systems to bypass authentication and log in as their victims on various websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In n8n, session cookies are generated by combining a user’s unique ID with a SHA256 hash of the user’s email and password and then signing the result with a secret key unique to each n8n installation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem is that all the information needed to rebuild session cookies is located in local files. The unique secret key is stored in &lt;code&gt;/home/node/.n8n/config&lt;/code&gt; and all user records are stored in the &lt;code&gt;/home/node/.n8n/database.sqlite&lt;/code&gt; file. Leaking the contents of these two files allows attackers to recreate &lt;code&gt;n8n-auth&lt;/code&gt; cookies for any users, including administrators.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With administrator privileges attackers can create new workflows, and n8n offers a node called Execute Command that does exactly what the name implies — executes commands on the underlying operating system with the privileges of the n8n service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Imagine a large enterprise with 10,000+ employees with one n8n server that anyone uses,” the researchers wrote in their report. “A compromised n8n instance doesn’t just mean losing one system — it means handing attackers the keys to everything. API credentials, OAuth tokens, database connections, cloud storage, all centralized in one place. N8n becomes a single point of failure and a goldmine for threat actors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113980/critical-rce-flaw-allows-full-takeover-of-n8n-ai-workflow-platform.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB security advisory (AV25-862) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mongodb-security-advisory-av25-862</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mongodb-security-advisory-av25-862</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 strategies for building a high-performance cybersecurity team</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110690/6-strategies-for-building-a-high-performance-cybersecurity-team.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Longtime security chief &lt;a href="https://silverjacket.mxficus.com/60da58dd67b70018824684dd/l/GvZr8SFqMhinKZ2RP?rn=&amp;amp;re=iQXZu5Cd0FmcwtWeyFWbARHdhJHcrlnch1mI&amp;amp;sc=false"&gt;George Gerchow&lt;/a&gt; had sought top-notch security engineers and developers to build his team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gerchow considered these workers “superstars” — and they proved him right in many ways. They were ambitious go-getters “who came in and absolutely killed it. They’d do a great job, but then they’d move on.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gerchow discovered that a collection of such superstars didn’t create a high-performing team, which he defines as one that works well together to protect the company, leans in, and builds trust among themselves and the business units. He realized to build a great team he needed a better mix of worker types.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such teams don’t come together without effort. “Everyone needs to work on creating better teams,” Gerchow says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here, he and other veteran security leaders share six strategies to do that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-build-a-diverse-team"&gt;1. Build a diverse team&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Having learned as CISO at a past company that having only one type of worker doesn’t get him the best overall team, Gerchow changed his &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1257437/how-cybersecurity-roles-are-changing-and-what-to-look-for-when-hiring.html"&gt;recruiting and hiring practices&lt;/a&gt;. He sought to balance out the highly ambitious engineers he hired for innovation and big initiatives — and whose tenures could be short-lived, as they chased other projects — with those he calls “rock stars” —diligent, focused workers who deftly and reliably handled the day-to-day routine tasks that make up the bulk of security department responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You need a mixture of both of those,” says Gerchow, now CSO at Bedrock Security and a faculty member at IANS Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gerchow also advocates for hiring workers with diverse backgrounds, saying “getting those different backgrounds brings different perspectives, and getting those into the security strategy is great; it builds different synergies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-be-clear-on-the-mission"&gt;2. Be clear on the mission&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.deloitte.com/us/en/about/people/profiles.shchand+8b8c8649.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sharon Chand&lt;/a&gt;, US cyber defense and resilience leader at professional services firm Deloitte, says a characteristic of a high-performing team is alignment on the team’s mission.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To do that, though, team members need to &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3485337/how-leading-cisos-build-business-critical-cyber-cultures.html"&gt;know what the mission is and buy into it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It has to be a very clear mission that the leaders have articulated,” she says, explaining that the mission gives guidance on what everyone should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs may think that the security’s department mission is clear — or that the mission is simply stated as “protect the organization from threats” — but Chand says a mission that provides clarity and details on the risks, threats, and security priorities that are unique to the organization based on its industry and business gives the teams an objective to rally around and direction on how to act “without having to check in and run things up the chain.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In that way, Chand says a clear mission allows for speed — a needed attribute for security teams in an era when the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3841865/what-cybersecurity-teams-need-to-know-about-shrinking-attack-timeframes.html"&gt;pace of attacks is accelerating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A mark of a high-performing team is when the team understands its role in helping the business be successful, because they understand it’s not just about driving down critical alerts or responding to events within certain SLAs; it’s about making sure the business can continue to run. That helps with purpose and motivation,” Chand adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gerchow also sees how a clear mission helps build a strong team: “Telling developers they have to do something for compliance doesn’t excite them,” he says, “but it does if you talk about risk and how to advance the business, if you put it in terms of what’s in it for the business.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-properly-equip-the-team-to-fulfill-the-mission"&gt;3. Properly equip the team to fulfill the mission&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571309/seven-strategies-for-building-a-great-security-team.html"&gt;high-performing team&lt;/a&gt; needs the right training, tools, and techniques to fulfill its mission, and that’s no different in the cybersecurity space, Chand says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, no CISO has an unlimited budget to fund every need staffers might identify, so it’s important to be strategic by knowing the team members’ strengths and by identifying where they need more training, what tools they’re best equipped to optimize, and where they must focus on improvement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CISOs need to be enabling them with the right training and technology to evolve their skills to meet the mission,” Chand adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That now includes ensuring the security team can use artificial intelligence to transform their roles, she says. “It’s teaching them to use data and analytics and how to use AI in a different way.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The use of AI also boosts the ability to improve team performance, Chand notes, as scaling the use of AI in the security department “creates bandwidth” that enables CISOs and their staffers to move out of reactive mode and gain time and resources to upskill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-be-great-at-prioritizing"&gt;4. Be great at prioritizing&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs can build a high-performing team by getting better at setting and communicating priorities so team members know where to focus their time and efforts, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathanwenzler/"&gt;Nathan Wenzler&lt;/a&gt;, field CISO for client advisory at cybersecurity firm Optiv.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’ve known in the industry for a long time that we can’t boil the ocean, we can’t patch every vulnerability, we can’t fix every line of code. There’s simply too much to do, and we don’t have the resources to do it all. So prioritization is the right path,” he says. “It’s a function that a lot of people say they do, but many aren’t executing it well.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs who consolidate data from their security tools to create a holistic view of threats and vulnerabilities and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080670/what-does-aligning-security-to-the-business-really-mean.html"&gt;align security strategy to the business&lt;/a&gt; are able to gain clarity on priorities and better direct their teams, Wenzler says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This isn’t an easy problem to solve,” he adds, “but where it does get solved, it becomes much easier to do an apples-to-apples comparison to where you’re at most risk and then prioritize what work needs to get done.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-build-workers-soft-skills-to-boost-engagement-with-business-peers"&gt;5. Build workers’ soft skills to boost engagement with business peers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security pros don’t always come with strong business, communication, and leadership skills. “We spent the past 20 years or so getting really good at the technical; now we absolutely need to start building the soft skills on our teams,” Wenzler says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He stresses the need for communications skills specifically, saying they’re essential for security teams to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1308238/breaking-down-the-language-barrier-how-to-master-the-art-of-communication.html"&gt;effectively articulate information about the policies and procedures&lt;/a&gt; that the business needs to follow to counteract cyber threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The teams that perform best today are the ones that successfully get everyone else to buy into what they’re doing,” Wenzler says. “They [achieve] that when they’re seen as business enablers and not just a division of IT, and they do that when they’re communicating in the language that the business understands.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ability for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/569687/how-to-make-your-security-team-more-business-savvy.html"&gt;security pros to effectively engage with their business peers&lt;/a&gt; through improved communication, business acumen, empathy, and the like helps them be better workers, too, Wenzler explains. That’s because they gain more insight and clarity into the risks that matter most to the business, insight that they can then apply to how they do their security jobs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Others note that security teams that have a strong rapport and collaboration with their business counterparts also have more cross-functional influence and higher levels of trust, both of which help them get buy-in on security rules and requirements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That means security gets done and actual improvements happen,” Wenzler adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-appoint-and-empower-deputies"&gt;6. Appoint — and empower — deputies&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;High-performing teams have CISOs who know they can’t do everything on their own and instead rely on deputies to help carry the load, says &lt;a href="https://silverjacket.mxficus.com/60da58dd67b70018824684dd/l/0InSHgjlu4fJK3vHG?rn=&amp;amp;re=iQXZu5Cd0FmcwtWeyFWbARHdhJHcrlnch1mI&amp;amp;sc=false"&gt;Steve Martano&lt;/a&gt;, faculty at IANS Research and a partner in Artico Search’s cybersecurity practice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A CISO should be identifying their top deputies or, if they already have them, they should be assigning them more of the operational tasks and the strategic needs related to their discipline, which enables the CISO to be more of that business risk executive and really serve as the peer of the CFO, the head of product, and the P&amp;amp;L leaders in the business,” Martano says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This may seem like more of a win for the CISO than the team as a whole, but that’s not the case, Martano says. Rather, this creates stronger leaders throughout the security department who can respond quickly to team members’ needs — rather than always having to escalate questions, issues, and plans up to the CISO and waiting for responses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Strong deputies mean that you as a CISO can save cycles, because you don’t have to be as attentive to the day-to-day operational work they’re leading,” Martano says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4015173/how-cisos-are-training-the-next-generation-of-cyber-leaders.html"&gt;Empowering deputies&lt;/a&gt; can be hard for CISOs, Martano says, noting “there are a lot of CISOs who operate out of an abundance of caution and therefore micromanage their teams.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He advises CISOs who want to build a stronger leadership team to first assess who they have, what skills they possess, and what skills they need to build. CISOs then need to plan how they’ll &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094734/the-cisos-greatest-risk-department-leaders-quitting.html"&gt;train those leaders to take on more executive-level tasks and oversight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Give them the latitude to make decisions, to make mistakes, and use you as a sounding board,” Martano says. “Have people represent you in meetings, and try to get the most out of people by making them think more business-wise and more strategically.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Martano says creating a strong leadership team has benefits that cascade throughout the ranks, as these deputies tend to bring the same approach to those they supervise, empowering their own direct reports and expecting them to do the same with those reporting to them. As a result, workers at all levels are upskilling, taking on more responsibilities, and accepting more accountability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These CISOs,” Martano says, “are creating an environment that is fostering leaders down the chain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110690/6-strategies-for-building-a-high-performance-cybersecurity-team.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-021 - Vulnerability affecting MongoDB - CVE-2025-14847</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-021-vulnerability-affecting-mongodb-cve-2025-14847</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-021-vulnerability-affecting-mongodb-cve-2025-14847</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-863)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-863</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-863</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 19:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-864)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-864</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-864</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 19:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-865)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-865</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-865</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 20:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New report explores use of robotics and unmanned systems in the fight against crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</link>
      <description>Europol has today published The Unmanned Future(s): The Impact of Robotics and Unmanned Systems on Law Enforcement. The report, produced by the Europol Innovation Lab, provides an in-depth analysis of how unmanned systems could change society, crime and law enforcement, and discusses the challenges and opportunities they present.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/new-report-explores-use-of-robotics-and-unmanned-systems-in-fight-against-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmarterTools security advisory (AV25-866)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity hat kein Budget-Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107963/cybersecurity-hat-kein-budget-problem.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Juggle 16z9" class="wp-image-4107974" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Dudarau-Dzmitry_shutterstock_1835831185_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Ein Tag im Leben eines Sicherheitsentscheiders…&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Dudarau Dzmitry | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn es um Security-Budgets geht, dreht sich ein Großteil der (Online-)Diskussionen darum, wie man das “Board” für sich gewinnt und Investitionen rechtfertigt. Einige Ansätze basieren auf spezifischen &lt;a href="https://www.secureworld.io/industry-news/economists-guide-defending-cybersecurity-budget" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Finanzmodellen&lt;/a&gt; und zielen darauf ab, den Return on Investment (ROI) zu rechtfertigen. Andere konzentrieren sich eher darauf, &lt;a href="https://hackernoon.com/the-roi-of-cybersecurity-investments-how-businesses-can-quantify-and-justify-security-spending" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Risiken&lt;/a&gt; zu quantifizieren und deren Minderung nachzuweisen. Gemein ist ihnen allen, das sie datengestützt funktionieren und auf rationalen Argumenten fußen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Allerdings stellt sich die Frage: Werden Entscheidungen in großen Organisationen wirklich auf diese Art und Weise getroffen? Tatsächlich sind diese Ansätze Teil der Bottom-up-Argumentation, die CISOs, Security-Berater und -Anbieter in den letzten zwei Jahrzehnten entwickelt haben, um Vorstände &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3809620/cisos-rucken-naher-an-den-vorstand.html" target="_blank"&gt;für sich zu gewinnen&lt;/a&gt;. Meiner Erfahrung nach steht das im Widerspruch zur realen Unternehmensdynamik. Und zwar in dreierlei Hinsicht.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="narrativ-trifft-realitat"&gt;Narrativ trifft Realität&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zunächst einmal: Die Entscheidungsfindung auf Unternehmensebene mag den Anschein von Rationalität erwecken. Tatsächlich wird sie jedoch von kognitiven Verzerrungen beeinflusst, wie &lt;a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Kahneman" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Kahneman&lt;/a&gt; und seine Denkschule nachgewiesen haben. Im Cybersecurity-Bereich ist das besonders offensichtlich – was mich zu meinem zweiten Punkt führt. Jeder, der ausreichend Zeit in der Sicherheitsbranche verbracht hat, kennt diese Situation. Zuvor verweigerte Gelder werden plötzlich in nicht geahnter Höhe verfügbar, weil:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regulatorische Überprüfungen anstehen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ein Audit-Report schlecht ausgefallen ist, oder&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ein aktueller Sicherheitsvorfall für Furore sorgt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In solchen Szenarien werden eher selten Bedenken bezüglich des Return on Invest (ROI) oder der Risikominderung geäußert. Die obersten Führungskräfte haben eher im Blick, nachweisen zu können, dass sie ihren Job erledigt haben, wenn es zu einem schwerwiegenden Breach kommt. Wenn die Umsetzung nicht entsprechend erfolgt, trägt jemand anderes dafür die Verantwortung. Das ist nicht selten der CISO – die Bezeichnung &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491966/chief-intrusion-scapegoat-officer-11-wege-aus-der-sundenbock-falle.html" target="_blank"&gt;Chief Incident Scapegoat Officer&lt;/a&gt; kommt nicht von ungefähr. Noch wichtiger: In vielen Vorstandsetagen ist inzwischen die Erkenntnis gereift, dass es weniger die Frage ist, ob ein Cyberangriff droht – sondern vielmehr wann. Nach zwei Jahrzehnten, die quasi einem fortlaufenden Breach gleichkommen, dürfte es schwierig sein, noch ein Board-Mitglied zu finden, das sich der möglichen Auswirkungen auf das Geschäft nicht bewusst ist.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das bringt mich zu meinem dritten Punkt: Ich habe viele Gespräche geführt, insbesondere mit CIOs. Die geben oft ganz offen zu, dass sie in ihre Cybersecurity-Budgets einplanen können, was sie möchten. Ihr Hauptproblem besteht vor allem darin, bei Security-Projekten auch Ergebnisse zu liefern. Woher kommt diese Diskrepanz zwischen CISOs und Anbietern, die mit Ressourcen kämpfen auf der einen Seite und Top-Führungskräften auf der anderen, die zunehmend verstehen, dass es wichtig ist, in den Schutz des Unternehmens zu investieren?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="der-mythos-von-der-unterfinanzierten-cybersecurity"&gt;Der Mythos von der unterfinanzierten Cybersecurity&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Natürlich sind Cybersecurity-Projekte oft komplex. Schließlich müssen sie Unternehmenssilos und geografische Grenzen hinter sich lassen, um einen wirksamen Schutz für das Unternehmen zu gewährleisten. In großen Unternehmen, die naturgemäß territorial und politisch geprägt sind, ist das nicht selbstverständlich. Darüber hinaus spielt auch das Profil der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072083/vom-ciso-zum-chief-risk-architect.html" target="_blank"&gt;CISOs&lt;/a&gt; eine wichtige Rolle: Die meisten haben einen technologischen Hintergrund und haben das letzte Jahrzehnt damit verbracht, Vorfälle zu bekämpfen – ohne jemals in die Lage zu kommen, eine langfristige Strategie zu entwickeln oder umzusetzen. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sie haben deshalb in vielen Fällen auch nicht die Management-Erfahrung, die politische Finesse oder das Charisma entwickelt, das nötig ist, um wirklich erfolgreich zu sein – jetzt, wo sie im Fokus der Unternehmensleitung stehen. Viele glauben wirklich, dass chronisches Underinvestment in Cybersicherheit die Hauptursache für unzureichende Reifegrade ist. In Wirklichkeit sind es meist chronische Ausführungsfehler in Verbindung mit einer endemischen, kurzfristigen Geschäftsausrichtung, die das Kernproblem darstellen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projekte werden zurückgestellt, sobald “Quick Wins” erzielt oder Compliance-Berichte abgehakt sind;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Es kommt zu Richtungswechseln, sobald ein neuer Geschäftsführer eintritt – oder ausscheidet;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Initiativen werden bei den ersten Anzeichen von Marktturbulenzen auf Eis gelegt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Solche Dinge deuten darauf hin, dass kulturelle und Governance-Aspekte das eigentliche Problem sind – und die Ursache für stagnierende Cybersecurity-&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492322/cybersecurity-messen-10-kennzahlen-die-cisos-weiterbringen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Reifegrade&lt;/a&gt;. Unter den CISOs, die diese kulturellen Aspekte nicht integriert haben und regelmäßig von diesen Entscheidungen ausgeschlossen bleiben, führt das zu Frust. Und dieser führt wiederum zu kurzen Amtszeiten (für viele nur etwa zwei bis drei Jahre). Dieser stete Wechsel verschärft dann das Missverhältnis zwischen Management und Führung weiter. Denn in großen Unternehmen sind wirklich transformativen Veränderungen in solchen Zeiträumen nicht zu bewirken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch für das Top-Management ist ein &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494661/9-dinge-die-cisos-den-job-kosten.html" target="_blank"&gt;CISO-Personalkarussell&lt;/a&gt; frustrierend: Sie haben schon allzu oft erlebt, dass neue CISOs mit großartigen Plänen und Millionenforderungen antraten – um dann nach wenigen Jahren alles halbfertig zurückzulassen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="in-100-tagen-an-den-strategietisch"&gt;In 100 Tagen an den “Strategietisch”&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Großteil dieser Diskrepanz entsteht in den ersten hundert Tagen des CISOs. Viele Sicherheitsentscheider treten ihre neue Stelle mit vorgefassten Meinungen an, die manchmal schon beim Vorstellungsgespräch entstanden sind. Dinge, die woanders funktioniert haben, Leib-und-Magen-Themen, -Anbieter oder -Berater. Viele haben außerdem den Drang, sich in den ersten hundert Tagen als Spezialisten zu beweisen. Das ist ein Fehler. Kompetenz wird in den ersten hundert Tagen vorausgesetzt (schließlich wurden Sie ja gerade erst &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494429/4-fragen-vor-dem-ciso-job.html" target="_blank"&gt;eingestellt&lt;/a&gt;). Die Herausforderungen liegen woanders: Es geht darum, Ihre Fähigkeit unter Beweis zu stellen, sich in die Organisationsstruktur des Unternehmens einzufügen und als Führungskraft zu agieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meiner Meinung nach beginnt das damit, zuzuhören. Zum Beispiel den Stakeholdern und Sponsoren, um deren Erwartungen und Pain Points zu verstehen. Oder das, was beim Vorgänger funktioniert hat und was nicht. Dieser Prozess sollte den Beginn markieren für die gemeinschaftliche Entwicklung einer Cybersicherheitsstrategie. Wenn Ziele mit den Stakeholdern und Sponsoren geteilt werden, reduziert das auch Reibungsverluste. Daraus können mit der Zeit Business Champions entstehen, die die Cybersicherheitsstrategie vorleben und weitergeben. Und zwar nicht, weil es die des CISO ist, sondern ihre eigene.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs sollten in den ersten hundert Tagen außerdem in die Governance- und Führungsdynamik des Unternehmens eingebunden werden. Nur Sicherheitsentscheider, die die kulturellen Strömungen im gesamten Unternehmen identifizieren und verfolgen, erlangen Zugang zu den informellen Vertrauensnetzwerken, in denen die tatsächlichen Entscheidungen getroffen werden. Budget-Diskussionen sind ab diesem Punkt deutlich weniger konfrontativ – sie entwickeln sich mehr zu einem gegenseitigen Austausch zwischen vertrauenswürdigen Partnern. Umgekehrt laufen CISOs, die ihre ersten hundert Tage damit verbringen, sich technisch zu beweisen, Gefahr, in einem Teufelskreis aus operativen Feuerwehreinsätzen gefangen zu bleiben. Und aus dieser Situation gibt es oft kein Entkommen mehr. Am Ende mögen Sie zwar als zuverlässige Kraft angesehen werden, aber es ist unwahrscheinlich, dass Sie so einen Platz am “Strategietisch” erhalten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Letztendlich wird die Zukunft denjenigen CISOs gehören, die erkennen, dass der Aufbau von Einfluss und Vertrauen Vorrang vor Maßnahmen und Investitionen haben muss. Vorstände müssen nicht mehr davon überzeugt werden, dass &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494359/der-grose-ki-risiko-guide.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cyberrisiken&lt;/a&gt; wichtig sind – sie brauchen selbstbewusste, kulturell versierte Führungskräfte, die sich in komplexen Unternehmensdynamiken zurechtfinden, Vertrauen zu allen Stakeholdern aufbauen und die Umsetzung über Silos hinweg koordinieren können. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dieser Beitrag wurde im Rahmen des &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4104251/cybersecurity-isnt-underfunded-its-undermanaged.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;englischsprachigen Experten-Netzwerks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; von Foundry veröffentlicht.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107963/cybersecurity-hat-kein-budget-problem.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical jsPDF vulnerability enables arbitrary file read in Node.js deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114360/critical-jspdf-vulnerability-enables-arbitrary-file-read-in-node-js-deployments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A now-fixed critical flaw in the jsPDF &lt;a href="https://github.com/parallax/jsPDF" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; could enable attackers to extract sensitive files from enterprise servers and embed them directly into generated PDF documents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tracked as &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-68428" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-68428&lt;/a&gt;, the flaw affects unpatched Node.js deployments of jsPDF, where untrusted input is passed to file-handling APIs without proper validation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to an Endor Labs analysis, the issue enables path traversal and local file inclusion, allowing an attacker to read arbitrary files from the underlying filesystem. In affected environments, this could expose credentials, configuration files, private keys, or environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability impacts jsPDF versions 3.0.4 and earlier, specifically the Node.js builds used in server-side PDF generation workflows, and does not affect browser-only usage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While a fix has been made available, Endor researchers warned that remediation goes beyond a simple version bump, particularly in production environments that rely on dynamic file handling. “The patch provides no protection if the runtime permits unrestricted filesystem access,” Endor researchers said in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PDF library turns into a file exfiltration vector&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CVE-2025-68428 issue lies in how jsPDF handles file paths when loading external resources in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562547/malicious-code-in-the-node-js-npm-registry-shakes-open-source-trust-model.html"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;. Several commonly used APIs, including “addImage”,“html”, and “addFont”, internally rely on a “loadFile()” function to read files from disk. Prior to version 4.0.0, these methods did not adequately validate or restrict file paths supplied at runtime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an application accepts user-controlled input, such as a filename, image path, or font reference, and passes it directly into these APIs, an attacker could supply a crafted path to reference sensitive application files. jsPDF would then read the file and embed its contents into the resulting PDF without triggering an error.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the library does not enforce file-type restrictions at this stage, the issue is not limited to images or fronts. Any file readable by the Node.js process can potentially be included.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bug has been assigned a critical severity rating at a base CVSS score of 9.2 out of 10. Researchers urged upgrading to the fixed version immediately to protect against exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Patching may not be enough&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The jsPDF maintainers addressed the issue in version 4.0.0 by restricting filesystem access by default. The fix relies on Node.js permission mode, which requires applications to explicitly grant read access to specific directories at runtime. When properly configured, this prevents jsPDF from accessing files outside approved paths.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, this approach introduces operational complexity. Node.js permission mode is evolving, and many production environments either run older Node versions or have not adopted permission-based execution. “Many environments run older Node.js versions that lack stable permission mode support, and enabling –permission may break existing functionality if filesystem access patterns haven’t been carefully mapped,” the researchers &lt;a href="https://www.endorlabs.com/learn/cve-2025-68428-critical-path-traversal-in-jspdf"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers outlined a set of steps to assess the exploitability of their deployments, which includes verifying if jsPDF is being used server-side ( as it is unexploitable on the client side), checking if the running version already implements permission mode and has filesystem permission properly configured, identifying affected code paths with SCA tools, and manual searching of the vulnerable codebase.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Endor Labs credited security researcher Kwangwoon Kim (KilkAt) for identifying and reporting the vulnerability on &lt;a href="https://github.com/parallax/jsPDF/security/advisories/GHSA-f8cm-6447-x5h2" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114360/critical-jspdf-vulnerability-enables-arbitrary-file-read-in-node-js-deployments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated data poisoning proposed as a solution for AI theft threat</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113463/automated-data-poisoning-proposed-as-a-solution-for-ai-theft-threat.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have developed a tool that they say can make stolen high-value proprietary data used in AI systems useless, a solution that CSOs may have to adopt to protect their sophisticated large language models (LLMs).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00274" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The technique&lt;/a&gt;, created by researchers from universities in China and Singapore, is to inject plausible but false data into what’s known as a knowledge graph (KG) created by an AI operator. A knowledge graph holds the proprietary data used by the LLM.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Injecting poisoned or adulterated data into a data system for protection against theft isn’t new. What’s new in this tool – dubbed AURA (Active Utility Reduction via Adulteration)– is that authorized users have a secret key that filters out the fake data so the LLM’s answer to a query is usable. If the knowledge graph is stolen, however, it’s unusable by the attacker unless they know the key, because the adulterants will be retrieved as context, causing deterioration in the LLM’s reasoning and leading to factually incorrect responses. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers say AURA degrades the performance of unauthorized systems to an accuracy of just 5.3%, while maintaining 100% fidelity for authorized users, with “negligible overhead,” defined as a maximum query latency increase of under 14%. They also say AURA is robust against various sanitization attempts by an attacker, retaining 80.2% of the adulterants injected for defense, and the fake data it creates is hard to detect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Why is all this important? Because KGs often contain an organization’s highly sensitive intellectual property (IP), they are a valuable target. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mixed-reactions-from-experts"&gt;Mixed reactions from experts&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the proposal has been greeted with skepticism by one expert and with caution by another.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Data poisoning has never really worked well,” said &lt;a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/about/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bruce Schneier&lt;/a&gt;, chief of security architecture at Inrupt Inc., and a fellow and lecturer at Harvard’s Kennedy School. “Honeypots, no better. This is a clever idea, but I don’t see it as being anything but an ancillary security system.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://josephsteinberg.com/cybersecurityexpertjosephsteinberg/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Joseph Steinberg&lt;/a&gt;, a US-based cybersecurity and AI consultant, disagreed, saying, “in general this could work for all sorts of AI and non-AI systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is not a new concept,” he pointed out. “Some parties have been doing this [injecting bad data for defense] with databases for many years.” For example, he noted, a database can be watermarked so if it is stolen and some of its contents are later used – a fake credit card number, for example — investigators knows where that piece of data came from. Unlike watermarking, however, which puts one bad record into a database, AURA poisons the entire database, so if it’s stolen, it’s useless.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AURA may not be needed in some AI models, he added, if the data in the KG isn’t sensitive. The real unanswered question is what the real-world trade-off between application performance and security would be if AURA is used.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He also noted that AURA doesn’t solve the problem of an undetected attacker interfering with the AI system’s knowledge graph, or even its data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The worst case may not be that your data gets stolen, but that a hacker puts bad data into your system so your AI produces bad results and you don’t know it,” Steinberg said. “Not only that, you now don’t know which data is bad, or which knowledge the AI has learned is bad. Even if you can identify that a hacker has come in and done something six months ago, can you unwind all the learning of the last six months?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why Cybersecurity 101 – defense in depth – is vital for AI and non-AI systems, he said. AURA “reduces the consequences if someone steals a model,” he noted, but whether it can jump from a lab to the enterprise has yet to be determined.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="knowledge-graphs-101"&gt;Knowledge graphs 101&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A bit of background about knowledge graphs: LLMs use a technique called Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to search for information based on a user query and provide the results as additional reference for the AI system’s answer generation. &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/graphrag-unlocking-llm-discovery-on-narrative-private-data/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In 2024, Microsoft introduced GraphRAG &lt;/a&gt;to help LLMs answer queries needing information beyond the data on which they have been trained. GraphRAG uses LLM-generated knowledge graphs to improve performance and lower the odds of hallucinations in answers when performing discovery on private datasets such as an enterprise’s proprietary research, business documents, or communications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proprietary knowledge graphs within GraphRAGs make them “a prime target for IP theft,” just like any other proprietary data, says the research paper. “An attacker might steal the KG through external cyber intrusions or by leveraging malicious insiders.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once an attacker has successfully stolen a KG, they can deploy it in a private GraphRAG system to replicate the originating system’s powerful capabilities, avoiding costly investments, the research paper notes.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the low-latency requirements of interactive GraphRAG make strong cryptographic solutions, such homomorphic encryption of a KG, impractical. “Fully encrypting the text and embeddings would require decrypting large portions of the graph for every query,” the researchers note. “This process introduces prohibitive computational overhead and latency, making it unsuitable for real-world use.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AURA, they say, addresses these issues, making stolen KGs useless to attackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-is-moving-faster-than-ai-security"&gt;AI is moving faster than AI security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the use of AI spreads, CSOs have to remember that artificial intelligence and everything needed to make it work also make it much harder to recover from bad data being put into a system, Steinberg noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI is progressing far faster than the security for AI,” Steinberg warned. “For now, many AI systems are being protected in similar manners to the ways we protected non-AI systems. That doesn’t yield the same level of protection, because if something goes wrong, it’s much harder to know if something bad has happened, and its harder to get rid of the implications of an attack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The industry is trying to address these issues, as the researchers observe in their paper. One useful reference, they note, is the US National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.600-1.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AI Risk Management Framework&lt;/a&gt; that emphasizes the need for robust data security and resilience, including the importance of developing effective KG protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113463/automated-data-poisoning-proposed-as-a-solution-for-ai-theft-threat.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 things CISOs can’t afford to get wrong in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110699/8-things-cisos-cant-afford-to-get-wrong-in-2026.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity leaders have a lot to consider when trying to keep their organizations safe. But some things stand out more than others — or might be under the radar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a new year dawns, here are some things CISOs should avoid falling short on in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="get-complacent-about-identity-controls-in-the-face-of-rising-ai-agents"&gt;Get complacent about identity controls in the face of rising AI agents&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deployment of AI agents is growing rapidly, as enterprises look to take advantage of the automation and efficiency they offer. The global AI agents market size was estimated at $5.40 billion in 2024 and is projected to reach $50.31 billion by 2030, according to Grand View Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The increased use of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4047974/agentic-ai-a-cisos-security-nightmare-in-the-making.html"&gt;AI agents presents a cybersecurity challenge&lt;/a&gt; for enterprises, especially &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089732/rethinking-identity-for-the-ai-era-cisos-must-build-trust-at-machine-speed.html"&gt;in terms of identity controls&lt;/a&gt;. Potential threats include identity spoofing and over-permissioned access. Cyber criminals can exploit agents through prompt injection or malicious instructions to bypass controls and gain unauthorized access to systems and applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Get identity — including AI agents — right and you control who can do what at machine speed,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/morgan-adamski-501094240/"&gt;Morgan Adamski&lt;/a&gt;, deputy leader for cyber, data, and tech risk at consulting firm PwC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Adversaries increasingly log in, not break in, and AI agents are now making real changes to systems and data,” Adamski says. “What leaders can’t afford to miss is treating every human, workload, and agent as a managed identity, setting them up with their own accounts, phishing-resistant MFA [multi-factor authentication], minimum access for only as long as needed, passwords/keys that change automatically, and monitoring for odd permission changes or hijacked sessions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises need to build AI-agent governance into everyday workflows,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;so that teams can move quickly without losing control, Adamski says. For example, require hardware-backed MFA for administrators, expire elevated privileges by default, and register each new agent as an application with its own policies.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Identity and access controls for AI agents and AI platforms are one of the most important areas of concern for CISOs,” says &lt;a href="https://isg-one.com/about-us/people/jason-stading"&gt;Jason Stading&lt;/a&gt;, director at global technology research and advisory firm ISG. “Right now, permissions and access rights for AI are a black box in many areas. We will see a major push over the next couple of years for tools and methods for more transparency and control in this area specifically.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ignore-increasingly-complex-supply-chains"&gt;Ignore increasingly complex supply chains&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Supply chains have been a growing area of risk for enterprises, given the rise of digital business and the growing complexity of supply chains in today’s global business market.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This area is particularly important for companies in the manufacturing, retail, and logistics sectors. “In 2026, CISOs who overlook cybersecurity in complex supply chains and manufacturing environments risk catastrophic consequences,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregory-zelo/"&gt;Greg Zelo&lt;/a&gt;, CTO of AMFT, a provider of metal products and components.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Modern manufacturing is no longer confined to a single plant; it’s a web of interconnected suppliers, IoT [internet of things]-enabled machinery, and cloud-driven production systems,” Zelo says. “This complexity creates an expansive attack surface where one weak link can cripple entire operations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent incidents underscore the stakes, Zelo says. For example, in September 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065991/dont-drink-or-drive-say-cyberattackers.html"&gt;Jaguar Land Rover suffered a supply chain cyberattack&lt;/a&gt; that halted production across the UK, Slovakia, India, and Brazil for weeks, costing an estimated $2.5 billion, he says. “The breach rippled through hundreds of suppliers, triggering layoffs and bankruptcies,” he adds. “This wasn’t just an IT failure; it was an operational crisis that exposed how deeply interdependent global manufacturing has become.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3595787/ot-security-becoming-a-mainstream-concern.html"&gt;increasingly target operational technology (OT) systems&lt;/a&gt; that control robotics, assembly lines, and quality checks because halting production forces companies to pay ransoms quickly, Zelo says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Beyond financial losses, the risks extend to intellectual property theft, regulatory penalties, and national security concerns,” Zelo says. “For CISOs, the lesson is clear: Traditional perimeter defenses are obsolete. Securing complex supply chains requires &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;zero-trust architectures&lt;/a&gt; across IT and OT environments, continuous monitoring of third-party risk, including firmware and software updates, rapid patching and segmentation to isolate critical systems, [and] incident response drills involving suppliers and contractors.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;Downplay escalating geopolitical tensions&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to imagine CISOs being so laser focused on protecting their organizations from external and internal threats that they take their eyes off geopolitical tensions. Or maybe they dismiss them as being irrelevant to the cybersecurity issues at hand for their organizations. Either way, it’s a big mistake.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Building systemic scenarios into organizational cyber resiliency plans is very important,” ISG’s Stading says. “This should include global developments and geopolitical friction that may affect the business.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is also an increasing push for industry-specific threat intelligence to give enterprises tailored indicators of compromise that might affect their business and their assets, Stading says. “Some of this can stem from potential advanced, persistent threats from malicious nation-states.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The increasing intersection of cybersecurity and geopolitics is a reality, says &lt;a href="https://www.northdoor.co.uk/about-us/management-team/aj-thompson/"&gt;AJ Thompson&lt;/a&gt;, chief commercial officer at IT consultancy Northdoor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cyber attacks via nation-state actors are part of much larger conflicts that target critical infrastructure and global supply chains,” he says. “Failure to incorporate geopolitical intelligence into threat modeling disproportionately exposes organizations to high-impact state-sponsored cyberattacks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, unintended involvement in such events can also have severe regulatory and reputational consequences, Thompson notes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="be-lax-about-organizational-cloud-use"&gt;Be lax about organizational cloud use&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As use of cloud services continues to increase, so do the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/555213/top-cloud-security-threats.html"&gt;security and privacy risks associated with the cloud&lt;/a&gt;. If CISOs neglect this area of cybersecurity they risk exposing their organizations to attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is important for both cloud services and AI tools, which are often cross-pollinated with each other,” Stading says. “Appropriate and modern security awareness and training tied to roles and responsibilities is key, and it needs to factor in usage of AI tools and technologies that are so prevalent in the workplace now.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is often a lack of training and education for cloud administrators and engineers around proper cloud security practices and procedures, Stading says. “Tool adoption and usage is also a key area many cloud teams are trying to improve,” he says. “Many organizations have invested in security tooling for clouds that is underutilized.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The traditional security perimeter no longer exists, “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4009247/5-multicloud-security-challenges-and-how-to-address-them.html"&gt;especially with multicloud adoption&lt;/a&gt;,” Thompson says. “Organizations relying on reactive cloud security often miss sophisticated threats.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Proactive &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;cloud security posture management (CSPM)&lt;/a&gt; and clear user security guidelines are critical steps toward the prevention of costly breaches and operational disruptions, Thompson says. “Safe user practices must be instilled continuously in order to minimize risks from human error in complex cloud environments,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="overlook-growing-compliance-burdens"&gt;Overlook growing compliance burdens&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some companies, particular in heavily regulated industries such as financial services and healthcare, have long faced the need to comply with data security and privacy regulations such as the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570125/glba-explained-what-the-graham-leach-bailey-act-means-for-privacy-and-it-security.html"&gt;Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570241/hipaa-explained-definition-compliance-and-violations.html"&gt;Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But these days, just about every type of business has to comply with a growing number of data privacy and protection laws around the world. Overlooking or underestimating these regulations could lead to fines and other repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s true that heavily regulated organizations take on a lot of extra overhead for compliance activities, and compliance fatigue is not unheard of,” Stading says. “Because the CISO role has evolved over the past few years to take on more accountability and responsibility for compliance, CISOs really cannot afford to overlook or undervalue compliance efforts.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs at global enterprises in particular need to be up on the latest developments. “The regulatory landscape for cybersecurity in the UK and Europe is escalating rapidly,” Northdoor’s Thompson says. “Frameworks such as the GDPR [General Data Protection Regulation] and DORA [&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570091/eus-dora-regulation-explained-new-risk-management-requirements-for-financial-firms.html"&gt;Digital Operational Resilience Act&lt;/a&gt;] are setting new benchmarks that require organizations to demonstrate not only documented controls, but also empirically verifiable cybersecurity effectiveness.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regulators will want to see robust evidence that cybersecurity and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2111061/cyber-resilience-a-business-imperative-cisos-must-get-right.html"&gt;operational resilience&lt;/a&gt; are deeply embedded within all layers of business processes, rather than handled as a compliance checkbox, Thompson says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Equally important is the management of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4012147/third-party-risk-management-how-to-avoid-compliance-disaster.html"&gt;third-party risk&lt;/a&gt;, for which regulators increasingly hold organizations accountable,” Thompson says. “As supply chains become more complex and distributed, vulnerabilities from external providers represent serious compliance and security liabilities. Failure to integrate these regulatory expectations into security strategies proactively risks not just heavy financial penalties, but also operational disruption and lasting reputational harm.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="underestimate-ai-chatbots-and-the-legal-exposure-they-create"&gt;Underestimate AI chatbots and the legal exposure they create&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI chatbots are an emerging risk for data privacy, says Daniel Woods, principal researcher at Coalition, a cybersecurity insurance provider. In Coalition’s analysis of nearly 200 privacy-related claims and scans of 5,000 business websites, 5% of claims targeted chatbot technologies, he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These claims alleged unlawful interception of customer conversations under state wiretap laws enacted long before such AI tools existed,” Woods says. “All the chatbot-related claims followed the same template, stating that the chat’s opening message should have disclosed that the conversation was being recorded.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The claims alleged violation of the decades-old Florida Security of Communications Act, Woods says. About 5% of websites deployed chatbot technologies, which equates to the same percentage of web privacy claims that focused on chatbots, he notes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Chatbot use was particularly common in the IT and financial industries, with 9% and 6% of sites in these industries using chatbots, respectively,” Woods adds. There will likely be an increase in usage of these chatbots and therefore, a potential increase in future claims, he contends.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The risk of getting chatbots wrong is that these systems can be easily manipulated with tactics like prompt injection, which has been documented dozens of times leaking customer data,” Woods says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="neglect-to-secure-the-cloud"&gt;Neglect to secure the cloud&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By now, nearly every business relies on cloud services to support at least some of their operations. Neglecting the security of these services is asking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cloud and SaaS will keep expanding — so pre-wire ‘golden’ landing zones with guardrails for identity, encryption, logging, and egress, and use policy-as-code so the compliant configuration is the default,” PwC’s Adamski says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs need to use tools to continuously inventory assets, spot misconfigurations, flag anomalous behavior, and auto-remediate where prudent, Adamski adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The act of firefighting alerts coming in from everywhere won’t keep up with multicloud sprawl and identity-centric attacks,” Adamski says. Modernize the security operations center with automation and AI to reduce the noise and correlate signals across cloud services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="forget-about-the-human-factor"&gt;Forget about the human factor&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With so many cybersecurity tools and services in place, it’s easy to sometimes forget about the human side of cybersecurity. That can lead to all kinds of things going wrong.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In my experience, the proximate cause of security breaches is usually human error,” says &lt;a href="https://www.cm.law/people/beth-fulkerson/"&gt;Beth Fulkerson&lt;/a&gt;, technology and cybersecurity partner at law firm CM Law. “Usually someone falls for a scam and opens the door [to] malicious code.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s human nature to want to react to a message or open a document, and this is what gets users into trouble. “The primary solution is not more tech, but more training to help employees feel comfortable pushing back on requests for access to their machines or for information,” Fulkerson says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An example of human error would be if someone fails to remember that a printer or fax machine is on a network, and does not install security protections or doesn’t remove it from the network, Fulkerson says.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Another issue is failure to properly use the security technology available or already in place,” Fulkerson says. The most recent litigation she worked on involved a defendant that claimed it was using file integrity management software as required by the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/569591/pci-dss-explained-requirements-fines-and-steps-to-compliance.html"&gt;PCI DSS&lt;/a&gt;), but either didn’t set the alerts up or failed to heed the alerts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It doesn’t matter if a company has tremendous security software if they do not set it up correctly and maintain it,” Fulkerson says.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110699/8-things-cisos-cant-afford-to-get-wrong-in-2026.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft warns of a surge in phishing attacks exploiting email routing gaps</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113746/microsoft-warns-of-a-surge-in-phishing-attacks-exploiting-email-routing-gaps.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s Threat Intelligence team has disclosed that threat actors are increasingly exploiting complex email routing and misconfigured domain spoof protection to make phishing messages appear as if they were sent from inside the organizations they’re targeting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These campaigns are relying on configuration gaps, specifically scenarios where mail exchanger (MX) DNS records don’t point directly to Microsoft 365 and where Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting &amp;amp; Conformance (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564563/mastering-email-security-with-dmarc-spf-and-dkim.html"&gt;DMARC&lt;/a&gt;) and Sender Policy Framework (SPF) policies are permissive or misconfigured.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Threat actors have leveraged this vector to deliver a wide variety of phishing messages related to various phishing-as-a-service (PhaaS) platforms such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4100393/hybrid-2fa-phishing-kits-are-making-attacks-harder-to-detect.html"&gt;Tycoon 2FA&lt;/a&gt;,” Microsoft said in a security blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The blog noted that while the attack vector isn’t brand new, the exploitation has picked up significantly since mid-2025, delivering phishing lures ranging from password resets to shared documents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="internal-routing-and-weak-policies-are-at-fault"&gt;“Internal” routing and weak policies are at fault&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fault is with how receiving mail servers interpret incoming messages. When MX records lead to complex mail paths, such as on-premises systems or third-party relays before Microsoft 365, standard spoof protection checks like SPF hard-fail and strict DMARC enforcement may not be applied correctly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In these cases, a phishing email can arrive with the recipient’s own address in both the “To” and “From” fields, a spoofed message that appears internal at a glance. In some cases, attackers change the sender name to make the message appear more convincing, while the “From” field is set to a valid internal email address.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Combined with permissive or absent DMARC and SPF policies, these messages may bypass spam filters and land directly in users’ inboxes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Phishing messages sent through this vector may be more effective as they appear to be internally sent messages,” Microsoft added in the&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2026/01/06/phishing-actors-exploit-complex-routing-and-misconfigurations-to-spoof-domains/"&gt; blog&lt;/a&gt;. “Successful credential compromise through phishing attacks may lead to data theft or business email compromise (BEC) attacks against the affected organization or partners and may require extensive remediation efforts, and/or lead to loss of funds in the case of financial scams.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond credential capture, the PhaaS infrastructure can facilitate adversary-in-the-middle (AiTM) attacks that relay authentication information in real time and may even circumvent multi-factor authentication protections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hardening configurations can help&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The disclosure emphasizes that proper configuration of mail authentication mechanisms is the most effective defense against this spoofing vector. Organizations are advised to adopt strict DMARC reject policies and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564563/mastering-email-security-with-dmarc-spf-and-dkim.html"&gt;enforce&lt;/a&gt; SPF hard fails so that unauthenticated mail claiming to be from their domains is rejected or safely quarantined.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Additionally, recommendations include ensuring that any third-party connectors, such as spam filters, archiving services, or legacy mail relays, are correctly set up so that spoof checks can be calculated and enforced consistently.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tenants with MX records pointing directly to Microsoft 365 aren’t vulnerable to this issue because Microsoft’s native spoof detection and filtering mechanisms are applied by default. For more complex mail infrastructures, Microsoft provided specific guidance on mail flow &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-in/exchange/security-and-compliance/mail-flow-rules/mail-flow-rules"&gt;rules&lt;/a&gt; and authentication practices to reduce exposure and block spoofed emails before they ever reach end users’ inboxes. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond mail authentication fixes, Microsoft urged organizations to harden identity defenses against AiTM phishing, which bypasses passwords by hijacking authenticated sessions. Recommended controls include phishing-resistant MFA such as FIDO2 security keys, Conditional Access enforcement, and protection like MFA number matching to limit the impact of stolen tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113746/microsoft-warns-of-a-surge-in-phishing-attacks-exploiting-email-routing-gaps.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to eliminate IT blind spots in the modern, AI-driven enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4112470/how-to-eliminate-it-blind-spots-in-the-modern-ai-driven-enterprise.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The more organizations lean on artificial intelligence (AI), spread workloads across different environments, and tie systems together, the harder it becomes for traditional security practices to present a complete picture of what’s going on. The result is a growing number of blind spots – hidden misconfigurations, inconsistent controls, and unpredictable behaviors across systems and AI agents – that can introduce significant risk long before a red flag appears in tooling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How can CSOs and other security leaders stay ahead of this increasingly dynamic attack surface while minimizing tool sprawl? We asked members of the Foundry Influencer Network to share their best advice for strengthening security posture. Across all experts, a clear message emerges: The answer lies in improving visibility across existing systems, normalizing data flows, and applying AI-driven intelligence to both human processes and technical signals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shift from reactive postures to unified visibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Avoiding blind spots requires a fundamental shift in how organizations think about visibility, says Mircea Trofimciuc (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirceatrofimciuc/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Mircea Trofimciuc&lt;/a&gt;), Vice President of Agentic AI (Product &amp;amp; Engineering) at RealPage, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To avoid blind spots without stacking yet another tool on the pile, CSOs need to shift from a purely reactive posture to a unified visibility strategy. The current API security, code scanning, observability, and monitoring capabilities all still have a clear place — they remain foundational,” he says. “But as enterprises become increasingly AI-dependent and distributed, these traditional signals must be complemented with a new layer of intelligence: the detection of agentic AI behavior via pattern adherence within systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He notes that many blind spots now emerge from the behavior of AI systems themselves—not just from static configuration issues—and this demands a more dynamic view of the environment. “By continuously evaluating whether AI agents, services, and automations are behaving within defined, governed controls, rather than simply checking for static misconfigurations, security leaders can surface hidden risks early, across the entire digital footprint,” Trofimciuc says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Peter van Barneveld (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-van-barneveld-foresight-innovation-catalyst/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Peter van Barneveld&lt;/a&gt;), Group Innovation Manager at Dustin, adds that AI introduces vulnerabilities that often fall outside traditional defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Besides traditional security risks, AI introduces new vulnerabilities such as data poisoning and prompt injection attacks, which often fall outside traditional security controls,” he says. “This is why it is essential to have a modular approach when it comes to security architecture and platform. It should be possible to leverage current possibilities on existing platforms, such as Azure or AWS, and to easily extend with new security building blocks so that the entire IT landscape can be covered, including the new AI stack components.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Align people, processes, and data to reveal hidden risks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several experts emphasized that more tooling is not the answer. Instead, the answer lies in greater alignment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Will Kelly (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/willkelly/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Will Kelly&lt;/a&gt;), a writer focused on AI and the cloud, notes that visibility often breaks down not because of missing tools but because of siloed processes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CSOs don’t always need to throw more tools at the problem to reduce blind spots. They need to better align people, processes, and data. Start by using existing FinOps and cloud cost metrics to identify anomalies in usage patterns, which often reveal hidden risks such as shadow IT or misconfigured services,” he says. “Collaboration between security and FinOps teams can help surface these insights without a new tool investment. Also, regular audits and tagging practices across cloud environments help make your cloud footprint more transparent and manageable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sarv Kohli (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarvkohli/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Sarv Kohli&lt;/a&gt;), CIO and VP Technology and Adjunct Professor at Georgia Tech Professional Education, agrees that the biggest opportunity for reducing blind spots comes from better orchestration, not expanding the stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Connect technology with data, people, and processes. As organizations push deeper into AI, their attack surface evolves faster than any one tool can contain,” he says. “The real opportunity isn’t buying more technology; it’s in orchestrating what already exists with tighter alignment between people, processes, and data. When teams share a single, living view of their AI, cloud, and identity landscape, and stay accountable for what changes, security leaders can reveal and resolve blind spots without expanding their security stack and close hidden gaps long before they become headlines.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Scott Schober (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/snschober/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Scott Schober&lt;/a&gt;), President/CEO at Berkeley Varitronics Systems, Inc., underscores the operational complexity facing modern security teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s tough to avoid blind spots in today’s digital without spending more. The environment is just too complex to manage manually. The attack surface keeps expanding, and old manual processes just can’t keep up with AI, cloud systems, and remote teams,” he says. “From my perspective, the key isn’t just adding more tools. It’s about connecting the ones you have more effectively, automating where it helps, and really knowing your existing systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use existing telemetry and governance models to their full potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vivek Singh (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/imdbest333/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Vivek Singh&lt;/a&gt;), Senior Vice President of IT and Strategic Planning at PALNAR, says unified visibility is achievable using what most enterprises already have in place—if they enforce standards and normalize existing signals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“All security leaders (CSO and VP’s) should ensure unified visibility across assets, identities, and data flows through continuous monitoring, well-defined governance, and collaboration with IT and engineering teams,” he says. “This way your dependencies on external security tools are very minimal. Removing blind spot requires normalizing existing telemetry and enforcing configuration standards and automation detection workflows.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anshul Gandhi (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anshul-gandhi/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Anshul Gandhi&lt;/a&gt;), former Senior Machine Learning Engineer at Dell Technologies, stresses the importance of treating the enterprise landscape as an interconnected system rather than isolated components.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security leaders need the ability to map their environment as a living, interconnected system, not as a collection of isolated components,” he says. He explains that this level of awareness depends on deeper visibility and “unifying telemetry across AI pipelines, cloud services, data platforms, and identity layers so the organization can observe how workloads, models, and data behave in real time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Once this visibility exists, a genuinely data-centric posture becomes possible, where leaders track how sensitive information moves through training pipelines, inference endpoints, and distributed applications, understand which models and services can access it, and anticipate how misconfigurations could expand the blast radius of an incident,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Others see enormous opportunity in using AI-driven automation to enhance (not expand) security tools already in use.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CSOs have to invest heavily in AI-powered automation through agents to proactively and continuously seek and eliminate blind spots,” says Kumar Srivastava (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kumarsrivastava/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn: Kumar Srivastava&lt;/a&gt;), Chief Technology Officer at Turing Labs. “Most existing enterprise investments in security tools are not fully leveraged to their max capacity. Without investing in new tools, CSOs can dramatically increase ROI by connecting, integrating existing tools and driving deeper insight.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A path forward: visibility through orchestration, not expansion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The expanding digital footprint created by AI, cloud services, and distributed applications cannot be secured by piling on additional tools. What’s needed is a unifying layer that grounds all this telemetry, governance, and automation in a single source of truth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where a modern CMDB becomes indispensable. Beyond serving as an accurate, continuously updated system of record, a CMDB provides the structured relationships needed to build enterprise knowledge graphs. By capturing assets, configurations, dependencies, and interactions as connected data, it gives AI applications the context they require to reason, correlate signals, and detect risk across complex environments. These knowledge graphs allow AI-driven security tools and agents to understand how systems, identities, workloads, and AI services relate to one another, thereby transforming raw telemetry into actionable intelligence grounded in a trusted, authoritative view of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In doing so, a CMDB transforms fragmented visibility into coordinated insight, allowing security leaders to reveal blind spots earlier, respond faster, and strengthen posture without expanding their security stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more, visit &lt;a href="https://solutions.opentext.com/cloudops/discovery-and-cmdb/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://solutions.opentext.com/cloudops/discovery-and-cmdb/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4112470/how-to-eliminate-it-blind-spots-in-the-modern-ai-driven-enterprise.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holes in Veeam Backup suite allow remote code execution, creation of malicious backup config files</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114165/holes-in-veeam-backup-suite-allow-remote-code-execution-creation-of-malicious-backup-config-files-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veeam &lt;a href="https://www.veeam.com/kb4792" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;says that four vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; could allow a person with certain oversight roles for its flagship Backup &amp;amp; Replication suite to do serious damage to – but not destroy –  a backup database.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company has already issued a patch for the bugs, which, it says, should be applied immediately.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The worst of the vulnerabilities, CVE-2025-59470, carries a criticality score of 9 and would allow a threat actor “to do something nefarious,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rickvanover/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rick Vanover&lt;/a&gt;, Veeam’s vice-president of product strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But he emphasized that, because of the immutable nature of the backup, data can’t be destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue: Veeam discovered that a person with the role of Backup Admin, Backup Operator, or Tape Operator status in unpatched version 13 of the suite (versions 13.0.1.180 and earlier) have more permissions than they should. The patch corrects that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the flaws addressed are:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CVE-2025-59470 (with a CVSS score of 9) allows a Backup or Tape Operator to perform remote code execution (RCE) as the Postgres user by sending a malicious interval or order parameter;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;CVE-2025-59469 (with a severity score of 7.2) allows a Backup or Tape Operator to write files as root;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;CVE-2025-55125 (with a severity score of 7.2) allows a Backup or Tape Operator to perform remote code execution (RCE) as root by creating a malicious backup configuration file;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;CVE-2025-59468 (with a severity score of 6.7) allows a Backup Administrator to perform remote code execution (RCE) as the Postgres user by sending a malicious password parameter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The patch to version 13.0.1.1071 will be an “easy installation” that won’t be disruptive, Vanover said. As of Tuesday afternoon, Veeam hadn’t received reports of exploitation, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The good news is, if a Veeam server is broken, we can create a new server right away – presumably with this patch installed – import the backups and carry on. The core data is completely unimpacted by this,” Vanover said. “The worst type of thing would be the [backup] environment isn’t working right or the Postgres database is messed up on the Veeam server, so jobs might not behave in a way one might expect.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In these cases, admins using the Veeam One monitoring management suite would get an alert if, for example, a job was unable to connect to the backup server or backup jobs were failing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The four vulnerabilities being patched are less severe than some because an attacker, internal or external, would need valid credentials for the three specific roles, noted &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, he added, backup systems like Veeam are targets for attackers, in particular those who inject ransomware, who often attempt to erase backups.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Backup systems should be regularly audited to ensure that access rights, such as those mentioned in this vulnerability, are properly managed and only accessible to users who actually need them,” he said. “Authentication credentials should be reviewed to ensure they comply with the respective standards.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kellman/?originalSubdomain=ca" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kellman Meghu&lt;/a&gt;, principal security architect at Canadian-based risk management firm DeepCove Cybersecurity, said the worry is how the vulnerabilities could be used by a threat actor to get root privileges to the backup, “which is the worst it can get as far as compromise. From the sounds of the exploit, just being able to update a config file could be the avenue for executing malicious commands at the highest privileges.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Admins who can’t patch quickly, or who have been running unpatched versions for any length of time, should first audit all config files and operations to ensure there have been no changes to the config files or execution of additional unexpected actions. Alerts should be set for every backup process run, so it is closely monitored until the suite can be patched.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Keep in mind,” he added, “if you do see unusual behavior, it is a sign that there is a malicious actor or inside threat operating, and you would need to take a holistic incident response.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4114036/holes-in-veeam-backup-suite-allow-remote-code-execution-creation-of-malicious-backup-config-files.html" target="_blank"&gt;NetworkWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114165/holes-in-veeam-backup-suite-allow-remote-code-execution-creation-of-malicious-backup-config-files-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Die wichtigsten CISO-Trends für 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109550/die-wichtigsten-ciso-trends-fur-2026.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Security-Trends 2026" class="wp-image-4109552" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/shutterstock_2673772875.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Lesen Sie, vor welchen Herausforderungen CISOs mit Blick auf das Jahr 2026 stehen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;SuPatMaN – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Jahr 2025 war für viele CISOs herausfordernd. Anfang des Jahres wurden mit dem Digital Operational Resilience Act (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3804883/dora-umsetzung-halt-banken-cisos-auf-trab.html"&gt;DORA&lt;/a&gt;) alle Finanzunternehmen dazu verpflichtet, ihre Cybersicherheit zu erhöhen. Zudem mussten sich in diesem Jahr zahlreiche Unternehmen mit der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4090107/bundestag-beschliest-nis2-umsetzung.html"&gt;NIS2-Umsetzung&lt;/a&gt; auseinandersetzen. Vor welchen Schwierigkeiten stehen CISOs im Jahr 2026?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="herausforderungen-2026"&gt;Herausforderungen 2026&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nach Meinung von Raphael Reiß, CISO der Vaillant Group, wird das Thema Compliance auch noch im neuen Jahr herausfordernd sein. Er bezeichnet das Ganze als „Regulatorik-Dschungel“.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch Vorwerk-CISO Florian Jörgens sieht die „zunehmend komplexen regulatorischen Anforderungen“ weiterhin als Herausforderung. Diese würden kontinuierliche Nachweise statt punktuelle Compliance verlangen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hinzu kämen wachsender Kostendruck trotz steigender Bedrohungslage und ein verschärfter Fachkräftemangel in allen sicherheitsrelevanten Rollen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Holger Bajohr, CISO der Technische Werke Ludwigshafen, stimmt dem zu: „Ich glaube, dass das Thema Fachkräftemangel noch deutlich spürbarer werden wird und dass Experten schwieriger zu bekommen sein werden.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="sicherheitstrends"&gt;Sicherheitstrends&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stefan Braun, CISO von Henkel, ist sich sicher: „2026 wird weniger durch neue Bedrohungen geprägt sein als durch steigende Komplexität. CISOs müssen gleichzeitig regulatorische Anforderungen, operative Resilienz in IT und OT sowie den sicheren Einsatz von KI beherrschen – oft mit begrenzten Ressourcen.“ Die größte Herausforderung ist seiner Ansicht nach, Sicherheit nicht als Verhinderer, sondern als Enabler von Geschwindigkeit und Innovation zu positionieren und messbar zum Geschäftserfolg beizutragen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jörgens sieht ebenfalls einen klaren Trend in der Kontrolle des Einsatzes von KI, „insbesondere der Umgang mit Shadow AI, also inoffiziellen KI-Tools in den Fachbereichen.“ Der Vorwerk-CISO prognostiziert zudem, dass Third-Party-Risk-Management stärker in den Fokus rückt, weil Lieferketten und externe Modelle zu den größten Angriffsflächen werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vor diesem Hintergrund zählt laut Vaillant-CISO Reiß Resilience by Design zu den wichtigsten Themen im kommenden Jahr.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Henkel-CISO Braun fügt hinzu: „Software-Supply-Chain-Security und transparente Risikosteuerung gewinnen an Bedeutung. Der Fokus verschiebt sich klar von reiner Prävention hin zu Resilienz und Recovery.“ Der Sicherheitsexperte geht zudem davon aus, dass &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4105647/zero-trust-umsetzung-die-richtige-kommunikation-zahlt.html"&gt;Zero Trust&lt;/a&gt; stärker operationalisiert wird, insbesondere über Identitäten, privilegierte Zugriffe und Maschinen-Accounts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Gleichzeitig werden wir mehr KI auf beiden Seiten sehen: Angreifer nutzen sie zur Skalierung, Verteidiger zur besseren Priorisierung, Korrelation und Automatisierung“, schließt Braun ab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109550/die-wichtigsten-ciso-trends-fur-2026.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top cyber threats to your AI systems and infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110008/top-cyber-threats-to-your-ai-systems-and-infrastructure.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attacks against AI systems and infrastructure are beginning to take shape in real-world instances, and security experts expect the number of these attack types will rise in coming years. In a rush to realize the benefits of AI, most organizations have played it &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3529615/companies-skip-security-hardening-in-rush-to-adopt-ai.html"&gt;fast and loose on security hardening&lt;/a&gt; when rolling out AI tools and use cases. As a result, experts also warn that many organizations aren’t prepared to detect, deflect, or respond to such attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most are aware of the possibility of such attacks, but I don’t think a lot of people are fully aware of how to properly mitigate the risk,” says &lt;a href="https://www.usf.edu/ai-cybersecurity-computing/people/faculty/licato-john.aspx"&gt;John Licato&lt;/a&gt;, associate professor in the Bellini College of Artificial Intelligence, Cybersecurity and Computing at the University of South Florida, founder and director of the Advancing Machine and Human Reasoning Lab, and owner of startup company Actualization.AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="top-threats-to-ai-systems"&gt;Top threats to AI systems&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Multiple attack types against AI systems are arising. Some attacks, such as data poisoning, occur during training. Others, such as adversarial inputs, happen during inference. Still others, such as model theft, occur during deployment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here is a rundown of the top threat types to AI infrastructure experts warn about today. Some are more rare or theoretical than others, though many have been observed in the wild or have been demonstrated by researchers through notable proofs of concept.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-poisoning"&gt;Data poisoning&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570555/how-data-poisoning-attacks-corrupt-machine-learning-models.html"&gt;Data poisoning&lt;/a&gt; is a type of attack in which bad actorsmanipulate, tamper with, and pollute the data used to develop or train AI systems, including machine learning models. By corrupting the data or introducing faulty data, attackers can alter, bias, or otherwise render inaccurate a model’s performance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Imagine an attack that tells a model that green means stop instead of go, says &lt;a href="file:///C:/Users/Owner/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/V6WVSWFS/Rob%20T.%20Lee"&gt;Robert T. Lee&lt;/a&gt;, CAIO and chief of research at SANS, a security training and certification firm. “It’s meant to degrade the output of the model,” he explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="model-poisoning"&gt;Model poisoning&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here, the attack goes after the model itself, seeking to produce inaccurate results by tampering with the model’s architecture or parameters. Some definitions of model poisoning models also include attacks where the model’s training data has been corrupted through data poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="tool-poisoning"&gt;Tool poisoning&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Invariant Labs identified this type of attack in spring 2025. When &lt;a href="https://invariantlabs.ai/blog/mcp-security-notification-tool-poisoning-attacks"&gt;announcing its findings&lt;/a&gt;, Invariant wrote that it had “discovered a critical vulnerability in the Model Context Protocol (MCP) that allows for what we term &lt;em&gt;Tool Poisoning Attacks&lt;/em&gt;. This vulnerability can lead to sensitive data exfiltration and unauthorized actions by AI models.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company went on to note that its experiments showed “that a malicious server can not only exfiltrate sensitive data from the user but also hijack the agent’s behavior and override instructions provided by other, trusted servers, leading to a complete compromise of the agent’s functionality, even with respect to trusted infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These attacks involve embedding malicious instructions inside MCP tool descriptions that, when interpreted by AI models, can hijack the model. These attacks essentially corrupt the MCP layer “to trick an agent to do something,” says &lt;a href="https://www.constellationr.com/users/chirag-mehta"&gt;Chirag Mehta&lt;/a&gt;, vice principal and principal analyst at Constellation Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more on MCP threats, see “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4023795/top-10-mcp-vulnerabilities.html"&gt;Top 10 MCP vulnerabilities: The hidden risks of AI integrations&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="prompt-injection"&gt;Prompt injection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During a prompt injection attack, hackers use prompts that look legitimate but actually have embedded malicious commands meant to get the large language model to do something it shouldn’t. Hackers use these prompts to trick the model to bypass or override its guardrails, to share sensitive data, or to perform unauthorized actions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With prompt injection, you can change what the AI agent is supposed to do,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fabien-cros-3b66a332/"&gt;Fabien Cros&lt;/a&gt;, chief data and AI officer at global consulting firm Ducker Carlisle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several notable prompt injection attacks and proofs of concept have been reported of late, including &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086965/researchers-trick-chatgpt-into-prompt-injecting-itself.html"&gt;researchers tricking ChatGPT into prompt injecting itself&lt;/a&gt;, attackers &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053107/ai-prompt-injection-gets-real-with-macros-the-latest-hidden-threat.html"&gt;embedding malicious prompts into document macros&lt;/a&gt;, and researchers &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4036868/black-hat-researchers-demonstrate-zero-click-prompt-injection-attacks-in-popular-ai-agents.html"&gt;demoing zero-click prompt attacks on popular AI agents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="adversarial-inputs"&gt;Adversarial inputs&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Model owners and operators use perturbed data to test models for resiliency, but hackers use it to disrupt. In an adversarial input attack, malicious actors feed deceptive data to a model with the goal of making the model output incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The changes to the perturbed input are typically small, or the deceptive data may be noise; the changes are deliberately designed to be subtle enough to evade detection by security systems but still capable of throwing off the model. This makes adversarial inputs a type of evasion attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="model-theft-model-extraction"&gt;Model theft/model extraction&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Malicious actors can replicate, or reverse-engineer, a model, its parameters, and even its training data. They typically do this using publicly available APIs — for example, the model’s prediction API or a cloud services API — to repeatedly query the model and collect outputs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They then can analyze how the model responds and use that analysis to reconstruct it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s enabling unauthorized duplication of the tools itself,” says &lt;a href="Allison%20W.%20%7C%20LinkedIn"&gt;Allison Wikoff&lt;/a&gt;, director and Americas lead for global threat intelligence at PwC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="model-inversion"&gt;Model inversion&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Model inversion refers to a specific extraction attack in which the adversary attempts to reconstruct or infer the data that was used to train the model.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The name comes from the hackers “inverting” the model, using its outputs to reconstruct or reverse-engineer information about the inputs used to train the model.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="supply-chain-risks"&gt;Supply chain risks&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Like other software systems, AI systems are built with a combination of components that can include open-source code, open-source models, third-party models, and various sources of data. Any security vulnerability in the components can show up in the AI systems. This makes AI systems vulnerable to supply chain attacks, where hackers can exploit vulnerabilities within the components to launch an attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For recent examples, see “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4015077/ai-supply-chain-threats-are-looming-as-security-practices-lag.html"&gt;AI supply chain threats loom — as security practices lag&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="jailbreaking"&gt;Jailbreaking&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also called model jailbreaking, attackers’ goal here is to get AI systems — primarily through engaging with LLMs — to disregard the guardrails that confine their actions and behavior, such as safeguards to prevent harmful, offensive, or unethical outputs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hackers can use various techniques to execute this type of attack. For example, they could employ a role-playing exploit (aka role-play attack), using commands to instruct the AI to adopt a persona (such as a developer) that can work around the guardrails. They could disguise malicious instructions in seemingly legitimate prompts or use encoding, foreign words, or keyboard characters to bypass filters. They could also use a prompt framed as a hypothetical or research question or a series of prompts that leads to their end objective.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those objectives, which also are varied, include getting AI systems to write malicious code, spread problematic content, and reveal sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When there is a chat interface, there are ways to interact with it to get it to operate outside the parameters,” Licato says. “That’s the tradeoff of having an increasingly powerful reasoning system.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="counteracting-threats-to-ai-systems"&gt;Counteracting threats to AI systems&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While their executive colleagues jump into AI initiatives in search of enhanced productivity and innovation, CISOs must take an active role in ensuring security for those initiatives — and the organization’s AI infrastructure at large — is a top priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://www.hackerone.com/report/ciso"&gt;recent survey&lt;/a&gt; from security tech company HackerOne, 84% of CISOs are now responsible for AI security and 82% now oversee data privacy. If CISOs don’t &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4011384/the-cisos-5-step-guide-to-securing-ai-operations.html"&gt;advance their security strategies to counteract attacks against AI systems&lt;/a&gt; and the data the feeds them, future issues will reflect on their leadership — regardless of whether they were invited to the table when AI initiatives were conceived and launched.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, CISOs have a “need for a proactive AI security strategy,” according to Constellation’s Mehta.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI security is not just a technical challenge but also a strategic imperative requiring executive buy in and cross-functional collaboration,” he writes in his 2025 report &lt;a href="https://www.constellationr.com/research/ai-security-beyond-traditional-cyberdefenses"&gt;AI Security Beyond Traditional Cyberdefenses: Rethinking Cybersecurity for the Age of AI and Autonomy&lt;/a&gt;. “Data governance is foundational, because securing AI begins with ensuring the integrity and provenance of training data and model inputs. Security teams must develop new expertise to handle AI-driven risks, and business leaders must recognize the implications of autonomous AI systems and the governance frameworks needed to manage them responsibly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Strategies for assessing, managing, and counteracting the threat of attacks on AI systems are emerging. In addition to maintaining strong data governance and other fundamental cyber defense best practices, AI and security experts say CISOs and their organizations should be evaluating AI models before deploying them, monitoring AI systems in use, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4101929/offensive-security-takes-center-stage-in-the-ai-era.html"&gt;using red teams to test models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs may need to implement specific actions to counter certain attacks, says PwC’s Wikoff. For example, CISOs looking to head off model theft can monitor for suspicious queries and patterns as well as have timeouts and capture rate-limited responses. Or, to help prevent evasion attacks, security leaders could employ adversarial training — essentially training models to guard against those types of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Adopting &lt;a href="https://atlas.mitre.org/"&gt;MITRE ATLAS&lt;/a&gt; is another step. This framework, short for Adversarial Threat Landscape for Artificial-Intelligence Systems, provides a knowledge base mapping how attackers target AI systems and details identifying tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security and AI experts acknowledge the challenges of taking such steps. Many CISOs are contending with more immediate threats, including &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4044007/shadow-ai-is-surging-getting-ai-adoption-right-is-your-best-defense.html"&gt;shadow AI&lt;/a&gt; and attacks that are getting faster, more sophisticated, and harder to detect, thanks in part to attackers’ use of AI. And given that attacks on AI systems are still nascent, with some attack types still considered theoretical, CISOs face challenges in getting resources to develop strategies and skills to counteract attacks on AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For the CISO this is something that’s really difficult, because attacks on AI backends is still being researched. We’re at the early stages of figuring out what hackers are doing and why,” Lee, of SANS, says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lee and others recognize the competitive pressure on organizations to make the most of AI, yet they stress that CISOs and their executive colleagues can’t let securing AI systems be an afterthought.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Thinking about what these attacks could be as they build the infrastructure is key for the CISO,” says &lt;a href="(35)%20Matt%20G.%20%7C%20LinkedIn"&gt;Matt Gorham&lt;/a&gt;, leader of PwC’s Cyber and Risk Innovation Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110008/top-cyber-threats-to-your-ai-systems-and-infrastructure.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIS2-Umsetzung: Neues BSI-Portal geht an den Start</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114344/nis2-umsetzung-neues-bsi-portal-geht-an-den-start.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 7500w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2691920437.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Unternehmen können sich ab sofort über das neue BSI-Portal als NIS2-Einrichtung registrieren und IT-Sicherheitsvorfälle melden.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;ImageFlow – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Seit Anfang Dezember gilt die EU-Sicherheitsrichtline &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4090107/bundestag-beschliest-nis2-umsetzung.html" target="_blank"&gt;NIS2&lt;/a&gt; auch in Deutschland. Rund 29.500 Unternehmen sind dadurch verpflichtet, sich als NIS-2-Einrichtungen zu registrieren und dem Bundesamt für Sicherheit in der Informationstechnik (BSI) erhebliche Sicherheitsvorfälle zu melden. Vor diesem Hintergrund hat das BSI ein neues Portal entwickelt, das gebündelte Informationen und Hilfestellungen bietet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="bsi-portal-soll-austausch-erleichtern"&gt;BSI-Portal soll Austausch erleichtern&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das &lt;a href="https://portal.bsi.bund.de/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BSI-Portal &lt;/a&gt;basiert auf einer Cloud-Infrastruktur von Amazon Web Services (AWS) und soll sukzessiv zu einer Informations- und Austauschplattform mit Echtzeit-Daten und aktuellen Analysen für schnelle Reaktionsmöglichkeiten ausgebaut werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„NIS2 sorgt dafür, dass wichtige und besonders wichtige Einrichtungen sowie die gesamte Bundesverwaltung ihre Cyberresilienz effektiv und effizient stärken. Um diesen und weitere Prozesse komfortabel und unbürokratisch zu gestalten, haben wir das BSI-Portal als One-Stop-Shop konzipiert“, erklärt BSI-Präsidentin Claudia Plattner. „Es soll den sicheren und zielgerichteten Austausch relevanter Cybersicherheitsinformationen zwischen Unternehmen, Behörden und Institutionen erleichtern.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Portal unterstützt Unternehmen unter anderem dabei, eine Risikoanalyse durchzuführen und Maßnahmen zum Risikomanagement umzusetzen. Zudem erhalten bereits registrierte Unternehmen und Institutionen ab sofort Informationen zu ihren gesetzlichen Pflichten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zudem können sich Organisationen über die Plattform der &lt;a href="https://www.bsi.bund.de/Webs/ACS/DE/Home/home_node.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Allianz für Cyber-Sicherheit&lt;/a&gt; (ACS) anschließen. Das IT-Sicherheits-Netzwerk unter dem Dach des BSI bietet seinen derzeit knapp 9.000 Mitgliedern vielfältige Formate zum Wissens- und Erfahrungsaustausch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus stellt das BSI seine Tageslageberichte und IT-Sicherheitsmitteilungen über die Plattform bereit. Auch Schwachstellen und Sicherheitslücken können über das BSI-Portal gemeldet werden – dies ist auch anonym und ohne Registrierung möglich, verspricht die Behörde.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="kritik-aus-der-security-szene"&gt;Kritik aus der Security-Szene&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Tatsache, dass das BSI-Portal auf AWS gehostet wird, sorgt allerdings bei einigen Security-Experten für Unmut. Auf LinkedIn bezeichnet &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7414960252967657472/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Benjamin Richter&lt;/a&gt;, CEO bei Cyber Complete, das Ganze vor dem Hintergrund der digitalen Souveränität als strategisches ein Eigentor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der IT-Sicherheitsexperte &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7414629985698611200/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jürgen Mayershofer&lt;/a&gt; stimmt dem zu: „Das ist ein ganz falsches Signal des BSI an den deutschen Markt, während quer durch Europa über digitale Souveränität und Resilienz diskutiert wird.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7414244650385039362/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Karsten Bartels&lt;/a&gt;, Rechtsanwalt für IT-Sicherheitsrecht, kann die Entscheidung des BSI für AWS nur schwer nachvollziehen. „Gerade diese Plattform dieser Behörde“, moniert der Experte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Ganz einfach, BSI steht für ‚Bundesamt für SICHERHEIT in der Informationstechnik‘, nicht “Bundesamt für Souveränität in der Informationstechnik‘“, spöttelt der auf Cloud und Datensouveränität spezialisierte Gartner-Analyst &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/renebuest_plattner-zum-bsi-portal-werden-nicht-die-activity-7414654080192798720-pWLC/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;amp;rcm=ACoAAAF1j5YBGyg76yL9ZDczpUIfAcxmrR76duk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;René Büst&lt;/a&gt;. „Und Sicherheit und Souveränität haben miteinander nichts zu tun. Man kann eine sehr sichere Cloud nutzen aber gleichzeitig zu 0% souverän sein. Das hat das BSI leider nicht verstanden.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103179/nis2-umsetzen-ohne-im-papierkrieg-zu-enden.html" target="_blank"&gt;NIS2 umsetzen – ohne im Papierkrieg zu enden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114344/nis2-umsetzung-neues-bsi-portal-geht-an-den-start.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phishing-Angreifer setzen vermehrt auf E-Mail-Routing-Lücken</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114453/phishing-angreifer-setzen-vermehrt-auf-e-mail-routing-lucken.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Phishing" class="wp-image-4114456" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2456545813.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Angreifer missbrauchen falsch konfigurierte Richtlinien, um Phishing-E-Mails wie interne E-Mails aussehen zu lassen, Filter zu umgehen und Anmeldedaten zu stehlen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;batjaket – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Threat Intelligence Team von Microsoft hat kürzlich festgestellt, dass Angreifer zunehmend komplexe E-Mail-Weiterleitungen und falsch konfigurierte Domain-Spoofing-Schutzmaßnahmen ausnutzen. Dabei lassen sie ihre Phishing-Nachrichten so aussehen, als würden sie von den angegriffenen Organisationen selbst stammen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In den Angriffskampagnen werden Konfigurationslücken missbraucht. Das gilt insbesondere für solche bei MX-DNS-Einträgen (Mail Exchanger), die nicht direkt auf Microsoft 365 verweisen und in denen die Richtlinien für Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting &amp;amp; Conformance (DMARC) und Sender Policy Framework (SPF) zu lax oder falsch konfiguriert sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Angreifer haben diesen Vektor genutzt, um eine Vielzahl von Phishing-Nachrichten im Zusammenhang mit verschiedenen Phishing-as-a-Service-Plattformen (PhaaS) wie Tycoon 2FA zu versenden“, erklärt &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2026/01/06/phishing-actors-exploit-complex-routing-and-misconfigurations-to-spoof-domains/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft in einem Blogbeitrag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Technikriese weist darauf hin, dass dieser Angriffsvektor zwar nicht neu ist, seine Nutzung jedoch seit Mitte 2025 deutlich zugenommen hat. Dabei reichen die Phishing-Köder von Passwort-Zurücksetzungen bis hin zu freigegebenen Dokumenten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="internes-routing-und-schwache-richtlinien"&gt;„Internes“ Routing und schwache Richtlinien&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Fehler liegt darin, wie empfangende Mailserver eingehende Nachrichten interpretieren. Wenn MX-Einträge zu komplexen Mail-pPfaden führen, zum Beispiel zu lokalen Systemen oder Microsoft 365 vorgeschalteten Relay-Servern von Drittanbietern , werden standardmäßige Spoofing-Schutzprüfungen wie SPF Hard-Fail und strenge DMARC-Durchsetzung möglicherweise nicht korrekt angewendet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In diesen Fällen kann eine Phishing-E-Mail mit der eigenen Adresse des Empfängers sowohl im „An”- als auch im „Von”-Feld ankommen, eine gefälschte Nachricht, die auf den ersten Blick wie eine interne E-Mail erscheint. In einigen Fällen ändern Angreifer zusätzlich den Absendernamen, um die Nachricht überzeugender erscheinen zu lassen, während das „Von”-Feld auf eine gültige interne E-Mail-Adresse gesetzt wird.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Kombination mit laxen oder fehlenden DMARC- und SPF-Richtlinien können diese Nachrichten Spam-Filter umgehen und direkt im Posteingang der Benutzer landen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Phishing-Nachrichten, die über diesen Vektor versendet werden, können effektiver sein, da sie wie intern versendete Nachrichten erscheinen“, betont Microsoft in seinem Beitrag. „Eine erfolgreiche Kompromittierung von Anmeldedaten durch Phishing-Angriffe kann zu Datendiebstahl oder Business Email Compromise &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494543/mehrstufige-angriffe-business-email-compromise-erreicht-neue-dimension.html" target="_blank"&gt;(BEC)-Angriffen &lt;/a&gt;auf das betroffene Unternehmen oder dessen Partner führen und umfangreiche Abhilfemaßnahmen erforderlich machen und/oder im Falle von Finanzbetrug zu finanziellen Verlusten führen.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Über die Erfassung von Anmeldedaten hinaus kann die PhaaS-Infrastruktur AiTM-Angriffe (Adversary-in-the-Middle) ermöglichen, bei denen Authentifizierungsinformationen in Echtzeit weitergeleitet werden und sogar Multi-Faktor-Authentifizierungsmaßnahmen umgangen werden können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="konfigurationen-zur-absicherung-konnen-helfen"&gt;Konfigurationen zur Absicherung können helfen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft betont, dass eine korrekte Konfiguration von E-Mail-Authentifizierungsmechanismen die wirksamste Verteidigung gegen diesen Spoofing-Vektor sei. Unternehmen wird empfohlen, strenge DMARC-Reject-Richtlinien einzuführen und SPF-Hard-Fails durchzusetzen, damit nicht authentifizierte E-Mails, die angeblich von ihren Domänen stammen, abgelehnt oder sicher unter Quarantäne gestellt werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus wird empfohlen, alle Konnektoren von Drittanbietern, wie Spamfilter, Archivierungsdienste oder ältere Mail-Relays, korrekt einzurichten. Damit können Spoof-Prüfungen konsistent berechnet und durchgesetzt werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mandanten mit MX-Einträgen, die direkt auf Microsoft 365 verweisen, sind von diesem Problem nicht betroffen. Die nativen Spoof-Erkennungs- und Filtermechanismen von Microsoft verhindern solche Angriffe und werden standardmäßig angewendet. Für komplexere E-Mail-Infrastrukturen hat Microsoft spezifische Richtlinien zu &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-in/exchange/security-and-compliance/mail-flow-rules/mail-flow-rules" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;E-Mail-Regeln und Authentifizierungsverfahren&lt;/a&gt; bereitgestellt, um das Risiko zu verringern und gefälschte E-Mails zu blockieren, bevor sie überhaupt den Posteingang der Endbenutzer erreichen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Über die Korrekturen zur E-Mail-Authentifizierung hinaus fordert Microsoft Unternehmen dazu auf, ihre Identitäts-Schutzmaßnahmen gegen AiTM-Phishing zu verstärken, einer Methode, bei der Passwörter durch die Übernahme authentifizierter Sitzungen umgangen werden. Zu den empfohlenen Kontrollmaßnahmen gehören Phishing-resistente MFA wie FIDO2-Sicherheitsschlüssel, die Durchsetzung bedingter Zugriffsrechte und Schutzmaßnahmen wie MFA-Nummernabgleich, um die Auswirkungen gestohlener Token zu begrenzen. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114453/phishing-angreifer-setzen-vermehrt-auf-e-mail-routing-lucken.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-001)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-001</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-001</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2 faces of AI: How emerging models empower and endanger cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113987/the-2-faces-of-ai-how-emerging-models-empower-and-endanger-cybersecurity.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my long career of safeguarding digital assets, I’ve seen technology shifts come and go, but nothing compares to the disruptive force of AI and large language models (LLMs). AI is quite literally a double-edged sword when it comes to cybersecurity. The same capabilities that allow us to automate threat detection and write secure code faster are being weaponized by adversaries to create a new generation of cyberthreats. For any CISO or security leader, our primary focus must shift; we are no longer just fighting human adversaries, we are fighting AI-augmented, automated threat agents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-offensive-edge"&gt;The offensive edge&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are witnessing a drastic reduction in the cost and expertise required for cybercrime. What used to take a skilled human weeks can now be orchestrated by an AI agent in hours, driving what we call cyberthreat inflation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="self-modifying-evasive-malware"&gt;Self-modifying, evasive malware&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More recently, the researchers at Google Threat Intelligence Group (GTIG) identified a disturbing new trend: malware that uses LLMs during execution to dynamically alter its own behavior and evade detection. This is not pre-generated code, this is code that adapts mid-execution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In June 2025, &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/threat-actor-usage-of-ai-tools"&gt;GTIG identified an experimental malware called PROMPTFLUX&lt;/a&gt;, which connects to a commercial LLM API (such as the Gemini API) to request new code-obfuscation and evasion scripts on the fly. This technique, which allows for just-in-time code generation, represents a significant step toward autonomous and adaptive malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In another case, GTIG identified PROMPTSTEAL, which was being used by the Russia-linked APT28 group against Ukraine. This malware queries an LLM (the Qwen2.5-Coder model on Hugging Face) to generate reconnaissance commands instead of having them hard-coded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some analysis projects that the percentage of all malware detections with an LLM contribution has &lt;a href="https://www.techrxiv.org/users/955300/articles/1324994/master/file/data/Updated_Dual-Use_Risks_LLM_Final_88_TechRxiv/Updated_Dual-Use_Risks_LLM_Final_88_TechRxiv.pdf?inline=true"&gt;soared from just 2% in 2021 to a projected 50% by 2025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The first autonomous espionage campaign&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anthropic recently &lt;a href="https://assets.anthropic.com/m/ec212e6566a0d47/original/Disrupting-the-first-reported-AI-orchestrated-cyber-espionage-campaign.pdf"&gt;disclosed a highly sophisticated cyber espionage operation, attributed to a state-sponsored threat actor, that leveraged its own Claude Codemodel to target roughly 30 organizations globally&lt;/a&gt;, including major financial institutions and government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The threat actor manipulated the model into functioning as an autonomous cyber attack agent, which executed 80% to 90% of tactical operations, from reconnaissance and vulnerability discovery to credential harvesting and data exfiltration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The human operator only stepped in at critical choke points, such as authorizing the progression from reconnaissance to active exploitation. The AI autonomously mapped networks, discovered vulnerabilities and performed post-exploitation activities at machine speed, an unprecedented rate that traditional, human-speed defenses cannot match.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="deepfake-driven-financial-fraud"&gt;Deepfake-driven financial fraud&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, generative AI has amplified social engineering through hyper-realistic deepfakes. Deepfake-based scams have skyrocketed, enabling voice and video forgeries that deceive even seasoned professionals. A dramatic example occurred when a Ferrari executive was nearly fooled by a voice-cloned deepfake of the CEO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even more recently, an employee at a global design firm was fooled by an AI-generated video call impersonating the company’s CFO and other executives, resulting in a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3982379/deepfake-attacks-are-inevitable-cisos-cant-prepare-soon-enough.html"&gt;$25 million loss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3982379/deepfake-attacks-are-inevitable-cisos-cant-prepare-soon-enough.html"&gt; transferred&lt;/a&gt; to the fraudsters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-defensive-edge"&gt;The defensive edge&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If adversaries are operating at AI speed, our defenses must too. The silver lining of this dual-use dynamic is that the most powerful LLMs are also being harnessed by defenders to create fundamentally new security capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="vulnerability-detection-from-zero-days-to-autonomous-pentesting"&gt;Vulnerability detection: From zero-days to autonomous pentesting&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLMs’ semantic code understanding and contextual reasoning offer a significant advantage over traditional, signature-based static analyzers, especially in the discovery of unknown threats before malicious actors find and exploit them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLMs have shown extraordinary potential in identifying unknown, unpatched flaws (zero-days). These models significantly outperform conventional static analyzers, particularly in uncovering subtle logic flaws and buffer overflows in novel software. For instance, Google’s &lt;a href="https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2024/10/from-naptime-to-big-sleep.html"&gt;Big Sleep project&lt;/a&gt; used an LLM to identify a zero-day vulnerability in the critical SQLite database used across the industry.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another example is &lt;a href="https://xbow.com/"&gt;XBOW&lt;/a&gt;, which is an autonomous AI penetration testing agent that leverages LLMs to simulate real-world attacks the same way a human counterpart would do. XBOW achieved the #1 spot on the HackerOne US Leaderboard, demonstrating that AI can match and, in some benchmarks, surpass expert human hackers in finding a broad range of vulnerabilities (e.g., injection flaws, XSS).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By deploying AI agents like XBOW against our own systems, we can systematically test every endpoint and attack vector. This scales ethical offensive security testing from a periodic audit into an on-demand, pre-production workflow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Google’s DeepMind has pioneered an AI-powered agent called CodeMender that automatically detects, patches and rewrites vulnerable code to eliminate whole classes of security flaws. This reactive and proactive approach represents a major step forward in defensive automation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="threat-hunting-and-behavioral-analysis"&gt;Threat hunting and behavioral analysis&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLMs are transforming threat hunting from a manual, keyword-based search to an intelligent, contextual query process that focuses on behavioral anomalies. By processing and correlating massive, unstructured datasets such as network logs, security incident reports and threat intelligence feeds (OSINT), LLMs gain the contextual understanding necessary to generate high-confidence hypotheses about potential threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/security/ai"&gt;Google Threat Intelligence with Gemini&lt;/a&gt; enhances this process by providing essential contextual grounding with data from multiple sources like VirusTotal and Mandiant to determine, in real-time, which global threat actor tactics, techniques and procedures (TTPs) that are most relevant to a particular industry or organization and prioritize what’s most important from tens of thousands of reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Palantir’s AIP (Artificial Intelligence Platform) utilizes LLMs to analyze anomalous user or system behavior across vast data lakes, identifies subtle indicators of compromise that span different systems and suggests a prioritized attack path for the human analyst to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Governance, compliance and regulation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LLMs also offer a profound scalable solution to managing non-technical risk compliance, privacy and regulatory complexity, which represent significant financial and legal liability. LLMs can be leveraged to shift governance from periodic audits to continuous policy enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href="https://www.itmagination.com/blog/eu-ai-act-compliance-in-practice-a-microsoft-centric-approach"&gt;Microsoft’s Compliance Manager&lt;/a&gt; can ingest and understand vast amounts of unstructured data, such as internal security policies, legal contracts and external regulatory texts like GDPR or the EU AI Act. It then automatically maps the requirements of one framework to another, dramatically reducing the manual effort needed to prove compliance during an audit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IBM’s Watsonx applies LLM capabilities for compliance and risk management. For a financial services firm, this might mean the model continuously scans new trading application code to verify that all data handling aligns with HIPAA or PCI DSS before deployment, automatically flagging any deviation from established policy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="bringing-it-all-together"&gt;Bringing it all together&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As AI systems continue to advance from generative models to autonomous agents, their dual-use nature can’t be ignored. The same tools that help defenders accelerate incident response can also empower attackers to craft deepfakes, launch social engineering campaigns and more. This tension isn’t a temporary byproduct of innovation, but it is a structural reality of AI’s rapid evolution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the challenge isn’t to halt AI progress but to guide it responsibly. That means building guardrails into models, improving transparency and developing governance frameworks that keep pace with emerging capabilities. It also requires organizations to rethink security strategies, recognizing that AI is both an opportunity and a risk multiplier.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the end, AI’s impact on cybersecurity will be shaped not just by what these systems can do, but by how we choose to use them. The future will belong to those who can harness AI’s defensive power while staying vigilant against its offensive potential.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113987/the-2-faces-of-ai-how-emerging-models-empower-and-endanger-cybersecurity.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity at the edge: Securing rugged IoT in mission-critical environments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113968/cybersecurity-at-the-edge-securing-rugged-iot-in-mission-critical-environments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Edge computing is no longer a futuristic concept; it’s a reality shaping mission-critical operations across defense, utilities and public safety. Rugged IoT devices, engineered to withstand extreme conditions, are the backbone of this transformation. They enable real-time decision-making in environments where traditional IT infrastructure cannot survive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But this progress comes with risk. These devices often operate outside secure perimeters, in disconnected environments and under physical stress. Unlike enterprise systems, rugged IoT deployments break the assumptions of conventional cybersecurity models: stable connectivity, frequent patching and controlled environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CIOs and IT leaders, rugged IoT security isn’t just a technical challenge, it’s a business-critical priority. The cost of failure is measured in millions of dollars, regulatory penalties and reputational damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-business-stakes"&gt;The business stakes&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity failures at the edge have cascading consequences. The following examples give a sense of the impact.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defense:&lt;/strong&gt; Compromised devices can leak mission-critical data or disrupt tactical communications.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utilities:&lt;/strong&gt; Operational paralysis halts power distribution or water treatment, impacting millions.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public safety:&lt;/strong&gt; Emergency response systems fail during crises, endangering lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Gartner, in 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.zscaler.com/press/zscaler-threatlabz-finds-400-increase-iot-and-ot-malware-attacks-year-over-year-underscoring"&gt;IoT-related incidents in critical infrastructure surged 400% over the previous three years&lt;/a&gt; and the average cost of an OT breach exceeded $3 million. This excluded reputational damage and compliance fines. For CIOs, this isn’t just about security, it’s about business continuity, compliance and risk management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-rugged-iot-is-different"&gt;Why rugged IoT is different&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Securing rugged IoT devices requires a fundamentally different approach than traditional IT systems. Conventional cybersecurity models are built on assumptions that rarely hold true in edge environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional IT assumptions:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stable connectivity:&lt;/strong&gt; Continuous network access for monitoring and patching.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controlled environments:&lt;/strong&gt; Secure, climate-controlled data centers.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequent patching:&lt;/strong&gt; Regular updates to address vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralized monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; Unified visibility across systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rugged IoT reality:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harsh conditions:&lt;/strong&gt; Devices operate at extreme temperatures, dust, moisture and vibration. These conditions accelerate hardware wear and complicate maintenance schedules.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermittent connectivity:&lt;/strong&gt; Edge devices often rely on unreliable or low-bandwidth links. Real-time patching and centralized monitoring become impractical, leaving systems exposed for longer periods.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational constraints:&lt;/strong&gt; Many rugged devices run unattended for years in remote or hazardous locations. Physical access for updates or repairs is limited, increasing reliance on secure remote workflows.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legacy integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Rugged IoT frequently coexists with outdated operational technology (OT) systems that lack modern security controls. This creates vulnerabilities at integration points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These factors dismantle the foundation of traditional security strategies. CIOs cannot assume continuous oversight or rapid response capabilities. Instead, rugged IoT demands adaptive, decentralized security architectures that:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operate effectively in disconnected environments.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Combine physical security with cyber protection.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Support offline patching and secure update chains.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Incorporate &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/sp/800-207/final"&gt;zero-trust principles&lt;/a&gt; even in bandwidth-constrained scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="standards-helpful-but-insufficient"&gt;Standards: Helpful but insufficient&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Industry frameworks such as &lt;a href="https://www.isa.org/standards-and-publications/isa-standards/isa-iec-62443-series-of-standards"&gt;ISA/IEC 62443&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/82/r2/final"&gt;NIST SP 800-82&lt;/a&gt; remain essential for guiding industrial cybersecurity, but their applicability to rugged IoT environments is limited. While these standards provide a strong foundation, they were designed for predictable, connected infrastructures, not for devices operating in remote, harsh and intermittently connected conditions. Standards fall short for rugged IoT in numerous aspects:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connectivity dependency:&lt;/strong&gt; Both frameworks assume continuous network availability for monitoring, patching and compliance validation. Rugged deployments often operate offline for extended periods, making real-time adherence impossible.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physical security blind spot:&lt;/strong&gt; ISA/IEC and NIST primarily address logical and network security layers, leaving physical protection underemphasized. Rugged devices deployed in the field face risks of theft, tampering and environmental damage that these standards do not fully address.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complexity and cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Full implementation of these frameworks can be resource-intensive, requiring specialized expertise and significant investment. For organizations with constrained budgets or distributed assets, achieving full compliance may be impractical.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static approach vs. dynamic reality:&lt;/strong&gt; Standards are prescriptive and slow to evolve, while rugged IoT environments demand adaptive strategies that respond to changing operational conditions and emerging threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compliance is a starting point, not the finish line. CIOs should adapt these frameworks for edge conditions, integrate physical hardening and prioritize risk-based implementation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="best-practices-for-cios"&gt;Best practices for CIOs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Securing rugged IoT devices requires a multi-layered, defense-in-depth approach that aligns with enterprise priorities and addresses the unique challenges of edge environments. Each layer plays a critical role in reducing risk and ensuring operational continuity:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-device-hardening"&gt;1. Device hardening&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The foundation of rugged IoT security begins at the device level. Implement secure boot to ensure devices only run trusted firmware by validating cryptographic signatures during startup. Encrypt storage to protect sensitive operational data and credentials from unauthorized access, even if the device is physically compromised. Reduce the attack surface by disabling unused interfaces such as USB or serial ports and turning off unnecessary services. Additionally, schedule periodic firmware integrity checks to detect tampering or unauthorized modifications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-access-control"&gt;2. Access control&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Strong identity and access management are essential for field-deployed devices. Multifactor authentication (MFA) should be required for administrative access, even in low-bandwidth environments, using token-based or offline-capable solutions. Role-based access control (RBAC) aligned with ISA/IEC 62443 principles ensures least-privilege access for technicians, operators and remote administrators.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To further strengthen security, automate credential rotation to prevent password or key reuse across devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-network-security"&gt;3. Network security&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Connectivity at the edge is often intermittent and insecure, demanding robust network protections. Adopt a zero-trust architecture to authenticate every device and transaction, regardless of network location. Use lightweight VPN protocols optimized for unreliable links to maintain confidentiality without degrading performance. For critical operations, consider secure connectivity options such as FirstNet or private 5G to reduce exposure to public networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Additionally, segment IoT traffic from enterprise networks to contain potential breaches and limit lateral movement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-physical-security"&gt;4. Physical security&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity must be complemented by physical safeguards to protect devices in harsh environments. Deploy tamper-evident seals to detect unauthorized access attempts quickly and use ruggedized enclosures to shield devices from environmental stressors and physical attacks. Secure mounting reduces theft risk by anchoring devices in fixed installations, while sensor-based alerts, such as accelerometers or intrusion sensors, can trigger notifications when devices are moved or opened.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-life-cycle-management"&gt;5. Life cycle management&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security is not a one-time effort; it spans the entire device life cycle. Regular patching and OS hardening are essential to maintain compliance with frameworks like &lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/services/cjis"&gt;CJIS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/topics/cyber-threats-and-advisories/federal-information-security-modernization-act"&gt;FISMA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/index.html"&gt;HIPAA&lt;/a&gt;. Develop offline update workflows for disconnected environments, ensuring cryptographic validation of update packages. Strengthen supply chain security by validating firmware and hardware integrity during procurement and deployment to prevent compromised components. Finally, implement secure end-of-life sanitization processes to wipe data and decommission devices safely, preventing residual data leaks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-remote-management"&gt;6. Remote management&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Remote capabilities are critical for mitigating risks in inaccessible locations. Enable remote lock and wipe functions to respond immediately to lost or stolen devices, even over intermittent connections. Use centralized management dashboards to maintain visibility into device health, patch status and overall security posture across distributed deployments. Configure automated alerts for anomalies such as unauthorized access attempts or connectivity failures to ensure timely intervention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprise-impact-roi-and-risk"&gt;Enterprise impact: ROI and risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, investing in rugged IoT security isn’t just a cost; it’s a risk mitigation strategy. CIOs need to consider:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downtime costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilities report losses of $500,000 per hour during outages, according to the Industrial Control Systems Cyber Emergency Response Team.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory exposure:&lt;/strong&gt; Non-compliance with CJIS or HIPAA can result in fines exceeding $1 million.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reputation:&lt;/strong&gt; Public safety failures erode trust and brand equity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CIOs, the message is clear: Rugged IoT security is not just an IT issue, it’s a business imperative. The cost of inaction is measured not only in dollars but in operational continuity and human safety.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="future-outlook"&gt;Future outlook&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Emerging technologies and developments will further reshape rugged IoT security:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI-driven anomaly detection for real-time threat identification.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Predictive maintenance aligning security patches with hardware health.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Regulatory evolution (&lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/"&gt;CISA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/cybersecurity-act"&gt;EU Cybersecurity Act&lt;/a&gt;) enforcing stricter compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forward-thinking CIOs should start integrating these capabilities into their edge strategies today. Rugged IoT deployments are mission-critical and increasingly targeted by cyberthreats. Securing these environments requires a shift from traditional IT models to adaptive strategies tailored for the edge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4113968/cybersecurity-at-the-edge-securing-rugged-iot-in-mission-critical-environments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-002)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-002</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-002</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV26-003)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-003</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-003</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV26-004)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-004</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-004</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-005)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-005</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-005</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-006)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-007)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV26-008)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-009)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-010)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-011)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trend Micro security advisory (AV26-012)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
