<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:19:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-760)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-761)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-762)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-763)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–764)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-765)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe tightens the net on sanctions evasion</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</link>
      <description>Europol is reinforcing its support to EU Member States in enforcing EU sanctions, as criminal networks develop ever more sophisticated methods to bypass restrictive measures linked to Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-767)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-768)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-769)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Teams’ guest chat feature exposes cross-tenant blind spot</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097381/microsoft-teams-guest-chat-feature-exposes-cross-tenant-blind-spot.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A newly highlighted flaw in Microsoft’s cross-tenant collaboration model shows that once a user accepts a guest invitation in Teams, their Defender for Office 365 protections are dropped entirely, leaving them exposed inside an external tenant even while logged in with their home account.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Ontinue threat researcher Rhys Downing, one of Microsoft’s recently enabled features, “MC1182004,” that allows Teams users to initiate chats with any email address, opens an attack vector for threat actors who know cross-tenant security limitations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many organizations assume their controls ‘follow’ the user wherever they go,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/julianbrownlowdavies/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Julian Brownlow Davies&lt;/a&gt;, senior vice president, offensive security strategy &amp;amp; operations at Bugcrowd. “In reality, attackers can spin up a poorly secured tenant, invite your users in with what looks like a perfectly legitimate Microsoft Teams email, and deliver links and files that never touch your own Defender stack at all.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This means the full suite of Defender protections, including URL scanning, safe links, file sandboxing, and zero-hour auto purge, can simply be disabled, turning a harmless-looking collaboration invite into an attack path.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft did not immediately respond to CSO’s request for comments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;New default triggers architectural flaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Downing explained in a &lt;a href="https://www.ontinue.com/resource/blog-microsoft-chat-with-anyone-understanding-phishing-risk/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that the issue isn’t a software bug in Teams, but an architectural reality of cross-tenant collaboration. When a user joins another tenant as a guest, the hosting (resource) tenant’s security settings apply–not the user’s original (home) tenant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, all protections provided by Defender for Office 365 are bypassed if the resource tenant has them disabled or never had them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making an attack easier is the default-enabled feature in Teams, &lt;a href="https://mc.merill.net/message/MC1182004" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MC1182004&lt;/a&gt;, that allows users to start a chat with any email address, even if the recipient isn’t yet part of Teams. That means attackers can simply spin up a Microsoft 365 tenant, invite victims via email, and deliver phishing links or malware-all without triggering the victim’s own security stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Davies echoed Downing’s argument that this is an architectural consequence of how &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/648486/beware-of-overly-permissive-azure-ad-cross-tenant-synchronization-policies.html"&gt;cross-tenant collaboration&lt;/a&gt; works. “At Bugcrowd, we see the same pattern across crowdsourced testing programs, particularly in our Red Team engagements: much of the risk now lives in the connectivity between tenants, identity systems, and collaboration tools, rather than in the individual apps themselves,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mitigations include vetting collaborations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, warns that this is not a mere “bypass bug,” but a blind spot in many organizations’ mental model of cross-tenant risk. “Security teams should respond by treating external guest access as a trust boundary that needs explicit governance rather than a convenience feature that can stay on by default,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Restricting B2B guest invitation to a vetted allow-list of trusted partner domains, and implementing cross-tenant access policies in Microsoft Entra ID to block suspicious guest-tenant access was recommended by Downing to stay ahead of this inherent threat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another key mitigation includes disabling the default “chat with Anyone” feature in Teams, which allows unsolicited external invitations to reach users. This is a practical step for many organizations that can simply do so through the Teams admin center by tightening external policies. Together with the Entra ID &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4060101/entra-id-vulnerability-exposes-gaps-in-cloud-identity-trust-models-experts-warn.html"&gt;warning&lt;/a&gt; from September, the disclosure underscores that a real danger sits in the gaps across Microsoft tenants, where convenience defaults and misplaced trust continue to outpace security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097381/microsoft-teams-guest-chat-feature-exposes-cross-tenant-blind-spot.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strike against synthetics: authorities seize tonnes of chemicals in Central and Eastern Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/strike-against-synthetics-authorities-seize-tonnes-of-chemicals-in-central-and-eastern-europe</link>
      <description>Emerging trends and strategies to combat synthetic drug trafficking were key topics at Europol’s annual Drugs Conference last week. In this context, the agency has supported two major operations in recent weeks targeting the entire supply chain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/strike-against-synthetics-authorities-seize-tonnes-of-chemicals-in-central-and-eastern-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow is in talks to buy identity security firm Veza for over $1 billion: report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097423/servicenow-is-in-talks-to-buy-identity-security-firm-veza-for-over-1-billion-report-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow is reportedly in advanced talks to acquire Veza, an identity security startup, for more than $1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For ServiceNow customers deploying AI agents across their organizations, the acquisition would address a critical gap: controlling what those agents can access and do. Veza’s technology maps permissions across enterprise systems, showing exactly which users, applications, and AI agents have access to what data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deal could be announced next week, The Information &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/servicenow-advanced-talks-buy-security-startup-least-1-billion" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deal would follow ServiceNow’s &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3842626/servicenow-to-acquire-moveworks-to-strengthen-agentic-ai-and-enterprise-search.html"&gt;$2.85 billion acquisition of Moveworks&lt;/a&gt;, announced in March. That purchase brought AI assistants and enterprise search capabilities to ServiceNow’s platform. Adding Veza would provide the identity security layer needed to govern those AI systems as they access data across cloud services, SaaS applications, and internal systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow and Veza did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="managing-machine-identities"&gt;Managing machine identities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow said in March that it deployed thousands of AI agents for customers across IT, HR, customer service, and security operations. As these agents take on more autonomous tasks, enterprises face mounting pressure to understand what they can access and whether those permissions align with security policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“ServiceNow is trying to build an enterprise platform where AI agents don’t just chat, but actually take meaningful actions inside the business,” said Akshat Tyagi, associate practice leader at HFS Research. “Moveworks gave them a strong automation layer, but trust and governance were the missing pieces. Handing over real-time authority to agents unless identity, permissions, and access rules are rock solid is a bluff no enterprise wants to play.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza addresses what security experts call the non-human identity problem. Every AI agent, API integration, and automated workflow creates service accounts and tokens that need management, according to the company. In most enterprises, these machine identities far outnumber human users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza’s Authorization Graph technology maps permissions across systems to show not just who has access, but what they can effectively do with that access. According to its website, the company manages more than 20 billion permissions for customers, including Blackstone, Expedia, and Workday. Veza has raised $235 million since its inception in 2020 and employed more than 190 people as of April 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tyagi said existing identity and access management tools were designed for human accounts but struggle with machine identities, API keys, and autonomous agents making real-time decisions. “This creates blind spots around privilege sprawl and cross-system access paths,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The two companies already work together. ServiceNow Ventures &lt;a href="https://veza.com/company/press-room/veza-strategic-announcement-servicenow-capitalone/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;invested in Veza in August 2023&lt;/a&gt; alongside Capital One Ventures. The companies have more than 250 joint customers, the report added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="customer-integration-questions"&gt;Customer integration questions&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For those joint customers, the acquisition would mean significant changes in how the two systems work together. Enterprises using both ServiceNow and Veza today run them as separate systems. Integration would allow ServiceNow’s AI agents to natively query and enforce access policies based on Veza’s permission intelligence, without customers building custom connections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That integration will take time, according to Tyagi. “ServiceNow is already a big and complex system, and adding a full identity security engine won’t be instant plug-and-play,” he said. Customers should expect changes to licensing and the introduction of new modules as the two platforms merge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations using Veza without ServiceNow will want clarity on whether the product remains available as a standalone offering. Those using ServiceNow with other identity vendors will need to know if their existing tools remain supported or if ServiceNow will push customers toward its own integrated stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow unveiled AI agents for security and risk management at its &lt;a href="https://www.servicenow.com/company/media/press-room/ai-driven-security-and-risk.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Knowledge 2025 conference&lt;/a&gt; in May, positioning them as tools for autonomous enterprise defense. Veza would provide the authorization controls those security agents need to safely investigate and remediate threats across systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza treats access as a relationship problem, connecting identities, permissions, and data to show effective access rather than just theoretical permissions, according to Tyagi.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="market-implications"&gt;Market implications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acquisition would give ServiceNow a more complete offering against rivals building AI-powered enterprise platforms. Salesforce, Microsoft, and Oracle all offer AI agents, but none had combined front-end automation with identity security in the way ServiceNow was attempting with Moveworks and Veza, according to Tyagi.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This deal can shake up the identity security landscape because it pulls deep authorization intelligence into a major enterprise platform instead of keeping it as a standalone specialty,” Tyagi said. Standalone identity vendors like CyberArk, SailPoint, and Okta may face pressure to find their own platform partnerships or acquisition targets, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097423/servicenow-is-in-talks-to-buy-identity-security-firm-veza-for-over-1-billion-report-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-770)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 arrested for smuggling migrants from Türkiye to France and Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</link>
      <description>On 13 November 2025, the German Federal Police, in close cooperation with French border police and with the support of Europol and Eurojust, have dismantled a criminal network believed to have smuggled nearly 600 people into Europe between 2021 and 2023.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-771)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-772)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-773)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-766) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-774)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-775)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 suspects arrested in two blows against human trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>France and Spain: disrupting a Chinese human trafficking networkConducted jointly by France and Spain, this operation targeted a Chinese organised crime group involved in trafficking human beings for sexual exploitation. The network, active for several years, coordinated sexual exploitation rings across France and multiple EU Member States. Members of the network rented apartments online for short terms, a modus operandi...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 arrests in Bulgaria in a large art trafficking investigation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</link>
      <description>On 19 November 2025, a coordinated effort led by Bulgarian authorities and supported by Europol, resulted in the dismantling of a criminal network involved in large-scale trafficking of cultural goods across Europe and beyond. This operation was conducted under the framework of a Europol operational taskforce. The action day involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Albania, France, Germany, Greece,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and partner countries combat online radicalisation on gaming platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</link>
      <description>Conducted on 13 November 2025, this operational action by the European Union Internet Referral Unit (EU IRU) involved the referral of thousands of URLs leading to dangerous and illicit online material. This includes around 5 408 links to jihadist content, 1 070 links to violent right-wing extremist and terrorist content, and 105 links to racist and xenophobic content.This joint action...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUR 47 million in crypto traced to disrupt digital piracy services</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November, Europol, in collaboration with the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional), organised an "Intellectual Property Crime Cyber-Patrol Week”. A total of 30 investigators participated in this operation hosted at the EUIPO headquarters in Alicante, Spain, where they used advanced Open-Source Intelligence Techniques (OSINT) and cutting-edge online investigative tools...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the winners of the 2025 Europol photo competition</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</link>
      <description>Three awards were given out, each decided by a different group of voters:the international law enforcement community represented at Europol’s headquarters,members of the public,and the Heads of Communication of the European law enforcement authorities.The winners of Capture25The Europol Community Vote by the Liaison Bureaux went to Johan Jacob Kleist from Denmark with his photo of a ‘police officer patrolling beneath...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-776)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-777)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grafana security advisory (AV25-778)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688) – Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16.6 million packages of fake and harmful toys taken off EU markets</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</link>
      <description>Fake toys are poisoning, deafening and injuring children across Europe, while causing major losses to the EU economy. 26 countries, coordinated by Europol, co-led by France, Spain and Romania, and supported by the EUIPO and OLAF, have once again led initiatives to take down the producers and importers of counterfeit toys. With the global toy market valued at up to EUR 300 billion annually, it also remains the second-most counterfeited industry globally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help4U: A new digital platform to support young people facing online sexual abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</link>
      <description>A new digital platform, Help4U, developed by Europol and CENTRIC, has been launched to support children and teenagers facing sexual abuse or online harm. Designed to be simple, private, and accessible, Help4U supports young people with finding trusted advice, understanding their rights, and connecting with people who can help. The platform offers clear, practical guidance for anyone under 18 who needs help, as well as information for parents, teachers, and professionals supporting them.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security researchers caution app developers about risks in using Google Antigravity</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097698/security-researchers-caution-app-developers-about-risks-in-using-google-antigravity.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google’s Antigravity development tool for creating artificial intelligence agents has been out for less than 11 days and already the company has been forced to update the known issues pages after security researchers discovered what they say are vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mindgard.ai/blog/google-antigravity-persistent-code-execution-vulnerability" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to a blog from Mindgard&lt;/a&gt;, one of the first to discover problems with Antigravity, Google isn’t calling the issue it found a security bug. But Mindgard says a threat actor could create a malicious rule by taking advantage of Antigravity’s strict direction that any AI assistant it creates must always follow user-defined rules.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Author Aaron Portnoy, Mindgard’s head of research and innovation, says that after his blog was posted, Google replied on November 25 to say a report has been filed with the responsible product team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, until there is action, “the existence of this vulnerability means that users are at risk to backdoor attacks via compromised workspaces when using Antigravity, which can be leveraged by attackers to execute arbitrary code on their systems. At present there is no setting that we could identify to safeguard against this vulnerability,” Portnoy wrote in his blog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even in the most restrictive mode of operation, “exploitation proceeds unabated and without confirmation from the user,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked for comment, a Google spokesperson said the company is aware of the issue reported by Mindguard, and is working to address it. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an email, Mindgard’s Portnoy told &lt;em&gt;CSOonline&lt;/em&gt; that the nature of the flaw makes it difficult to mitigate. “Strong identity would not help mitigate this issue, because the actions undertaken by Antigravity are occurring with the identity of the user running the application,” he said. “As far as the operating system can tell, they are indistinguishable. Access management control could possibly do so, but only if you were able to restrict access to the global configuration directory, and it may have downstream impact on Antigravity’s functionality.” For example, he said, this could cause Model Context Protocol (MCP), a framework for standardizing the way AI systems share data, to malfunction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The attack vector is through the source code repository that is opened by the developer,” he explained, “and doesn’t need to be triggered through a prompt.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other researchers also have found problems with Antigravity:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.deadbits.ai/p/indirect-prompt-injection-in-ai-ides" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Adam Swanda says he discovered and disclosed &lt;/a&gt;to Google an indirect prompt injection vulnerability. He said Google told him the particular problem is a known issue and is expected behavior of the tool.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;another researcher who goes by the name Wunderwuzzi &lt;a href="https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2025/security-keeps-google-antigravity-grounded/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blogged about discovering five holes&lt;/a&gt;, including data exfiltration and remote command execution via indirect prompt injection vulnerabilities. &lt;br /&gt;This blog notes that, according to Google’s Antigravity Known Issues page, &lt;a href="https://bughunters.google.com/learn/invalid-reports/google-products/4655949258227712/antigravity-known-issues" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company is working on fixes for several issues.  &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked for comment about the issues reported in the three blogs, a Google spokesperson said, “We take security issues very seriously and encourage reporting of all vulnerabilities so we can identify and address them quickly. We will continue to post &lt;a href="https://bughunters.google.com/learn/invalid-reports/google-products/4655949258227712/antigravity-known-issues" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;known issues&lt;/a&gt; publicly as we work to address them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-is-antigravity"&gt;What is Antigravity?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Antigravity is an integrated application development environment (IDE), released on November 18, that leverages the Google Gemini 3 Pro chatbot. “Antigravity isn’t just an editor,” &lt;a href="https://antigravity.google/blog/introducing-google-antigravity?utm_source=deepmind.google&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=gdm&amp;amp;utm_content=" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google says&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s a development platform that combines a familiar, AI-powered coding experience with a new agent-first interface. This allows you to deploy agents that autonomously plan, execute, and verify complex tasks across your editor, terminal, and browser.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Individuals — including threat actors — can use it for free.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Antigravity streamlines workflows by offering tools for parallelization, customization, and efficient knowledge management, the company says, to help eliminate common development obstacles and repetitive tasks. Agents can be spun up to tackle routine tasks such as codebase research, bug fixes, and backlog tasks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="agent-installs-the-malware"&gt;Agent installs the malware&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem Mindgard discovered involves Antigravity’s rule that the developer has to work within a trusted workspace or the tool won’t function. The threat manifests through an attacker creating a malicious source code repository, Portnoy says. “Then, if a target opens it (through finding it on Github, being social engineered, or tricked into opening it) then that user’s system becomes compromised persistently.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malicious actor doesn’t have to create an agent, he explained. The agent is part of Antigravity and is backed by the Google Gemini LLM. The agent is the component that is tricked into installing the backdoor by following instructions in the malicious source code repository that was opened by the user.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In Antigravity,” Mindgard argues, “’trust’ is effectively the entry point to the product rather than a conferral of privileges.” The problem, it pointed out, is that a compromised workspace becomes a long-term backdoor into every new session. “Even after a complete uninstall and re-install of Antigravity,” says Mindgard, “the backdoor remains in effect. Because Antigravity’s core intended design requires trusted workspace access, the vulnerability translates into cross-workspace risk, meaning one tainted workspace can impact all subsequent usage of Antigravity regardless of trust settings.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For anyone responsible for AI cybersecurity, says Mindguard, this highlights the need to treat AI development environments as sensitive infrastructure, and to closely control what content, files, and configurations are allowed into them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="process-perplexing"&gt;Process ‘perplexing’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In his email, Portnoy acknowledged that Google is now taking some action. “Google is moving through their established process, although it was a bit perplexing on the stop-and-start nature. First [the reported vulnerability] was flagged as not an issue. Then it was re-opened. Then the Known Issues page was altered in stealth to be more all encompassing. It’s good that the vulnerability will be reviewed by their security team to ascertain its severity, although in the meantime we would recommend all Antigravity users to seriously consider the vulnerability found and means for mitigation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Adam Swanda says in his blog that he was able to partially extract an Antigravity agent’s system prompt, enough to identify a design weakness that could lead to indirect prompt injection. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="highlights-broader-issues"&gt;Highlights broader issues&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem is, the prompt tells the AI to strictly follow special XML-style tags that handle privileged instructions in a conversation between a user and the chatbot, so there would be no warning to the user that special, and possibly malicious, instructions were retrieved. When the agent fetches external web content, Swanda says, it doesn’t sanitize these special tags to ensure they are actually from the application itself and not untrusted input. An attacker can embed their own special message in a webpage, or presumably any other content, and the Antigravity agent will treat those commands as trusted system instructions. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This type of vulnerability isn’t new, he adds, but the finding highlights broader issues in large language models and agent systems:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLMs cannot distinguish between trusted and untrusted sources;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;untrusted sources can contain malicious instructions to execute tools and/or modify responses returned to the user/application;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;system prompts should not be considered secret or used as a security control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="advice-to-developers"&gt;Advice to developers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Swanda recommends that app development teams building AI agents with tool-calling:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assume all external content is adversarial. Use strong input and output guardrails, including tool calling; Strip any special syntax before processing;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;implement tool execution safeguards. Require explicit user approval for high-risk operations, especially those triggered after handling untrusted content or other dangerous tool combinations;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;not rely on prompts for security. System prompts, for example, can be extracted and used by an attacker to influence their attack strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, Portnoy recommends that developers work with their security teams to ensure that they sufficiently vet and assess the AI-assisted tools that they are introducing to their organization. “There are numerous examples of using AI-assisted tools to accelerate development pipelines to enhance operational efficiency,” he said. “However, from experience, security in bleeding-edge (recently dropped) tools is somewhat of an afterthought. Thinking seriously about the intended use case of the AI tool, what data sources it can access, and what it is connected to are fundamental to ensuring you remain secure.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097698/security-researchers-caution-app-developers-about-risks-in-using-google-antigravity.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU ‘Chat Control’ proposals should be red flag to businesses everywhere</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097728/eu-chat-control-proposals-should-be-red-flag-to-businesses-everywhere.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data privacy campaigners have warned that any celebration of the news that the European Union (EU) has abandoned its plans to break end-to-end encryption in mobile messaging apps could be short-lived.  According to one expert, this announcement should be a “red flag” to organizations operating within Europe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There has been a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2154094/chat-apps-end-to-end-encryption-threatened-by-eu-legislation.html" target="_blank"&gt;long-standing threat to end-to-end encryption&lt;/a&gt; within Europe, as tech companies have battled with legislators over the EU Council’s attempt to limit messages shared by child sexual abusers through scanning of communications. Hoping to calm companies’ fears, on November 26, the &lt;a href="https://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/press/press-releases/2025/11/26/child-sexual-abuse-council-reaches-position-on-law-protecting-children-from-online-abuse/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Council issued a statement&lt;/a&gt; saying that all monitoring of communications will be performed by providers on a voluntary basis. It also announced a modified approach to the automated scans, dubbed &lt;a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/posts/chat-control/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chat Control&lt;/a&gt; by privacy campaigners, as a new way of tackling child abuse online.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, privacy campaigner and former member of European parliament &lt;a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Patrick Breyer&lt;/a&gt; noted, “the enterprise aspect was often overlooked in this debate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While there has been plenty of talk about the protection of individuals, Breyer said that, for CISOs and enterprises, the EU proposals should be a red flag. He pointed out there could be a real risk of the leakage of sensitive data. “The technology has high error rates. For a corporation, a ‘false positive’ could mean that confidential internal documents, code, or strategic plans are flagged and sent to external authorities or police forces without the company’s knowledge,&lt;strong&gt;”&lt;/strong&gt; he said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breyer has been a long time critic of the EU proposals, and feels that the move to voluntary monitoring of communications is not enough protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;The headlines are misleading: Chat Control is not dead, it is just being privatized&lt;strong&gt;,”&lt;/strong&gt;  wrote &lt;a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/reality-check-eu-council-chat-control-vote-is-not-a-retreat-but-a-green-light-for-indiscriminate-mass-surveillance-and-the-end-of-right-to-communicate-anonymously/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Breyer on his website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;What the Council endorsed today is a Trojan Horse. By cementing ‘voluntary’ mass scanning, they are legitimizing the warrantless, error-prone mass surveillance of millions of Europeans by US corporations, while simultaneously killing online anonymity through the backdoor of age verification.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breyer’s position is supported by another digital privacy group, European Digital Rights (EDRi). It posted &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/european-digital-rights_chatcontrol-csaregulation-encryption-activity-7399432202427748352-Psot/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a statement on LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; saying that digital rights may still be at risk. “We want to be absolutely certain that lawmakers don’t leave loopholes that would lead to harm,” it said. “For example, the Council text would have been better if it expressly rejected the use of ‘client-side scanning’ tools, as a lot of discretion is still left to national authorities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In particular, EDRi drew attention to the possibility of voluntary monitoring. “This means that Big Tech companies can decide to scan your personal messages, without suspicion that you’re doing anything wrong, and apply error-prone predictive AI tools to look for evidence of abuse. This sort of scanning already happens, with very little transparency and oversight, and no proper legal basis,” said the organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And for corporations looking to protect their intellectual data and maintain secure communications, the threat is very real, said Breyer. “In short: If this proposal passes, no European company can guarantee the confidentiality of its communications any more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097728/eu-chat-control-proposals-should-be-red-flag-to-businesses-everywhere.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSO in eigener Sache: Mit Smart Answers zu mehr Information</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095215/cso-in-eigener-sache-mit-smart-answers-zu-mehr-information.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 5350w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Mit Smart Answers werden alle Ihre Fragen bei uns auf der CSO-Website beantwortet.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;witsarut sakorn – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie können CISOs ihre Karriere pushen? Welche Auswirkungen haben Ransomware-Angriffe auf Unternehmen? Wie läuft die Kommunikation nach einem Cyberangriff ab? Diese und viele weitere Fragen beantworten wir Ihnen auf der Website der CSO über unser neues KI-Tool “Smart Answers”.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO Smart Answers" class="wp-image-4096495" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-26-084908.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Smart Answers ist in allen Artikeln auf CSO.de eingebaut.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bei Smart Answers handelt es sich um einen Chatbot, der Leserinnen und Lesern dabei helfen soll, drängende Fragen der Security-Community zu beantworten, Inhalte auf unseren Webseiten zu entdecken und sich eingehend mit wichtigen IT- und Leadership-Themen zu befassen, die für Security-Entscheiderinnen und -Entscheider wichtig sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Tool ist praktisch in allen Artikeln auf der Website der CSO eingebettet. Um loszulegen, können Sie Ihre Fragen direkt in das Smart-Answers-Suchfeld eingeben. Alternativ können Sie auch aus einer Reihe zum Thema passender, vorkonfektionierter Fragen auswählen, um tiefer in ein Thema einzusteigen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO Smart Answers" class="wp-image-4096498" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-26-084621.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Klar strukturiert gibt Smart Answers Antworten auf Ihre Fragen&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In den Antworten finden Sie Links zu den Quelldokumenten sowie zusätzliches Informationsmaterial und Artikelempfehlungen. Darüber hinaus können Sie weitere Detailfragen stellen, um noch tiefer in ein bestimmtes Thema einzusteigen. Alternativ schlagen wir Ihnen außerdem weitere Fragen vor, über die Sie zusätzliche Aspekte zu dem von Ihnen angefragten Thema beleuchten können.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO Smart Answers" class="wp-image-4096500" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-26-090752.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Über die Quellenangaben zu den Antworten von Smart Answers können Sie Inhalte prüfen und tiefer in bestimmte Themen eintauchen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Smart Answers basiert auf einer Generative-AI-Plattform, die in Zusammenarbeit mit unserem Partner Miso.ai entwickelt wurde. Das KI-Tool greift ausschließlich auf redaktionelle Inhalte aus dem Netzwerk unserer deutschsprachigen Medienmarken zurück – CIO, COMPUTERWOCHE, CSO und ChannelPartner – und wurde mit Fragen trainiert, die für professionelle IT-Anwender aus Unternehmen relevant sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wir haben uns viel Mühe gegeben, um sicherzustellen, dass Smart Answers eine hochwertige Benutzererfahrung bietet. Die Antworten basieren ausschließlich auf Artikeln, die von unseren Journalistinnen und Journalisten verfasst wurden. Smart Answers verwendet keine Daten aus &lt;a href="https://a1.adform.net/C/?bn=85522444;gdpr=%24%7Bgdpr%7D;gdpr_consent=%24%7Bgdpr_consent_50%7D" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;externen Quellen. Hinter den Kulissen wurden umfangreiche Tests durchgeführt, um das Modell zu trainieren, sodass wir davon überzeugt sind, Ihnen mit Smart Answers zuverlässige Informationen für Ihre Arbeit an die Hand geben zu können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="probieren-sie-smart-answers-aus-und-teilen-sie-ihr-feedback"&gt;Probieren Sie Smart Answers aus und teilen Sie Ihr Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie bei allen von KI generierten Inhalten empfehlen wir jedoch, diese zu überprüfen. Wir haben intensiv mit unserem Partner Miso.ai zusammengearbeitet, um „Halluzinationen“ zu vermeiden. Irreführende oder falsche Informationen, die ausgegeben werden können, wenn die Antwort nicht bekannt ist oder die zur Beantwortung der Frage erforderlichen Daten unvollständig sind, sollten so weitgehend ausgeschlossen sein. Wenn Smart Answers Ihre Frage nicht beantworten kann, teilt Ihnen das KI-Tool dies mit. Angezeigt wird außerdem, wenn die Antwort von Smart Answers vor allem auf Inhalten beruht, die vor dem Jahr 2020 veröffentlicht wurden. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wir laden Sie ein, mit Smart Answers zu experimentieren. Stellen unser neues KI-Tool auf die Probe. Wir hoffen, ihnen damit weiteren wertvollen Content und Input für Ihre Arbeit zur Verfügung stellen zu können. Und wir sind natürlich gespannt auf Ihr Feedback. Teilen Sie uns gerne Ihre Erfahrungen mit Smart Answers mit und schicken Sie uns Ihre Anmerkungen an julia.mutzbauer@csoonline.com.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095215/cso-in-eigener-sache-mit-smart-answers-zu-mehr-information.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empathetic policy engineering: The secret to better security behavior and awareness</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4092639/empathy-meets-it-security-the-path-to-active-compliance.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#_ftnref1" id="_ftn1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In many companies, IT security guidelines encounter resistance because employees perceive them as obstructive or impractical. This makes implementation difficult, undermines effectiveness, and strains collaboration between the security department and business units.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, instead of being seen as a partner, cybersecurity is often perceived as a hindrance — a fatal security risk. For CISOs, this means that, in addition to technically sound guidelines, acceptance in everyday work is crucial. A new approach with empathetic policy engineering and strategic security communication can help foster a sustainable security culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="it-security-work-pressure-and-social-influences"&gt;IT security: Work pressure and social influences&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many IT departments believe that users are poorly motivated to comply with security guidelines. Companies rely on sanctions and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;security awareness training&lt;/a&gt; to enforce compliance. However, a two-day experiment investigating the impact of security designs on policy-compliant user behavior revealed that while participants initially had a positive attitude toward security guidelines, these guidelines became increasingly perceived as a hindrance under rising work pressure, leading to more frequent violations. Stress and situational factors had a noticeable influence on the participants’ security-related behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Safe behavior therefore does not arise solely from knowledge transfer, but depends heavily on individual risk assessment and concrete everyday situations. Users do not always act as the guidelines prescribe — often not out of unwillingness, but because other factors outweigh or are considered more important. Ambitious goals, time pressure, and the need for seamless collaboration frequently conflict with abstract security requirements. These conflicts of interest quickly lead to tensions between security, IT, and other departments. This ultimately jeopardizes the security culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security managers can counteract this by addressing three points.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-conduct-stakeholder-analysis"&gt;1. Conduct stakeholder analysis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should first ask themselves why users are not behaving securely. A variety of factors play a role here: For example, users may not be aware of the threat, may not see the benefits of secure behavior, or may perceive security measures as hindering their work. There may also be a conflict of interest with the users’ goals, or they may be under time pressure. Often, the resources are simply lacking — for example, if regulations require secure data exchange with suppliers and customers, but employees are not provided with a platform for such data exchange — or there may be a lack of role models in the environment&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before implementing security measures, it is important to identify and balance conflicting goals and priorities among the various stakeholder groups (IT department, technical departments, management, administration, production staff). This can be done, for example, through stakeholder analysis — a method from business informatics used to ascertain the preferences of all stakeholders involved. The more security managers know about the realities of work and the goals of the different departments, the better they can tailor security measures accordingly — leading to greater acceptance and ultimately successful implementation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-design-security-guidelines-with-the-user-in-mind"&gt;2. Design security guidelines with the user in mind&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Insecure behavior is often blamed on users, when the problem often lies in the measure itself. In IT security research, the focus is often on individual user behavior — for example, on whether secure behavior depends on personality traits. The question of how well security measures actually fit the reality of work — that is, how likely they are to be accepted in everyday practice — is neglected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For every threat, there are usually several available security measures. But differences in effort, acceptance, compatibility, or complexity are often not taken into account in practice. Instead, security or IT departments often make decisions based solely on technical aspects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To establish effective IT security policies, they must not only be technically correct — they must also be sensible and practical from an employee perspective. The key to this lies in empathetic policy engineering: Security guidelines should be designed so that they are understandable, accepted, and compatible with everyday work goals. This is best achieved when employees are involved in the development process early on — including their conflicting goals and practical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A subsequent pilot project helps to identify potential stumbling blocks and obstacles early on and to adjust the measures accordingly. It has proven effective to start with the “early adopters” — that is, the group of users who are open to innovations and can subsequently provide constructive feedback. This should be taken into account before the large-scale rollout. In this way, a safety culture can develop that is effective — and actually practiced in everyday work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-communicate-with-respect"&gt;3. Communicate with respect&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Safety measures and guidelines are often communicated in a way that doesn’t resonate with users’ work reality because they don’t aim to engage employees and motivate them: for example, through instructions, standard online training, or overly playful formats like comics that employees don’t take seriously. A “respect approach” works better: It relies on communication on equal terms, instead of prohibitions and punishments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The crucial difference: Employees are treated as competent, responsible adults. The focus is on an empathetic understanding of their needs and work realities — without losing sight of safety goals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are several techniques for successfully communicating safety policies and avoiding conflicts:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tactical empathy:&lt;/strong&gt; This creates recognition, strengthens trust, and thus ensures that employees feel heard and are willing to accept security-relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Help me to help you’instead of ‘No’:&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of enforcing security requirements, CISOs can use targeted “how” questions to encourage users to think about the proposed solutions. If users have change requests regarding the security requirements, security shouldn’t simply say “no.” It’s helpful to ask what the employees themselves suggest to both comply with security requirements and enable efficient work. This creates a dialogue and makes it easier to find a compromise acceptable to all parties involved&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical experience instead of dry theory:&lt;/strong&gt; A training concept that relies on direct experience confronts participants with realistic scenarios — such as cyberattacks like phishing, ransomware, or USB attacks. They experience firsthand, in a realistic environment that replicates typical workplaces in small and midsize enterprises, how cyberattacks unfold. This creates a deep, lasting understanding of IT security. Instead of lectures, the focus is on people and their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cisos-as-shapers-of-an-effective-security-culture"&gt;CISOs as shapers of an effective security culture&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The limited success of many security measures is not solely due to the users — often it’s unrealistic requirements, a lack of involvement, and inadequate communication. For security leaders, this means: Instead of relying on education and sanctions, a strategic paradigm shift is needed. They should become a kind of empathetic policy architect whose security strategy not only works technically but also resonates on a human level. They create frameworks in which secure decisions are naturally integrated into everyday work. This requires a good sense of conflicting objectives, communication on equal terms — and the ability to anchor security as a shared value within the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4092639/empathy-meets-it-security-the-path-to-active-compliance.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Security-Praktiken zum Abgewöhnen</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4024816/7-security-praktiken-zum-abgewohnen.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Floppy Headscratch  16z9" class="wp-image-4024818" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Sergio-Delle-Vedove-shutterstock_2188612669_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Aus der Zeit gefallen?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Sergio Delle Vedove | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Schlechte Angewohnheiten &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493061/positiv-denken-fur-sicherheitsentscheider-6-mindsets-die-sie-sofort-ablegen-sollten.html" target="_blank"&gt;abzustellen&lt;/a&gt; (oder bessere zu entwickeln), ist ein Prozess, der Geduld, Selbstbeherrschung und Entschlossenheit erfordert. Das gilt sowohl auf persönlicher als auch auf Security-technischer Ebene. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In diesem Artikel haben wir sieben Sicherheitspraktiken für Sie zusammengestellt, deren Haltbarkeitsdatum schon eine ganze Weile abgelaufen ist.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-perimeter-sicherheit-fur-ausreichend-halten"&gt;1. Perimeter-Sicherheit für ausreichend halten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die meisten Arbeitsumgebungen sind heute Cloud-basiert – in vielen Fällen mit Remote-Anteil. Das beobachtet auch &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/amitbasu/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amit Basu&lt;/a&gt;, CIO und CISO bei International Seaways, einem Transportdienstleister für Erdölprodukte. Seine Schlussfolgerung: “Die alte Praxis, eine fest definierte Grenze abzusichern, funktioniert einfach nicht mehr in hybriden und Cloud-First-Arbeitsumgebungen. Weil sich Benutzer und Daten sowohl innerhalb als auch außerhalb des traditionellen Perimeters befinden, sind Unternehmen, die ausschließlich auf Perimeter-Sicherheit setzen, gefährlichen Bedrohungen ausgesetzt.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dazu gehören dem Sicherheits- und IT-Entscheider zufolge etwa Ransomware-Angriffe. Die bessere, zeitgemäßere Lösung sei es, auf &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491851/was-ist-zero-trust.html" target="_blank"&gt;Zero Trust&lt;/a&gt; zu setzen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-security-an-der-compliance-ausrichten"&gt;2. Security an der Compliance ausrichten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In den Augen von &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgegerchow/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;George Gerchow&lt;/a&gt;, CSO beim Security-Dienstleister Bedrock Security, lassen sich zu viele Teams von Compliance leiten, wenn es darum geht, Sicherheitsprogramme auf die Beine zu stellen. Das laufe letztlich nur darauf hinaus, Checklisten abzuarbeiten, statt Herausforderungen im Bereich Cybersecurity zu lösen: “Diese GRC-orientierte Mentalität ist veraltet und dysfunktional.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie Gerchow ausführt, vermittle eine Compliance-orientierte Security ein falsches Gefühl der Sicherheit und binde Ressourcen, die eigentlich für &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3840232/11-ruinose-ransomware-bedrohungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;tatsächliche Bedrohungen&lt;/a&gt; eingesetzt werden sollten: “Das kann dann dazu führen, dass große GRC-Teams ihre Arbeitszeit damit verbringen, Kundenfragebögen zu beantworten oder sich an Audits abzuarbeiten. Stattdessen käme es eher darauf an, Daten zu schützen, Zugriffskontrollen zu managen und neue Bedrohungen im Blick zu behalten.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Deshalb ist der CSO überzeugt, dass Unternehmen zu den grundlegenden Prinzipien der IT-Sicherheit zurückkehren müssen. Abbilden lässt sich das seiner Meinung nach über einen &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2826282/die-wichtigsten-ztna-anbieter-und-loesungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Zero-Trust-Ansatz&lt;/a&gt; sowie Continuous Monitoring, beispielsweise mit dem &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@RocketMeUpCybersecurity/continuous-adaptive-risk-and-trust-assessment-carta-protocols-for-enterprise-security-e5ba998a2493" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CARTA-Ansatz&lt;/a&gt; (Continuous Adaptive Risk and Trust Assessment).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-legacy-vpns-beibehalten"&gt;3. Legacy-VPNs beibehalten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veraltete &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491715/7-vpn-alternativen-wie-fernzugriff-sicherer-geht.html" target="_blank"&gt;VPN-Instanzen&lt;/a&gt; können ineffizient und schwerfällig sein, was zu erheblichen Ausfallzeiten führen kann und es diffiziler gestaltet, sie zu managen. Auch &lt;a href="https://www.cdw.com/content/cdw/en/articles/contributors/buck-bell.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Buck Bell&lt;/a&gt;, Leiter der globalen Sicherheitsstrategie beim IT-Dienstleister CDW, ist kein “Fan”: “Legacy-VPNs können die Anforderungen des modernen Arbeitsplatzes nicht erfüllen. Insbesondere weil Führungskräfte heute einen nahtloseren und flexibleren Zugriff auf Ressourcen für ihre Teams benötigen – unabhängig davon, ob diese im Büro oder remote arbeiten.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zudem seien solche Legacy-Systeme nicht skalierbar, weil sie mit den sich verändernden Sicherheitsanforderungen wachsender Unternehmen nicht Schritt halten können, meint Bell: “Das führt mit zunehmender Angriffsfläche zu Herausforderungen. Dass veraltete VPNs oft nicht mehr regelmäßig mit Aktualisierungen und Patches versorgt werden, vergrößert das Risikopotenzial noch weiter.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein besserer Ansatz: auf &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493712/secure-access-service-edge-der-grose-sase-kaufratgeber.html" target="_blank"&gt;Secure Access Service Edge&lt;/a&gt; (SASE) umsteigen und sich dem Zero-Trust-Ansatz verschreiben. Das kann auch Security-Experte Bell nur wärmstens empfehlen: “Diese Strategien erhöhen das Sicherheitsniveau, indem sie jeden Benutzer und jedes Gerät überprüfen, das auf Netzwerkressourcen zugreifen möchte.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-nur-auf-edr-setzen"&gt;4. Nur auf EDR setzen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3616110/edr-software-ein-kaufratgeber.html" target="_blank"&gt;Endpoint Detection and Response&lt;/a&gt; (EDR)-Lösungen stellen ohne Zweifel einen erheblicher Fortschritt gegenüber herkömmlicher Antivirus-Software dar. Allerdings reicht dieser Ansatz allein in der heutigen Bedrohungslandschaft nicht mehr aus, wie &lt;a href="https://www.nopalcyber.com/leadership-team/michel-sahyoun-" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Michel Sahyoun&lt;/a&gt;, Chief Solutions Architect beim Security-Anbieter NopalCyber, erklärt: „EDR eignet sich hervorragend, um Aktivitäten an Endpunkten zu überwachen, darauf zu reagieren und komplexe Angriffe zu erkennen. Allerdings umgehen Angreifer Endpunkte zunehmend und nehmen stattdessen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495515/7-fundamentale-cloud-bedrohungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cloud-Umgebungen&lt;/a&gt;, Netzwerkgeräte und eingebettete Systeme ins Visier.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eine übermäßige Abhängigkeit von EDR könne deshalb dazu beitragen, dass kritische Sicherheitslücken unbeachtet bleiben. Im schlimmsten Fall ermögliche das Cyberkriminellen, sich über längere Zeit unbemerkt im Unternehmensnetzwerk einzunisten, warnt der Manager: “Die Angreifer könnten beispielsweise &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494981/bosartige-oauth-apps-cyberangreifer-missbrauchen-microsoft-privilegien.html" target="_blank"&gt;OAuth-Token ausnutzen&lt;/a&gt;, um sich unbefugten Zugriff auf Cloud-Plattformen zu verschaffen – ohne jemals mit einem Endpunkt zu interagieren, der über EDR-Software abgesichert ist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In ähnlicher Weise stellten Netzwerk- und IoT-Devices in vielen Fällen blinde Flecken dar – auch weil diese oft keine robusten Monitoring- und Forensik-Funktionen aufwiesen: “Cloud-Umgebung erschweren die Detection zusätzlich aufgrund begrenzter Logging- sowie kostenpflichtiger Visibility-Funktionen. Weil sich die Angriffe zunehmend darauf verlagern, Trust-Beziehungen, Identitäten und APIs auszunutzen, ist ein Endpoint-zentrierter Ansatz allein unzureichend”, konstatiert Sahyoun.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-sms-fur-2fa-nutzen"&gt;5. SMS für 2FA nutzen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die SMS-basierte Zwei-Faktor-Authentifizierung galt einst als enormer Fortschritt in Sachen Security (verglichen mit der Authentifizierung per Passwort). Doch auch dieses Verfahren ist inzwischen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494553/was-sind-passkeys.html" target="_blank"&gt;veraltet&lt;/a&gt; – und risikobehaftet.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.isc2.org/b/sp/aparna-ash-himmatramka-5702" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Aparna Himmatramka&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Security Assurance Lead bei Microsoft, erklärt: “Leider wurde die TK-Infrastruktur nicht mit Blick auf Sicherheitsaspekte konzipiert. Darüber hinaus verwenden Mobilfunknetze auch heute noch veraltete Protokolle, die ausgenutzt werden können – und der Prozess der Übertragung von Telefonnummern zwischen Netzbetreibern erfolgt in vielen Fällen ohne strenge Identitätsprüfung. Das öffnet &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2794098/so-stehlen-hacker-ihre-handynummer.html" target="_blank"&gt;SIM-Swapping-Angriffen&lt;/a&gt; Tür und Tor.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-on-premises-siems-einsetzen"&gt;6. On-Premises-SIEMs einsetzen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lokal installierte &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3835828/siem-kaufratgeber.html" target="_blank"&gt;SIEM-Tools&lt;/a&gt; sind Security-Manager Gerchow ebenfalls ein Dorn im Auge. Denn sie führten oft zu einer Flut von Warnmeldungen und seien zudem in vielen Fällen nicht Cloud-fähig. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Das zwingt Unternehmen entweder dazu, enorme Datenmengen unter hohen Kosten zu verschieben und zu speichern – oder das Risiko einzugehen, wichtige Protokolle zu übersehen, die essenziell sind, um Cloud-Deployments abzusichern”, mahnt Gerchow. Er fügt hinzu: “Viele Unternehmen halten an lokalen SIEM-Installationen fest, weil sie sich scheuen, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494345/der-kaufratgeber-fur-cloud-access-security-broker.html" target="_blank"&gt;sensible Daten in der Cloud zu speichern&lt;/a&gt;. Aber seien wir ehrlich: Dieser Zug ist abgefahren – es ist Zeit, weiterzuziehen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-passivitat-zulassen"&gt;7. Passivität zulassen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kaum jemand sieht sich selbst als potenzielles Opfer eines Phishing-Angriffs – dennoch fallen jeden Tag wieder viele Menschen auf &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3993294/diese-social-engineering-trends-sollten-sie-kennen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Social-Engineering-Taktiken&lt;/a&gt; herein.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-sullivan-3204292b/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kevin Sullivan&lt;/a&gt;, Principal Technology Consultant beim Softwareanbieter XTIUM, ist überzeugt, dass eine aktive Sicherheitskultur die Lösung ist, um das im Unternehmensumfeld zu verhindern: “Die richtigen Sicherheits-Tools und -Praktiken sind für jedes Unternehmen wichtig. Entscheidend sind dabei jedoch gute &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html" target="_blank"&gt;Security-Awareness-Programme&lt;/a&gt;, die die Belegschaft aufklären und dazu befähigen, Daten, Systeme und Geschäftsprozesse aktiv zu schützen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unternehmen, die ein kontinuierliches Engagement für Weiterbildung vermissen ließen, sabotierten sich selbst, so der Berater – in diesem Fall würden auch erhebliche Investitionen in Security-Tools und -Strategien ins Leere laufen: “Eine gut geschulte und gut vorbereitete Benutzerbasis ist die erste und stärkste Verteidigungslinie.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4024816/7-security-praktiken-zum-abgewohnen.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CSO guide to top security conferences</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/559539/the-cso-guide-to-top-security-conferences.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is nothing like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/539824/data-protection-security-conferences-why-go.html"&gt;attending a face-to-face event&lt;/a&gt; for career networking and knowledge gathering, and we don’t have to tell you how helpful it can be to get a hands-on demo of a new tool or to have your questions answered by experts. Fortunately, plenty of great &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/1622033/2022-new-zealand-tech-conference-and-event-guide.html"&gt;conferences&lt;/a&gt; are coming up in the months ahead. If keeping abreast of security trends and evolving threats is critical to your job — and we know it is — then attending some top-notch security conferences is on your must-do list for 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From major events to those that are more narrowly focused, this list from the editors of CSO, will help you find the security conferences that matter the most to you. We’ll keep it updated with new conferences so check back often. While we don’t expect this calendar to be comprehensive, we do aim to have it be highly relevant. If there’s something we’ve missed, let us know. You can email your additions, corrections and updates to &lt;a href="mailto:samira_sarraf@foundryco.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samira Sarraf&lt;/a&gt;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="december-2025"&gt;December 2025&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.passwordscon.org/"&gt;PasswordsCon&lt;/a&gt;, Prague, Czech Republic: 1-3 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://it-security-summit.com/munich/"&gt;IT Security Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Munich, Germany and virtual: 1-5 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/dallas-2025"&gt;SANS Dallas 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US and virtual: 1-6 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://heliview.com/state-cyber-security-sweden/"&gt;State of Cyber Security 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Stockholm, Sweden: 2 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/austin-tx-2025/"&gt;FutureCon Austin Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 4 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.conf42.com/devsecops2025"&gt;Conf42 DevSecOps 2025&lt;/a&gt;, virtual: 4 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cybersecuritysummit.com/summit/jacksonville25/"&gt;3rd Annual Jacksonville Cybersecurity Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Florida, US: 4 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsidescapetown.co.za/"&gt;BSides Cape Town&lt;/a&gt;, Cape Town, South Africa: 6 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.riskgcc.com/"&gt;#Risk GCC&lt;/a&gt;, Dubai, UAE: 8-9 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/na/identity-access-management-us"&gt;Gartner Identity &amp;amp; Access Management Summit 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 8-10 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://msspalertlive.com/2025"&gt;MSSP Alert Live&lt;/a&gt;, Maryland, US: 8-10 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/nashville-tn-2025/"&gt;FutureCon Nashville Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Tennessee, US: 10 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://luma.com/defenders-tour-arlington"&gt;Defenders Tour: SecOps Workshop&lt;/a&gt;, Virginia, US: 11 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/cyber-defense-initiative-2025"&gt;SANS Cyber Defense Initiative 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Washington D.C., US: 12 – 17 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="january-2026"&gt;January 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/nashville-winter-2026"&gt;SANS Nashville Winter 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Tennessee, US: 12-17 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/los-angeles-ca-2026/"&gt;Los Angeles Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and California, US: 15 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://identityshield.miniorange.com/"&gt;IdentityShield Summit&lt;/a&gt; ‘26, Pune, India: 16-17 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/dallas-tx-2026/"&gt;Dallas Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 22 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSidesPanamá&lt;/a&gt;, Panama city, Panama: 23-24 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/cyber-threat-intelligence-summit-2025/?msc=summit-home"&gt;SANS Cyber Threat Intelligence Summit &amp;amp; Training&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and Virginia, US: 26 January – 2 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.americanconference.com/cybersecurity-law/"&gt;Cybersecurity Law and Compliance&lt;/a&gt;, Washington, DC, US: 28 – 29 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/chicago-il-2026/"&gt;Chicago Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and Illinois, US: 29 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="february-2026"&gt;February 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cybersec-asia.net/"&gt;Cybersec Asia Shield your Core&lt;/a&gt;, Bangkok, Thailand: 4-5 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.intelliguards.com/intellic0n-speakers"&gt;Intellic0n&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 5-6 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cruisecon.com/"&gt;CruiseCon&lt;/a&gt;, departs from Florida, US: 7-12 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hackcon.org/hackcon21"&gt;HackCon&lt;/a&gt;, Oslo, Norway: 9-10 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://anz.cs4ca.com/"&gt;#CS4CA ANZ&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, Australia: 10-11 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://planetcybersec.com/021126-conference/"&gt;Planet Cyber Sec Conference&lt;/a&gt;, California, US: 11 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/detroit-mi-2026/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Detroit Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Michigan, US: 19 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSidesGalway&lt;/a&gt;, Galway, Ireland: 21 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cosac.net/apac/"&gt;Cosac APAC&lt;/a&gt;, Melbourne, Australia: 24-26 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSides Seattle&lt;/a&gt;, Washington State, US: 27-28 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="march-2026"&gt;March 2026&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cyberflorida.org/sunshine/"&gt;CyberBay 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Florida, US: 12-13 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/sans-osint-summit-2025/"&gt;SANS OSINT Summit &amp;amp; Training&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and Virginia, US: 16-22 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://heliview.com/security-leadership/"&gt;Security Leadership 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Utrecht, Netherlands: 24 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="april-2026"&gt;April 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cyphercon.com/"&gt;Cyphercon&lt;/a&gt;, Wisconsin, US: 1-2 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="may-2026"&gt;May 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.devopsbootcamp.net/cybersecfest-saopaulo"&gt;CyberSecFest SP&lt;/a&gt;, São Paulo, Brazil: May TBC&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/559539/the-cso-guide-to-top-security-conferences.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-779)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-780)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-781)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25-782)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-784)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-783)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI admits data breach after analytics partner hit by phishing attack</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097488/openai-admits-data-breach-after-analytics-partner-hit-by-phishing-attack-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI has suffered a significant data breach after hackers broke into the systems of its analytics partner Mixpanel and successfully stole customer profile information for its API portal, the companies have said in coordinated statements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://mixpanel.com/blog/sms-security-incident/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a post by Mixpanel CEO Jen Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, the incident took place on November 8 when the company “detected a smishing campaign and promptly executed our incident response processes.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Smishing is a form of phishing-by-SMS against targeted employees, popular with hackers because text messages bypass normal enterprise controls. This gave the attackers access to Mixpanel’s system, allowing them to steal a range of metadata relating to platform.openai.com account profiles:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name provided to OpenAI on the API account &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Email address associated with the API account&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Approximate location based on API user browser (city, state, country)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Operating system and browser used to access the API account&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Referring websites&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Organization or User IDs associated with the API account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We proactively communicated with all impacted customers. If you have not heard from us directly, you were not impacted,” said Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/mixpanel-incident/"&gt;separate OpenAI post&lt;/a&gt;, Mixpanel shared the affected customer dataset with it on November 25. After review, OpenAI had terminated its use of Mixpanel, it said, implying that this might be permanent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident affects some customers with platform.openai.com accounts, but not users of ChatGPT or other OpenAI products, OpenAI said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are in the process of notifying impacted organizations, admins, and users directly. While we have found no evidence of any effect on systems or data outside Mixpanel’s environment, we continue to monitor closely for any signs of misuse,” OpenAI said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This was not a breach of OpenAI’s systems. No chat, API requests, API usage data, passwords, credentials, API keys, payment details, or government IDs were compromised or exposed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-should-customers-react"&gt;How should customers react?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are three levels of concern here: which OpenAI API customers are affected, how attackers might use stolen data if they are, and the possibility, however hypothetical, that more valuable data such as API keys or account credentials could be at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the first issue, as noted above, both companies have said they have contacted customers caught up in the breach without specifying how many users are affected. OpenAI has set up an email address customers can use if they have further questions: mixpanelincident@openai.com. Mixpanel has set up an equivalent contact address: support@mixpanel.com⁠.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, if &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567531/the-biggest-data-breach-fines-penalties-and-settlements-so-far.html"&gt;decades of data breaches&lt;/a&gt; have taught the world anything it’s that companies don’t always know the full extent of a data breach even when they say they do. For that reason, it would be wise for OpenAI customers who have not been contacted to conduct the same security review as those that have.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI said that customers should be on their guard for phishing attacks targeting breached email addresses and to check that messages that appear to be sent from OpenAI’s domain are genuine. They should also turn on multi-factor authentication (MFA).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If phishing sounds generic, in the context of an API connection the dangers are more specific and include more nuanced fake alerts for things like billing, quota messages, and suspicious logins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to OpenAI, there is no need for customers to rotate or reset account credentials or API keys, which attackers could use to steal data or consume services. Despite this, cautious developers are likely to ignore this and rotate and reset credentials because this removes the risk. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several organizations involved in API and AI security have offered more detailed breakdowns of recommendations in the light of the OpenAI-Mixpanel incident, including &lt;a href="https://www.ox.security/blog/openai-mixpanel-3rd-party-data-breach/"&gt;Ox Security&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://dev.to/alifar/the-openai-mixpanel-security-incident-explained-2ok5"&gt;Dev Community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="downstream-attack-surface"&gt;Downstream attack surface&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI uses external analytics platforms such as Mixpanel to track how customers interact with models through the API. This includes which models a customer selects plus basic metadata such as location and email ID listed above. It does not track the user ‘payload’, that is chatbot queries and responses being sent to the model from a browser, which are encrypted.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest incident underlines that the security of the primary platform is only one part of the risk: secondary platforms and partners are a backdoor that can expose even careful organizations, as some Salesforce customers have seen with &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4046407/attackers-steal-data-from-salesforce-instances-via-compromised-ai-live-chat-tool.html"&gt;data breaches at its partner Salesloft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack surface exposed by AI platforms is bigger than it looks, a security and governance challenge enterprises should assess before jumping in with both feet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4097479/openai-admits-data-breach-after-analytics-partner-hit-by-phishing-attack.html"&gt;Infoworld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097488/openai-admits-data-breach-after-analytics-partner-hit-by-phishing-attack-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-785)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-786)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-787)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-788)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
