<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 23:22:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International takedown of cryptocurrency fraud network laundering over EUR 700 million</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</link>
      <description>The final actions in a sweeping international operation have successfully dismantled a large-scale cryptocurrency fraud and money laundering network that had laundered over EUR 700 million. Coordinated across multiple jurisdictions, these actions, carried out last month and earlier this week, mark the culmination of years of investigation and the effective disruption of a criminal operation that spanned Europe and beyond.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/international-takedown-of-cryptocurrency-fraud-network-laundering-over-eur-700-million</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-817)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-817</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-817</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-818)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-818</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-818</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-819)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-819</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-820)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-820</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – December 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-822)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-december-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-822</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to create a ransomware playbook that works</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106753/how-to-create-a-ransomware-playbook-that-works.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563507/what-is-ransomware-how-it-works-and-how-to-remove-it.html"&gt;Ransomware&lt;/a&gt; attacks continue to plague organizations, and they’re getting ever more sophisticated via tactics such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3825545/5-things-to-know-about-ransomware-threats-in-2025.html"&gt;double- and multi-extortion&lt;/a&gt; and the use of artificial intelligence to create more refined attacks, and the growth of the ransomware-as-a-service model.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs and CSOs need to make it a priority to create a playbook for their organizations to better defend against such attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s clear that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3842496/the-state-of-ransomware-fragmented-but-still-potent-despite-takedowns.html"&gt;ransomware remains a big cybersecurity threat&lt;/a&gt;. Security firm CrowdStrike, in its new State of Ransomware Survey, notes that ransomware readiness is lagging as cyber criminals “use AI across the attack chain to accelerate intrusion, encryption, and extortion.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report, based on a global survey of 1,100 IT and cybersecurity decision-makers, shows that 76% of organizations are struggling to match the speed and sophistication of AI-assisted attacks. About half of the respondents cite &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4075912/ai-enabled-ransomware-attacks-cisos-top-security-concern-with-good-reason.html"&gt;AI-enabled attack chains as today’s greatest ransomware threat&lt;/a&gt;, and 85% say traditional detection is becoming obsolete against AI-enhanced attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When it comes to ransomware, most companies are still treating it like a distant threat until it hits. Then it’s chaos,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/trevorhorwitz/"&gt;Trevor Horwitz&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at security company TrustNet. “A good ransomware playbook isn’t just documentation. It’s muscle memory. You have to train like you fight.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are some key elements to consider for an effective ransomware approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="planning-and-tabletops-preparedness-begins-with-practice"&gt;Planning and tabletops: Preparedness begins with practice&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Any organization that doesn’t have a cohesive plan in place for how to handle ransomware threats is asking for trouble. Planning an overall strategy — encompassing tools, processes, and people — is vital for maintaining business continuity and minimizing financial losses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without a plan in place, enterprises risk launching a disorganized and ineffective response to attacks, which can result in lost data, significant systems downtime, compliance issues, and damaged brand or reputation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A key component of the planning process is to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2144047/mastering-the-tabletop-exercise-3-cyberattack-scenarios-and-how-to-plan-a-robust-response.html"&gt;conduct cybersecurity tabletop exercises&lt;/a&gt; to simulate how teams would conduct themselves &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069236/corporate-executives-exposed-to-cyber-attacks-talk-about-the-pitfalls-of-response-measures.html"&gt;during an actual ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt;. This enables organizations to test and improve their &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829684/how-to-create-an-effective-incident-response-plan.html"&gt;incident response plan&lt;/a&gt; in a no-risk environment, with a focus on decision-making, communication, and establishing clear-cut roles.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Tabletop exercises are where everything starts,” Horwitz says. “If your executive team hasn’t sat in a room and worked through a simulated ransomware attack, start there. You don’t want to be figuring out who has the authority to pay a ransom or issue a public statement in the middle of an actual breach. You want to know how fast legal, IT, and [communications] can work together. The pressure is intense, and the decisions come fast. So the playbook should guide those decisions, not just sit on a shelf.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4006349/operation-999-ransomware-tabletop-tests-cyber-execs-response.html"&gt;These exercises&lt;/a&gt; enable enterprises to “create and maintain a ransomware-specific incident response playbook that defines roles, containment processes, forensic collection procedures, and communications templates,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnotte/"&gt;John Otte&lt;/a&gt;, senior security consultant at technology consulting firm Resultant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Perform realistic tabletop exercises with legal, communications, IT, and executive stakeholders, at a minimum annually, to test decision-making,” Otte says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570871/tabletop-exercises-explained-definition-examples-and-objectives.html"&gt;Tabletop exercises&lt;/a&gt; need to simulate real business disruption scenarios, not just technical failures, says &lt;a href="https://www.iansresearch.com/our-faculty/faculty/detail/george-gerchow"&gt;George Gerchow&lt;/a&gt;, CSO at security firm Bedrock Data and faculty member at IANS Research, a research and advisory firm. “Effective ransomware preparedness begins with practice, not panic,” he says. “The most valuable sessions include leaders from operations, legal, finance, HR, and communications, because these teams face the toughest decisions under pressure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Staffing, skills, and training&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many organizations continue to find that cybersecurity experts are in short supply, so staffing up teams is a challenge. That can be problematic for a ransomware strategy. Companies need to have a variety of skills in place, including expertise in incident detection and prevention, incident response, firewall configuration, and other areas.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They also need to be equipped to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;train all employees&lt;/a&gt; in how to help prevent ransomware attacks. This includes teaching them how to recognize, deal with, and report threats such as phishing emails, suspicious links, and questionable attachments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“On the staffing side, you &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3846318/6-hard-earned-tips-for-leading-through-a-cyberattack-from-csos-whove-been-there.html"&gt;need people who know what they’re doing&lt;/a&gt;,” Horwitz says. “Not just cybersecurity folks, but people across legal, PR, and leadership. And not just headcount. You need readiness. A named incident commander. Someone with forensic skills. Someone who understands business risk and knows when to escalate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations often invest in tools before investing in people, and that’s backwards, Gerchow says. “Resilience relies on cross-functional preparedness, where employees understand not just what to do but why it matters,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises need to hold role-appropriate security training for users, including business leaders, IT teams, finance, etc., on realistic threats such as social engineering and malicious attachments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Business leaders should encourage ongoing training that connects cybersecurity risk to business continuity and reputation, Gerchow says. “It’s about building a culture where everyone, from the help desk to the boardroom, understands their role in maintaining operational integrity,” he says. “Regular awareness programs, role-specific response drills, and executive briefings help translate technical risks into business terms.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="prevention-steps"&gt;Prevention steps&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises can invest in a range of technology solutions for both protection against ransomware attacks and remediation following an incident. Ransomware prevention requires a layered approach that includes regular software updates and patching, effective data and systems backups, and other cybersecurity tools such as firewalls, multi-factor authentication (MFA), and antivirus software.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3520881/patch-management-a-dull-it-pain-that-wont-go-away.html"&gt;Patch management&lt;/a&gt; and vulnerability remediation are vitally important elements of ransomware defense, because ransomware attackers oftentimes exploit security flaws — &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074945/network-security-devices-endanger-orgs-with-90s-era-flaws.html"&gt;increasingly in security devices themselves&lt;/a&gt;. By addressing both of these areas, companies can proactively defend against ransomware threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Maintain a prioritized and trackable patching program that keeps exploitable exposure to a minimum,” Otte says. “Couple automated deployment of patches with human verification of high-risk systems, and regularly run scans to identify drift or skipped patches.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/568045/what-is-edr-endpoint-detection-and-response.html"&gt;Endpoint detection and response (EDR)&lt;/a&gt;, antivirus (AV) software, email security and phishing defenses, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4031659/windows-tips-for-reducing-the-ransomware-threat.html"&gt;identity and access management/MFA&lt;/a&gt; are also important pieces of any ransomware strategy, Otte says. “Use a modern EDR that contains behavior-based detection, rollback, and isolation capabilities rather than relying solely on signature AV,” he advises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the main ways ransomware attackers carry out their missions is via email. “From an IT security standpoint, the No. 1 attack vector is an email system,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/russbernst/"&gt;Russ Ernst&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at Blancco, a provider of data erasure and mobile lifecycle diagnostics products. “Email security best practices must be implemented across the entire organization.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Email security can include advanced phishing filters to prevent common ransomware delivery mechanisms, Otte says. Sophisticated access management can help minimize threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Implement MFA anywhere you can, particularly for privileged accounts and remote access, and implement least-privilege principles to restrict opportunities to move laterally by attackers,” Otte says. “Keep admin credentials secured within a centrally managed secrets store, regularly rotate them, and don’t have shared local admin accounts. Insist on MFA before any privilege elevation. Track anomalous credential usage and apply detection against brute-force or lateral movement that employs privileged credentials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="recovery-and-remediation"&gt;Recovery and remediation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If a company experiences a ransomware attack, it needs to go into recovery and remediation mode as quickly as possible to minimize the damage. This includes recovering systems and data as well as repairing any damage affecting employees, customers, and the corporate brand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Create comprehensive recovery playbooks with system restore sequence prioritized and public communications strategies that target customers, regulators, and law enforcement,” Otte says. “Engage legal counsel, cyber insurance points of contact, and forensic responders in advance to make informed, timely, and notification requirement-appropriate determinations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When a ransomware attack happens, “the remediation needs to be fast but precise,” Horwitz says. “You have to isolate systems immediately. Stop the spread. Kill off the malware’s communication paths. Bring in forensics to figure out how they got in. Because if you don’t understand the entry point, restoring from backup might just reintroduce the threat.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises need to verify their backups before using them, Horwitz says. “I’ve seen companies restore clean-looking data only to discover the malware had been sitting dormant for weeks,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They also need to ensure regular backup processes are in place, Ernst says. “It is important to regularly back up data and also to test these backups regularly,” he says. “Data that is regularly backed up in an offline environment will not be affected by a direct ransomware attack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Access to this stored data should help minimize downtime, Ernst says. “Backups also help you rebuild infrastructure if you choose to pay the ransom and get encryption keys — only to find your data has been corrupted and made unusable. If the organization understands how long it takes to rebuild from a backup, then it can infer the estimated downtime from a ransomware attack,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations that might consider negotiating with ransomware gangs on ransom payments should also &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3568817/the-ransomware-negotiation-playbook-adds-new-chapters.html"&gt;keep on top of the latest advice and tactics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The recovery process is not just technical, Horwitz says, but also reputational. “If customer trust is shaken, you have to rebuild that fast,” he says. “That means communicating clearly, owning what happened, and explaining what’s being done. Law enforcement has to be notified. Regulators too. And the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4002175/8-things-cisos-have-learnt-from-cyber-incidents.html"&gt;lessons from that attack&lt;/a&gt; need to go right back into the playbook. What worked? What didn’t? Where did the team freeze up? That feedback loop is what strengthens your program.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Having an effective internal and external ransomware communications plan is vital. “A ransomware attack communications strategy should be part of an organization’s general company playbook related to security breaches,” Ernst says. “It should spell out who must be informed — employees, customers, investors, other stakeholders — as well as how and when, what any communications will say, and who will do the communicating.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106753/how-to-create-a-ransomware-playbook-that-works.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-823)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-823</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-824)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-824</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-825)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-825</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-826)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-826</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordinated strike hits violent criminal network behind large-scale illegal gambling and money laundering in Sweden</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</link>
      <description>A coordinated law enforcement operation carried out in Sweden and Spain between 28 and 29 November targeted a violent criminal network operating in the Stockholm area. The group is believed to run extensive illegal gambling operations and launder significant criminal proceeds, both for its own benefit and for other criminal actors. The network is also linked to drug trafficking in Sweden and across the Nordic region, reinforcing its presence in local and regional criminal markets.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/coordinated-strike-hits-violent-criminal-network-behind-large-scale-illegal-gambling-and-money-laundering-in-sweden</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data breaches: guidance for individuals and families</title>
      <link>https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/guidance/data-breaches</link>
      <description>How to protect yourself from the impact of data breaches</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/guidance/data-breaches</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mistold story of a software failure that grounded 6,000 jets</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106566/the-mistold-story-of-a-software-failure-that-grounded-6000-jets.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You should fly.  It’s safer.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s a fact. The odds are in your favor when compared to auto travel.  It’s not even close, we often remind the flight-fearing traveler.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yet two of the smartest people I have known refuse to fly despite agreeing with this statistic. I think of them every time I board a flight.  It was no different when I returned from vacation on a JetBlue flight that retraced some of the northbound path taken by a JetBlue flight some weeks earlier.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The flight in question was likely also filled with vacationers, an Airbus A320 journeying from Cancún International Airport in Mexico to Newark Liberty International Airport on October 30, 2025. As &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/31/travel/jetblue-flight-cancun.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reported the next day in the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, passengers aboard Flight 1230 were likely dozing off two and a half hours into the flight from the Mexican resort when they were jolted to attention by a sudden drop in altitude. When the unwanted acrobatic maneuver was over, 15 or more passengers involuntarily extended their vacations at hospitals in Tampa, where the JetBlue pilots managed a successful emergency landing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JetBlue representatives said the plane was taken out of service for inspection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are occasional commercial aviation mishaps, along with the rare disaster. For the flying public, reports of these mishaps are regular enough that a news story like this one can be safely tucked away until a broader pattern emerges. Understandably, had that been the end of the story, especially considering that it’s been Boeing planes subject to unwanted excitement of this variety since the 737 Max woes began. The plane involved in this JetBlue flight, as well as the one where I now occupied seat 23A, was an Airbus, thought to be less subject to what an FAA Expert Panel Report in February 2024 called “gaps in Boeing’s safety journey.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; plane, I thought to myself. What did the ensuing investigation uncover? Mechanical failure?  Software, perhaps even malware (though very unlikely)?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The “cause”&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Times dutifully &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/28/business/airbus-software-a320-jets.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reported the results&lt;/a&gt; of that investigation in a story they ran on November 28, 2025, the same day of my return flight to JFK. The story, adapted in part from an &lt;a href="https://www.airbus.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-11-airbus-update-on-a320-family-precautionary-fleet-action" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Airbus press release&lt;/a&gt;, opened with:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The European airplane maker said a recent incident had shown that “intense solar radiation may corrupt data critical to the functioning of flight controls.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The impact on the Airbus A320 fleet and the airlines that have deployed them would be widespread.  Potentially, 6,000 planes could be affected, with some requiring hardware changes, The Times reported after studying the extent to which the A320 has been chosen by airlines worldwide. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s a major impact, I thought. And then I read,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In most cases, the issue can be addressed relatively quickly by reverting to a previous software version.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hold on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Single event upset”&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, how often is this radiation impact occurring?  What’s the underlying physics? &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It turns out that there’s a history of science story to be told.  Nobel Prize winner Victor Hess discovered the existence of cosmic rays by measuring radiation levels at higher altitudes during balloon flights. That was before World War I. By the 1960s, it was a concern for crew health in the space program. A 1975 paper identified a satellite anomaly as a “single-event upset” (SEU) caused by radiation, and by 1979, it was understood that electronics could be disrupted at sea level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By 1990, the FAA acknowledged that there was a risk to air travelers. The Airbus A320, a fly-by-wire aircraft with greater reliance on computers, was designed during a time when this phenomenon was well understood in the aeronautical engineering community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As software engineers at the time would have understood, addressing SEUs would require hardware and software features. ECC memory, for instance.  Sanity checks, too, in case a flipped bit would produce wildly out-of-range instructions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Features.  So why would rolling back to an earlier version of software be the remedy for the A320 late in 2025?  Wouldn’t features to address SEU from radiation in the current release also be present in earlier releases?  Or perhaps was there some new, innovative way to address SEU that would supersede the approaches taken in earlier releases?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Software life cycle management fundamentals&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At this point, the software quality engineer in me perked up. Somehow, the entire radiation part of the story seemed curiously irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I was not to be the only one asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tony Fernandez is the founder of AirAsia Aviation Group. AirAsia’s current operations include a significant number of Airbus jets, and it has orders for almost 400 more Airbus aircraft. Fernandez expressed his concerns in a recent interview.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It seems a bit bizarre; it is something it [Airbus] has to look at, it’s obvious it wasn’t tested,” Fernandez &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3334876/airasia-boss-says-bizarre-airbus-software-glitch-good-warning-sector?module=perpetual_scroll_0&amp;amp;pgtype=article" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;told South China Morning Post&lt;/a&gt;. Fernandez speculated that Airbus might be stressed by commitments to meet its current goal of producing 820 planes in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Apart from the eye-catching radiation storyline, the surface cause was described as a problem in the Elevator Aileron Computer (ELAC 2) software, which manages the aircraft’s pitch and roll by sending commands from the pilot’s side-stick to elevators at its rear. The software rollback involved restoring a version dubbed “L103,” replacing “L104.” Thales, developer of the ELAC hardware, told Reuters that the software involved was not its responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The sudden nose-down movement experienced by the JetBlue passengers bound for Newark could also affect a wide variety of Airbus models, not only the A320:  multiple variations of the A319 and A321 series are also affected. &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2025/11/28/airbus-issues-major-a320-recall-after-flight-control-incident" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;One estimate&lt;/a&gt; speculated that more than 3,000 A320 jets were in the air around the time of the Airbus announcement. Picture those passengers on November 28, many equipped with WiFi on board, reading about this software vulnerability and mentally reworking their safety calculations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;4 SDLC lessons. 2 inherent risks unbowed&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond sensationalized “solar radiation” or “cosmic ray” talk, there’s a serious software development life cycle (SDLC) conversation to be had at Airbus. I’d list these four main takeaways, all of them familiar:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test engineering&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;CI/CD and pipeline quality&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Observability&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Supply chain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Notice that “coding” is not one of the takeaways. True, the L104 might have introduced a build packaging mistake, or a coding error, such as an accidentally deleted call to a service, misconfigured or misunderstood API parameters, or even a syntax error in the source code. These are all normal; a healthy SDLC addresses them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test engineering.&lt;/strong&gt; A good test harness could simulate the out-of-band telemetry that was supposed to invoke the range checks for ELAC.  Test harnesses need to be designed and built concurrently with software, not as a separate stage.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CI/CD and pipeline quality.&lt;/strong&gt; You can add Change or Configuration Management to this group. Whether or not Airbus used CI/CD in its SDLC pipeline in L104, it will be moving in that direction. Something broke in the SDLC pipeline, which allowed this fundamental feature to “regress.”  The cause is unlikely to be a one-off.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observability.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m adding this one partly because I’m part of a small working group at IEEE working on a new version of the &lt;a href="https://standards.ieee.org/ieee/2675.2/11839/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DevOps standard&lt;/a&gt; that will incorporate observability principles. The SEU is an excellent use case for observability because a test engineer can’t wait for a cosmic ray to strike, yet must ensure that a failure to respond to a critical SEU event can be observed. This involves more careful requirements engineering and understanding of the telemetry needed for critical features.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supply chain.&lt;/strong&gt; While Thales may not have been involved in the problematic release of L104, the Airbus platform includes software and hardware from many suppliers. Integration across the computing supply chain presents challenges magnified by both the safety requirements and the desired product longevity. The apparent “Not our problem” response from Thales could indicate issues with joint information and problem-solving, or even limited visibility for the third-party risk management team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It could get worse, a lot worse. Lapses in any one of these four areas of the SDLC create opportunities for malware, a nightmare scenario for avionics.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AI to the rescue?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I worry that two inherent risks remain largely unmitigated: &lt;em&gt;complexity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;specialization&lt;/em&gt;. Managing the entire A320 feature set, or even its software bill of materials (SBOM / API-BOM), is a nontrivial undertaking. Consider that it is a product launched in 1987 with the need to support legacy hardware and software across a large installed base.  Both complexity and specialization will march steadily toward greater opacity, challenging attempts at traceability, transparency and manageability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No doubt Airbus, like the rest of us, will bring AI on board to help out — perhaps in L105. This will add both to the specialties needed and to the plane’s overall complexity.  Considering public trepidation over AI generally, at what point will more travelers feel the odds are no longer in their favor?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106566/the-mistold-story-of-a-software-failure-that-grounded-6000-jets.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-827)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-827</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-828)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-828</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-829)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-829</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rapidly evolving criminal ecosystem: the escalating exploitation of vulnerable individuals</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</link>
      <description>Migrant smugglers and human traffickers are exploiting today’s geopolitical instability and economic pressures with unprecedented agility. Their business models continue to evolve at high speed, allowing criminals to recruit, transport and exploit vulnerable individuals while maximising profits. As a result, the EU faces a constantly shifting and increasingly digital criminal landscape. Both crime areas have undergone significant transformation in recent years, fuelled in particular by the rapid expansion of online tools for recruitment, advertising and exploitation. These and other latest trends are outlined in the 2025 Europol’s European Migrant Smuggling Centre yearly activity overview, published today.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/rapidly-evolving-criminal-ecosystem-escalating-exploitation-of-vulnerable-individuals</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying risk in AI</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106574/demystifying-risk-in-ai.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Given the facts about the importance of Artificial Intelligence, for several months, I have been delving into this topic, but with caution, seeking to understand the key point of how we can protect applications based on Gen AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are living in times when AI has been the central theme in all areas that can provide benefits to organizations and end users. In addition to adding benefits to protection and anticipation in detecting cyber threats, whether with threat intelligence, incident response and EDR, SOAR solutions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the question we must ask is how much we are looking at the risks of this emerging technology. As AI gains traction through the use of solutions like ChatGPT, Claude.ai, Meta.ai, Copilot, Gemini, Grok, among other SaaS-based solutions, it is a fact that AI is invading and taking over our routine. Those who do not adapt to this technology may be considered a piece off the board.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s to record meetings and create automated summaries with Hynote.ai, or to prepare a Cyber Risk Management plan, we really have to recognize the speed and agility that AI provides to daily tasks. We already see that in some companies, where an employee decides to change jobs, the position may no longer be replaced, and the organization considers conducting studies evaluating the feasibility of replacing certain tasks with AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-importance-of-understanding-the-risks-behind-ai"&gt;The importance of understanding the risks behind AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here comes a point of concern that perhaps some professionals are not noticing. Are we being dominated by AI? Perhaps the answer may be “Yes,” “No” or “Maybe.” However, it will depend on the degree of visibility we have of this technology; the reality is that there is a danger behind it, and so our job is to know how to prepare to remediate such risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Should we presume where we should fit professionally and how we should prepare to maintain our employability? Given that risks of hallucinations are still feasible and occur in AI solutions, the answer to a given question may not be accurate, as the existing methods behind diffusion models used in AI training utilize code generation techniques such as “transformers” in LLMs used by most AI tools like ChatGPT, Gemini and Claude. For now, they still have limitations to validate a certain piece of data before providing the answer to the question that was entered by the requester (end user, API, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This means and indicates that it is still necessary to consider the human factor to evaluate certain responses before providing a decision that may involve relevant decision-making in the corporate and human context, such as the result of an analysis of a medical diagnosis still requires an evaluation by a specialist, or in the case of a quantitative risk assessment of a critical system. In fact, it is a point to think about!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another important question to be asked is “how far should we limit and trust an AI solution?” Certainly, as mentioned above, many results can be positive, but remembering that every organization should think and maintain caution with privacy, bias, fairness and transparency risks through the data provided, among other points, which have raised the attention of information security professionals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Basically, the execution process of an AI model is composed of 3 phases:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data that is inserted in a request.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;This data is evaluated by a training model that involves an entire architecture.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The result of the information that will be delivered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From an information security point of view. That is the point that we, information security professionals, must judge in the scope of evaluation from the perspective of data security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the market, there are already frameworks such as &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework"&gt;NIST RMF AI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://safety.google/cybersecurity-advancements/saif/"&gt;SAIF Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/42001"&gt;ISO 42001,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/blog/2025/07/10/introducing-the-csa-ai-controls-matrix-a-comprehensive-framework-for-trustworthy-ai"&gt;AI Control Matrix (AICM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/artifacts/ai-model-risk-management-framework"&gt;AI Model Risk Management Framework&lt;/a&gt; from Cloud Security Alliance (CSA), in addition to &lt;a href="https://atlas.mitre.org/"&gt;MITRE ATLAS&lt;/a&gt; for the Threat Intelligence line and &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-project-top-10-for-large-language-model-applications/"&gt;OWASP Top 10 LLMs&lt;/a&gt; for security in AI application development, which presents the main known vulnerabilities in the AI/ML field, which I intend to explore in another article.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have particularly been studying NIST RMF AI and the AI Model Risk Management Framework from CSA, and in my view, they are effective in helping to map and add AI/ML solutions to the scope of the organization’s Cyber Risk Management program. These frameworks help to understand and map the AI applications used, address risks, impacts and damages that can occur with the use of this technology in the corporate context.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="about-the-use-of-nist-ai-rmf-and-ai-control-matrix-aicm-frameworks"&gt;About the use of NIST AI RMF and AI Control Matrix (AICM) Frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making an agenda about the most popular frameworks, NIST AI RMF 1.0 focuses on looking at the group of people, organization and the ecosystem involved. In which they are divided into phases of&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Govern (cultivates a risk culture)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Map (context of identified risk and asset classification)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Measure (identifies, assesses and mitigates risk)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Manage (risks are prioritized according to impact)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This model allows integration with &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework"&gt;NIST CSF&lt;/a&gt; for the lens of cybersecurity controls. The most interesting thing about this is that the framework is free.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another model that I cannot fail to mention is the AI Control Matrix (AICM), which contains 243 control objectives divided into 18 security domains and allows evaluating all security pillars of an AI solution, specifically in a cloud environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/artifacts/ai-controls-matrix"&gt;AICM&lt;/a&gt; is integrated with AI-CAIQ, which covers frameworks including BSI AIC4 Catalog, NIST AI RMF and ISO 42001. Any robust AI solution needs large processing and energy, which can only be found in data centers. For this reason, we have seen large investments by big techs in the expansion of new data centers in all regions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Therefore, deeply understanding cloud concepts and shared responsibilities is fundamental to implement an AI solution with precision, securely and that satisfies the business, leveraging the organization’s capacity against competition.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, I have been doing some research on GenAI and especially studying these frameworks. In view of this, characterizing and visualizing the great challenge for us, cybersecurity professionals, is to establish the relevance of the connection between the teams involved in an AI project. Therefore, the connection is a priority for the project’s success and, therefore, we should not neglect the involvement of the areas of governance, cyber risk, ethics, regulatory and compliance, cybersecurity, data scientists, AI and ML developers, human Resources and infrastructure and IT operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cybersecurity-professionals-need-to-be-trained"&gt;Cybersecurity professionals need to be trained&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another great challenge, which I emphasize, is that cybersecurity professionals need to be trained in this AI/ML technology, understanding the technical aspects of architecture, training models used, techniques such as &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/use-cases/retrieval-augmented-generation?hl=en"&gt;RAG (retrieval-augmented generation)&lt;/a&gt; that propose improvements in the model, and the application of the cybersecurity strategy to be judged. The eyes of the CISO and the cybersecurity team and other fronts involved must look at the importance of controls within these areas:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Model&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Application&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Assurance&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="looking-at-the-shared-responsibility-perspective-in-cloud"&gt;Looking at the shared responsibility perspective in cloud&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another factor to be considered in scope: I reinforce the &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/framework/security/shared-responsibility-shared-fate"&gt;shared responsibility&lt;/a&gt; of AI applications in a cloud environment. The security principles of GenAI models and respective applications must consider how the AI application model will run.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here, I highlight some crucial points to establish &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/security/fundamentals/shared-responsibility"&gt;shared responsibilities&lt;/a&gt; in the cloud:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GenAI as an application (Public, SaaS)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;GenAI as a platform (IaaS or PaaS)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Build your own AI application (IaaS, on premises).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this model, with the help of the frameworks mentioned above, it will be possible to map, order and manage risks in the AI strategy adopted regarding access control for data and training models, data management and training, prompt controls, model development, model inference, model monitoring and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="thinking-outside-the-box"&gt;Thinking outside the box&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, the key point I wish to awaken readers in this article is to lead them to think about how we cybersecurity professionals are observing the risks and impacts in our environment, and how to prepare to evaluate such GenAI solutions in our realistic world.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have particularly been exploring some of these known models in a cloud environment (SaaS), but I have been having a lot of fun with the Anthropic solution (claude.ai). In this model, it is possible to build robust solutions with code; you just have to be creative. As an example, I requested that it create a complete Cyber Risk Management (GRC) solution and suggested comparing it with some solutions on the market and meet best practices such as PCI-DSS, NIST, CRI, ISO 27001, etc. So that the solution created the entire back-end, only missing the front-end creation. A project that could take months can be reduced to a few months or weeks, depending on the investment and effort of the workforce involved.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="certifications-that-can-add-value-to-a-career"&gt;Certifications that can add value to a career&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, as I had the opportunity to participate as a contributor to the review program for the Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) recently launched new certification, &lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/education/taise"&gt;Trusted AI Safety Expert (TAISE)&lt;/a&gt;. I definitely recommend it for those who are interested in understanding and exploring the architecture and main protection mechanisms in AI/ML solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, taking into account other certifications in this area, I have also been exploring and recommending &lt;a href="https://www.isaca.org/credentialing/aaism?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;amp;utm_campaign=aaism&amp;amp;utm_term=cert_na_acq_branded_ext&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gad_campaignid=22940868601&amp;amp;gbraid=0AAAAAD_A9K9wACMjWJDefWgA6HQuljaVc"&gt;ISACA’s AAISM&lt;/a&gt; certification material, which in turn is very interesting from the point of view of risk governance and security in AI/ML. Nevertheless, &lt;a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/education/taise"&gt;TAISE&lt;/a&gt; brings a more comprehensive root in the technical scope that also incorporates risk management and governance in cloud environments, which is the real world. AI needs large processing and the ideal environment to run is the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, both complement each other and it is up to the professional to evaluate the best alternative and direction to follow. As the wise proverb says: “Do not abandon wisdom and knowledge, and it will guard you; love it, and it will protect you.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4106574/demystifying-risk-in-ai.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-830)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-830</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreePBX security advisory (AV25–831)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/freepbx-security-advisory-av25-831</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian APT group pivots to network edge device misconfigurations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107406/russian-apt-group-pivots-to-network-edge-device-misconfigurations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A Russian state-sponsored cyberespionage group has been targeting energy companies and critical infrastructure providers by exploiting misconfigurations in network-edge devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group has been operating since at least 2021 and has exploited device misconfigurations before but also known vulnerabilities such as CVE-2022-26318 in WatchGuard Firebox and XTM appliances, CVE-2021-26084 and CVE-2023-22518 in Confluence or CVE-2023-2753 in Veeam Backup.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/amazon-threat-intelligence-identifies-russian-cyber-threat-group-targeting-western-critical-infrastructure/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to&lt;/a&gt; telemetry collected by Amazon Threat Intelligence, the group has heavily focused on targeting misconfigurations this year, pivoting away from zero-day or N-day vulnerabilities. The main targets have been enterprise routers and routing infrastructure, VPN concentrators and remote access gateways, network management appliances, collaboration and wiki platforms and cloud-based project management systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This tactical adaptation enables the same operational outcomes, credential harvesting, and lateral movement into victim organizations’ online services and infrastructure, while reducing the actor’s exposure and resource expenditure,” the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="links-to-sandworm-and-curly-comrades"&gt;Links to Sandworm and Curly COMrades&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Amazon’s telemetry, the group’s infrastructure has overlaps with Sandworm, a group also known as APT44 and Seashell Blizzard that’s associated with Russia’s military intelligence agency, the GRU. There are also overlaps with a group whose activity was documented in the past by security firm Bitdefender, under the name &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4085272/russian-apt-abuses-windows-hyper-v-for-persistence-and-malware-execution.html" target="_blank"&gt;Curly COMrades&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, these could be subgroups within the GRU that work together, with the one tracked by Amazon handling initial access and lateral movement and Curly COMrades handling the host persistence through its CurlyShell and CurlCat custom malware implants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Amazon detected attacks against customer network edge appliances hosted on AWS EC2 instances with actor-controlled IP addresses achieving persistent connections that indicate interactive access to the compromised devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="credential-harvesting"&gt;Credential harvesting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers also observed credential replay attacks against victims’ other online services using stolen domain credentials following network edge device compromises. This indicates that the attackers are likely harvesting credentials by leveraging the traffic capturing and analysis capabilities of the compromised devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Time gap between device compromise and authentication attempts against victim services suggests passive collection rather than active credential theft,” the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Network traffic interception is consistent with Sandworm’s known tradecraft and the targeting of network edge devices specifically positions the attackers to intercept credentials in transit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-critical-infrastructure-providers-can-defend-against-this-threat"&gt;How critical infrastructure providers can defend against this threat&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group has a strong focus on the energy sector, with victims including electric utility companies, energy providers and even MSSPs with energy sector clients. However, it has also targeted technology and service cloud providers, as well as telecommunications companies across multiple regions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Amazon Threat Intelligence team advises organizations to audit their network edge devices for packet capture files or utilities that shouldn’t be present, to review their device configurations and isolate management interfaces, and implement multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies should also review authentication logs and monitor authentication attempts from unexpected geographic locations. Anomaly detection for authentication patterns should be implemented for all online services and the use of plain text protocols that could expose credentials in transit should be audited.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Amazon report includes indicators of compromise associated with this attack campaign as well as security recommendations specific to AWS environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107406/russian-apt-group-pivots-to-network-edge-device-misconfigurations.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The devil of proposed SEC AI disclosure rule is in the details</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107317/the-devil-of-proposed-sec-ai-disclosure-rule-is-in-the-details.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A US Securities and Exchange Commission committee has recommended a new rule that would mandate companies to analyze and report all AI efforts — including decisions to &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;use AI for some purposes. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attorneys who have studied the proposal note that the AI rule — just like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1247504/how-us-sec-legal-actions-put-cisos-at-risk-and-what-to-do-about-it.html"&gt;the SEC’s cybersecurity rule&lt;/a&gt; from about two years ago — won’t technically require anything to be reported that wouldn’t have already required reporting. The new rule refers only to material AI efforts and ever since the creation of the SEC some 90 years ago, anything material has always required disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But they theorize that the SEC committee believes that many public-company boards and their senior executives don’t fully understand the scope and potential impact of their various AI efforts. The new rule would force those executives to create committees and to formally review all AI decisions, potentially unearthing material issues that would otherwise not have occurred to those executives. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, argues that this extra focus could make a significant difference for many enterprises. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It will help focus people. It puts it in front of everyone who needs to be thinking about AI,” Levine said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As for requiring companies to examine and disclose where they are either &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;using or where they might be underinvesting compared to rivals, Levine said that could help executives understand “that there is a risk that our implementation of AI may not keep up with stakeholders and competitors.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/files/sec-iac-artificial-intelligence-recommendation-111825.pdf"&gt;proposed rule&lt;/a&gt; comes from the SEC Investor Advisory Committee (IAC) and was discussed during the Dec. 4 IAC meeting. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="companies-can-write-their-own-definitions-of-ai"&gt;Companies can write their own definitions of AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another controversial aspect of the proposed rule is that it fails to define AI, instead instructing companies to write their own definitions. Some legal experts have suggested that the committee didn’t literally want companies to evaluate all uses of AI, given that the technology dates back to the 1950s and exists in some form in just about every piece of software that businesses use. They more likely intended for such evaluations to focus on relatively recent AI popularizations, especially generative AI and agentic AI. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Under the proposed rule, companies would “self-define what they mean by artificial intelligence and then rely on that definition throughout its disclosures in describing AI-related risks, their AI deployment strategy if any and capital expenses and R&amp;amp;D expenditures related to the implementation and deployment of AI, amongst other material information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jnylaw.com/our-staff/monica-j-washington-rothbaum/"&gt;Monica Washington Rothbaum&lt;/a&gt;, a senior attorney with J&amp;amp;Y Law, said that it would be “risky for a company to define AI differently” because it makes “apple to apple” investor comparisons difficult if not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Requiring companies to disclose AI-related risks is a smart move. But letting each company define AI however they see fit is a loophole waiting to be exploited. Without a consistent baseline, you risk turning disclosures into PR spin rather than meaningful accountability,” Rothbaum said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Rothbaum does find value in forcing companies to disclose where management has opted to not use AI or to use it less than they might have otherwise. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Under-disclosing material risks like reliance on flawed AI models can expose companies to liability when things go wrong. Failing to invest in AI responsibly could also lead to competitive disadvantages that shareholders deserve to know about,” Rothbaum said. “This isn’t theoretical. AI is already shaping the way we look at hiring, customer service, and security. These are core operations that can affect a company’s value. If you can’t clearly explain how your AI decisions are made and who’s accountable for making them, then you’re already behind. Transparency like that has to be the cost of doing business today.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://kennyhertzperry.com/attorneys/braden-perry"&gt;Braden Perry&lt;/a&gt;, a litigation, regulatory, and government investigations attorney with law firm Kennyhertz Perry, is not a fan of the proposed rule because he sees it unlikely to help investors make decisions. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked the probability that such a rule would deliver useful information to investors and potential investors, Perry said, “None. In terms of an overall understanding from a shareholder, there will likely be zero usable information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="will-filing-reveal-anything-useful"&gt;Will filing reveal anything useful?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This concern is partly based on the many SEC cybersecurity filings that have used boilerplate language — and use SEC exemptions to reveal nothing specific.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Perry, the key part of the AI definition portion is that the definition — once used — has to be used consistently throughout all filings. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Adopt a clear, enterprise-wide definition of AI and use it consistently across SEC filings, internal policies, and marketing, so you do not redefine the term to suit the story you want to tell in a given quarter,” Perry said. “The IAC recommendation explicitly contemplates requiring issuers to define what they mean by AI, in part because inconsistent definitions are already making disclosures hard for investors to compare. Allowing companies to define AI themselves is a double-edged sword, since it can either promote honest, business-specific clarity or invite opportunistic word games.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some attorneys suggested that companies should be careful about AI phrasing or face potential actions from the SEC and the US Federal Trade Commission (FTC). &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;Be very cautious about AI marketing. The SEC has already shown, through its AI washing enforcement actions, that it is willing to charge firms that exaggerate their AI capabilities or mislead investors about how embedded AI is in their products and processes,” Perry said. “A disclosure regime that asks companies to explain where AI is used, how it is governed, and how it affects operations will only make it easier for the SEC to test whether those claims are real.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lexireese/"&gt;Lexi Reese&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of AI vendor Lanai, also expressed concern about allowing companies to write their own AI definitions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Giving companies the freedom to define AI may reduce short-term compliance friction, but it creates exactly the kind of fragmented, incomparable disclosure environment that leaves investors guessing,” Reese said. “If one company calls an autonomous decision system AI and another calls the same thing a data-driven tool, their disclosures will look compliant while describing two different universes of risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI specialist &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/rob-lee"&gt;Rob Lee&lt;/a&gt;, chief of research for the cybersecurity training firm the SANS Institute, said the rule might prove helpful in raising board and C-level awareness about what companies are actually doing with AI. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But as with the earlier SEC cybersecurity rule, Lee said he was unhappy that the rule includes “a massive number of get-out-of-jail-free cards. Who is going to actually disclose anything? What are they disclosing? They don’t even mention shadow IT. How do you track unsanctioned AI use in your company?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not even all members of the IAC were happy with the rule’s phrasing. IAC member John Gulliver submitted &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/files/john-gulliver-written-statement-dissent-ai-20251204.pdf"&gt;an official dissent &lt;/a&gt;to the proposed rule, expressing particular concern with each company’s ability to write its own AI definition. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These definitions would likely change from year-to-year or quarter-to-quarter. I don’t see how this benefits investors,” Gulliver wrote. But he also said that he doubted the details required are realistic. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposed rule would “require public companies to provide highly specific disclosures of how their use of AI impacts employees at their company and the company’s customers. It’s good that this is only required when the use of AI is financially material to the company. But unfortunately, I think this is an impossible task,” Gulliver wrote. “Does the SEC really have the AI expertise necessary to determine what these line-item disclosures should be? And how is a company supposed to know the precise impact of AI on hiring or their customers? There are many macroeconomic and industry-specific factors that affect jobs and customers. In my view, accurately isolating AI-specific impacts would be a difficult guessing game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107317/the-devil-of-proposed-sec-ai-disclosure-rule-is-in-the-details.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CASB buyer’s guide: What to know about cloud access security brokers before you buy</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/557365/cloud-access-security-broker-buyers-guide.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-access-security-brokers-casbs-explained"&gt;Cloud access security brokers (CASBs) explained&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, a cloud access security broker (CASB) manages access between enterprise endpoints and cloud resources from a security perspective. CASBs can be deployed on-premises or in the cloud; as a hardware appliance or software-only, as a proxy, reverse proxy, or through specific APIs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises have untold numbers of endpoints, both managed (corporate-owned devices) and unmanaged (devices owned by employees or third-party contractors). Endpoints can be on-premises or remote. And endpoints can include internet of things (IoT) devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ Download our editors’ PDF &lt;a href="https://us.resources.csoonline.com/resources/download-our-cloud-access-security-broker-casb-enterprise-buyers-guide/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;cloud access security broker (CASB) enterprise buyer’s guide&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; today! ]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="in-this-buyers-guide"&gt;In this buyer’s guide:&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud access security brokers (CASBs) explained&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Why enterprises need cloud access security brokers (CASBs)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to look for in a cloud access security broker (CASB) tool&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Core cloud access security broker (CASB) services&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Leading cloud access security broker (CASB) vendors&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to ask before cloud access security broker (CASB) tool&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Essential reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a multicloud environment, each endpoint could connect to multiple cloud resources over the course of a single day — productivity apps (like Microsoft 365), SaaS apps (like Salesforce and Workday), collaboration apps (like Slack and Zoom), and cloud storage (like Amazon Web Services and Dropbox). Not to mention homegrown apps that have been migrated to the cloud, or apps that have been developed in the cloud (that is, cloud-native).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CASBs sit between an organization’s endpoints and cloud resources, acting as a gateway that monitors everything that goes in or out, providing visibility into what users are doing in the cloud, enforcing access control policies, and looking out for security threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some vendors have begun incorporating additional features into core CASB functionality, such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/569559/what-is-dlp-how-data-loss-prevention-software-works-and-why-you-need-it.html"&gt;data loss prevention (DLP)&lt;/a&gt;, secure web gateway (SWG), &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;cloud security posture management (CSPM)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/553329/user-entity-behavior-analytics-next-step-in-security-visibilty.html"&gt;user and entity behavior analytics (UEBA)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, it is important to note that CASBs are also a key component of a broader security strategy that goes by several names:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gartner calls that broader strategy &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/957252/10-questions-to-ask-about-secure-service-edge-sse.html"&gt;Secure Service Edge (SSE)&lt;/a&gt;, an integration of CASB, secure web gateway (SWG), and &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/971137/who-is-selling-zero-trust-network-access-ztna-and-what-do-you-get.html"&gt;zero trust network access (ZTNA)&lt;/a&gt;. According to Gartner, by 2026, 85% of organizations seeking to secure their web, SaaS, and private applications will obtain the security capabilities from a Security Service Edge (SSE) offering. The Gartner nomenclature has become the de facto standard. They and others have used a second acronym, Security Access Service Edge (SASE).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;IDC defines the category as network edge security as a service (NESaaS), with the same three core components: CASB, SWG, and ZTNA. “The network security market is in the process of a much-needed convergence trend. Security vendors have shifted from a focus on à la carte, individualized security services to a consolidated, cloud-delivered network security platform that treats individual services as optional modules,” IDC states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-enterprises-need-cloud-access-security-brokers-casbs"&gt;Why enterprises need cloud access security brokers (CASBs)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The original use case for CASBs was to address &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563803/shadow-it-its-not-what-you-think.html"&gt;shadow IT&lt;/a&gt;. When security execs deployed their first CASB tools, they were surprised to discover how many employees had their own personal cloud storage accounts, where they squirreled away corporate data. CASB tools can help security teams discover and monitor unauthorized or unmanaged cloud services being used by employees. This has grown to also include &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3964282/cisos-no-closer-to-containing-shadow-ais-skyrocketing-data-risks.html"&gt;shadow AI services&lt;/a&gt;, as more enterprise users pick various machine learning models and use personal accounts to access public-facing generative AI tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, CASBs encompass a variety of other use cases:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data protection&lt;/strong&gt;: The COVID-19 pandemic drove employees to remote work and applications to the cloud, where they could be more easily accessed. The pandemic has passed, and many employees have returned to the office, but those applications and that data are still in the cloud. Organizations must protect sensitive data as it moves across a hybrid cloud environment. Today’s CASB often integrates DLP functionality.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; Data privacy regulations continue to tighten. CASBs are an important tool in an organization’s overall regulatory compliance framework, enforcing data privacy policies.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote workforce&lt;/strong&gt;: Regardless of the location of employees, CASBs allow enterprises to implement more consistent security standards and secure remote access to cloud resources.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat detection&lt;/strong&gt;: CASBs can detect malicious activity, intrusion attempts, ransomware, and other types of security events. CASB tools can generate real-time alerts to enable quick response by security teams and feed these alerts into other security platforms to mitigate and resolve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-look-for-in-a-cloud-access-security-brokers-casb-tool"&gt;What to look for in a cloud access security brokers (CASB) tool&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From a purely functional perspective, there are four key features of a CASB tool:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visibility:&lt;/strong&gt; CASBs provide comprehensive visibility into cloud usage, user activities, and data flows.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control:&lt;/strong&gt; CASBs offer granular control over user permissions and data access.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data protection:&lt;/strong&gt; CASB solutions provide data protection capabilities to safeguard sensitive information across multiple cloud services.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; CASB tools help maintain compliance with data privacy regulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond those core features, organizations need to make sure the CASB tool well integrates with existing cloud services, applications, and security infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are three deployment modes: forward proxy, reverse proxy and API-based. Most experts say that API-based CASBs provide better functionality, but organizations need to make sure that the vendor’s list of application programming interface (API) connections matches up with the organization’s inventory of cloud apps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="core-casb-services"&gt;Core CASB services&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Take note about the use or requirements for deploying various agents with each product. This is where the CASB vendors often place their secret sauce, which could be an issue depending on how agent-friendly or agent-adverse your IT department is. For example, Skyhigh uses a single agent that functions across all three operational modes. Some of the other CASBs have multiple agents — such as for specific functional areas like antivirus, DLP, or VPN — that can get messy, not to mention tough to deal with unmanaged endpoints such as personal mobile phones and embedded devices such as internet of things controllers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The following three basic services that all CASBs offer are at the core of what CASBs do and why you would buy one:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor and control your most sensitive data flows&lt;/strong&gt;: CASBs were originally designed to stem the tide of shadow IT products and to control and make SaaS applications more secure. Now they have broadened their use and can fit into a variety of situations, including operating across multiple cloud providers and mixing SaaS, mobile, and on-premises applications, too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply uniform DLP policies across all servers and apps:&lt;/strong&gt; As your data appetite increases, you need better ways to ensure that you aren’t leaking customer- and business-sensitive information, either through a malicious insider or inadvertently through a bad combination of security loopholes. While DLP products have been around for years, having DLP-like features in your CASB can be a nice way to track these potential weak spots, especially as more of your data moves into the cloud and is accessed by unmanaged mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage cloud-native encryption keys:&lt;/strong&gt; Ideally, your CASB should automatically keep track of your encryption needs and keys so you don’t have to do this manually, and so you can encrypt more of your data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some CASB tools are better at some things than others. For example:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitglass has an Ajax virtual machine-like layer that handles near-real-time DLP on unmanaged devices. The only caveat is that these devices have to access data through their browsers.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Some CASBs, such as Fortra, has field-level encryption on some SaaS structured data services, which can be a handy mechanism for protecting sensitive information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond these basics, all CASBs offer the potential to operate in one (or more) of three different modes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forward proxy&lt;/strong&gt;, usually deployed with endpoint agents or VPN clients.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverse proxy&lt;/strong&gt;, which doesn’t require agents and can work better for unmanaged devices.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API control&lt;/strong&gt;, which provides visibility into data already stored in cloud repositories or data that is used in a cloud process that never enters a corporate network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="feature-sets-across-casb-operational-modes-vary"&gt;Feature sets across CASB operational modes vary&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Part of the CASB evaluation challenge is understanding how the feature set extends to each operational mode if indeed the product operates in more than one mode. Broadcom’s Symantec CASB, for example, has reverse proxies just for Microsoft 365 and no other application. Meanwhile, Cisco Systems and Palo Alto Networks both offer API-only CASB products. Such differences mean you need to understand the types of protection and not just which apps are supported but how they are supported, and what is the exact API portfolio that is covered by each product.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You really need the API support if you want to get granular with your CASB protection to understand the state of your public cloud security exposure and to stop any cloud-based malware too. API deployments also can trap cloud-to-cloud activities and to retrospectively inspect archived traffic flows. You will also need some level of proxying to handle application gateways and for implementing specific security policies. It pays to read the fine print and develop an appropriate test plan that will reveal the relevant features for each vendors’ product.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="nice-to-have-sets-of-casb-features"&gt;Nice-to-have sets of CASB features:&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conduct continuous risk assessments and compliance audits on demand:&lt;/strong&gt; A CASB can show in a single place where a corporation has the most risk and summarizes issues that a security team can quickly focus on for suspicious behavior that other products couldn’t easily do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forcepoint, Netskope, and Proofpoint all have nice risk summary dashboards that you can customize to display the things you need to understand how your environment is behaving and what needs immediate attention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply uniform adaptive authentication policies across all logins, servers, and apps&lt;/strong&gt;: This should include read-only access (Gartner suggests this would be a good situation for unsanctioned SaaS services that are nonetheless needed), step-up authentication, and more granular access rights management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity management and single sign-on (SSO) tools are the usual go-to reasons for these sorts of tasks, and one important trend is that more CASBs are integrating with traditional SSO products. The trick is to understand that the typical level of integration happens (usually) in reverse proxy mode only, and the SSO authentication is only passed to the CASB at the initial application login moment. This means that if you want a more complete adaptive authentication to trap when more risky behavior happens, you will probably have to stick with your dedicated SSO product.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As you can see, CASBs touch a lot of different existing security products across your enterprise. The challenge for successful integration is being able to understand these interactions and ensure that you overall security profile is enhanced rather than degraded with their use.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leading-cloud-access-security-broker-casb-vendors"&gt;Leading cloud access security broker (CASB) vendors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The list of leading CASB vendors (in alphabetical order) includes pure-play companies as well as traditional security vendors that have added CASB capabilities to their portfolios either by acquisition or through internal development. Most vendors would not share their pricing details, but we have found approximate clues on AWS and Azure marketplaces where we could.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/zero-trust/products/casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an add-on to their One SASE platform, using the same overall agent. There is a free version for under 50 users which allows two SaaS components, and prices start at $7/user/month above that level, with custom pricing for larger installations. The CASB product is now four years old and integrates with visibility and control of various AI services such as ChatGPT and Google Gemini. It doesn’t support reverse proxies, includes DLP and integrates with the risk scores and metadata sources available with Microsoft’s cloud services, such as with protecting Office 365 documents and emails.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cisco.com/site/us/en/products/security/cloudlock/index.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cisco Cloudlock:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cisco Systems has had a CASB since it acquired Cloudlock back in 2016. Cisco Cloudlock is a cloud-native CASB that protects users, data, and apps with an automated approach that uses APIs to manage the risks in the cloud app ecosystem. It integrates with Cisco’s SSE platform for its protective policies and a uniform dashboard. Cloudlock uses advanced machine learning algorithms to detect anomalies. It also provides DLP functionality and targets shadow IT with policy-based controls that can block dangerous activities, depending on permissions and risk levels. It uses machine learning to produce risk scores for more than 1,300 applications along with having tools to manage AI supply chains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.forcepoint.com/product/casb-cloud-access-security-broker"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forcepoint ONE CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Forcepoint bought Bitglass in 2021, one of the original standalone CASB vendors and a leader in Gartner’s Magic Quadrant for CASB. Forcepoint has integrated Bitglass technology with its own DLP capabilities to provide an SSE solution. Forcepoint excels in monitoring and reporting on shadow IT, and its user analytics feature is popular. The software also supports a zero-trust architecture, providing device and user authentication. Pricing is $120 per user per year on AWS Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fortra.com/products/cloud-access-security-broker"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fortra’s CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;is the result of acquiringendpoint protection vendor Lookout who previously acquired CASB innovator CipherCloud. Fortra now has a solid SSE platform that covers zero trust access controls, advanced DLP capabilities to automate the data discovery process, and supports a range of purpose-built integrations that covers identity access management and security orchestration, among others. It can provide visibility across managed and unmanaged cloud-based applications, users, endpoints, and data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.netskope.com/products/casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netskope CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the original pure-play CASB vendors, Netskope is a leader in CASBs as well as SSE. According to Forrester Research, Netskope has shown innovation across its technology stack, including significant investments in an impressive new private global network, artificial intelligence and generative AI security. Netskope merged SWG functionality into its CASB tool and sells separate in-line and API versions each for $35,000 per year for 100 users on AWS Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.paloaltonetworks.com/next-gen-casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palo Alto Networks Prisma CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;Palo Alto Networks touts its CASB as being “next-generation,” based on the proposition that it’s less a standalone product and more of a range of integrated solutions such as inline security, SSPM, and enterprise DLP. The Palo Alto Networks CASB is designed to secure apps and data across cloud and hybrid workforce environments, protects data in transit between users and SaaS providers, facilities regulatory compliance and minimizes risks from shadow IT.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proofpoint&lt;/strong&gt;’s CASB&lt;/a&gt; is focused on extending DLP and threat protection from email to cloud apps. Proofpoint takes a people-centric approach; it provides granular visibility into who creates sensitive data and who owns, downloads, uploads, shares and edits that data. It identifies users who have been successfully phished, and those who have been attacked the most by hackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.skyhighsecurity.com/products/cloud-access-security-broker.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skyhigh Security &lt;/strong&gt;CASB&lt;/a&gt; supports all deployment modes and enables real-time control over user access to sanctioned and unsanctioned cloud services. Skyhigh (a unit of Indian IT tech provider Musarubra that also owns Trellix) focuses on providing comprehensive multimode coverage that feeds security events into a machine learning system to provide sophisticated event correlation, helping security teams to focus on real threats rather than false alarms. CASB is just part of its overall SSE platform which integrates across SWG, ZTNA, DSPM and DLP, along with remote browser isolation. Protective policies are developed platform-wide and include management of AI usage and prevention of shadow AI and crafting user risk scores from all these metrics. Pricing is based on per protected service per user per year, the unlimited services is $88/user/year, with extra charges for shadow services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symantec&lt;/strong&gt;, a division of Broadcom, offers its &lt;a href="https://www.broadcom.com/products/cybersecurity/information-protection/data-loss-prevention-cloud/cloud-application-security-cloudsoc"&gt;CloudSOC CASB&lt;/a&gt; to monitor and control the use of sanctioned SaaS apps through extensive API integrations and in-line traffic analysis. The Symantec CASB provides full visibility and automatic detection of high-risk users, compromised accounts, and malicious insiders. Individualized behavioral-based user threat scores allow fast identification of risky user accounts. The tool automates the classification regulated data flowing in and out of apps, and it enforces controls that align with corporate policies. The tool includes DLP functionality and CSPM.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://versa-networks.com/products/casb/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versa’s CASB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; is part of its One Universal SSE Platform &lt;/strong&gt;that contains a unified dashboard and policy rule set for a variety of security services, including DLP, ZTNA, applications firewall, analytics and reporting. All its modules were entirely developed in-house, include various AI-based tools, and it supports all three modes of operation. &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Users can create protective policies using natural language queries of its embedded AI, as well as explore alerts and remediations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zscaler.com/products-and-solutions/cloud-access-security-broker-casb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zscaler&lt;/strong&gt; CASB&lt;/a&gt; offers inline, real-time capabilities and out-of-band scanning functionality to protect data, block threats, provide visibility, and assure compliance. Key features include agentless cloud browser isolation to secure BYOD and third-party devices where software installations are infeasible, advanced threat protection to stop malware from reaching cloud resources in real time, cloud sandboxing to detect new ransomware and other zero-day infections, shadow IT discovery to automatically identify unsanctioned apps used by employees and create a risk score for each. It uses AI to classify and detect data leaks and will have additional AI-based tools in early 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-ask-before-buying-a-casb-tool"&gt;What to ask before buying a CASB tool&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Buying a CASB tool can be complex. There’s a laundry list of possible features that fall within the broad CASB definition (DLP, SWG, etc.) And CASB tools themselves are part of a larger trend toward SSE and SASE platforms that include features such as ZTNA or SD-WAN. Enterprises need to identify their specific pain points — whether that’s regulatory compliance or shadow IT — and select a vendor that meets their immediate needs and can also grow with the enterprise over time. Here are the key questions to ask yourself before buying a CASB tool:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I have a good handle on what cloud services my users are accessing, including employees, contractors, and other third-parties?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have a solid data classification system in place, so that I know what types of data are sensitive or mission critical?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have policies in place for access control across both on-prem and cloud environments, including SaaS applications?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have clear objectives? What are my priorities when shopping for a CASB?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How will a CASB tool integrate with my existing security infrastructure such as firewalls, endpoint protection and web gateways. Examine how it will protect my entire applications’ estate, including custom-written apps. What happens as I migrate apps from on-premises to the cloud or in reverse?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I get DLP and SWG as part of the CASB, or are those additional modules?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How will the purchase of a CASB tool play into my broader security roadmap that might include the adoption of SSE or SASE?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What is the initial cost, as well as the longer-term total cost of ownership?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have the budget for a new tool?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Can your product scale as my company grows?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Does your product cover all the geographic regions where I operate?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have the inhouse staff to deploy and manage the tool on-premises, or should I take the cloud-based, managed service route?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="essential-reading"&gt;Essential reading&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562793/how-do-you-secure-the-cloud-new-data-points-a-way.html"&gt;How do you secure the cloud? New data points a way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/969119/what-is-sase-a-cloud-service-that-marries-sd-wan-with-security.html"&gt;What is SASE? A cloud service that marries SD-WAN with security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/557365/cloud-access-security-broker-buyers-guide.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JumpCloud agent turns uninstall into a system shortcut</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107744/jumpcloud-agent-turns-uninstall-into-a-system-shortcut.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JumpCloud’s Remote Assist for Windows agent contained a critical local privilege escalation flaw, allowing full system compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Disclosed by XM Cyber, the vulnerability stems from insecure file operations during uninstall or update flows that execute with Windows NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM privileges. The bug could allow a low-privileged local user to elevate themselves to full system control or induce denial-of-service conditions on corporate machines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JumpCloud’s agent is widely used in enterprise environments as part of its cloud-based Directory-as-a-service platform, managing device access and remote support features across Windows endpoints. According to XM Cyber’s Hillel Pinto, attackers only need a local foothold to exploit the flaw, generally &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3970094/cybercriminals-switch-up-their-top-initial-access-vectors-of-choice.html"&gt;obtainable&lt;/a&gt; from phishing, remote support sessions, or developer machines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Systems running Remote Assist for Windows before version 0.317 are vulnerable and need to be updated immediately to mitigate risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="privileged-uninstall-in-a-untrusted-temp-space"&gt;Privileged uninstall in a untrusted temp space&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The flaw, tracked as &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-34352"&gt;CVE-2025-34352&lt;/a&gt; and rated at CVSS 8.5 out of 10, highlights risks from improper handling of privileged operations on Windows endpoints. During uninstall or update operations, the JumpCloud agent triggers the Remote Assist uninstaller with system-level privileges, the highest possible authority in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, that routine performs create, write, execute, and delete actions on files in a user-writable %TEMP% subdirectory without validating the trustworthiness of the path or resetting access control lists.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the uninstaller performs privileged file operations inside a user-controlled %TEMP% directory, a low-privileged attacker can abuse those operations to overwrite or delete protected system files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What we have is a JumpCloud process with NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM privileges that is deleting, writing, and executing a file with a predictable filename from an untrusted path,” Pinto said in a blog &lt;a href="https://xmcyber.com/blog/jumpshot-xm-cyber-uncovers-critical-local-privilege-escalation-cve-2025-34352-in-jumpcloud-agent/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;. “The core of the exploit involves Link Following, utilizing mount points and symbolic links to redirect the privileged I/O operation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="full-privilege-escalation-and-denial-of-service"&gt;Full privilege escalation and denial of service&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability opens two primary exploitation vectors with significant operational impact: full privilege escalation to system level, and denial of service (DoS).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By manipulating filesystem paths and leveraging race conditions, an attacker can redirect the uninstaller’s operations to delete or overwrite protected installer configuration targets, ultimately triggering techniques that give them a system-level command prompt. System access on an enterprise endpoint effectively grants control over policy enforcement, credential theft paths, and lateral movement capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, attackers can get the privileged process to write arbitrary data to sensitive system files (such as drivers), corrupting them and forcing blue screen of death (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2589942/blue-screen-of-death-strikes-crowd-of-crowdstrike-servers.html"&gt;BSOD&lt;/a&gt;) conditions. This not only knocks machines offline but can require substantial remediation effort, particularly across distributed fleets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pinto said that updating to JumpCloud Remote Assist for Windows version 0.317.0 or later will remediate this issue. “My team and I responsibly disclosed the vulnerability to JumpCloud, which confirmed the findings and promptly released a patch.” While &gt;NIST&lt;/span&gt;’s National Vulnerability Database (NVD) marks the flaw as fixed and references the JumpCloud Agent release notes for patching, there is currently no note dedicated to the flaw on the page or on JumpCloud’s support site. JumpCloud did not immediately respond to CSO’s request for comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107744/jumpcloud-agent-turns-uninstall-into-a-system-shortcut.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-832)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-832</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-833)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-833</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV25-834)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av25-834</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-835)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-835</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-836)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-836</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-837)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-837</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–838)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-838</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-839)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-839</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectWise security advisory (AV25-840)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-840</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-841)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-841</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-821) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-821</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-842)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-842</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-843)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-843</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-845) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-845</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-846)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-846</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-847)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-847</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-848) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-848</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
