<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:54:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-117)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-117</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-117</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-118)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-118</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-118</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-119)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-119</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-119</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commvault security advisory (AV26-120)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-121)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OTF GRIMM: Swedish teenager arrested for prison shooting in the Netherlands</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-teenager-arrested-for-prison-shooting-in-netherlands</link>
      <description>A Swedish minor has been arrested in Sweden on 23 January for his alleged involvement in a shooting outside a prison in the Netherlands, following intelligence development provided by Europol. The shooting was carried out in Alphen aan den Rijn on 16 January.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-teenager-arrested-for-prison-shooting-in-netherlands</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV26-123)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD security advisory (AV26-124)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drug trafficking network supplying cocaine to Iceland dismantled</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/drug-trafficking-network-supplying-cocaine-to-iceland-dismantled</link>
      <description>A criminal network involved in cocaine trafficking from South America to Europe has been dismantled following a coordinated investigation by authorities in Iceland, Lithuania and Spain, with the support of Europol and Eurojust. The group is believed to have generated EUR 4 million in criminal profits through the large-scale trafficking of illicit substances.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/drug-trafficking-network-supplying-cocaine-to-iceland-dismantled</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PayPal launches latest struggle to get rid of SMS for MFA</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134258/paypal-launches-latest-struggle-to-get-rid-of-sms-for-mfa.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When PayPal started emailing customers this month that it was backing off unencrypted SMS for multifactor authentication (MFA) at login, it came with the typical approach-avoidance asterisk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The financial services giant signaled that it was turning the page on the much-maligned authentication method while simultaneously offering no timeline and assuring customers SMS wouldn’t entirely go away — a curious strategy that could help smooth over customer loss.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SMS has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/566075/why-sms-banking-is-still-a-bad-idea.html"&gt;a long history&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567203/why-unauthenticated-sms-is-a-security-risk.html"&gt;opposition from security executives&lt;/a&gt;, mostly pointing to how easily it can be sniffed and subject to man-in-the-middle attacks, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4070281/clayrat-spyware-turns-phones-into-distribution-hubs-via-sms-and-telegram.html"&gt;among others&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, &lt;a href="https://www.bitdefender.com/en-us/blog/hotforsecurity/google-drops-sms-gmail"&gt;Google has backed off SMS&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;a href="https://www.vissensa.com/blog/microsoft-mfa-microsoft-to-remove-sms-multi-factor-authentication/"&gt;has Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://documentation.meraki.com/Platform_Management/Product_Information/Privacy%2C_Security%2C_Compliance/Overview_and_FAQ%3A_Cisco_Meraki_SMS_MFA_Deprecation"&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt;, and even the &lt;a href="https://www.bankinfosecurity.com/uae-central-bank-tells-fis-to-drop-sms-otp-authentication-a-28589"&gt;United Arab Emirates Central Bank&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“SMS as an authentication factor is devil spawn and should be banned by an act of Congress,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gwlongsine/"&gt;Gary Longsine&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at IllumineX, encapsulating the frustration of many security specialists.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, SMS remains, largely due to convenience, given that many business executives fear any change to MFA processes will be viewed as friction that could lead to customer loss or reduced engagement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They don’t want to lose users who won’t do anything other than SMS as a second factor,” says cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov. “Although app-based MFA is generally considered more secure than SMS-based MFA, not all users are willing to take the time to set up app-based MFA, so making it an absolute requirement tends to result in fewer conversions.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youattest.com/our-team/"&gt;Garret Grajek&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of access certification firm YouAttest, has experienced this business unit pushback directly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We designed a very strong authentication and the CISO loved it, but the security teams did not want to push back against user requests” for unencrypted SMS, he says, adding that a business unit executive argued that the security boost “is going to cost us money.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I feel sorry for PayPal because they [are a victim of] the battles that go on in business units versus security. And security doesn’t always win,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="muddled-effort-mixed-messages"&gt;Muddled effort, mixed messages&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fvillanustre/"&gt;Flavio Villanustre&lt;/a&gt;, CISO for the LexisNexis Risk Solutions Group, says he’s “always found it odd” that PayPal still supports SMS as its primary secondary authentication factor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Everyone in financial services and government has abandoned it for not being sufficiently secure and are moving to even phishing-resistant authentication, such as passkeys, Yubikeys,” he explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s shift was announced via email sent to some customers earlier this month. “Starting March 2026, we’ll start removing SMS codes [for login MFA] but they’ll still be available as part of our standard security checks,” PayPal’s email said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s reference to standard security checks refers to when its system, leveraging behavioral analytics, flags a customer interaction as potentially fraudulent based on factors such as transaction size or deviation from historic patterns. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, Grajek finds PayPal’s decision to keep SMS in use for fraud checks to be odd. When the system flags a potential problem, he says, “you want to do a higher level [of authentication]. Why would you de-escalate [to a lower level of authentication]?” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s customer email said the company would “start removing” SMS in March, but how long that process will take is unclear. Logistics is one factor, as these communications are going to a global customer base of roughly 439 million people and businesses. PayPal will batch those messages over an extended time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal will likely also assess customer reaction, giving itself flexibility by not committing to a firm end date. PayPal declined to comment on the record for this story.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PayPal’s email suggested that customers switch their MFA method to an authenticator app or a onetime-password-issuing fob such as those compliant with FIDO2 security keys. Strangely, the email instructed security key users to “Put the device into your USB slot and you’re all set,” despite the fact that mobile devices communicate with keys via NFC or mobile connectors, not via USB slots, and most users transact with PayPal via mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The PayPal email also instructed customers to “update your verification method at paypal.com. Log in to your account and use the gear icon to go to security settings and update your 2-step verification.” The problem? When the email was received, that security page offered no direct way to make the change. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Customer service suggested to customers that they could deactivate MFA entirely and then reactivate it. That less-than-secure option did work and the user was then able to make the change. Further testing revealed that a user could click the “add a new device” button, even if they had no intention of adding a new device. That also presented a screen where the customer could change their MFA method. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://moorinsightsstrategy.com/team/melody-brue/"&gt;Melody Brue&lt;/a&gt;, principal analyst for Moor Insights &amp;amp; Strategy, says using SMS can still be valuable for some isolated situations, but that PayPal appears to be trying to have it both ways.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It sounds to me that they are trying to soften the blow of saying ‘SMS isn’t safe enough.’ They are saying that you can’t use it to verify who you are unless we are worried that you are not you,” Brue says. “They are clearly actively inching away from SMS. They have to do that. They have to align with new standards. In financial services you don’t even want to mess around with” SMS.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="financial-cost-of-sms-may-be-final-straw"&gt;Financial cost of SMS may be final straw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Brue also referred to another reason PayPal may be stepping back from SMS authentication: cost reduction. Sending SMS messages involves hard costs for PayPal, whereas telling customers to authenticate with a FIDO2 key or an authenticator app is free for the company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cost of individual SMS messages is low — for example, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sns/sms-pricing/"&gt;AWS charges a fraction of a penny&lt;/a&gt; for each message. But given that PayPal handles about 25 billion transactions a year, those fractions quickly add up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also, attackers test PayPal systems routinely “and they can trigger millions of SMS codes,” Brue adds. “For a company &lt;a href="https://247wallst.com/investing/2026/02/13/paypal-stock-falls-31-as-new-ceo-inherits-execution-crisis/"&gt;under new leadership and especially margin sensitive right now&lt;/a&gt;, sending millions of codes to bots that are not needed? That is an easy line to cut and it’s an OPEX win.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://acceligence.com/talent/profiles/justin-greis/"&gt;Justin Greis&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of consulting firm Acceligence and former head of the North American cybersecurity practice at McKinsey, says his main concern with SMS authentication is “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4022848/7-obsolete-security-practices-that-should-be-terminated-immediately.html"&gt;SIM swapping, SIM jacking&lt;/a&gt; — we have seen that go up.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“PayPal is one of the most spoofed and spammed emails out there,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/steveneric/"&gt;Steven Eric Fisher&lt;/a&gt;, an independent cybersecurity and risk advisor who served as the director of cybersecurity, risk, and compliance for Walmart until August 2025, agrees about SMS’s many authentication drawbacks, dubbing SMS “a very low bar of protection.” But he is less enthusiastic than most about authenticator apps. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Authenticator apps “are only marginally better than SMS. Each has its own faults,” Fisher says. “FIDO2 is the best option from a security standpoint but end user adoption” may slow down because the customer has to pay for each FIDO2 device “as well as [experience] the difficulty placed on the user for the enrollment and use.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134258/paypal-launches-latest-struggle-to-get-rid-of-sms-for-mfa.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL security advisory (AV26-125)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/postgresql-security-advisory-av26-125</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/postgresql-security-advisory-av26-125</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-126)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-126</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-126</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-127)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-127</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-127</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol report: evolving tactics in maritime cocaine trafficking operations</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</link>
      <description>A new Europol report published today provides a comprehensive analysis of the evolving tactics employed by criminal networks to traffic cocaine into Europe via maritime routes. The report, 'Diversification in Maritime Cocaine Trafficking Modi Operandi', provides an in-depth analysis of the shifting tactics employed by organised crime networks, which continue to exploit vulnerabilities and evade detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-111) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV26-122) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV26-128)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-128</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-128</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-129)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-129</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-129</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fact Check: Europol’s support to Ukraine and entries into the Schengen Information System</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fact-check-europol-support-to-ukraine-and-entries-schengen-information-system</link>
      <description>The clarification below provides information to help accurately understand a recent media article on Europol’s support to Ukraine.Case at hand:A recent media article headlined: Separated by war — and by Schengen described how data and alerts in the EU’s Schengen Information System (SIS), originally designed to keep Europe safe from security threats, is now trapping Ukrainian refugees, including those who...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fact-check-europol-support-to-ukraine-and-entries-schengen-information-system</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication of a vacancy notice for the position of Europol Executive Director</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/publication-of-vacancy-notice-for-position-of-europol-executive-director</link>
      <description>Catherine De Bolle has served as Europol’s Executive Director since 1 May 2018, her mandate will conclude on 1 May 2026. The incoming Executive Director will have the opportunity to shape Europol's future and strengthen its role in safeguarding the European Union’s internal security.About EuropolEuropol, based in The Hague, the Netherlands, supports and strengthens action by and cooperation of the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/publication-of-vacancy-notice-for-position-of-europol-executive-director</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol supports French investigation into alleged criminal activity linked to platform X</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</link>
      <description>The investigation is conducted by the Paris Public Prosecutor’s Office with the support of the French Gendarmerie’s cybercrime unit (UNCyber) and Europol.On the action day, French authorities carried out investigative measures in the offices of the platform in France. Europol supported the investigation through its European Cybercrime Centre (EC3), providing specialised cybercrime expertise and deploying an analyst on the ground...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>103 arrests and 36 labs dismantled in strike against synthetic drug network</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/103-arrests-and-36-labs-dismantled-in-strike-against-synthetic-drug-network</link>
      <description>Between 12 and 17 February 2026, Europol supported law enforcement authorities in Ukraine, Poland, and Moldova in a joint operation against an international criminal network involved in the production and trafficking of synthetic drugs, primarily synthetic cathinones such as alpha-PVP. The action day saw the Ukrainian National Police and the Polish Police Central Bureau of Investigation conducting coordinated checks at approximately 510 locations. Law enforcement officers dismantled 36 illicit production sites and 74 storage facilities for ready-to-distribute drugs. A total of 129 persons faced criminal charges, 103 persons were taken into custody.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/103-arrests-and-36-labs-dismantled-in-strike-against-synthetic-drug-network</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-097) - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compromised npm package silently installs OpenClaw on developer machines</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4135449/compromised-npm-package-silently-installs-openclaw-on-developer-machines.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new security bypass has users installing AI agent OpenClaw — whether they intended to or not.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have discovered that a compromised npm publish token pushed an update for the widely-used Cline command line interface (CLI) containing a malicious postinstall script. That script installs the wildly popular, but increasingly condemned, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129867/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-clawdbot-i-mean-moltbot-i-mean-openclaw.html" target="_blank"&gt;agentic application OpenClaw&lt;/a&gt; on the unsuspecting user’s machine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This can be extremely dangerous, as OpenClaw has broad system access and deep integrations with messaging platforms including WhatsApp, Telegram, Slack, Discord, iMessage, Teams, and others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to research by security platform Socket, the script was live for eight hours on the registry.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It should be emphasized that, in this case, OpenClaw wasn’t inherently malicious. However, it does represent yet another chapter in OpenClaw’s shaky security saga, and situations like this could earn it ‘potentially unwanted application’ (PUA) status.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I mean, they effectively turned OpenClaw into malware that EDR [endpoint detection and response ] isn’t going to stop,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt; of Beauceron Security. It is “deviously, terrifyingly brilliant.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="users-love-openclaw-attackers-do-too"&gt;Users love OpenClaw; attackers do, too&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw (formerly Clawdbot and Moltbot) is a free, open-source, autonomous AI agent that &lt;a href="https://openclaw.ai/blog/introducing-openclaw" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;launched on January 29&lt;/a&gt; and almost immediately went viral. According to its developer, Peter Steinberger, its repo had more than 2 million visitors over the course of a single week, and it’s estimated that it has been &lt;a href="http://www.ox.security/blog/how-to-uninstall-openclaw-remove-data-revoke-access/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;downloaded 720,000 times a week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw runs locally on a user’s hardware rather than in the cloud, and can perform autonomous, real-world actions on their behalf, such as reading emails, browsing web pages, running apps, or managing calendars.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, almost immediately after release, it raised &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4125939/by-whatever-name-moltbolt-clawd-openclaw-this-uber-ai-assistant-is-a-security-nightmare.html" target="_blank"&gt;serious security issues&lt;/a&gt;: It is prone to prompt injection attacks, authentication bypasses, and server-side request forgery (SSRF), among other &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4134540/six-flaws-found-hiding-in-openclaws-plumbing.html" target="_blank"&gt;attacks&lt;/a&gt;. Many enterprises have responded by severely restricting, or outright banning, the AI agent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While, in the Cline situation, it was merely installed, but not inherently malicious, “the attacker had the ability to install anything,” &lt;a href="https://socket.dev/blog/cline-cli-npm-package-compromised-via-suspected-cache-poisoning-attack" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Socket’s Sarah Gooding&lt;/a&gt; wrote. “This time it was OpenClaw. Next time it might be something malicious.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Cline CLI is widely-used across the developer ecosystem, with about 90,000 weekly downloads from npm. The compromised token pushed cline@2.3.0, which contained a modified package.json with a postinstall script that installed the latest version of OpenClaw, to the npm registry. The addition of that script was the only modification to the package; otherwise the CLI binary and other contents were identical to the legitimate prior release, Gooding noted, making it easy to miss.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The compromised package was pushed on February 17, although the underlying problem had been &lt;a href="https://adnanthekhan.com/posts/clinejection/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;discovered six weeks prior&lt;/a&gt; by security researcher Adnan Khan. The package sat live on the registry for an estimated eight hours before it was deprecated and Cline published a corrected version (2.4.0).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Khan had initially published his research about the vulnerable workflow on February 9, after unsuccessful attempts to get a response to his reports from Cline, and Cline fixed it within 30 minutes. However, while the patch closed the entry point, the token could have been stolen during an attacker’s initial reconnaissance, meaning the fix came too late to prevent the February 17 publish (which, ultimately, was the day it was exploited).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cline had no prior install scripts, so a new one appearing was an anomalous signal worth investigating,” Gooding noted, adding that Socket has marked the unauthorized publish as malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For devs who installed or updated the Cline CLI in the roughly eight-hour window on February 17, Socket advises:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update to the latest version: npm install “-g cline@latest.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;If on version 2.3.0, update to 2.4.0 or higher.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Check for and immediately remove OpenClaw if it hadn’t been intentionally installed (“npm uninstall -g openclaw”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gooding noted, “nothing ran automatically beyond the install,” but added there was still a risk: “OpenClaw is a capable agentic tool with broad system permissions, not a trivial package to have silently dropped onto a developer’s machine.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-no-win-scenario"&gt;A no-win scenario&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;EDR, managed detection and response (MDR), and other security providers are going to be forced to declare OpenClaw as either a PUA or “flat out as malware, which, honestly, it can be,” said Shipley, or these kinds of attack win.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I hate to give it to attackers, but you kind of have to on this one,” he said. “This is why agentic AI is going to get so many people pwned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it’s a no-win scenario, Shipley noted, particularly if any organization was “so foolish” as to have allowed OpenClaw into their enterprise environment and built business-reliant work processes on it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As he put it: “Attackers combined the two biggest dumpster fires in 2026 cybersecurity into a city-scale landfill fire by chaining supply chain hacks via npm and the smoking-hot-vibe-coded AI agent disaster of OpenClaw.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4135449/compromised-npm-package-silently-installs-openclaw-on-developer-machines.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 02:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-003 - Vulnerability affecting BeyondTrust - CVE-2026-1731</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-003-vulnerability-affecting-beyondtrust-cve-2026-1731</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-003-vulnerability-affecting-beyondtrust-cve-2026-1731</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-131)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-131</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-131</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-132)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-132</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-132</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-133)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-133</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-133</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26-134)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-134</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-134</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-135)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-135</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-135</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-136)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-136</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-136</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-137)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-137</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-137</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-130) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-130</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-130</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-139)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-139</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-139</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-140)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-140</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-140</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV26-141)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-141</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-141</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV26-142)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av26-142</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av26-142</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-143)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-143</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-143</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-138) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-138</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-138</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV26-144)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-144</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-144</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-145)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-145</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-145</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV26-146)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-146</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-146</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-147)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-147</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-147</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IceWarp security advisory (AV26-148)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/icewarp-security-advisory-av26-148</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/icewarp-security-advisory-av26-148</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-149)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-149</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-149</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-150)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-150</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-150</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roundcube security advisory (AV25-309) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/roundcube-security-advisory-av25-309</link>
      <description>On June 1, 2025, Roundcube published security advisories to address vulnerabilities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/roundcube-security-advisory-av25-309</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Virtual Event] Shields Up: Key Technologies Reshaping Cybersecurity Defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 2279.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
