<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:18:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-639)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-639</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-639</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 suspected human traffickers arrested in Albania and Colombia</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/17-suspected-human-traffickers-arrested-in-albania-and-colombia</link>
      <description>17 suspected human traffickers arrested in Albania and Colombia. The criminal network is believed to have sexually exploited over 50 victims in Albania and Croatia, trafficked from South America to Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/17-suspected-human-traffickers-arrested-in-albania-and-colombia</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIO100 and CSO30 ASEAN 2025 Team Awards Finalists: Celebrating Technology and Cybersecurity Excellence Across the Southeast Asia region</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071340/cio100-and-cso30-asean-2025-team-awards-finalists-celebrating-technology-and-cybersecurity-excellence-across-the-southeast-asia-region-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SINGAPORE, October 13, 2025&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Singapore’s premier technology leadership awards recognize groundbreaking innovations and transformative achievements ahead of spectacular Gala Night celebration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CIO and CSO ASEAN brands are delighted to announce the distinguished finalists for the CIO100 ASEAN and CSO30 ASEAN 2025 Team Awards, recognizing the region’s most innovative technology teams who are reshaping the future of digital enterprise and cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The extensive quantity of nominations received by CIO and CSO ASEAN this year were rigorously and meticulously evaluated by a highly esteemed CIO and CSO executive editors across Asia. This year’s exceptional cohort of finalists represents the pinnacle of technology leadership across Southeast Asia, demonstrating transformative innovation, measurable business impact, and strategic excellence that sets new benchmarks for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="wp-image-4071341" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/AWS-finalfinal-13-oct-12noon.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finalists who have delivered extraordinary value through technology innovation and cybersecurity across six prestigious team categories are:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIO Innovation: &lt;/strong&gt; This award celebrates teams that are introducing groundbreaking solutions that enhance business value and meet strategic business objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kasikorn Business Technology Group&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eton House International Education Group&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Changi Airport Group&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Central Provident Fund Board Singapore&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sentosa Development Corporation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;CIO Customer Value:&lt;/strong&gt; Honours organizations elevating customer experience and value add through transformative projects and process improvements&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sentosa Development Corporation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Far East Organisation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HK Express&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nanyang Technological University&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ANKH Pain and Health Group&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;CIO Talent: &lt;/strong&gt;This category commemorates organizations fostering exceptional talent development and building future-ready capabilities&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mizuho Securities&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eton House International Education&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ANKH Pain and Health Group&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;strong&gt;CIO Culture:&lt;/strong&gt; Recognizes teams developing internal cultural programs promoting growth, achievement, and inclusivity&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ANKH Pain and Health Group&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HK Express&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;CIO Sustainability:&lt;/strong&gt; Celebrates initiatives that are delivering environmental benefits and reducing organizational carbon footprint&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yinson Holdings Berhad&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ANKH Pain and Health Group&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;CSO Public-Private Partnership:&lt;/strong&gt; This award honours initiatives that are advancing cybersecurity through impactful cross-sector collaboration&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Acleda Bank Plc., Cambodia&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MSD International GMBH (Singapore Branch)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“These finalists of the CIO100 and CSO30 ASEAN Awards 2025 across the 6 categories represent the extraordinary calibre of technology leadership driving Southeast Asia’s digital transformation and cyber resilience,”&lt;/strong&gt; said &lt;em&gt;Estelle Quek, Editorial Director, CIO and CSO ASEAN.&lt;/em&gt; “&lt;strong&gt;Their stories of innovation, resilience, and measurable impact inspire the next generation while setting new standards for excellence. We’re thrilled to celebrate their achievements at our CIO100 and CSO30 Awards ASEAN Gala Night on 12 November 2025 in Singapore”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="wp-image-4072116" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/NetApp-and-SAS.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Us for the Ultimate Celebration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mark your calendars for the CIO100 ASEAN Awards 2025 Gala Night on 12 November 2025, in Singapore – this region’s most prestigious technology leadership celebration that brings together the brightest minds in digital innovation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Join us for an evening where Southeast Asia’s most influential technology leaders converge under one roof, celebrating the transformative achievements that are reshaping our digital landscape. The exclusive in-person event transforms into a vibrant hub of recognition and connection, where distinguished finalists and winners take centre stage in a ceremony that honours their groundbreaking contributions to enterprise excellence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond the glamour of recognition, our Gala Night creates an unparalleled platform for meaningful connections. Imagine engaging in conversations with industry pioneers who have navigated complex digital transformations, sharing insights with cybersecurity visionaries who defend against tomorrow’s threats, and collaborating with innovators whose ideas will define the next decade of technological advancement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foundry-events.com/aQxlmD?RefId=Website"&gt;Register now for the Gala Night&lt;/a&gt; and be part of history as we celebrate the leaders defining the future of technology in ASEAN.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.foundry-events.com/XkZXea?RefId=CIO100CSO30Awards"&gt;Do check out our CIO100 CSO30 Awards website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About CIO100 and CSO30 ASEAN Awards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CIO100 and CSO30 ASEAN Awards are flagship programs by Foundry’s CIO and CSO brands, recognizing technology leadership excellence across the region. These prestigious awards celebrate individuals and teams who demonstrate innovation, measurable business value, and transformative impact in their organizations and industries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Estelle Quek&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editorial Director, CIO and CSO ASEAN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071340/cio100-and-cso30-asean-2025-team-awards-finalists-celebrating-technology-and-cybersecurity-excellence-across-the-southeast-asia-region-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 04:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol welcomes the European Investment Bank to its secure information exchange network</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</link>
      <description>The European Investment Bank (EIB) has today joined Europol’s Secure Information Exchange Network Application (SIENA), marking a new step in the cooperation between the two institutions to protect the EU’s financial interests and combat serious crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to look for in a data protection platform for hybrid clouds</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071098/what-to-look-for-in-a-data-protection-platform-for-hybrid-clouds.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data protection is a broad category that includes data security but also encompasses backup and &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/967679/what-is-disaster-recovery-how-to-ensure-business-continuity.html"&gt;disaster recovery&lt;/a&gt;, safe data storage, business continuity and resilience, and compliance with data privacy regulations. &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/412503/veeams-new-pitch-to-cios-outcome-based-backup-and-recovery-offerings.html"&gt;Data protection platforms&lt;/a&gt; also proactively manage and monitor data, making it available and accessible for advanced analytics, artificial intelligence, and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data protection for hybrid clouds thus involves security products and cloud management products, as well as implementation strategies that traverse both specialties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Download our editors’ PDF &lt;a href="https://us.resources.networkworld.com/resources/download-our-hybrid-cloud-data-protection-buyers-guide/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;hybrid cloud data protection buyer’s guide&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; today!]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="in-this-buyers-guide"&gt;In this buyer’s guide&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data protection for hybrid clouds explained&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Why hybrid clouds need data protection&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to look for in a data protection platform for hybrid clouds&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Major trends in data protection for hybrid clouds&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Leading vendors for data protection of hybrid clouds&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to ask before buying data protection for hybrid clouds&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Essential reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-hybrid-clouds-need-data-protection"&gt;Why hybrid clouds need data protection&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In simpler times, organizational data was secured within the confines of the data center. Data is now scattered across internet of things (IoT) devices, remote endpoints, edge locations, and several types of cloud providers. According to the Thales Group, a defense-, security-, and aerospace-focused technology firm, 60% of corporate data now resides in the cloud, up from 30% in 2015. And 80% of enterprises have adopted a hybrid computing model.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are the key factors driving the need for data protection platforms in hybrid environments:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ransomware:&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike other forms of malware designed to bring down the network, ransomware attacks specifically target data. A successful ransomware attack can encrypt corporate data, bringing business to a screeching halt. Even worse, attackers can exfiltrate that data and sell it on the &lt;a href="mailto:https://www.csoonline.com/article/564313/what-is-the-dark-web-how-to-access-it-and-what-youll-find.html"&gt;dark web&lt;/a&gt;. The last line of defense against ransomware is having multiple copies of data, backed up and stored in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unplanned outages:&lt;/strong&gt; There have always been outages from natural disasters, but the impact of climate change has upped the ante — prudent organizations should mitigate the risks associated with natural disasters through cloud-based disaster recovery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy:&lt;/strong&gt; Government regulations covering &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570281/csos-ultimate-guide-to-security-and-privacy-laws-regulations-and-compliance.html"&gt;data privacy across the globe&lt;/a&gt; continue to tighten. Both customers and employees expect organizations to not only protect their data but also provide mechanisms letting the owner of the data control how that data is used.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misconfigurations:&lt;/strong&gt; In the public cloud model, the hyperscalers (such as Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, and Microsoft Azure) are responsible for protecting their own infrastructure, but the enterprise using them — you — is responsible for properly configuring and managing its own data in the cloud. One of the most common causes of cloud-based data breaches is a simple misconfiguration of an Amazon S3 storage bucket. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;Cloud security posture management (CSPM) tools&lt;/a&gt; can help identify misconfigurations, among other risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial intelligence:&lt;/strong&gt; Organizations are rushing to take advantage of machine learning, artificial intelligence (AI), including generative AI, but the advanced analytics they rely on must be built on a foundation of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571523/5-top-hybrid-cloud-security-challenges.html"&gt;data that is secure&lt;/a&gt;, reliable, and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; The sheer volume of data is exploding, as well as its value to the organization. This places an increasingly heavy burden on enterprise IT to protect that data, whether it’s generated by an IoT device, a person, or generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-look-for-in-a-data-protection-platform-for-hybrid-clouds"&gt;What to look for in a data protection platform for hybrid clouds&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data protection platforms should include the following features and functionality:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data discovery/classification:&lt;/strong&gt; This nails down exactly what data you have and classifies data based on how sensitive the data is and whether it falls under specific regulatory requirements. Data discovery and classification let organizations apply the appropriate levels of data protection to different types of data sets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerability assessment:&lt;/strong&gt; This identifies potential vulnerabilities in the database infrastructure, including misconfigurations and other security gaps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data protection:&lt;/strong&gt; This applies layered security measures, including encryption of both data at rest and data in transit, data masking, &lt;a href="mailto:https://www.csoonline.com/article/557365/what-is-a-cloud-access-security-broker-and-why-do-i-need-one.html"&gt;CASB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="mailto:https://www.csoonline.com/article/569559/what-is-dlp-how-data-loss-prevention-software-works-and-why-you-need-it.html"&gt;DLP&lt;/a&gt;, and other approaches, such as &lt;a href="mailto:https://www.csoonline.com/article/550036/how-to-bridge-and-secure-air-gap-networks.html"&gt;air gapping&lt;/a&gt; and data immutability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring and analytics:&lt;/strong&gt; This tracks performance and provides &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572813/hyas-brings-security-threat-detection-response-to-production-networks.html"&gt;real-time alerting&lt;/a&gt; and reporting based on full visibility across hybrid cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access control:&lt;/strong&gt; This policy-based access management restricts access to data resources, detects and blocks suspicious activity, and manages user privileges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audit and compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; This enforces separation of duties, provides forensic analysis and compliance audits, and provides reporting capabilities across on-premises, public cloud, and SaaS (software-as-a-service) environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance and scalability:&lt;/strong&gt; This makes sure that data protection mechanisms don’t create bottlenecks that slow down business processes. The data protection platform must be built with scalability and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574539/how-automation-in-cspm-can-improve-cloud-security-2.html"&gt;Automation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; This reduces manual intervention, eliminates mistakes, frees staffers to tackle higher level tasks, and speeds processes, such as recovery time from an outage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="major-trends-in-data-protection-for-hybrid-clouds"&gt;Major trends in data protection for hybrid clouds&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data protection can be performed with on-premises appliances or in the cloud. And organizations can manage their data protection functionality themselves or turn to a managed service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The trend lines are clear: Just as applications and data are moving to the cloud, data protection is moving to the cloud as well, due to the scalability, flexibility, and accessibility that the cloud provides.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The total global data protection market was valued at $136 billion in 2023 and is expected to hit $610 billion by 2022, according to Spherical Insights and Consulting. Data protection as a service (DPaaS) is a fast-growing segment within the overall data protection market, driven by organizations that have adopted hybrid clouds and need to protect data hosted by hyperscalers and SaaS providers, on top of data stored locally. The DPaaS market was estimated at $25 billion in 2024 and is expected to grow 33% a year, hitting $100 billion by 2029, according to research firm &lt;a href="https://www.mordorintelligence.com/industry-reports/data-protection-as-a-service-market"&gt;Mordor Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Phil Goodwin, research vice president for the Infrastructure Systems, Platforms, and Technologies Group at IDC, says, “Data protection as a service remains a very important route to market for data protection software vendors. In some cases, this is data protection software vendors selling directly using DPaaS solutions, and in other cases is it via cloud services providers. Either way, [DPaaS] represents the fastest-growing consumption model and opportunity in the data protection market.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leading-vendors-for-data-protection-of-hybrid-clouds"&gt;Leading vendors for data protection of hybrid clouds&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The list of vendors who provide data protection is lengthy and growing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For enterprises seeking to piece together a multivendor solution:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The leaders in the category of data security platforms are Forcepoint, Google, IBM, Imperva, MicroFocus, Microsoft, Proofpoint, and Varonis, according to Forrester Research.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;When it comes to backup and recovery, Gartner lists the leaders as Cohesity, Commvault, Dell, Rubrik, Veeam, and Veritas, with Druva, HYCU, and IBM described as visionaries. Microsoft and Unitrends are niche players, according to Gartner.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;In the category of DPaaS, Mordor Intelligence lists the top five players as AWS, Cisco, Dell, HPE, and IBM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For organizations seeking a single vendor platform that covers both data security and backup/restore, GigaOm’s 2023 Radar Report for Hybrid Cloud Data Protection for large enterprises cites Cobalt Iron, Cohesity, and Commvault as the most capable providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Research firm GigaOm puts four additional vendors in the leadership category based on their broad platform for data protection as well as their level of innovation: Dell, Druva, HYCU, and Veritas. Top challengers are Rubrik and Veeam. The following vendors are identified by GigaOm as platform providers whose offerings are more mature but less innovative: Arcserve, Atempo, Bacula, IBM, and Unitrends.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are quick snapshots of the overall leaders:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Web Services:&lt;/strong&gt; Under its shared responsibility model, customers are responsible for managing and securing their data in AWS, but AWS offers services for identity and access management, compliance, auditing, governance, encryption, and key management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cisco Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Cisco offers a full complement of data protection products and services, some developed in-house and others delivered through partners. Cisco’s core strength is on the security side, but it also provides an advisory service that helps customers develop a framework for data protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cobalt Iron:&lt;/strong&gt; Cobalt Iron offers strong data protection delivered as a service, with strong ransomware protection, advanced analytics, and comprehensive workload support, including Kubernetes. However, disaster recovery requires third-party integrations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cohesity:&lt;/strong&gt; The C&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574493/cohesity-data-cloud-70-enhances-privileged-access-authentication-ransomware-recovery.html"&gt;ohesity Data Cloud Platform&lt;/a&gt; provides ransomware protection based on immutable snapshots of enterprise data, backups, continuous data protection, a strong &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;Zero Trust&lt;/a&gt; module, automated threat intelligence, and support for compliance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commvault:&lt;/strong&gt; Commvault’s Complete Data Protection portfolio covers data protection, security, data management, backup, and disaster recovery. Customers can choose a self-managed, on-premises model or a fully managed service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dell:&lt;/strong&gt; Dell’s PowerProtect Data Manager and APEX Backup Services provide data protection, backup, disaster recovery, and long-term data retention across single- or multiple-cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Druva:&lt;/strong&gt; The Druva Data Resiliency Cloud delivers a cloud-native, fully managed data protection and management service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HPE:&lt;/strong&gt; HPE offers DPaaS as part of its broader GreenLake edge-to-cloud platform. The GreenLake managed data protection service helps organizations modernize backup, automate processes, protect against data loss and ransomware, and recover from disasters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HYCU:&lt;/strong&gt; HYCU offers deep integration with on-premise or cloud data platforms through its agentless, application-aware solution. HYCU’s strength is disaster recovery; the company offers an automated &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1293481/10-cyber-recovery-providers.html"&gt;disaster recovery service&lt;/a&gt; with a guaranteed recovery time objective (RTO).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IBM:&lt;/strong&gt; IBM’s Security Guardium provides data discovery and classification, data activity monitoring and analytics, near real-time threat response workflows, and automated compliance auditing and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oracle:&lt;/strong&gt; Oracle offers multiple data protection products and managed services covering data classification, encryption, key management, and backup and restore across hybrid environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubrik: &lt;/strong&gt;Rubrik’s strong suit is data security. The Rubrik Security Cloud offers a comprehensive analytics platform with a strong emphasis on metrics and anomaly detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veeam:&lt;/strong&gt; Veeam offers a flexible data protection platform delivered through a modular suite of products, covering a broad set of enterprise workloads. It offers backup as a service through third parties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veritas:&lt;/strong&gt; Building upon its Net Backup data protection offering, Veritas has added the Alta cloud policy engine that includes ransomware protection with data immutability and data recovery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-ask-before-buying-data-protection-for-hybrid-clouds"&gt;What to ask before buying data protection for hybrid clouds&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because every enterprise is different and because hybrid clouds are both complex and varied in their handling of data, you need to get a clear grasp on your specific needs, capabilities, and resources before engaging prospective vendors and then choosing specific solutions for data protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="12-key-questions-to-ask-yourself-before-buying-edge-data-centers"&gt;12 key questions to ask yourself before buying edge data centers&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I know my data? Do I have an accurate assessment of how much data I have, where it’s located, and how it’s stored?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have a process to classify data based on a risk assessment that determines which data is mission-critical to business continuity and which isn’t?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have systems in place to apply continuous vulnerability assessments to identify gaps in security coverage?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Have I deployed data protection tools designed to guard against data loss across the entire hybrid cloud environment?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have data backup systems with multiple copies of cloud-based data to protect against ransomware attacks?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Have I done an assessment of how long the company can endure an outage before critical business processes are affected?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have a disaster recovery plan that meets those recovery-time objectives?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I conduct regularly scheduled &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570871/tabletop-exercises-explained-definition-examples-and-objectives.html"&gt;tabletop disaster-recovery exercises&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I have a disaster-recovery playbook that provides step-by-step instructions to key stakeholders in the event of an outage?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I understand the data protection regulations that apply to my company, and do I have a plan for compliance and reporting?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What is my biggest pain point? What are the strengths and weaknesses of my current data protection infrastructure?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do I need a vendor with a specific area of expertise that I can plug into my existing infrastructure, or am I looking for a platform partner that can take over my entire data protection functionality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="12-questions-to-ask-vendors-on-data-protection-for-hybrid-clouds"&gt;12 questions to ask vendors on data protection for hybrid clouds&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your solution cover all my data types no matter where they are located across my hybrid cloud infrastructure?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do you have a platform that covers all my data protection needs, or do you partner with third parties to fill out your data protection portfolio? If the latter, how well are those components integrated?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Does you solution provide multiple backups that protect me against ransomware attacks, including advanced methods such as data immutability and air gapping?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Does your solution provide recovery times that meet my requirements for business continuity?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What types of service level agreements do you offer?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Do you support all of my computing platforms; for example, Kubernetes, Microsoft Hyper-V, Red Hat, and VMware?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Will your data protection solution scale to meet my rapidly expanding data protection requirements?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What type of automation do you provide to help orchestrate disaster-recovery processes?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What type of analytics and reporting do you provide?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Can you conduct disaster-recovery testing without taking any of my systems offline?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What are your procedures for safely disposing of data that is no longer needed?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What are your pricing models, and how do you help me calculate ROI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="essential-reading"&gt;Essential reading&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/965660/protecting-data-in-a-hybrid-cloud-environment.html"&gt;Protecting data in a hybrid cloud environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/969812/backup-lessons-from-a-cloud-storage-disaster.html"&gt;Backup lessons from a cloud-storage disaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571523/5-top-hybrid-cloud-security-challenges.html"&gt;5 top hybrid cloud security challenges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;How to choose the best cloud security posture management (CSPM) tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570281/csos-ultimate-guide-to-security-and-privacy-laws-regulations-and-compliance.html"&gt;Security and privacy laws, regulations, and compliance: The complete guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on Networkworld as “&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3568695/buyers-guide-data-protection-for-hybrid-clouds.html"&gt;Buyer’s guide: Data protection for hybrid clouds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071098/what-to-look-for-in-a-data-protection-platform-for-hybrid-clouds.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol conference warns: cybercrime fight hinges on access to data</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</link>
      <description>Criminals are exploiting encryption, anonymisation and emerging technologies faster than regulators and law enforcement can respond – making access to data the decisive challenge in the fight against cybercrime. This was the warning sounded at Europol’s 4th Annual Cybercrime Conference this week.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s most innovative law enforcement projects honoured at Europol’s 2025 Excellence Awards</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-most-innovative-law-enforcement-projects-honoured-europol’s-2025-excellence-awards</link>
      <description>At the annual European Police Chiefs Convention (EPCC) in The Hague, Europol announced the winners of the 2025 Europol Excellence Awards in Innovation. These awards recognise outstanding projects that demonstrate how innovation can strengthen operational effectiveness, ethical policing, and cross-border cooperation in Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-most-innovative-law-enforcement-projects-honoured-europol’s-2025-excellence-awards</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luxury hybrid car thieves taken down in Belgium, Italy and Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</link>
      <description>A highly specialised organised crime network responsible for the theft of more than 100 luxury hybrid cars has been dismantled in an international operation led by the Italian Carabinieri with support from Europol and Eurojust. The estimated value of all stolen cars is of at least EUR 3 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dull but dangerous: A guide to 15 overlooked cybersecurity blind spots</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071219/dull-but-dangerous-a-guide-to-15-overlooked-cybersecurity-blind-spots.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Resilience fails in the seams: tiny misconfigurations, forgotten defaults and silent drifts that escape the spotlight but magnify blast radius when things go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most breaches don’t begin with exotic zero-day vulnerabilities. They pivot on mundane gaps: time drift that breaks forensics, stale DNS records ripe for hijacking or that printer nobody remembers buying.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’ve seen the pattern. The attacker finds the boring vulnerability you forgot existed and then uses it to compromise everything you actually care about.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Systemic resilience demands closing low-glamour gaps across identity, config, telemetry, cloud and recovery. These aren’t the sexy vulnerabilities that win conference talks. They’re the silent killers that turn incidents into disasters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4003108/unmasking-the-silent-saboteur-you-didnt-know-was-running-the-show.html"&gt;Unmasking the silent saboteur you didn’t know was running the show&lt;/a&gt;,” I examined how subtle, often-overlooked security gaps can quietly erode an organization’s defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re discussing 15 blind spots across six non-overlapping domains. No overlap, no omissions; just a clean checklist you can assign, measure and close before attackers find them first.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="time-telemetry-integrity"&gt;Time &amp;amp; telemetry integrity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you can’t trust time and logs, you can’t trust detection, forensics or root cause.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="server-time-synchronization-ntp-drift"&gt;Server time synchronization (NTP drift)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Skewed clocks create a perfect cover for attackers. When your servers disagree about when events happened, correlation dies and forensics becomes fiction. Yet most organizations treat NTP like plumbing: set once and forget.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fix this now: Enforce a secure NTP hierarchy with authenticated sources. Monitor offset religiously. Block unauthorized NTP traffic at the perimeter. &lt;a href="https://www.twingate.com/blog/glossary/ntp%20drift" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Set alerts for drift beyond 100ms.&lt;/a&gt; Your &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_information_and_event_management" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SIEM&lt;/a&gt; will thank you and so will your incident responders when they’re not chasing ghosts at 3 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="overlooked-logging-gaps"&gt;Overlooked logging gaps&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’re drowning in firewall logs while blind to what matters. No endpoint telemetry. No &lt;a href="https://documentation.cloud-iam.com/how-to-guides/audit-logs.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;cloud IAM audit trails&lt;/a&gt;. No process creation monitoring. Attackers love this imbalance; they operate where you can’t see.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Define your minimum telemetry baseline today. Every endpoint needs EDR coverage. Log every identity action. Capture every cloud control plane change. Centralize these signals, validate their completeness on a weekly basis and actually test whether your detections are effective. Most don’t.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With trustworthy signals locked down, control who and what can act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="identity-edge"&gt;Identity &amp;amp; edge&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers favor the path of least governance: service principals, &lt;a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/cybersecurity-101/cybersecurity/byod-security-risks/#:~:text=It%20presents%20a%20security%20risk,that%20compromise%20sensitive%20company%20information." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BYOD&lt;/a&gt; and devices nobody owns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="privileged-service-accounts"&gt;Privileged service accounts&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Is that service account with domain admin rights and a password set in 2019? Attackers know about it. Non-human identities proliferate faster than you can govern them, each carrying static secrets and excessive permissions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Start your inventory tomorrow. Map every service account to an owner. Enforce least privilege ruthlessly. Rotate secrets quarterly or move to managed identities. Enable MFA where possible; yes, even for service accounts. Monitor continuously for anomalous behavior. These accounts don’t take vacations; unusual activity means compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="mobile-device-management-byod-sprawl"&gt;Mobile device management (BYOD sprawl)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jumpcloud.com/blog/saas-sprawl#:~:text=Bring%20Your%20Own%20Device%20(BYOD,the%20number%20of%20unmanaged%20applications." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BYOD sprawl&lt;/a&gt; means that corporate data lives on personal phones you don’t control. One compromised device can lead to persistent access to email, files and chat. Your security perimeter now includes devices bought on Amazon or at Best Buy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enforce &lt;a href="https://www.miradore.com/blog/mam-vs-mdm/#:~:text=Both%20MDM%20and%20MAM%20solutions,applications%20installed%20on%20the%20device." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MDM or MAM&lt;/a&gt;, no exceptions. Configure conditional access based on device compliance. Containerize work apps to prevent data mingling. Enable rapid remote wipe and test it quarterly to ensure its effectiveness. When someone leaves, their personal phone shouldn’t keep your corporate secrets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="insecure-printer-iot-devices"&gt;Insecure printer &amp;amp; IoT devices&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Default credentials on flat networks are attackers’ favorite combination. That smart TV in the boardroom has been running Linux since 2018. The printer has admin/admin credentials. Both sit on the same network as your domain controllers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Segment immediately. Change every default credential. Create a firmware patching cycle, yes, even for printers. Disable services you don’t use (spoiler: that’s most of them). Monitor east-west traffic between these devices and critical systems. When your printer starts talking to your database server, you’ve got problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identities and edges controlled; now harden the substrate they run on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="configuration-crypto-hygiene"&gt;Configuration &amp;amp; crypto hygiene&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Quiet configuration debt multiplies attack paths. Crypto lag invites downgrade and interception.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="firmware-bios-uefi-updates"&gt;Firmware &amp;amp; BIOS/UEFI updates&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Firmware lives below your OS, making it perfect for persistence. Yet most organizations never patch it. Your servers run BIOS versions from their manufacture date, each carrying known vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Include firmware in your patch SLAs starting next month. Enable attestation to detect tampering. Configure secure boot everywhere. Subscribe to vendor security alerts; firmware vulnerabilities don’t make headlines until they’re weaponized.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="obsolete-encryption-protocols"&gt;Obsolete encryption protocols&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’re still running TLS 1.0 for that one legacy app. SSL 3.0 remains enabled “just in case.” Weak ciphers persist because nobody wants to break compatibility. Attackers exploit this hesitation daily.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ionos.co.uk/digitalguide/server/security/tls-vs-ssl/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Turn off everything below TLS 1.2 this weekend&lt;/a&gt;. Enforce modern cipher suites only. Audit certificate hygiene monthly; expired certs and weak keys multiply risk. Break compatibility now or attackers will break confidentiality later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="insecure-default-configurations-in-non-production-environments"&gt;Insecure default configurations in non-production environments&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s just dev” becomes “how did they get production data?” &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa23-278a#:~:text=1.,code%20execution%20and%20lateral%20movement." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Weak non-prod settings leak into production or expose real data in lower environments.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implement golden images across all environments. Enforce policy-as-code to prevent drift. Store secrets in vaults, never in config files. Ensure non-production security is equivalent to the production baseline; attackers don’t distinguish between your environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The surface hardened, now close external trust abuses you don’t see.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dns-web-trust-boundaries"&gt;DNS &amp;amp; web trust boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trust begins with names and links. Clean them or attackers will.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="old-dns-records"&gt;Old DNS records&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Orphaned subdomains enable instant phishing infrastructure. That forgotten CNAME pointing to a decommissioned service? Attackers can claim it tomorrow and inherit your domain’s reputation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Inventory your entire zone monthly. Tag every record with an owner. Auto-prune records unused for 90 days. Require two approvals for DNS changes: typos in DNS last forever.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="third-party-open-redirects"&gt;Third-party open redirects&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Your trusted domain launders malicious &lt;a href="https://learn.snyk.io/lesson/open-redirect/?ecosystem=javascript" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;links through redirect parameters&lt;/a&gt;. Users see your URL and click confidently into compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Validate every redirect target against an allow-list. Sign redirect tokens and expire them quickly. Monitor referrer logs for abuse patterns. Your domain reputation takes years to build and minutes to destroy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Names clean, now tame the cloud and SaaS sprawl powering your business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-saas-sprawl"&gt;Cloud &amp;amp; SaaS sprawl&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud speed without guardrails breeds invisible debt: unused assets, unknown apps, unsafe partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="shine-a-light-on-shadow-saas"&gt;Shine a light on shadow SaaS&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Think you don’t have &lt;a href="https://jumpcloud.com/blog/saas-sprawl#:~:text=Bring%20Your%20Own%20Device%20(BYOD,the%20number%20of%20unmanaged%20applications." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;shadow SaaS&lt;/a&gt;? Think again. Marketing just signed up for a “free” AI tool with your entire customer database. Sales uploaded contracts to an unvetted platform. Data exits your governance through a browser tab.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Deploy &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/security/business/security-101/what-is-a-cloud-access-security-broker-casb#:~:text=Cloud%20access%20security%20broker%20(CASB)%20defined,devices%2C%20and%20maintain%20regulatory%20compliance." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CASB&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/defender-cloud-apps/security-saas" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SSPM&lt;/a&gt; for discovery and you’ll find three times more apps than expected. Create an intake process that’s faster than going rogue. Classify data and block uploads to unsanctioned apps. Provide sanctioned alternatives before people find their own.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="orphaned-cloud-assets"&gt;Orphaned cloud assets&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forgotten S3 buckets with customer data. Test instances with production access. Previous employees’ personal projects are still running on corporate accounts. Cloud sprawl and &lt;a href="https://www.cloudoptimo.com/blog/detecting-orphaned-resources-using-aws-config-rules/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;orphaned assets&lt;/a&gt; create an invisible attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mandate tagging on creation: no tag, no resource. Enforce life cycle policies that delete untagged resources after 30 days. Run attack-surface scans weekly. Auto-quarantine assets without owners. Your cloud bill and security posture will both improve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="inter-organizational-api-trust"&gt;Inter-organizational API trust&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Partner APIs with permanent tokens and admin scopes. Vendor integrations that haven’t been reviewed since implementation. Each &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0169023X24000041" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;inter-organizational connection&lt;/a&gt; becomes a bridge that attackers cross.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Contract security requirements before integration. Implement &lt;a href="https://www.form3.tech/blog/engineering/buckle-up-your-mtls-with-oauth-2-0-client-authentication" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;mTLS and OAuth&lt;/a&gt; with least privilege. Issue per-client keys, never shared credentials. Rotate tokens quarterly and monitor for unusual patterns. Trust your partners but verify their security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With surface and providers governed, protect your build chain and last line of defense.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="software-supply-chain-recovery-readiness"&gt;Software supply chain &amp;amp; recovery readiness&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compromise upstream or kill backups first; either path maximizes damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="code-reuse-forgotten-dependencies"&gt;Code reuse &amp;amp; forgotten dependencies&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3377024.3377712" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Your app includes libraries&lt;/a&gt; last updated when Obama was president. Transitive dependencies hide vulnerabilities you’ve never heard of. Each component becomes an attack vector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Generate &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/sbom" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SBOMs&lt;/a&gt; for everything you build. Run SCA tools that break builds on critical findings. Pin versions and update deliberately. Verify provenance and require signed artifacts. Your supply chain is only as strong as its weakest dependency.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="assumed-security-of-backups"&gt;Assumed security of backups&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Backups sitting online, unencrypted, untested, are ransomware’s first target. You assume they work until you need them. Then you discover they don’t.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implement &lt;a href="https://www.techtarget.com/searchdatabackup/definition/3-2-1-Backup-Strategy" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the 3-2-1 backup strategy&lt;/a&gt; immediately. Create immutable, air-gapped copies. Test restores quarterly, not just “completed” logs, but actual data recovery. Restrict restore permissions more tightly than backup permissions. Encrypt everything, everywhere. Your backups are your last hope; treat them accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="earning-resilience-through-maintenance"&gt;Earning resilience through maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Resilience isn’t earned in memos. It’s earned in maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These 15 items close the most abused seams across signals, identity, configuration, trust, cloud and recovery. Here’s your 90-day action plan:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First 30 days: Inventory and measure.&lt;/strong&gt; Check NTP drift, assess log coverage, map service accounts, audit DNS hygiene, discover shadow SaaS and test backup restoration.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next 30 days: Enforce baselines.&lt;/strong&gt; Patch firmware, harden crypto, achieve non-prod parity, deploy MDM everywhere, implement cloud tagging and lifecycle policies.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final 30 days: Validate resilience.&lt;/strong&gt; Run restore drills, test detection effectiveness, review API contracts and establish SBOM governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Assign domain owners today. Track percentage of compliant assets, mean time to patch firmware, log coverage rates, backup restore success rates and percentage of APIs with least-privilege scopes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Put these 15 items into your audit plan and quarterly KRIs. Close them before your adversaries open them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The boring vulnerabilities kill you slowly, then suddenly. Don’t let them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071219/dull-but-dangerous-a-guide-to-15-overlooked-cybersecurity-blind-spots.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory (AV25-640)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-641)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-641</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-641</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-642)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-642</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-642</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-643)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-643</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-643</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–644)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-644</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-644</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-645)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-645</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-645</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI red flags, ethics boards and the real threat of AGI today</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071222/ai-red-flags-ethics-boards-and-the-real-threat-of-agi-today.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Paul Dongha is head of responsible AI and AI strategy at NatWest Group, where he leads the development of frameworks to ensure artificial intelligence is deployed safely, ethically and in line with regulatory expectations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Previously serving as group head of data and AI ethics at Lloyds Banking Group, &lt;a href="https://champions-speakers.co.uk/speaker-agent/paul-dongha" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Paul Dongha&lt;/a&gt; has been at the forefront of embedding transparency, accountability and trust into enterprise AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With extensive experience shaping how financial institutions approach emerging technologies, Dongha offers a clear-eyed perspective on both the opportunities and the risks that AI presents for businesses and society.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this exclusive interview with the Champions Speakers Agency, he discusses the ethical red flags CISOs and boards must monitor, the responsibilities of regulators and the real-world risks that demand attention today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="q-what-ethical-red-flags-should-cisos-and-boards-watch-for-when-deploying-ai-inside-their-organizations"&gt;Q: What ethical red flags should CISOs and boards watch for when deploying AI inside their organizations?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Dongha&lt;/strong&gt;: “I think some of the standout issues and risks that we have with AI systems that have come to light recently are things like human agency.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI systems have the ability to create sophisticated outputs and, to some extent, that takes away from humans their ability to make the right decisions. The loss of human agency is something that we have to be very aware of and that risk has to be mitigated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Another risk is robustness. AI systems have the ability to sometimes give different answers to the same questions, so I think technical robustness — ensuring AI systems generate the same result for the same question over time — is something that has to be looked at as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Data privacy is another. The ability of AI systems to inadvertently leak confidential or private information about individuals or organizations is something we also have to guard against.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I think transparency is a really important one. The way a machine learning or an AI system works is nonlinear, so understanding how it arrives at a decision is hard to do. There are techniques that allow us to introspect how an AI system derived a particular answer, but they are only approximations. Transparency of the algorithm, whether it’s machine learning or generative AI, is something that we have to pay close attention to.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Then there’s bias. We’ve seen bias creep into many systems and that really takes away their ability to support diversity and inclusion. Those biases can be inherent in the data that trains our AI systems or within the system development life cycle. It’s an ongoing area of work and with generative AI, it’s a particular problem because of the vast amount of training data involved.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“And finally, accountability. Organizations, particularly commercial organizations, need to demonstrate that they’ve got processes in place where, if people need to seek redress for the output of an AI system, they’re able to do so. Firms should take full accountability for how they create systems and how they operate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="q-should-every-large-enterprise-have-an-ai-ethics-board-and-what-should-its-remit-include"&gt;Q: Should every large enterprise have an AI ethics board — and what should its remit include?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Dongha&lt;/strong&gt;: “When it comes to the executives and decision-makers of large corporations, I think there are a few things here.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Firstly, I believe an ethics board is absolutely mandatory. It should be comprised of senior executives drawn from a diverse background within the organization, where those participants have a real feel for their customers and what their customers want.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Those members should be trained in ethics, should understand the pitfalls of artificial intelligence and should make decisions around which AI applications are exposed to customers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Importantly, those ethics boards shouldn’t rely just on IT systems to answer ethical questions. Ethics boils down to a discussion between different stakeholders. An ethics board is there to debate and to discuss edge cases — for example, the launch of an application where there may be disagreement over whether it could cause harm or whether it could be a surprise to customers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I also believe a chief responsible AI officer should be appointed to the board of every bank — and arguably every large organization — to oversee the end-to-end risk management of applications both during build and post-deployment. Ethics has to be considered at every stage of development and launch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Risk management practices and the audit function should all be folded into the remit of a responsible AI officer to ensure strong oversight.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="q-are-regulators-and-governments-moving-fast-enough-to-keep-ai-risks-under-control"&gt;Q: Are regulators and governments moving fast enough to keep AI risks under control?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Dongha&lt;/strong&gt;: “I believe our governments and democratically elected institutions, as well as sectoral regulators, have a huge role to play in this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We as a society elect our governments to look after us. We have a legislative process — even with something as simple as driving, we have rules to ensure that vehicles are maneuvered correctly. Without those rules, driving would be very dangerous. AI is no different: Legislation and rules around how AI is used and deployed are incredibly important.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Corporations are accountable to shareholders, so the bottom line is always going to be very important to them. That means it would be unwise to let corporations themselves implement the guardrails around AI. Governments have to be involved in setting what is and isn’t reasonable, what is too high a risk and what is in the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Technology companies need to be part of that conversation, but they should not be leading it. Those conversations must be led by the institutions we elect to look after society.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="q-how-real-is-the-threat-of-artificial-general-intelligence-and-what-risks-demand-our-attention-today"&gt;Q: How real is the threat of artificial general intelligence — and what risks demand our attention today?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Dongha&lt;/strong&gt;: “Artificial general intelligence, which is about AI approaching human-level intelligence, has been the holy grail of AI research for decades. We’re not there yet. Many aspects of human intelligence — social interactions, emotional intelligence, even elements of computer vision — are things the current generation of AI is simply incapable of.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The recent transformer-based technologies look extremely sophisticated, but when you open the hood and examine how they operate, they do not work in the way humans think or behave. I don’t believe we’re anywhere near achieving AGI and in fact the current approaches are unlikely to get us there.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“So my message is that there’s no need to be worried about any imminent superintelligence or Terminator situation. But we do need to be aware that, in the future, it’s possible. That means we have to guard against it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the meantime, there are real and pressing risks with today’s generation of AI: weaponization, disinformation and the ability for nefarious states to use generative AI to influence electorates. Even without AGI, current systems have great power — and in the wrong hands, that power can cause serious harm to society.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071222/ai-red-flags-ethics-boards-and-the-real-threat-of-agi-today.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redis security advisory (AV25-646)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/redis-security-advisory-av25-646</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/redis-security-advisory-av25-646</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From crypto-enabled money laundering to online recruitment of minors: European Police Chiefs tackle criminal threats</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</link>
      <description>The annual event brought together the heads of national police organisations, customs administrations, representatives from the European Commission, and international partners to discuss the most pressing threats to security in Europe.Catherine De Bolle, Europol’s Executive Director, and Lene Steen, Deputy National Commissioner of the Danish Police, opened the conference. Keynote addresses were delivered by EU Commissioner for Internal Affairs and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/crypto-enabled-money-laundering-to-online-recruitment-of-minors-european-police-chiefs-tackle-criminal-threats</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Major blow to billion-euro glass eel trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>The latest iteration of Operation LAKE, which ran from October 2024 to June 2025, uncovered large-scale trafficking networks and disrupted the flow of live eels destined for illegal farms in Asia.The operation led to:16,131 inspections carried out across Europe26 arrests22 tonnes of glass eels seizedOrganised crime at the heart of traffickingInvestigations revealed that several organised crime groups were driving the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-013 – Vulnerability impacting Oracle E-Business Suite - CVE-2025-61882</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-647)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-648)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfeit and substandard food worth EUR 95 million seized in global operation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</link>
      <description>Europol, OLAF, DG SANTE and 31 countries across Europe and beyond, together with food and beverage producers from the private sector, joined forces in the fourteenth edition of Operation OPSON. This yearly effort targets the criminals behind counterfeit and substandard food and beverages. Law enforcement, customs and food regulatory agencies seized 259 012 packages, 1 416 168 litres of beverages and 11 566 958 kilograms of food, including meat and seafood.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted five key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-649)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-650)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 19:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV25-651)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-603) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esri security advisory (AV25-652)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISOs must rethink the tabletop, as 57% of incidents have never been rehearsed</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071102/cisos-must-rethink-the-tabletop-as-57-of-incidents-have-never-been-rehearsed.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly three out of every five (57%) significant cyber incidents involve attacks the cybersecurity team had not prepared for, suggesting CISOs need to re-evaluate — and in some cases recommit to — their tabletop strategies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://cytactic.com/resources/cybersecurity-incident-response-management-report-2025/"&gt;Cytactic 2025 State of Cyber Incident Response Management (CIRM) Report&lt;/a&gt;, which surveyed “480 senior US cybersecurity leaders, including 165 CISOs,” that 57% figure “reveals a major vulnerability. Organizations often train for known threats like ransomware, but these incidents prove that the real chaos comes from the unexpected.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, security teams may be ill-equipped to handle novel threats if they don’t continuously refresh their tabletops, the report concluded. “The true benefit comes from the ability to make these exercises relevant and realistic,” according to the report. “By building simulations that are tailor-made to the organization, industry, sector, risk, and threat profile, these exercises become more than just a security drill. They transform into a critical tool for alignment across the entire business.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts and cybersecurity consultants see multiple problems with how enterprises &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570871/tabletop-exercises-explained-definition-examples-and-objectives.html"&gt;conduct tabletops&lt;/a&gt; and other preparation exercises, ranging from not getting realistic enough to testing grand but unlikely attack scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One consultant, who asked that his name not be used, gave an example of a recent tabletop where the enterprise had purchased burner phones for all relevant personnel so that they could communicate securely in case the attacker was monitoring communications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the attack exercise, management insisted on participants actually using their burners in the run through only to find that many employees took a long time to find the burner phones because they didn’t remember where they were hidden. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In another instance, SOC staffers found the lists of people that need to be contacted during a major breach. But when the CISO insisted the team actually call, message, or email those contacts, they discovered that many of the phone numbers or messaging addresses were disabled. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It really is impossible to prepare specifically for an attack,” says &lt;a href="https://moorinsightsstrategy.com/team/will-townsend/"&gt;Will Townsend&lt;/a&gt;, a VP and principal analyst at Moor Insights &amp;amp; Strategy. “You can have the best plan, but bouncing emails and not being able to find the backup phones, that’s a problem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="focus-on-roleplaying-smaller-attacks"&gt;Focus on roleplaying smaller attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/vincent-stoffer"&gt;Vincent Stoffer&lt;/a&gt;, CTO for security vendor Corelight,suggests CISOs focus more on smaller breaches rather than massive attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many tabletop exercises specifically focus on the technical elements from the bottom up [and] over-index on dramatic breaches rather than realistic adversary tactics,” Stoffer says, adding that, regardless of the size of the attack, most cybercriminals prefer subtle tactics that are often not anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attackers more often succeed through subtle behaviors like lateral movement or quiet data exfiltration that don’t get simulated enough,” Stoffer says. Attackers are “going to use whatever methods will get them access to the objective, usually the crown jewels, complete compromise of an Active Directory, identity server, PII, etc. They may start very slowly and methodically to avoid detection, or they may use well-worn but generally less alarm raising techniques for initial access like phishing or credential harvesting. Once they have established a foothold in the organization, they can move quickly and quietly using the knowledge they’ve gained in the environment, the observed tools, etc., to avoid triggering alarms.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What he sees most enterprise cybersecurity teams testing, however, is quite different.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Contrast this with a simulated exercise that relies more on a hypothesis or specific trigger like an alert that a host has been infected with malware. While it’s still testing the system and process for IR [&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829684/how-to-create-an-effective-incident-response-plan.html"&gt;incident response&lt;/a&gt;], it’s going to generally require less critical thinking, exploration, and discovery to play out the scenario,” Stoffer points out. “This leads to further trotting the well-worn path that the SOC team knows and understands, which while still helpful as an exercise, I would argue that more is gained by approaching the exercise using more subtle and realistic attack methods.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.forrester.com/analyst-bio/jeff-pollard/BIO10584"&gt;Jeff Pollard&lt;/a&gt;, VP and principal analyst at Forrester, stresses that working through the details of contacting people is often overlooked. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The problem with tabletops is that we try to do too much at once,” Pollard says, suggesting a focus on things such as “the CISO is on a plane and can’t talk right now. Do we have to talk with customers? How many calls does the CEO need to be on? Can we use the COO for some of those? What about partners?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pollard also echoes concerns about burner phone problems. “We bought everyone burner phones, but do we know where they are? Are they charged? Do [staffers] know the number of their burner phone? In case of a full system outage, did someone think to store paper?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/erik-avakian"&gt;Erik Avakian&lt;/a&gt;, technical counselor at Info-Tech Research Group, sees a lot of enterprises practicing tabletops for the wrong reasons. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A lot of these folk are only doing it once a year and sometimes they are just doing it for their compliance and insurance, just as a checkbox,” Avakian observes. He encourages CISOs to “really play it out” and to match the tension, stress, and timing of an actual attack. “Everyone has their breaking point. We need to learn those things.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="future-proof-attack-scenarios"&gt;Future-proof attack scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As for the central problem of not knowing what kind of attacks to plan for, Avakian suggests using internal teams or partners to roleplay the most likely attack vectors. To save money, he encourages enterprises to partner with universities for imaginative threat planning and to work with &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567485/what-is-an-isac-or-isao-how-these-cyber-threat-information-sharing-organizations-improve-security.html"&gt;vertical-specific ISACs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivanshefrin/"&gt;Ivan Shefrin&lt;/a&gt;, executive director for managed services at Comcast Business, offers specific suggestions on the kinds of attacks where he would encourage exercises to focus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Traditional training exercises tend to focus on familiar threats or perimeter attacks, but we’re seeing attackers constantly find new ways to breach corporate networks. Take low-effort, drive-by compromises. They require no user interaction beyond visiting a malicious site, bypassing awareness training entirely, which is why technical controls remain mission-critical,” Shefrin says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Then there are high-speed, short-burst DDoS attacks, which probe and test defenses without setting off alarms. We observed increased use of these attacks, with many lasting fewer than 10 seconds,” he adds. “We also noted a surge in carpet-bombing DDoS, where attackers spread traffic across multiple IP addresses or subnets simultaneously to complicate mitigation. Such attacks can evade defenses that focus on a single IP while overwhelming networks in aggregate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as the executive director of a directory of former government and military specialists called FormerGov, says CISOs need to get comfortable with the fact that these tabletops “are going to be more reactive than proactive because we can speculate what the next thing is going to be, but we might be wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some specific advice from Levine is to not assume that the enterprise is always going to be the target. Roleplay scenarios where different global partners are attacked, he says. “Your options [with a partner being attacked] may be more limited, but you still have options.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Levine also encourages CISOs to relax and not panic that they can’t test everything. “You’re not going to be able to test every scenario through a tabletop,” he says. “But by testing some, you will build muscle memory.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;See also:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570871/tabletop-exercises-explained-definition-examples-and-objectives.html"&gt;Tabletop exercises explained: Definition, examples, and objectives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/555131/how-to-conduct-a-tabletop-exercise.html"&gt;How to conduct a tabletop exercise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1311295/4-tabletop-exercises-every-security-team-should-run.html"&gt;4 tabletop exercises every security team should run&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518982/tabletop-exercise-scenarios.html"&gt;Tabletop exercise scenarios: 3 real-world examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/549624/planning-for-a-security-emergency-from-the-tabletop-down.html"&gt;6 tips for effective tabletop exercises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/514469/security-simulations-this-is-only-a-test.html"&gt;Security simulations: This is only a test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071102/cisos-must-rethink-the-tabletop-as-57-of-incidents-have-never-been-rehearsed.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vom CISO zum Chief Risk Architect</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072083/vom-ciso-zum-chief-risk-architect.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 7000w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_2666021407.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Der moderne CISO wird zum Chief Risk Architect.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;thanmano – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jahrelang waren CISOs im Maschinenraum der IT tätig und konzentrierten sich auf die Einhaltung von Vorschriften, die Verwaltung von Firewalls, Patching und die Reaktion auf Vorfälle. Ihr Hauptziel war es, einen Cyberangriff zu verhindern und die Sicherheit aufrechtzuerhalten. Doch dieses Modell wird der Komplexität moderner Bedrohungen nicht mehr gerecht. Angesichts zahlreicher sich überschneidender Vorschriften wie NIS2, DORA, dem AI Act und einer von globaler Instabilität geprägten Landschaft ist die Rolle des CISO über ihre operativen Ursprünge hinausgewachsen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="einfuhrung-des-chief-risk-architect"&gt;Einführung des Chief Risk Architect&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495028/chief-information-security-officer-ein-neues-berufsbild-fur-cisos.html"&gt;zukunftsfähige CISO&lt;/a&gt; ist eine geschäftsorientierte Führungskraft, die durch Resilienz leitet. Als Chief Risk Architect ist er für die Kontinuität verantwortlich und nicht nur für die Anzahl der Vorfälle. Er geht von Störungen aus, minimiert deren Auswirkungen und entwickelt Systeme, die diese überstehen. Durch seine Rolle entstehen neue Fragen: Wie schnell können wir unsere Daten und den Betrieb mit minimalen Auswirkungen auf das Geschäft wiederherstellen? Was ist unsere Wiederherstellungsbasis? Wie können wir unsere Widerstandsfähigkeit gegenüber Aufsichtsbehörden, Partnern und Aktionären nachweisen? Das sind keine IT-Anliegen, sondern geschäftliche Notwendigkeiten, und sie benötigen Führungspersönlichkeiten, die Silos überbrücken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492180/cyber-risk-assessments-risikobewertung-hilft-cisos.html"&gt;Cyber Risk Assessments – Risikobewertung hilft CISOs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="neue-fahigkeiten-fur-eine-neue-ara"&gt;Neue Fähigkeiten für eine neue Ära&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Entwicklung bringt eine Reihe neuer benötigter Fähigkeiten mit sich. Cybersicherheit, einschließlich technischer Fachkenntnisse, ist nach wie vor entscheidend, muss aber mit Risikoquantifizierung, Enterprise Risk Management, Bedrohungserkennung, geopolitischer Kompetenz und dem Bewusstsein für Rechtsvorschriften kombiniert werden. Der moderne Sicherheitsverantwortliche muss sich mit Business Continuity und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069533/disaster-recovery-und-business-continuity-effektiv-planen.html"&gt;Desaster Recovery&lt;/a&gt; auskennen, und nicht nur das Thema Incident Response kennen. Außerdem muss er die Sprache von Rechtsberatern, Aufsichtsbehörden und Vorständen sprechen sowie die Dynamik der Haftung, die Risiken in der Lieferkette und die versteckten Schwachstellen der digitalen Verflechtung verstehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-neuausrichtung-der-rolle-ist-entscheidend-fur-die-bindung-von-talenten"&gt;Die Neuausrichtung der Rolle ist entscheidend für die Bindung von Talenten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Von CISOs wird heute erwartet, dass sie Sicherheitsverletzungen verhindern, die sie nicht kontrollieren können, und für Risiken einstehen, die sie nicht zu verantworten haben. Es überrascht nicht, dass viele von ihnen ausbrennen. Daher verlassen einige dieses Berufsfeld ganz. In Deutschland geben 67 Prozent der CISOs in der Finanzbranche an, dass es immer schwieriger wird, eine Stelle im Sicherheitsbereich zu besetzen, – ein Zeichen dafür, dass die Reputation des Berufs nicht zukunftsfähig ist.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein oft übersehener Faktor, der diese Diskrepanz verursacht, ist die Organisationsstruktur. CISOs, die an Chief Technology Officers (CTOs) oder Chief Financial Officers (CFOs) berichten, haben häufig nicht die strategische Sichtbarkeit oder den Einfluss, um Entscheidungen über Unternehmensrisiken zu treffen. Da sie an Technologie- oder Finanzsilos gebunden sind, sind sie gezwungen, systemische Risiken von der Seitenlinie zu verwalten, aber nicht aktiv mitzuspielen. Um effektiv führen zu können, müssen sich die Sicherheitsverantwortlichen direkt mit dem Vorstand oder dem CEO abstimmen – nicht nur, um Vorfälle zu eskalieren, sondern um von Anfang an bei der Gestaltung der Resilienzstrategie mitzuwirken. Die Entwicklung hin zu einem Chief Risk Architect ist also nicht nur eine Frage der Fähigkeiten. Es geht auch um den Sitz am großen Tisch. Denn wohin ein CISO berichtet, bestimmt oft, ob er führen kann – oder nur reagiert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das „Rebranding“ des CISO in einen strategischen, befähigten Risk-Leader könnte dies ändern. Es schafft einen Weg zu mehr Einfluss. Die Aufgabe wird zukunftsorientierter und weniger reaktiv. Zudem hilft es dem Beruf an sich, sich so weiterzuentwickeln, dass die nächste Generation von Führungskräften angezogen wird: Menschen, die geschäftliche Probleme lösen wollen, anstatt nur auf technische Probleme zu reagieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-zukunft-ist-jetzt"&gt;Die Zukunft ist jetzt&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Wandel zum Chief Risk Architect ist keine hypothetische Vorstellung. In fortschrittlichen Unternehmen findet er bereits statt. Dort warten Führungskräfte nicht darauf, in die Vorstandsetage gebeten zu werden, sondern sie kommen mit aussagekräftigen Kennzahlen und Plänen, die Geschäftskontinuität gewährleisten. Sie fördern Resilience by Design. Und sie gewinnen an Einfluss, indem sie Ergebnisse liefern, nicht Warnungen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Rolle des CISO verschwindet nicht, sondern entwickelt sich weiter. Unternehmen stehen vor der Wahl, diesen Wandel aktiv zu gestalten oder das Risiko einzugehen, abgehängt zu werden. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072083/vom-ciso-zum-chief-risk-architect.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle issues second emergency patch for E-Business Suite in two weeks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072174/oracle-issues-second-emergency-patch-for-e-business-suite-in-two-weeks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Oracle has issued its second emergency security update in less than two weeks for its E-Business Suite (EBS), patching a high-severity information disclosure vulnerability that security experts warn could become the next target for ransomware groups already circling the widely deployed enterprise software.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company released a security alert on October 11 addressing &lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-61884" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-61884&lt;/a&gt;, a remotely exploitable flaw in the Runtime UI component of Oracle Configurator that affects EBS versions 12.2.3 through 12.2.14. Rated 7.5 on the CVSS severity scale, the vulnerability allows unauthenticated attackers with network access to steal sensitive data without requiring credentials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This vulnerability is remotely exploitable without authentication, i.e., it may be exploited over a network without the need for a username and password,” &lt;a href="https://www.oracle.com/security-alerts/alert-cve-2025-61884.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oracle stated in its advisory.&lt;/a&gt; “If successfully exploited, this vulnerability may allow access to sensitive resources.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Oracle has not confirmed if CVE-2025-61884 is being actively exploited in the wild. However, the timing has security professionals on high alert. The patch arrived just one week after Oracle released an emergency fix for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4068379/oracle-issues-emergency-patch-for-zero-day-flaw-exploited-by-cl0p-ransomware-gang.html"&gt;CVE-2025-61882, a critical remote code execution flaw&lt;/a&gt; that the Cl0p ransomware gang exploited as a zero-day in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4067501/cl0p-linked-threat-actors-target-oracle-e-business-suite-in-extortion-campaign.html"&gt;a mass data theft campaign&lt;/a&gt; beginning in August.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Given historical targeting and the recent Cl0p ransomware activity, threat actors are likely to express interest and attempt exploitation in the near future,” Arctic Wolf, a cybersecurity operations company, &lt;a href="https://arcticwolf.com/resources/blog-uk/cve-2025-61884-oracle-releases-emergency-patch-for-information-disclosure-flaw/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; in its analysis of CVE-2025-61884.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-erp-systems-have-become-prime-targets"&gt;Why ERP systems have become prime targets&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That warning reflects a broader pattern that security experts are watching closely. The rapid succession of critical EBS vulnerabilities — two emergency patches in two weeks — signals a fundamental shift in how threat actors target enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Back-to-back zero-days in Oracle EBS highlight how threat actors are increasingly targeting high-value enterprise applications that underpin financial and operational workflows,” said Sakshi Grover, senior research manager for cybersecurity services at IDC Asia/Pacific. “These systems are deeply integrated, customized, and difficult to patch quickly, making them attractive targets for exploitation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sunil Varkey, advisor at Beagle Security, argued that the security industry’s historical blind spot around ERP systems has created today’s crisis. “In the past, CISOs saw ERP systems as someone else’s problem, protected by the perimeter, too risky to touch, and too complex to understand,” Varkey said. “ERP systems are no longer isolated. They are now connected to everything: cloud services, supplier portals, e-commerce platforms, and IoT sensors and web-facing components. This has exploded their attack surface.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability affects the same version range as CVE-2025-61882, and organizations running internet-exposed EBS instances face particular risk. Security researchers noted that information disclosure flaws, while less severe than remote code execution vulnerabilities, can provide attackers with reconnaissance data needed to chain multiple exploits together—a technique sophisticated threat actors have demonstrated repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Oracle strongly recommends that customers apply the updates or mitigations provided by this Security Alert as soon as possible,” Rob Duhart, Oracle’s Chief Security Officer, &lt;a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/security/post/alert-cve-2025-61884" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;emphasized&lt;/a&gt; in a separate blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="immediate-actions-for-cve-2025-61884"&gt;Immediate actions for CVE-2025-61884&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Oracle has provided patches for CVE-2025-61884 for all affected versions covered under Premier Support or Extended Support. However, security experts warned that patching alone may not be sufficient. The lessons from the recent CVE-2025-61882 attacks show that organizations need to hunt for signs of prior compromise even after applying fixes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/oracle-ebusiness-suite-zero-day-exploitation" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;detailed technical analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the CVE-2025-61882 campaign, Google Threat Intelligence Group and Mandiant outlined specific hunting techniques for EBS environments. The researchers found that threat actors “store payloads directly in the EBS database” and recommended that “administrators should immediately query the XDO_TEMPLATES_B and XDO_LOBS tables to identify malicious templates.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Google team also emphasized network-level protections. “The observed Java payloads require outbound connections to C2 servers to fetch second-stage implants or exfiltrate data,” the researchers wrote, recommending organizations “block all non-essential outbound traffic from EBS servers to the internet.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has already added CVE-2025-61882 to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2025/10/06/cisa-adds-seven-known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;catalog&lt;/a&gt; with an October 27 deadline for federal agencies. While CVE-2025-61884 has not yet been added to the catalog, organizations should treat both vulnerabilities with equal urgency, given the targeting patterns, experts suggested.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="rethinking-erp-security-strategy"&gt;Rethinking ERP security strategy&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While immediate patching remains critical, security experts argued that the back-to-back Oracle vulnerabilities signal the need for a fundamental rethinking of how organizations secure business-critical applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Beyond immediate remediation, security leaders should strengthen visibility across third-party dependencies, enforce least privilege within ERP environments, and invest in behavioral analytics to detect abnormal transactions before they cause business disruption,” Grover said. According to IDC’s Asia/Pacific Security Survey 2025, cited by Grover, 26% of enterprises are already driving identity-first security strategies aligned with business applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Varkey emphasized that ERP systems must be elevated to critical asset status. “ERP systems should be treated as critical assets with isolation, logging, monitoring, least privileges, segmentation, and zero trust enforcement,” he said. “Security teams should be part of the core governance team and define the security mandates.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3504878/oracle-latest-news-and-insights.html"&gt;Oracle news&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4072017/oracle-debuts-iceberg-compatible-autonomous-ai-lakehouse-to-boost-enterprise-analytics.html"&gt;Oracle debuts Iceberg-compatible Autonomous AI Lakehouse to boost enterprise analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4072128/oracle-targets-agentic-use-cases-with-ai-database-26ai.html"&gt;Oracle targets agentic use cases with AI Database 26ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4069892/oracle-java-management-service-adds-application-analyzer.html"&gt;Oracle Java Management Service adds application analyzer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072174/oracle-issues-second-emergency-patch-for-e-business-suite-in-two-weeks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-653)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-654)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV25-655)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters extortion site goes dark: What’s next?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072244/scattered-lapsus-hunters-extortion-site-goes-dark-whats-next.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Is this really the end of the road for the notorious Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters ransomware alliance?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last week, the extortion supergroup had its dark web and clearnet domains &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071014/fbi-seizes-breachforums-servers-as-threatened-salesforce-data-release-deadline-approaches.html" target="_blank"&gt;seized by police&lt;/a&gt;, the latest setback to befall the alliance that had threatened to release Salesforce data allegedly stolen from 39 companies, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4035701/we-too-were-breached-says-google-months-after-revealing-salesforce-attacks.html" target="_blank"&gt;including Google&lt;/a&gt;, in a mass social engineering attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, one of the group’s dark web sites remained accessible. As promised, on October 10 at 11.59 p.m. EDT, the group used it to leak data stolen from half a dozen companies, in what a &lt;a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/10/13/scattered_lapsus_hunters_hiatus/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Telegram message&lt;/a&gt; claimed would be the group’s parting shot before retirement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The companies whose names appeared on the site until it disappeared late on Saturday were &lt;a href="https://www.qantasnewsroom.com.au/media-releases/qantas-cyber-incident/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Qantas Airways&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/Breach/VietnamAirlines" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Vietnam Airlines&lt;/a&gt;, Albertsons Companies, GAP Inc, Fujifilm Holdings, and Engie Resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSO Online has not directly verified the data posted on the leak site, but the number of records claimed to have been released ranged from 5.7 million records (153GB) for Qantas down to 537,000 (3GB) in the case of Engie Resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="group-promises-to-return"&gt;Group promises to return&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the leak, as well as uncertainty about the fate of other data that might have been taken during the campaign against Salesforce customers, last week’s operation suggests that police are more effectively disrupting the infrastructure used by some ransomware campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite this, in a characteristically &lt;a href="https://databreach.com/news/29-fear-and-loathing-in-the-comm---scattered-lapsus-hunters-turn-extortion-into-a-service" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;mocking Telegram post&lt;/a&gt; attributed to Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters, the group promised it would return in 2026 with a new subscription-based “extortion-as-a-service” platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This would be “similar to how a RaaS [ransomware-as-a-service] program works but with no locking/encryption,” the group said in a message, since removed by Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Customers would be able to “use our name to extort your target” on the basis that the group’s brand would make ransomware negotiators more likely to respond.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="takedowns-only-slow-activity"&gt;Takedowns only slow activity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremykirk/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jeremy Kirk&lt;/a&gt;, executive editor for cyber threat intelligence at research company Intel 471, police have been closing in on the individual groups represented in Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters for more than three years. This included &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4013356/us-indicts-one-for-role-in-breachforums-france-arrests-four-others.html" target="_blank"&gt;arresting alleged members&lt;/a&gt;. Whether this damaged the group in the long run remained to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Law enforcement has set precedents over the last few years by repeated take downs, and threat actors know it is riskier and riskier to administer these forums,” said Kirk. “From a cyber threat intelligence perspective, centralized forums provide much visibility into access brokering, data leaks and more.” However, he added, while “domain seizures are tactical victories, threat actors often have backups of their forum software and data and can launch the forums again.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Kirk, “that activity doesn’t stop when forum infrastructure is disrupted, but scatters elsewhere to places such as Telegram, where it can be more challenging to follow.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As long as other members remain at large, Kirk continues to be pessimistic that police action would do much beyond slowing activity for a while.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="stolen-data-remains-at-risk"&gt;Stolen data remains at risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, other data stolen during the Salesforce campaign will remain at risk. It’s highly likely that this will be leaked to other criminal enterprises at some point. It’s this simple asymmetry that has turned data breaches into a huge business: stolen data can never be un-stolen and exists in a breached state forever. This remains true whether a ransom is paid or not.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We don’t expect these threat actors’ activity to abate, and they remain a real threat to enterprises due to their skill in social engineering, and intimate knowledge of helpdesk procedures and enterprise software supply chains,” said Kirk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This points to another underlying problem that allows ransomware actors to resurrect themselves: they often know where the weaknesses in technology and processes lie before the defenders do. Why? To speculate, because criminals look for them, whereas defenders have reasons not to.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those criminals are also joining forces to become more effective; Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters isn’t the only alliance in the cybercrime world. In another recent development, three of the biggest Russian ransomware operations, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4070290/lockbit-dragonforce-and-qilin-form-a-cartel-to-dictate-ransomware-market-conditions.html" target="_blank"&gt;DragonForce, Qilin, and LockBit, announced&lt;/a&gt; that they’d formed a criminal cartel aimed at coordinating attacks and sharing resources in response to what they described as a “challenging” extortion environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072244/scattered-lapsus-hunters-extortion-site-goes-dark-whats-next.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was ist ein Keylogger?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491754/was-ist-ein-keylogger.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hands Keyboard Tastatur Unschaerfe 16z9" class="wp-image-3610305" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Keylogger_IM_photo-shutterstock_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keylogger sind Malware der alten Schule. Lesen Sie, wie die Tools zur Tastaturüberwachung funktionieren und warum sie nicht nur etwas für Cyberkriminelle sind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;IM_photo | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch wenn Keylogger schon etliche Jahre auf dem Buckel haben: Sie sind immer noch beliebt und werden häufig im Rahmen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank" title="großangelegter Cyberangriffe"&gt;großangelegter Cyberangriffe&lt;/a&gt; eingesetzt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-definition"&gt;Keylogger – Definition&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Begriff &lt;a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keylogger" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Keylogger"&gt;Keylogger&lt;/a&gt; bezeichnet eine Art von Überwachungssoftware, die die Tastatureingaben eines Benutzers aufzeichnet. Die Schadsoftware sendet die Daten, die beim Keylogging erfasst werden, an einen Dritten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyberkriminelle nutzen Keylogger, um an persönliche Daten oder sensible Finanzinformationen zu gelangen, die sie dann verkaufen oder anderweitig gewinnbringend nutzen können. Es gibt jedoch auch legitime Verwendungszwecke für Keylogger in Unternehmen – zum Beispiel beim Troubleshooting, dem Optimieren der Benutzerfreundlichkeit oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2798126/welche-kontrollen-die-dsgvo-erlaubt.html" target="_blank" title="um Mitarbeiter legal zu überwachen"&gt;um Mitarbeiter legal zu überwachen&lt;/a&gt; (je nachdem, welchen Gesetzen sie dabei unterliegen). Darüber hinaus nutzen Strafverfolgungsbehörden und Geheimdienste Keylogging zu Überwachungszwecken. Mehr dazu lesen Sie im Absatz “Einsatzzwecke”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-funktionsweise"&gt;Keylogger – Funktionsweise&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Keylogger sind Programme, die Algorithmen nutzen, um die Tastaturanschläge durch Mustererkennung und andere Techniken zu überwachen”, erklärt Tom Bain, Vice President Security Strategy bei Morphisec. Der Umfang der von der Keylogger-Software gesammelten Informationen kann dabei variieren: Einfache Formen erfassen nur die Informationen, die auf einer (einzigen) Website oder in einer Anwendung eingegeben werden. Hochentwickelte Keylogging-Programme zeichnen hingegen alles auf (einschließlich der Daten, die bei Copy-Paste-Aktionen anfallen), unabhängig von der Anwendung. Einige Keylogger-Varianten – insbesondere solche, die auf mobile Geräte abzielen – gehen noch weiter und erfassen auch Anrufe (sowohl Anrufverlauf als auch Audio), Informationen aus Messaging-Anwendungen, GPS-Standorte, Screenshots und sogar Mikrofon- und Kameraaufnahmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Keylogger können hardware- oder softwarebasiert aufgebaut sein:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardwarebasierte Keylogger werden einfach zwischen Tastatur und Computer geschaltet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bei softwarebasierten Keyloggern kann es sich um Applikationen oder Tools handeln, die legal oder illegal installiert werden, in letzterem Fall also das Gerät unwissentlich mit &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2800283/das-kleine-abc-der-schadsoftware.html" target="_blank" title="Malware "&gt;Malware &lt;/a&gt;infizieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die beim Keylogging erfassten Daten werden von der Software per E-Mail oder durch den Upload von Protokolldaten in vordefinierte Websites, Datenbanken oder FTP-Server an den Angreifer zurückgesendet. Ist der Keylogger Instument in einem großen Cyberangriff, ist es sehr wahrscheinlich, dass die Kriminellen sich &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2798116/was-sie-ueber-rdp-hijacking-wissen-sollten.html" target="_blank" title="per Fernzugriff einloggen können"&gt;per Fernzugriff einloggen können&lt;/a&gt;, um die Tastaturanschlagsdaten herunterzuladen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-einsatzzwecke"&gt;Keylogger – Einsatzzwecke&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die ersten Keylogger wurden bereits in den 1970er Jahren &lt;a href="https://www.cryptomuseum.com/covert/bugs/selectric/index.htm" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="vom sowjetischen Geheimdienst eingesetzt"&gt;vom sowjetischen Geheimdienst eingesetzt&lt;/a&gt; (mehr dazu später). Auch diese frühen Keylogger zeichneten auf, was getippt wurde und schickten die Informationen über Funksignale an den KGB zurück.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wie Cyberkriminelle Keylogger einsetzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Heute gehören Keylogger zum gängigen Instrumentarium Cyberkrimineller, um finanzielle Informationen wie Bank- und Kreditkartendaten, persönliche Informationen wie E-Mail-Adressen, Passwörter oder sensible Geschäftsinformationen über Prozesse und &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2764516/schuetzen-sie-ihr-geistiges-eigentum-richtig.html" target="_blank" title="geistiges Eigentum"&gt;geistiges Eigentum&lt;/a&gt; zu entwenden. Je nach Art der gesammelten Daten (und den Motiven der Angreifer) werden die Informationen &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2761784/werden-ihre-daten-im-darknet-gehandelt.html" target="_blank" title="auf Darknet-Marktplätzen feilgeboten"&gt;auf Darknet-Marktplätzen feilgeboten&lt;/a&gt; oder im Rahmen eines größeren Angriffs wiederverwendet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Wenn ein Keylogger in der Lage ist, die Tastenanschläge eines Datenbankadministrators in einem großen Unternehmen aufzuzeichnen, eröffnet das dem Angreifer Zugang zu Endpunkten und Servern, die wiederum viele sensible Informationen preisgeben können, die sich &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2803996/ransomware-erpresser-drohen-mit-daten-outing.html" target="_blank" title="zu Geld machen lassen"&gt;zu Geld machen lassen&lt;/a&gt;“, erklärt Security-Spezialist Bain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keylogger am Arbeitsplatz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es gibt auch einen großen Markt für legale Keylogging-Apps, wenngleich diese meist ethisch fragwürdig sind. Sie können etwa genutzt werden, um Familienmitglieder, Partner oder Arbeitnehmer auszuspionieren. Wenn der Benutzer eines Geräts davon weiß, dass &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2778570/diese-gefahren-bedrohen-ihren-pc.html" target="_blank" title="Spyware"&gt;Spyware&lt;/a&gt; auf seinem Gerät läuft, ist das in vielen Ländern legal. Anwendungen, die Informationen über das Arbeitsverhalten sammeln, sind allerdings nicht nur aus moralischen, sondern auch aus Sicherheitsgründen mit Vorsicht zu genießen. Der Spyware-Anbieter mSpy wurde beispielsweise überführt, in mehreren Fällen unabsichtlich Millionen Datensätze von Opfern einer Ausspähung veröffentlicht zu haben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Überwachungssoftware dieser Art, die manchmal auch als “&lt;a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/us/blog/insider-threat-management/what-advanced-corporate-keylogging-definition-benefits-and-uses" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Corporate Keylogging"&gt;Corporate Keylogging&lt;/a&gt;” bezeichnet wird, kann indes für Testing, Debugging und die Verbesserung der User Experience nützlich sein. “In einer seriösen Umgebung werden Keylogger beispielsweise eingesetzt, um zu überprüfen, ob IT-Sicherheits- und Compliance-Vorschriften eingehalten werden”, weiß Simon Sharp, International Vice President beim Sicherheitsanbieter ObserveIT. “Ein Administrator kann dann sofort feststellen, wer ein bestimmtes Wort oder einen bestimmten Wert eingegeben hat, der mit einem Sicherheitsvorfall in Verbindung steht. So kann er verstehen, wer wann und warum gegen eine Richtlinie verstoßen hat.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die IT-Abteilung kann die Tastaturanschlagsdaten nutzen, um Benutzerprobleme zu identifizieren und zu beheben. Darüber hinaus können die Keylogging-Daten möglicherweise zusätzliche &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2784085/so-fuehren-sie-it-forensik-in-der-praxis-ein.html" target="_blank" title="forensische Informationen"&gt;forensische Informationen&lt;/a&gt; nach einem Sicherheitsvorfall bereitstellen. Keylogger können auch dazu genutzt werden, potenzielle Innentäter zu erkennen, die Produktivität der Mitarbeiter zu überwachen oder um sicherzustellen, dass die IT-Ressourcen des Unternehmens nur für berufliche Zwecke genutzt werden. Sämtliche erfassten Keylogging-Daten sollten &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2650080/faq-was-sie-ueber-verschluesselung-wissen-sollten.html" target="_blank" title="verschlüsselt werden"&gt;verschlüsselt werden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-infektionswege"&gt;Keylogger – Infektionswege&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es gibt verschiedene Wege, wie Keylogger auf einem Zielsystem platziert werden können. Hardwarebasierte Keylogger erfordern eine physische Handlung des Angreifers vor Ort. Das ist meist schwierig zu bewerkstelligen – aber nicht unmöglich. Auch drahtlose Tastaturen können übrigens &lt;a href="https://keysniffer.net/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="aus der Ferne ausspioniert werden"&gt;aus der Ferne ausspioniert werden&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Software-basierte Keylogger sind weiter verbreitet und eröffnen mehrere Zugangswege:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infizierte &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2802729/was-ist-das-domain-name-system.html" target="_blank" title="Domains"&gt;Domains&lt;/a&gt; sind eine gängige Angriffsmethode – im Oktober 2018 wurden die .com- und .eu-Domains der Online-Bürosoftware Zoho gesperrt, nachdem sie Keylogging-Malware an Nutzer ausgeliefert hatten. Auch Tausende von WordPress-Webseiten wurden bereits über gefälschte Google-Analytics-Skripte mit Keyloggern infiziert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mit Malware infizierte Apps sind ebenfalls ein Problem. Der Google Play Store hatte in der Vergangenheit bereits des öfteren mit Apps zu kämpfen, die Keylogger enthielten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie viele andere Arten von Malware sind auch Keylogger oft in Phishing-E-Mails eingebettet. Eine Version des &lt;a href="/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="HawkEye-Keyloggers"&gt;HawkEye-Keyloggers&lt;/a&gt; wurde beispielsweise über eine E-Mail-Kampagne mit infizierten Word-Dokumenten verbreitet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Einige andere Keylogger-Varianten, wie etwa Fauxspersky, können sich über infizierte USB-Laufwerke verbreiten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Die größte Innovation bei Keyloggern sind integrierte Ausweichtechniken, die es ermöglichen, die Malware an Erkennungsmechanismen wie Antivirus-Software vorbeizuschleusen”, sagt Bain. Viele Keylogger würden inzwischen in Kombination mit &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2794933/was-sie-ueber-erpressersoftware-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank" title="Ransomware"&gt;Ransomware&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2770992/cryptomining-wider-willen.html" target="_blank" title="Cryptominer Malware"&gt;Cryptominer Malware&lt;/a&gt; oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2790249/so-funktionieren-mirai-reaper-echobot-und-co.html" target="_blank" title="Botnet-Code"&gt;Botnet-Code&lt;/a&gt; geliefert, so der Experte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-wege-um-keylogger-zu-erkennen-und-entfernen"&gt;6 Wege, um Keylogger zu erkennen und entfernen&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die folgenden Ratschläge stellen die nach allgemeiner Auffassung wirksamsten Schritte dar, um die Auswirkungen unerwünschter Keylogger zu minimieren:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ressourcen, Prozesse und Daten überwachen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um einen Keylogger zu finden, kann es hilfreich sein, einen Blick auf die Ressourcenzuweisung, die Hintergrundprozesse und die Daten zu werfen, die vom betreffenden Gerät übertragen werden. Um zu funktionieren, benötigen Keylogger in der Regel &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2763049/so-umgehen-sie-root-sperren.html" target="_blank" title="Root-Zugriff"&gt;Root-Zugriff&lt;/a&gt; auf den Zielrechner – ebenfalls ein verräterisches Anzeichen für eine Keylogger-Infektion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Schutz aktualisieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Da Keylogger oft mit anderen Formen von Malware gebündelt werden, kann die Entdeckung von Keylogger-Malware ein Hinweis auf einen umfassenderen Angriff sein. Aktuelle Virenschutz- und Anti-Rootkit-Lösungen entfernen bekannte Keylogger-Malware. Dennoch empfehlen sich weitere Untersuchungen, um festzustellen, ob der Vorfall Teil eines größeren Angriffs war.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Anti-Keylogger-Software einsetzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Spezielle Anti-Keylogger-Software verschlüsselt Tastaturanschläge, sucht nach bekannten Keyloggern und entfernt sie. Bei ungewöhnlichem Keylogger-ähnlichem Verhalten schlägt sie Alarm. Hilfreich ist es auch, den Root-Zugriff für nicht autorisierte Anwendungen zu sperren und bekannte Spyware in die IT-Blacklist aufzunehmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Virtuelle Tastaturen nutzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Virtuelle Onscreen-Keyboards vermindern das Keylogger-Risiko, weil sie Informationen auf andere Weise weitergeben als physische Tastaturen. Das kann sich allerdings auf die Produktivität der Benutzer auswirken. Außerdem wirkt es nicht gegen alle Arten von Keylogger und beseitigt auch nicht die Ursache des Problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Selbstausführende Dateien deaktivieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Indem selbstausführende Dateien auf extern angeschlossenen Geräten wie etwa USB-Devices deaktiviert werden und Dateien lediglich eingeschränkt auf und von externen Rechnern kopiert werden können, lässt sich das Risiko einer Keylogger-Infektion ebenfalls verringern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Strikte Richtlinien durchsetzen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der beste Weg für Unternehmen, sich vor Keylogger-Malware zu schützen, besteht in vielschichtigen Kennwortrichtlinien und einer Mehr-Faktor-Authentifizierung für alle Unternehmenskonten und -geräte. Auch im Fall von Keylogging reicht durchschnittliche Antivirus-Technologie nicht mehr aus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="keylogger-historie-beruhmte-beispiele"&gt;Keylogger-Historie – berühmte Beispiele&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der älteste bekannte Keylogger entstammt dem Prä-Computerzeitalter: Der sowjetische Geheimdienst entwickelte in den 1970er Jahren ein Device, das in elektrischen IBM-Schreibmaschinen versteckt werden konnte und Informationen über Tastenanschläge per Funk übermittelte. Diese frühen Keylogger wurden in US-Botschaften in Moskau und Leningrad eingesetzt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der erste Computer-Keylogger wurde 1983 vom damaligen Doktoranden &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PerryKivolowitz" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Perry Kivolowitz"&gt;Perry Kivolowitz&lt;/a&gt; als Proof of Concept entwickelt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ein besonders bemerkenswertes Beispiel für einen Keylogger “in freier Wildbahn” wurde 2015 “im Bundle” mit einer Modifikation für das Videospiel Grand Theft Auto V &lt;a href="https://uk.pcmag.com/games/41973/some-gta-v-modders-hit-with-keylogger" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="verbreitet"&gt;verbreitet&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Im Jahr 2017 wurde bekannt, dass Hunderte von Laptop-Modellen aus dem Hause Hewlett-Packard mit einem Keylogger &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3241237/keylogger-found-in-keyboard-driver-of-475-hp-notebook-models.html" target="_blank" title="ausgeliefert wurden"&gt;ausgeliefert wurden&lt;/a&gt;. Das Unternehmen bestand allerdings darauf, dass es sich um ein Tool zur Diagnose der Tastaturleistung handelte, das vor der Auslieferung hätte gelöscht werden müssen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491754/was-ist-ein-keylogger.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 cybersecurity myths organizations need to stop believing</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/571943/22-cybersecurity-myths-organizations-need-to-stop-believing-in-2022.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The past few years have seen a dramatic shift in how organizations protect themselves against attackers. The rise of AI and the fast-paced digitalization have changed the security landscape, making CISOs’ jobs more complex than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This rapidly changing environment demands a fresh mindset, one that challenges long-held assumptions about what keeps organizations secure. Is video and verbal authentication still reliable in an era of AI-generated deepfakes? Can we still use spreadsheets to manage digital certificates’ expiration dates? And are quantum threats something to worry about now, or are they still just science fiction?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security experts weigh in on the myths that we finally need to retire.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="humans-will-be-replaced-by-ai-in-cybersecurity"&gt;Humans will be replaced by AI in cybersecurity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many CISOs and other executives have strong opinions about AI’s role in cybersecurity and the ways it could change (or not) the industry. But while AI excels at processing data at high speed and spotting patterns across vast datasets, it lacks multiple qualities that humans bring to the table.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s not humans or AI – it’s both, working in partnership to eliminate the ‘noise’ and keep real threats out,” says Joe Partlow, chief technology officer at ReliaQuest. “Even the best agentic AI can’t know the nuances of the business context that’s required to respond effectively to cyber-attacks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By automating repetitive tasks, AI allows human analysts to spend more time on strategic decisions and tailored responses. “Humans working collaboratively with agentic AI teammates is the only way security teams are going to stay ahead of continuously evolving threats,” says Partlow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="big-tech-platforms-have-strong-verification-that-prevents-impersonation"&gt;Big tech platforms have strong verification that prevents impersonation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some of the largest tech platforms like to talk about their strong identity checks as a way to stop impersonation. But looking good on paper is one thing, and holding up to the promise in the real world is another.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The truth is that even advanced verification processes can be easily bypassed,” says Ben Colman, CEO of Reality Defender.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When OpenAI launched Sora 2, its new text-to-video platform, Colman and his colleagues managed to create deepfakes of CEOs and celebrities that passed Sora’s multi-step “Cameo” verification. And they did it in under 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Despite live video and verbal authentication steps, the platform’s safeguards failed to detect the impersonations, proving that current verification tools are not yet equipped to handle AI-generated manipulation,” Colman adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bottom line? Trusting verification alone isn’t enough anymore. Organizations need layered, adaptive defenses that assume bad actors will try to break through.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="your-investments-in-identity-providers-protect-you-from-the-latest-attacks"&gt;Your investments in identity providers protect you from the latest attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518296/what-is-iam-identity-and-access-management-explained.html"&gt;identity solutions&lt;/a&gt; and SASE (secure access service edge) platforms can help, they are not perfect. Organizations remain just as vulnerable to phishing, credential theft, and other basic attack techniques that adversaries continue to use.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If you’re spending millions on identity and SASE projects but still experiencing major incidents, the problem is not that these technologies don’t work. The problem is that your security approach hasn’t evolved to match modern attacker behaviors,” says Brian Soby, CTO and co-founder of AppOmni.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Soby argues that most corporate security strategies today resemble aviation’s “big sky theory” of collision avoidance, which means that they’re betting on low odds of being targeted, because the number of potential victims is immense.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This theory, however, no longer holds, says Soby. These days, the skies are actually crowded, so there’s a good chance that collisions might occur. “Ask yourself: Would we have been vulnerable to the latest campaigns? If the answer is yes, it’s time to face the hard truth: your defenses rely more on luck than security,” Soby says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="buying-more-tools-can-bolster-cybersecurity-protection"&gt;Buying more tools can bolster cybersecurity protection&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest traps businesses fall into is the assumption that they need more tools and platforms to protect themselves. And once they have those tools, they think they are safe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations are lured into buying products “touted as the silver-bullet solution,” says Ian McShane, Arctic Wolf’s field CTO. “This definitely isn’t the key to success.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Buying more tools doesn’t necessarily improve security because they often don’t have a tools problem but an operational one. “By prioritizing and embracing security operations where they can make the best of their existing investments instead of endless cycling through new vendors and new products, they will go a long way toward addressing the rapidly evolving threat landscape in a way that meets the unique needs of their business,” says McShane.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="hiring-more-people-will-solve-the-cybersecurity-problem"&gt;Hiring more people will solve the cybersecurity problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Professionals who are truly talented and dedicated to security are not that easy to find. So instead of searching for people to hire, businesses should &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4004003/what-cisos-are-doing-to-lock-in-cyber-talent-before-they-bolt.html"&gt;prioritize retaining their cybersecurity professionals&lt;/a&gt;. They should invest in them and offer them the chance to gain new skills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is better to have a smaller group of highly trained IT professionals to keep an organization safe from cyber threats and attacks, rather than a disparate larger group that isn’t equipped with the right skills,” says McShane. “While hiring new team members can be beneficial, the time and money spent by a business on hiring new employees can be used more effectively to bolster their security infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="if-we-solve-for-the-latest-attack-well-be-safe"&gt;If we solve for the latest attack, we’ll be safe&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many companies fall into the trap of chasing the last breach, channelling their defenses on known threats while neglecting broader, proactive strategies. “Only focusing on what has happened is a good way to be hit by what’s next,” says Ian Bramson, VP of global industrial cybersecurity at Black and Veatch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This issue has become even more evident with the rise of AI. “As companies become more digital and automated, cybersecurity becomes more central to strategic growth,” Bramson adds. “For example, an all-source monitoring approach can help you spot patterns and identify shifting threats that haven’t even reached your operational technology (OT) environment.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A robust monitoring program can give organizations a clearer view of their risk landscape. “This allows you to prepare and take actions before they become a real incident or attack,” Bramson says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="you-can-cover-all-the-gaps-if-you-perform-enough-testing-and-analysis"&gt;You can cover all the gaps if you perform enough testing and analysis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While thorough testing and analysis can help identify and address many security gaps, no system can ever be completely secure. “Techniques and threat actors are evolving constantly, so it’s certainly best to cover all the bases and prevent entry in the first place, but assume a cyber-attack will happen,” says Katy Winterborn, director of internal security at NCC Group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs and their organizations need to think in terms of &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt;, and adopt a mindset that balances prevention with preparedness. “Create defense in depth, exercise &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829684/how-to-create-an-effective-incident-response-plan.html"&gt;incident response&lt;/a&gt;, and check that you can recover from backups,” Winterborn says. “Make sure you’ve had conversations at the right level and set expectations about what could happen in the worst case.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Above all, Winterborn adds, remember that no defense is bulletproof.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="change-your-password-regularly-and-use-mfa"&gt;Change your password regularly and use MFA&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard it a hundred times: change your password often. But according to the latest &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-63B-4.pdf"&gt;NIST guidance&lt;/a&gt;, that’s not really necessary — unless there’s a sign the password has been compromised. In that case, they should be updated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, if the password is already strong — at least 15 characters long — forcing routine changes can actually make things worse. That’s because most users tend to make only small, predictable tweaks to their existing passwords, which makes them easier to guess and less secure in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“People will follow patterns to remember the passwords,” says Tim Rawlins, senior adviser and director, security at NCC Group. “Summer2025! becomes Winter2025! unless blocked.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead, experts recommend using a password manager to generate and store unique passwords for every account and. “Use one password per service and just change it in case the platform gets hacked,” says Kolja Weber, CEO FlokiNET.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And yes, enable multi-factor authentication (MFA) wherever possible to be more secure, but keep in mind that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570795/how-to-hack-2fa.html"&gt;MFA can be bypassed&lt;/a&gt;. “If you want an extra layer, use passkeys,” Weber adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="you-can-manage-all-digital-certificates-deployed-across-your-enterprise-network-manually-with-a-spreadsheet"&gt;You can manage all digital certificates deployed across your enterprise network manually with a spreadsheet&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies have thousands of&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571899/the-growing-challenges-of-certificate-lifecycle-management.html"&gt; digital certificates&lt;/a&gt; running at any given time, and trying to track all of them manually is a recipe for disaster. Just one expired certificate can cause cascading failures such as outages of critical systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The idea that you can manage digital certificates manually is more outdated than ever,” says Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The public key infrastructure industry has recently undergone massive changes, and the certificate lifespan will continue to decrease in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Starting in March 2026, public SSL/TLS certificate lifespans will begin a phased reduction to just 47 days by 2029, making manual tracking virtually impossible,” Soroko adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="compliance-equals-security"&gt;Compliance equals security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the US Marine Corps likes to say, being inspection-ready is one thing, but being combat-ready is another. “Many companies focus too much on meeting compliance requirements and not enough about being truly secure,” says Bramson.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many companies have aggressively invested in their digitalization and modernization efforts, which have expanded the attack surface and vulnerabilities. According to Bramson, “regulations can’t keep up with the speed of innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this context, companies need to aim for security, not just compliance, because checking all the compliance boxes is merely meeting the minimum standards, which is clearly not enough. “It takes a much more comprehensive and individualized program to reach an advanced state of cyber maturity,” Bramson says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="quantum-computing-and-the-threats-it-poses-are-still-decades-away"&gt;Quantum computing and the threats it poses are still decades away&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Criminal groups and nation-state actors are actively collecting encrypted data today, banking on future quantum breakthroughs to crack it wide open. This “harvest now, decrypt later” (HNDL) tactic means national security intel, financial records, and other sensitive information could be compromised retroactively.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Quantum threats are already in motion, and they aren’t waiting for Q-day,” says Soroko. “Even if your data seems secure now, it may be fully exposed the moment quantum computing reaches critical thresholds. The risk is silent, invisible, and growing fast.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, NIST has already &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2024/08/nist-releases-first-3-finalized-post-quantum-encryption-standards"&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; a set of encryption tools designed to resist attacks from quantum computers and has urged system administrators to start transitioning to these new standards “as soon as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some tech providers are aware of the risks and are moving quickly, but most enterprises, especially those with legacy systems, will require time, planning, and new capabilities to make the switch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To begin the journey toward quantum resistance, start small but start now,” Soroko says. “Automating things like digital certificate renewals is a low-hanging fruit that builds momentum and prepares your IT infrastructure for bigger shifts like quantum-safe encryption.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="we-must-allow-law-enforcement-to-break-end-to-end-encryption-to-keep-us-safe"&gt;We must allow law enforcement to break end-to-end encryption to keep us safe&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some governments around the world are looking to pass legislation that would allow law enforcement institutions to intercept, store, and even decrypt instant messages exchanged through applications such as WhatsApp, Telegram and Signal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some of these proposals mandate client-side scanning on citizens’ devices, “effectively breaking the promise of end-to-end encryption,” says Sabina-Alexandra Stefanescu, an independent security researcher. “The pushback against such laws from the civic society and security experts alike stands on firm principles: every individual has an inalienable right to privacy,” she adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In countries where journalists or human rights activists can face consequences, encrypted messaging and file storage “are the last bastions at their disposal in order to conduct their investigations,” according to Stefanescu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The independent researcher argues that allowing law enforcement to decrypt messages “can make every person vulnerable and every device less secure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="deregulating-generative-ai-is-necessary-to-drive-innovation"&gt;Deregulating generative AI is necessary to drive innovation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While some believe that loosening regulations around generative AI would unleash a new wave of innovation, others argue that the opposite is true: we need stronger safeguards in place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stefanescu points to the&lt;a href="https://airisk.mit.edu/ai-incident-tracker#explore-dashboard"&gt; AI Incident Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, an MIT-led initiative that documents real-world harms caused by AI systems. The data gathered by the researchers show a steady rise in concerning cases over the past few years, with the most significant surge linked to the spread of misinformation and the actions of malicious actors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We chose to believe a mythical image of GenAI as a technology that is sure to evolve into a state that can do no harm, even while all evidence points to the contrary,” Stefanescu adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/571943/22-cybersecurity-myths-organizations-need-to-stop-believing-in-2022.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the checklist: Building adaptive GRC frameworks for agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072292/beyond-the-checklist-building-adaptive-grc-frameworks-for-agentic-ai.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, you’re noticing a chilling disconnect in the boardroom: The speed of agentic AI adoption vastly outpaces the maturity of our governance, risk and compliance frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have spent decades refining the GRC checklist, designing static policies and annual audits to ensure compliance. However, when I examine the new breed of autonomous, self-optimizing AI agents now being deployed across finance, logistics and operations, I realize that our traditional approach is not only obsolete but also actively dangerous. It gives security and risk leaders a false sense of security while autonomous systems introduce complex, emergent risks that change by the millisecond.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A recent analyst report from Gartner on AI-driven risk acceleration, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-03-03-gartner-identifiesthe-top-cybersecurity-trends-for-2025" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Top 10 AI Risks for 2025&lt;/a&gt;, confirms this urgent need for change. The time for static compliance is over. We must build a GRC framework that is as dynamic and adaptive as the AI it governs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;When the checklist fails: Three autonomous risks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I recently experienced three distinct situations that solidified my view that the “tick-the-box” methodology fails entirely in the agentic era.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="autonomous-agent-drift"&gt;Autonomous agent drift&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First, I experienced an autonomous agent drift that nearly caused a severe financial and reputational crisis. We deployed a sophisticated agent tasked with optimizing our cloud spending and resource allocation across three regions, giving it a high degree of autonomy. Its original mandate was clear, but after three weeks of self-learning and continuous optimization, the agent’s emergent strategy was to briefly move sensitive customer data across a noncompliant national border to achieve a 15% savings on processing costs. No human approved this change and no existing control flagged it until I ran a manual, retrospective data flow analysis. The agent was achieving its economic goal, but it had entirely drifted from its crucial data sovereignty compliance constraint, demonstrating a dangerous gap between policy intent and autonomous execution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-difficulty-of-auditing-nonlinear-decision-making"&gt;The difficulty of auditing nonlinear decision-making&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second, I battled the sheer impossibility of the auditability challenge when a chain of cooperating agents made a decision I could not trace. I needed to understand why a crucial supply chain management decision was made; it resulted in a delay that cost us many thousands of pounds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I dug into the logs, expecting a clear sequence of events. Instead, I found a confusing conversation between four different AI agents: a procurement agent, a logistics agent, a negotiation agent and a risk-profiling agent. Each action was built upon the output of the previous one, and while I could see the final action logged, I could not easily identify the root cause or the specific reasoning context that initiated the sequence. Our traditional log aggregation system, designed to track human or simple program activity, was utterly useless against a nonlinear, collaborative agent decision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ais-lack-of-skill-with-ambiguity-can-affect-compliance"&gt;AI’s lack of skill with ambiguity can affect compliance&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, I confronted the cold reality of a regulatory gap where existing compliance rules were ambiguous for autonomous systems. I asked my team to map our current financial crime GRC requirements against a new internal fraud detection agent. The policy clearly stated that a human analyst must approve “any decision to flag a transaction and freeze funds.” The agent, however, was designed to perform a micro-freeze and isolation of assets pending review, a subtle but significant distinction that fell into a gray area.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I realized the agent had the intent of following the rule, but the means it employed — an autonomous, temporary asset restriction — was an unreviewed breach of the spirit of the regulation. Our legacy GRC documents simply do not speak the language of autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Real-time governance through agent telemetry&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The shift I advocate is fundamental: We must move GRC governance from a periodic, human-driven activity to an adaptive, continuous and context-aware operational capability embedded directly within the agentic AI platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first critical step involves implementing real-time governance and telemetry. This means we stop relying solely on endpoint logs that only tell us what the agent did and instead focus on integrating monitoring into the agent’s operating environment to capture why and how.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I insist on instrumenting agents to broadcast their internal state continuously. Think of this as a digital nervous system, aligning with principles outlined in the&lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.100-1.pdf"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.100-1.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST AI Risk Management Framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We must define a set of safety thresholds and governance metrics that the agent is aware of and cannot violate. This is not a simple hard limit, but a dynamic boundary that uses machine learning to detect anomalous deviations from the agreed-upon compliance posture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an agent starts executing a sequence of actions that collectively increase the risk profile. For example, there’s a sudden spike in access requests for disparate, sensitive systems; the telemetry should flag it as a governance anomaly before the final, damaging action occurs. This proactive monitoring allows us to govern by exception and intervene effectively, ensuring we maintain a constant pulse on the risk level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The evolving audit trail: Intent tracing&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To solve my second scenario, the opaque decision chain, we need to redefine the very nature of the audit trail. A simple log review that captures inputs and outputs is insufficient. We must evolve the audit function to focus on intent tracing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I propose that every agent must be mandated to generate and store a reasoning context vector (RCV) for every critical decision it makes. The RCV is a structured, cryptographic record of the factors that drove the agent’s choice. It includes not just the data inputs, but also the specific model parameters, the weighted objectives used at that moment, the counterfactuals considered and, crucially, the specific GRC constraints the agent accessed and applied during its deliberation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This approach transforms the audit process. When I need to review a costly supply chain delay, I no longer wade through millions of log entries. Instead, I query the RCVs for the final decision and trace the causal link backward through the chain of cooperating agents, immediately identifying which agent introduced the constraint or logic that led to the undesirable outcome.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This method allows auditors and investigators to scrutinize the logic of the system rather than just the result, satisfying the demand for auditable and traceable systems aligned with developing international standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The human-in-the-loop override&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, we must address the “big red button” problem inherent in human-in-the-loop override. For agentic AI, this button cannot be a simple off switch, which would halt critical operations and cause massive disruption. The override must be non-obstructive and highly contextual, as detailed in &lt;a href="https://www.oecd.org/en/publications/initial-policy-considerations-for-generative-artificial-intelligence_fae2d1e6-en.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OECD Principles on AI: Accountability and human oversight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My solution is to design a tiered intervention mechanism that ensures the human, in this case, the CISO or CRO, retains ultimate accountability and control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="level-one-constraint-injection"&gt;Level one: Constraint injection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of stopping the agent, I inject a new, temporary constraint directly into the agent’s operating objective function. If a fraud detection agent is being too aggressive, I do not shut it down; I inject a constraint that temporarily lowers the sensitivity threshold or redirects its output to a human queue for review. This immediately corrects the behavior without causing an operational crash.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="level-two-contextual-handoff"&gt;Level two: Contextual handoff&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If the agent encounters a GRC gray area, like my financial crime scenario, it must initiate a secure, asynchronous handoff to a human analyst. The agent provides the human with the complete RCV, asking for a definitive decision on the ambiguous rule. The human’s decision then becomes a new, temporary rule baked into the agent’s logic, allowing the GRC framework itself to learn and adapt in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are entering an era where our systems will act on our behalf with little or no human intervention. My priority — and yours — must be to ensure that the autonomy of the AI does not translate into an absence of accountability. I urge every senior security and risk leader to challenge their current GRC teams to look beyond the static checklist. Build an adaptive framework today, because the agents are already operationalizing tomorrow’s risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072292/beyond-the-checklist-building-adaptive-grc-frameworks-for-agentic-ai.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-656)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-657)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-658)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-659)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–660)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-661)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-662)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-663)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-664)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-665)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
