<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:33:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Europol supports French investigation into alleged criminal activity linked to platform X</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</link>
      <description>The investigation is conducted by the Paris Public Prosecutor’s Office with the support of the French Gendarmerie’s cybercrime unit (UNCyber) and Europol.On the action day, French authorities carried out investigative measures in the offices of the platform in France. Europol supported the investigation through its European Cybercrime Centre (EC3), providing specialised cybercrime expertise and deploying an analyst on the ground...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719 - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-061)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-062)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-064)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-065)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay or should I go?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125356/should-i-stay-or-should-i-go-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even the most seasoned CISOs sometimes run into insurmountable roadblocks at their organizations. Despite their best efforts at building relationships, and even with their technical depth and business acumen, they can’t garner the support needed to protect their organizations — and themselves — from pending disaster.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the big picture, CISO roles are hard, and so the majority of CISOs switch jobs every two to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4049347/lack-of-board-access-the-no-1-ciso-dissatisfaction.html#:~:text=" target="_blank"&gt;three years or less&lt;/a&gt;. Lack of support from senior leadership and lack of budget commensurate with the organization’s size and industry are top reasons for this CISO churn, according to The life and times of cybersecurity professionals &lt;a href="https://issa.org/new-research-from-techtargets-enterprise-strategy-group-and-the-issa-reveals-crisis-in-leadership-as-the-cybersecurity-profession-grows-increasingly-difficult/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from the ISSA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More specifically, CISOs leave on account of limited board engagement, high accountability with insufficient authority, executive misalignment, and ongoing barriers to implementing risk management and resilience, according to an ISSA spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many of these roadblocks are common across industries, so how does a CISO know when it’s time to move on?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They look for the flags.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-flag-playing-lip-service"&gt;Red flag: Playing lip service&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A common red flag and reason CISO’s leave their jobs is because leadership is paying “lip service” to auditors, customers and competitors, says FinTech CISO Marius Poskus, a popular blogger on security leadership who posted an essay about resigning from “security‑theater roles.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, even before signing onto a new job, Poskus suggests looking for recent events proceeding the organization hiring its first-ever CISO. “I see this often. Usually after an impactful breach, they negotiate fines down by saying they’ll hire their first CISO. In fact, a friend in New Zealand reached out to me today with just such a story,” he tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other indicators that executives are playing lip service to security include constant resource denials, lack of risk ownership, and failure to sign off on identified risks at the top level, leaving the CISO vulnerable. To this end, Poskus shared a &lt;a href="https://www.mpcybersecurity.co.uk/blog/why-you-need-a-cybersecurity-charter-and-how-to-get-it-approved" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;security executive charter&lt;/a&gt; that outlines responsibilities of senior executives’ accountability around the cybersecurity program.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, since lack of access to the board is a top-cited reason for leaving, Poskus says to look for problematic reporting lines that block access to executives, such as through a boss who refuses to report issues and requests to executives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-flag-cognitive-disconnect"&gt;Red flag: Cognitive disconnect&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lack of access to executives and the board comes up repeatedly in Cybersecurity Ventures &lt;a href="https://cybersecurityventures.com/cybersecurity-almanac-2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; as a top reason CISO’s decide to leave their jobs, according to Steve Morgan, founder of Cybersecurity Ventures. He cites lack of support as another top reason CISO’s leave.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Splunk’s &lt;a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/campaigns/ciso-report.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 CISO report&lt;/a&gt; found 29% of respondents had adequate budget compared to 41% of boards who felt cybersecurity budgets were adequate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This cognitive disconnect was clear in &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nawabkabir/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nawab Kabir’s&lt;/a&gt; case. He declined on the prospect of taking a full-time CISO role to become a fractional CISO after a merger left him reporting to an IT director rather than the CEO as he previously had reported to. “One of the key red flags for CISO’s is if their boss, usually the CIO or CTO, repeatedly blocks attempts to escalate missions to the CEO by downplaying the real risk, asking the CISO to accept that risk, and saying that the CEO simply doesn’t care. So, the risk never gets mentioned in executive leadership meetings,” Kabir says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After the merger, the initiatives and intervention strategies he developed never got past the director of IT (who came from the merger) to executive leadership. So, Kabir knew it was time to leave. “That’s one of the reasons I became a fractional cybersecurity leader, which I love because now I’m being hired to make a difference at my client companies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="red-flag-pushing-ethical-boundaries"&gt;Red Flag: Pushing ethical boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Above all these, the biggest red flag is when leadership pushes against your professional and personal ethics. For example, when a CEO or board wants to conceal compliance gaps, cover up reportable breaches, and refuse to sign off on responsibility for gaps and reporting failures they’ve been made aware of. “This happens more often than we know because most CISOs won’t make public what happened behind the scenes that made them quit, especially when they’re looking for new jobs,” Poskus explains. “Your integrity is your most important asset, so that’s the biggest red flag when we talk about leaving a role rather than staying and fighting.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In these types of scenarios, the CISO likely lacks critical allies within the organization. Acknowledge this sense of vulnerability, Poskus advises, because it’s a huge red flag. Human resources and legal teams in these situations won’t help because they owe their loyalty to the business, he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such was the case with former Uber CISO &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575375/former-uber-cso-joe-sullivan-and-lessons-learned-from-the-infamous-2016-uber-breach.html" target="_blank"&gt;Joe Sullivan&lt;/a&gt; who was thrown under the bus by Uber’s shady leadership after a 2016 breach. In contrast, SolarWinds CISO Tim Brown felt fully supported after a historic &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570191/solarwinds-supply-chain-attack-explained-why-organizations-were-not-prepared.html" target="_blank"&gt;supply chain hack in 2020&lt;/a&gt; spread to 18,000 business clients &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570191/solarwinds-supply-chain-attack-explained-why-organizations-were-not-prepared.html" target="_blank"&gt;through its Orion&lt;/a&gt; network management product patch update system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Joe was in such a difficult situation. The company was aggressive towards him, which was so different from my experience at SolarWinds,” says Brown, who had responded to the breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="green-flag-they-have-your-back"&gt;Green flag: They have your back&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In contrast to Sullivan’s employer, Brown shares that everyone involved in responding to the SolarWinds breach — from IT responders to communications, legal, and executives — felt the same way he did in terms of making things right for clients and regulators. “My situation was difficult, but manageable in many ways because of that support from my team. From day one, we had no question about doing the right thing. We decided on transparency to our customers all the way through the SEC filings,” Brown explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even as a new CEO came onboard under a planned transition shortly after the breach, and as the SEC charged SolarWinds and Brown with fraud for certifying compliance with SolarWinds security shortly before the sophisticated supply-chain hack occurred, Brown has felt ongoing support.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Given his access to the board and CEO, Brown knew well before the breach that the company had his back. He also points to another green flag: The company’s commitment to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518982/tabletop-exercise-scenarios.html" target="_blank"&gt;tabletop exercises&lt;/a&gt; of impactful breaches. Throughout the practice scenarios, teams worked together under a customer-centric mandate that advocated transparency and education, the same playbook that they followed in the 2020 breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109992/what-cisos-should-know-about-the-solarwinds-lawsuit-dismissal.html" target="_blank"&gt;SEC dropped its charges against Brown&lt;/a&gt;, and in November, he attended a virtual toast in his honor to celebrate the SEC dropping the case against him “without prejudice.” More than 200 CISOs of top companies joined, including co-host Joe Sullivan. Ultimately, as Brown had hoped, the entire experience provided teachable moments to help push the CISO role up the maturity curve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="changing-internal-mindsets"&gt;Changing internal mindsets&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As CISOs burn out or leave under stressful circumstances, many turn to fractional work as Kabir has. And, in his case, working with new clients gives him plenty of opportunities to turn red flags into green flags.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, he points to lack of board access and resources. In many cases he steps into, the former cybersecurity leaders didn’t understand the business and talked technically over their executives’ heads. As a result, he’s had to convert fatigued, resistant executive teams that don’t want to repeat those experiences with a new cybersecurity leader.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For these clients, he likes to call “all hands” to a meeting and conduct what he calls interactive “business continuity stress tests” in table-top scenarios that impact a revenue-generating activity. “Take manufacturing, if this machine is down for six to eight hours what would be our revenue costs associated with this downtime? That gets attention,” Kabir says. “Then finance starts talking within their teams and it goes beyond that to the CEO because now it’s seen as a business issue.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs, then, can change culture to turn a red flag into a green flag. But knowing when and how to do so depends on the indicators mentioned. Even with a fractional role, CISOs should still expect some of their clients to try and compromise ethics by covering up findings for example. Fortunately, that red flag usually reveals itself early in the audit, when the executives and business units appear afraid to answer questions as if trying to hide something.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A lot of red flags have to do with lack of security culture or mismatch in understanding the risk tolerance of the company and what the actual risks are. This red flag goes beyond: If they don’t want to be questioned about what they’ve done so far, that is a huge red flag that they’re covering something up,” Kabir explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To be safe, he carries indemnity insurance and retains his own legal counsel — as should all CISO’s with large enough salaries who are reporting to the board and C-suite. Because, as in the case with Joe Sullivan and many other examples that go unreported, CISO’s can’t count on their organizations to have their backs legally or professionally should the big one hit&lt;a&gt; —&lt;/a&gt; especially if those executives, by virtue of their unresponsiveness and lack of support, are the cause of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125356/should-i-stay-or-should-i-go-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-066)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-067)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminals set sites on identities</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126064/identities-in-the-crosshairs-of-cybercriminals.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eye Security’s &lt;a href="https://www.eye.security/de/trend-report-der-stand-der-incident-response-2026" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2026 State of Incident Response Report&lt;/a&gt; shows that cyberattacks on companies are increasingly going undetected, and the damage occurs within minutes. According to the report, attackers are now focusing less on hacking systems and more on exploiting existing access points.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity-based attacks dominate the field, with passwords being involved in 97% of incidents tracked by Eye Security. Abuse of legitimate accounts is a primary cause of cloud security incidents and drives the business of initial access brokers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the study’s results show that attackers’ fundamental methods remain unchanged. “Even in 2026, compromise will still begin with phishing, exploiting misconfigured or vulnerable internet-enabled systems, social engineering, or attacks via the software supply chain,” explains Lodi Hensen, VP of security operations at Eye Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="bec-attacks-are-particularly-common"&gt;BEC attacks are particularly common&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570999/business-email-compromise-bec-attacks-take-phishing-to-the-next-level.html" target="_blank"&gt;Business email compromise (BEC)&lt;/a&gt; is the most common form of attack, according to the study: More than 70% of incidents fall into this category. In 40% of these cases, phishing served as the initial point of entry. Analysts say that BEC attacks can remain undetected for weeks without continuous monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the study highlights that ransomware remains one of the biggest threats. “The proliferation of Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS), BuilderLeaks, and access broker marketplaces has lowered the barriers to entry and created a professional ecosystem,” the authors explain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report reveals a dangerous trend: the commercialization of insider knowledge. “Groups like ShinyHunters are actively recruiting employees to buy access credentials. This blurs the line between external attacks and insider threats,” the security researchers explain. “For ransomware actors, this purchased access is often faster and more reliable than technical hacking.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies in the industrial, construction, and transport and logistics sectors are particularly affected. Many ransomware attackers exploit everyday vulnerabilities: unprotected applications, insecure remote access, or phishing emails through which employees unknowingly disclose login credentials. The analysis evaluated a total of 630 security incidents in Europe from 2023 to 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126064/identities-in-the-crosshairs-of-cybercriminals.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero trust in practice: A deep technical dive into going fully passwordless in hybrid enterprise environments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126694/zero-trust-in-practice-a-deep-technical-dive-into-going-fully-passwordless-in-hybrid-enterprise-environments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the past three years, I’ve led passwordless migration initiatives at three Fortune 500 companies, and I can tell you with confidence that eliminating passwords from a hybrid Active Directory and Microsoft Entra ID environment is one of the most rewarding — and most underestimated — technical challenges in modern identity management. The theoretical appeal is obvious: no passwords means no credential compromise, phishing becomes exponentially harder and your security posture fundamentally shifts from “prevent breaches” to “assume breach.” But the reality of implementation in environments spanning on-premises and cloud infrastructure? That’s where the genuine complexity lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most organizations I’ve worked with start this journey with romantic notions of flipping a switch and sailing into a passwordless future. What they discover instead is that achieving true passwordless authentication requires rethinking identity architecture from the ground up. It’s not about swapping one authentication method for another — it’s about fundamentally restructuring how you verify identity across every layer of your infrastructure. The transition demands careful planning, technical rigor and unwavering commitment to security principles over convenience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="prerequisites-building-the-foundation-before-the-migration"&gt;Prerequisites: Building the foundation before the migration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before we can talk about passwordless authentication, we need to address what I call the “prerequisite triangle”: cloud Kerberos trust, device registration and Conditional Access policies. Skip any one of these, and your migration will stall before it gains momentum.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud Kerberos trust is the unsung hero of hybrid passwordless deployments. When I started working on my first full migration, I underestimated how critical this piece was. Traditional Kerberos assumes a managed network with domain controllers you control. Cloud Kerberos allows your cloud-based services to issue Kerberos tickets to hybrid-joined devices without requiring a domain controller on the internet. This is your bridge between on-premises and cloud identity, and it’s non-negotiable for seamless hybrid authentication. The mechanics of Kerberos itself haven’t changed significantly since its introduction in the 1980s, but extending it to cloud environments required a fundamental rethinking of how authentication tickets are issued and validated across trust boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Getting cloud Kerberos working requires Azure AD Connect to run version 2.0 or later with the cloud sync agent configured for password hash synchronization (even if you’re not using it for authentication — this remains a prerequisite). Your hybrid-joined devices need to be running Windows 10 20H2 or later, and they must have reliable network connectivity to both your on-premises domain controllers and Azure. In one deployment, my team spent two weeks troubleshooting authentication failures before discovering that a firewall rule was blocking the necessary communication on port 88. This single finding reinforced why network validation should occur before pilot rollout, not during.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Device registration and management come next. Every device attempting passwordless authentication must be either Azure AD joined, hybrid AD joined or registered with Entra ID. I’ve found that hybrid-joined devices work best in truly hybrid environments because they maintain connection to on-premises infrastructure while gaining cloud identity benefits. Your Intune Mobile Device Management deployment becomes critical here — devices must be compliant with your policies before they’re trusted for passwordless sign-in. This means ensuring that disk encryption is enabled, that antivirus is running and that devices meet your organization’s baseline security posture. The compliance baseline isn’t punitive; it’s the minimum acceptable security threshold.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Conditional Access policies form the final leg of the prerequisite triangle. These aren’t optional — they’re how you enforce the “trust zero, verify always” principle of Zero Trust. The &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/sp/800-207/final"&gt;National Institute of Standards and Technology&lt;/a&gt; defines Zero Trust architecture as requiring continuous verification and explicit access grants based on all available data points. I configure policies that require device compliance, enforce multi-factor authentication for sensitive operations, and block legacy authentication entirely. The policy I typically recommend as a starting point requires hybrid-joined devices, compliant Intune status and MFA for all access to on-premises resources, while allowing seamless sign-in for fully compliant devices. This creates a virtuous cycle where security and user experience reinforce each other.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="architecture-decisions-hybrid-authentication-flows-and-windows-hello-for-business"&gt;Architecture decisions: Hybrid authentication flows and Windows Hello for Business&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once your prerequisites are in place, you face critical architectural decisions that will shape your deployment for years to come. The primary decision point is whether to use Windows Hello for Business, FIDO2 security keys or phone sign-in as your primary authentication mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my experience, Windows Hello for Business is the foundation for hybrid environments. It leverages biometric or PIN authentication on the device itself, preventing credentials from ever being transmitted across the network. When a user signs in with Windows Hello, they’re not sending a password or even a credential — they’re using a private key stored in the device’s Trusted Platform Module (TPM) to prove their identity. For hybrid-joined devices, this works seamlessly because the device can authenticate both to your on-premises domain controller (using cloud Kerberos) and to Entra ID in a single operation. This eliminates the attack surface that traditional password-based authentication creates. Organizations seeking more information on passwordless authentication approaches can review guidance from the &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/"&gt;Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency&lt;/a&gt;, which has published extensive recommendations on moving beyond passwords.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However — and this is crucial — not all devices have TPM 2.0, which is required for the most secure implementations. In one organization where we deployed to 15,000 devices, we discovered that 12% didn’t meet hardware requirements. We ended up implementing a phased approach: Windows Hello for Business on compliant devices, with FIDO2 security keys as the backup for devices that couldn’t support it. FIDO2 keys, which conform to the open &lt;a href="https://fidoalliance.org/fido2/"&gt;FIDO2 standard&lt;/a&gt;, are also your answer for scenarios where you need physical authentication tokens — particularly useful for privileged accounts or high-risk scenarios. They’re resistant to phishing and account takeover because possession of the physical token is required. Research from the &lt;a href="https://www.idsalliance.org/"&gt;Identity Defined Security Alliance&lt;/a&gt; has shown that organizations using FIDO2-compliant authenticators reduce account compromise incidents by over 90% compared to password-dependent systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The architectural decision also includes determining how you handle legacy applications that still require passwords. Your options are limited: implement a passwordless-compatible application gateway, deprecate the application entirely or use Entra ID’s smart lockout and password protection features to reduce risk while you transition. I typically recommend treating legacy application support as a temporary bridge, not a permanent architecture. Organizations that treat this as permanent inevitably find themselves maintaining password infrastructure indefinitely, undermining the entire security posture you’re building.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="migration-workflows-the-step-by-step-reality"&gt;Migration workflows: The step-by-step reality&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The migration itself needs to follow a structured approach that I’ve refined across multiple organizations. Start with a pilot group — I recommend between 50 and 200 users who are willing to accept some friction in exchange for security improvements. This group should include IT staff and security-conscious users who can provide meaningful feedback without becoming frustrated with early-stage issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the pilot phase, configure Windows Hello for Business using Group Policy on your on-premises infrastructure for domain-joined devices, while using Intune policies for cloud-managed devices. Configure Entra ID to require Windows Hello as the preferred authentication method. During this phase, maintain traditional password authentication as a fallback — not because you lack confidence, but because user trust in the system matters. I typically see a three to four week period where you’re supporting both methods while users adapt. This period provides invaluable data about real-world usage patterns and edge cases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second phase involves expanding to department-level groups. At this point, you should have identified and documented all the troubleshooting patterns that emerged in your pilot. Common issues I’ve encountered include PIN complexity policies that conflict with Windows Hello configuration, credential caching issues on hybrid-joined devices and confusion around how to recover access when a device is lost or compromised. A well-designed help desk knowledge base at this stage prevents the third phase from becoming a support crisis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The final phase is organization-wide rollout with password authentication disabled. This is where you must have complete confidence in your fallback mechanisms and your support team’s ability to handle edge cases. I recommend maintaining password authentication for break-glass scenarios (though heavily restricted and logged) for at least 90 days after full rollout. This safety net provides psychological comfort to leadership and creates a genuine escape hatch if something unexpected occurs at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="troubleshooting-patterns-and-lessons-learned"&gt;Troubleshooting patterns and lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After guiding three large-scale deployments, I’ve compiled a list of issues that deserve attention before they become production problems rather than documented solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Device compliance checking often becomes a bottleneck. If your Intune policies are too strict, you’ll have users locked out of passwordless authentication because their devices are non-compliant. The solution isn’t to loosen policies — it’s to automate compliance remediation. Use Intune’s remediation scripts to automatically enable required features and update settings rather than blocking access. When a device becomes non-compliant due to a missing security update, remediation scripts can deploy that update silently, restoring access without support interaction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud Kerberos ticket refresh failures occur when devices lose network connectivity. I’ve found that users appreciate understanding that brief network outages might require them to use an alternative authentication method temporarily. Documenting this expectation and providing clear error messages reduces support burden significantly. One organization I worked with created a simple status dashboard showing cloud connectivity health, which dramatically improved user confidence in the system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Windows Hello PIN reset flow needs careful planning. Users will forget PINs — not because they’re careless, but because they now have one less password to remember and are redirecting that cognitive effort elsewhere. Implement Entra ID’s self-service PIN reset capability, but test it thoroughly in various network conditions. I discovered in one deployment that users couldn’t reset their PIN while offline, which created support tickets even though the feature was technically available online. A simple offline reset option would have eliminated those tickets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recovery mechanisms deserve special attention. What happens when a user’s device is stolen? What if the TPM fails? What if they forget their PIN and can’t reach your self-service portal? Document these scenarios and test them with your help desk before full rollout. I’ve found that help desk confidence in recovery procedures directly correlates with user confidence in passwordless authentication.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-endpoint-a-genuinely-passwordless-enterprise"&gt;The endpoint: A genuinely passwordless enterprise&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Reaching true passwordless authentication in a hybrid environment means accepting that you’re building a new security model, not just changing how users authenticate. The effort required is substantial, but the security improvement is profound. I’ve watched organizations move from breach-heavy authentication scenarios to Zero Trust architectures where every access request is evaluated in context, and where the compromise of a single device doesn’t cascade into wholesale account takeover.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The passwordless journey isn’t a destination you reach in months — it’s a direction you move in consistently. The organizations that succeed view passwordless migration not as a project with an end date, but as a fundamental shift in how they think about identity and trust. They maintain that momentum by continuously updating policies, expanding coverage to new applications and use cases, and refining their architecture as technology evolves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The view from the other side is worth the journey. Once you’ve lived in a passwordless environment, going back to password-based authentication feels like removing your seatbelt during a drive. The risk seems obvious in retrospect, and the safety you’ve gained becomes non-negotiable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126694/zero-trust-in-practice-a-deep-technical-dive-into-going-fully-passwordless-in-hybrid-enterprise-environments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-068) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV26-069)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-070)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-071)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyberspy Group Hacked Governments and Critical Infrastructure in 37 Countries</title>
      <link>https://www.securityweek.com/cyberspy-group-hacked-governments-and-critical-infrastructure-in-37-countries/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks has not attributed the APT activity to any specific country, but evidence points to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com/cyberspy-group-hacked-governments-and-critical-infrastructure-in-37-countries/"&gt;Cyberspy Group Hacked Governments and Critical Infrastructure in 37 Countries&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com"&gt;SecurityWeek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.securityweek.com/cyberspy-group-hacked-governments-and-critical-infrastructure-in-37-countries/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asian government’s espionage campaign breached critical infrastructure in 37 countries</title>
      <link>https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/asian-governments-espionage-campaign-breached-critical-infrastructure-in-3/811472/</link>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgproxy.divecdn.com/pCgkrOGpuvq69nAqrgMVTMO-JTdGFXpDOFmTtSan3Kg/g:ce/rs:fill:1600:900:1/Z3M6Ly9kaXZlc2l0ZS1zdG9yYWdlL2RpdmVpbWFnZS9HZXR0eUltYWdlcy0xMjU2NjI3NDU1LmpwZw==.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The victims included national telecommunications firms, finance ministries and police agencies, with most targets suggesting an economic focus, Palo Alto Networks said.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/asian-governments-espionage-campaign-breached-critical-infrastructure-in-3/811472/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:34:18 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.5 million AI agents are at risk of going rogue</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127733/1-5-million-ai-agents-are-at-risk-of-going-rogue.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study released Wednesday by API management platform vendor Gravitee indicates that upwards of half of the three million agents currently in use by organizations in the US and UK “are ungoverned and at the risk of going rogue.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on a December 2025 &lt;a href="https://www.einpresswire.com/article/889263114/gravitee-warns-of-invisible-risk-nearly-half-of-ai-agents-run-without-oversight" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;survey of 750 IT executives and practitioners&lt;/a&gt; conducted by Opinion Matters, the results revealed that AI agents are being deployed faster than security teams can keep up. There are, said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rory-blundell-a7545832/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rory Blundell&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Gravitee, now over three million AI agents operating within corporations, which he described as a workforce larger than the entire global employee count at Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The three million number is based on an extrapolation of survey results, based on government estimates of 8,250 UK businesses and 77,000 US businesses that employ 250 employees or more. The mean number of AI agents deployed per business is 36.9, and when respondents were asked if their organization “experienced or suspected an AI agent-related security or data privacy incident in the past 12 months,” 88% said that they had.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The mean percentage of agents that are not actively monitored and secured, according to the findings, was 53%&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked what prompted the study, Blundell wrote in an email, “we’re all familiar with stories of AI agents going rogue: deleting codebases, leaking confidential information, inventing fake data. The working hypothesis that prompted this research was that, while agentic deployment is reaching an exciting stage, businesses have not yet caught up with agent governance. The research validates that.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-global-problem"&gt;A global problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agents, he said, “can offer businesses a huge productivity gain, but we have to be realistic about the risks: without governance and oversight, they can easily start becoming liabilities, and a danger to consumers and businesses alike.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, said Blundell, despite respondents being only from the UK and US, “this is absolutely a global problem. Companies around the world are using AI agents, and across the board there is a gap between the level of deployment and the level of governance. We have a strong customer base in the EU, where we see the same problems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian-based security awareness training firm Beauceron Security, said, “the only thing that shocks me is that people think it’s only 53% of agents that aren’t monitored. It’s higher.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He likened the results from the Gravitee study to a “lesson about the Titanic that everyone in technology keeps ignoring. The Titanic disaster didn’t happen because they didn’t know there would be icebergs on the trip. They knew it was peak iceberg season, they knew they were going too fast.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley said that the ship’s captain and his crew “thought they’d detect [an iceberg]; if they didn’t, and hit one, that their technology controls would protect them to help them recover.” They put their faith in the so-called watertight compartments that, it turned out, weren’t watertight at the top, but, most importantly, they trusted the new wireless communications technology that they could use to call for help if they got in trouble. The equivalent today: “Well, IT and security can fix it if we get in trouble with our agents.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Wrong then, super wrong now,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He said, “we know AI agents are inherently dangerous and unreliable. There’s literally math proofs out there that show it. So, we know there are icebergs. Let me repeat this for those at the back of the room: 100% of AI agents have the potential to go rogue. If a vendor assures you it isn’t possible and their core technology is an LLM, they’re lying. We know we’re going too fast in adoption for the risks we know exist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shipley added, “now, the funny part: imagine if the Titanic still made the choices it did, knowing the watertight compartments didn’t work (aka monitoring is missing for 53% of AI agents), we know by the time IT and security roll on an AI agent risk, the damage is done (the ship’s sinking too fast and radio isn’t going to help because help will be too late). And we still made the choices we’re making.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-real-issue-is-invisible-ai-not-rogue-ai"&gt;The real issue is invisible AI, not rogue AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/manish-jain" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Manish Jain&lt;/a&gt;, principal research director at Info-Tech Research Group, said that as the “exponential” speed of AI development continues, his firm, based on experiences with CIOs and CDOs, predicts that there will be more AI agents globally by the year 2028 than the number of human employees. “It would be one of the biggest challenges for business and IT executives to govern them without curtailing the innovation that these AI agents bring with them,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even today, he noted, “we see that most enterprise AI agents are running without oversight. Many organizations don’t even know how many agents they have, where they’re running, or what they can touch. If you don’t know how many mules are in the barn, don’t act surprised when one kicks the door down.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jain pointed out that AI agents are no different. “Unaccounted agents often emerge through sanctioned, low-code tools and informal experimentation, bypassing traditional IT scrutiny until something breaks. You cannot govern what you can’t see. So, we need to understand that the real issue isn’t ‘rogue AI’, it’s invisible AI.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; Info-Tech, he added, “strongly believes that governing AI models or pre-approving agents is no longer enough, because invisible, rogue agents will do &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tandava" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;tandava&lt;/a&gt; (the dance of destruction) at runtime. This is because, when it comes to governing these AI agents, the number is so huge that approval gates will not be sustainable without halting the innovation. Continuous oversight should be the priority for AI governance after setting initial guardrails as part of the AI strategy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perspective, he said, also needs to change: “AI agents are no longer helpful bots. They often operate with delegated yet broad credentials, persistent access, and undefined accountability. This can become a costly mistake as overprivileged agents are the new insider threat. We need to define tiered access for AI agents. While we can’t avoid giving a few people keys to our house to speed up things, if you trust every stranger with your house keys, we wouldn’t be able to blame the locksmith when things go missing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127733/1-5-million-ai-agents-are-at-risk-of-going-rogue.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software supply chain risks join the OWASP top 10 list, access control still on top</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126865/software-supply-chain-risks-join-the-owasp-top-10-list-access-control-still-on-top.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Software supply chain failures and mishandling of exceptional conditions are some of the additions to the updated &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/Top10/2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt;, a list of top web application vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most of the list has remained unchanged since 2021. In fact, the top item, broken access control, has been on the Open Worldwide Application Security Project’s list since it was first released in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Everyone tries to craft their own authentication and access control mechanisms,” says Jeff Williams, CTO and cofounder at Contrast Security. Williams created the list and served as the chair of the OWASP board for eight years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are standard mechanisms out there, but most applications have specialized needs, he says. “I’ve seen some really god-awful horrific machines that people have built to do access control checks, and they don’t build them elegantly. They build them piece by piece. ‘Oh, we’re building this function, we need to do an access check’ &lt;strong&gt;— &lt;/strong&gt;and they build their own access check. And almost nobody tests access control.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A typical web application may have a hundred endpoints, Williams says, each one of which can be accessed by a number of different roles. “Now you have to make sure that each of those routes work in each of those roles. Most people do a scan of their application with one role in mind, like that of a normal user. And maybe with an admin user. But there could be twenty different roles, so it’s very difficult to verify.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI didn’t make the top ten list, but it was included in a “next steps” section of issues on the cusp of inclusion, in addition to a lack of application resilience and memory management failures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This AI category is titled: &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/Top10/2025/X01_2025-Next_Steps/#x032025-inappropriate-trust-in-ai-generated-code-vibe-coding" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;X03:2025&lt;/a&gt; Inappropriate Trust in AI Generated Code (‘Vibe Coding’).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Although we didn’t have data to support the fact that AI-generated code is causing significantly more risk than human-written code available, thanks to community feedback, professional experience, and constant online sharing of such data, we felt it prudent to add a section,” says Tanya Janca, lead author of the OWASP Top 10.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers should read and fully understand AI-generated code before committing it, she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The OWASP Top 10 list is based on a combination of security data from a dozen different organizations, covering nearly 3 million applications, as well as a survey of 221 security experts, says security metrics expert Aram Hovsepyan, CEO at Codific and an OWASP contributing member.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 10:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-broken-access-control"&gt;1 – Broken access control&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When applications fail to properly enforce restrictions on what authenticated users are allowed to do, allowing attackers to access unauthorized functionality or data. For example, an attacker might manipulate an URL parameter to access another user’s account information or escalate their privileges from a regular user to an administrator. This item now includes server-side request forgery, which was its own list item in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-security-misconfiguration"&gt;2 – Security misconfiguration&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security settings are not properly defined, implemented, or maintained, leaving systems exposed to attack. Common examples include default credentials that are never changed, unnecessary features left enabled, verbose error messages that reveal sensitive information, or cloud storage buckets left publicly accessible. This vulnerability jumped from fifth place in 2021 to second place in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-software-supply-chain-failures"&gt;3 – Software supply chain failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers compromise software during the build, distribution or updates to inject malicious code that gets distributed to multiple organizations. For example, attackers might &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2119450/the-threats-of-third-party-software-supply-chains-continue-to-plague-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;compromise a popular open-source library&lt;/a&gt; and inject malicious code that then gets incorporated into thousands of applications that depend on it or breach a vendor’s system to insert backdoors into legitimate software updates. This is a new list item, though there was a narrower related item in 2021 &lt;strong&gt;— &lt;/strong&gt;vulnerable and outdated components.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Developers have become a primary target for many online attacks now,” says Janca. “It is no longer a problem of including a library that has a questionable dependency.” Instead, she says, there are now active attacks against the IDE, against the CI/CD pipeline, against plugins and repositories, against developer workstations, and more. “The entire software supply chain is currently a focus for attackers,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-cryptographic-failures"&gt;4 – Cryptographic failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to properly protect sensitive data through encryption or use weak or broken cryptographic algorithms. Examples include transmitting sensitive data in clear text, using weak encryption algorithms, not properly validating SSL/TLS certificates, or storing passwords without proper hashing. These failures often lead to sensitive data exposure or system compromise. This item moved down from second place on 2021’s list.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-injection"&gt;5 – Injection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Untrusted data is submitted as part of a command or query, tricking the application into executing unintended commands or accessing unauthorized data. Examples range from cross-site scripting, where attackers inject malicious scripts into web pages viewed by other users, to SQL injection, where they use database queries to access or modify sensitive data. This item has also moved a couple of spots down on this year’s list.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-insecure-design"&gt;6 – Insecure design&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security wasn’t properly considered during the design phase of the application, resulting in missing or ineffective controls. Examples include failing to implement proper threat modeling, not establishing security requirements before development begins, or designing systems that lack defense in depth. This category was introduced in 2021 to focus on design and architectural flaws rather than implementation bugs, but it’s moved down a couple of places because the industry has made noticeable improvements in threat modeling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-authentication-failures"&gt;7 – Authentication failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to properly verify the identity of users or fail to protect authentication credentials and session tokens. Examples include allowing brute force attacks, permitting weak passwords, exposing session IDs in URLs, not properly invalidating sessions after logout, or failing to implement &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570795/how-to-hack-2fa.html" target="_blank"&gt;multi-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; for sensitive functions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="8-software-or-data-integrity-failures"&gt;8 – Software or data integrity failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to maintain trust boundaries and verify the integrity of software, code, and data artifacts. Examples include applications that rely on plugins, libraries, or modules from untrusted sources without integrity checks, insecure CI/CD pipelines that allow code to be modified before deployment, or applications that auto-update without verifying digital signatures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="9-security-logging-and-alerting-failures"&gt;9 – Security logging and alerting failures&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to log security-relevant events or fail to alert security teams when suspicious activities occur. Examples include not logging failed login attempts, storing logs locally without backup, logging insufficient detail to reconstruct attacks or generating logs that don’t integrate with security information and event management (SIEM) systems. Great logging with no alerting is of minimal value in identifying security incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="10-mishandling-of-exceptional-conditions"&gt;10 – Mishandling of exceptional conditions&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applications fail to properly handle errors, edge cases, and abnormal conditions, leading to security vulnerabilities. Examples include displaying detailed error messages that reveal sensitive information about system architecture, security checks that fail and allow unauthorized access when errors occur, or applications that crash and expose sensitive data in memory dumps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a category that has been just outside the top 10 for several years, says Brian Glas, department chair of computer science at Union University and an OWASP project leader. What took this item over the top was not the data about existing vulnerabilities, he says, but the survey of experts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If it was purely data-driven, we would not have an accurate list as it would only be looking into the past.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related stories:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/575497/owasp-lists-10-most-critical-large-language-model-vulnerabilities.html" target="_blank"&gt;10 most critical LLM vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html" target="_blank"&gt;Managing agentic AI risk: Lessons from the OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3828216/understanding-owasps-top-10-list-of-non-human-identity-critical-risks.html" target="_blank"&gt;Understanding OWASP’s Top 10 list of non-human identity critical risks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1313475/keeping-up-with-ai-the-owasp-llm-ai-cybersecurity-and-governance-checklist.html" target="_blank"&gt;Keeping up with AI: OWASP LLM AI Cybersecurity and Governance Checklist&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3828216/understanding-owasps-top-10-list-of-non-human-identity-critical-risks.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4126865/software-supply-chain-risks-join-the-owasp-top-10-list-access-control-still-on-top.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building trust with the board through evidence-based proof</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127327/building-trust-with-the-board-through-evidence-based-proof.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is a boardroom issue, but meaningful dialogue often breaks down at the table. Boards ask about cybersecurity investments and cyber resilience; they need answers rooted in reality, not prognostication. When cybersecurity leaders respond with a list of technologies deployed and potential risks that require additional investment, board members may get frustrated by a lack of clear answers and lose trust. This is a great opportunity for CISOs to take a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Part of the challenge is that most boards don’t have cybersecurity practitioners and expertise, making it challenging to understand the linkage between technical risks and business impact. It’s the responsibility of the CISO to translate technical cybersecurity outcomes into business terms that enable board members to make well-informed decisions on future investments and financial protection for the business. Additionally, senior leadership teams need to be prepared to discuss concepts like risk appetite and potential degrees of business interruption. That’s because no amount of cybersecurity investment can guarantee zero disruptions; a certain amount of risk must be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this unintentional communication gap comes with the nature of cyber threats. The board wants to know how well-positioned the company is to avoid costly business interruptions, regulatory penalties or class action lawsuits from cyber incidents. It’s tempting to rely on internal audits and regulatory compliance (such as &lt;a href="https://www.aicpa-cima.com/topic/audit-assurance/audit-and-assurance-greater-than-soc-2"&gt;SOC2&lt;/a&gt; attestations), but these don’t provide a robust answer to cyber resilience: many companies have failed to stop cyberattacks despite extensive investments in cybersecurity tools and compliance. (In fact, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-07-29-gartner-forecasts-worldwide-end-user-spending-on-information-security-to-total-213-billion-us-dollars-in-2025"&gt;Gartner predicts&lt;/a&gt; worldwide end-user spending on information security will reach $240 billion in 2026)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity leaders desperately need to prove the performance of cybersecurity investments and demonstrate confidently and with evidence that safeguards are working as intended all the time. There’s an obvious opportunity to change the conversation with boards and senior leadership teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-trust-fails-the-limits-of-compliance-and-communication"&gt;Why trust fails: The limits of compliance and communication&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity frameworks like &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework"&gt;CSF&lt;/a&gt; — and complying with these frameworks — are key. However, while they were designed to standardize and validate an acceptable level of controls, they don’t guarantee positive cybersecurity outcomes. Passing an audit once a year doesn’t mean your controls work every day. For instance, a misconfigured control can create direct breach exposure. A backup gap might break your recovery time objective (RTO) promise. A missing insurance requirement at the time of an attack could void coverage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting for CISOs to present heatmaps and dashboards that are too technical for board members. When executives ask why something is red, the conversation may wander into what seems to the board like subjectivity. The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3609804/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-the-secs-breach-disclosure-rules.html"&gt;cybersecurity disclosure requirements&lt;/a&gt; have forced boards to engage. New rules have increased visibility and consequences for both boards and CISOs without necessarily improving fluency. CISOs are accountable but still lack the means to prove the outcome of their team’s work. Bridging the language gap between cybersecurity leaders and business requires translation, but it’s also an opportunity to redefine the role of cybersecurity and focus on the desired outcome sought after by business leaders: cyber resilience. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-a-common-language-to-get-to-heres-the-proof-of-cyber-resilience"&gt;Building a common language to get to “Here’s the proof of cyber resilience”&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;CISOs can reframe the discussion using data and evidence. Modern cybersecurity tools produce a large volume of data and information on how they operate at any point in time, the status of controls deployed, the validation of configuration and more. There’s an opportunity to collect such data, sanitize it and derive continuous insights that validate, at any point in time, not just compliance with cybersecurity regulations but also overall cybersecurity posture. Because these insights are proof of actual state, the CISO can illuminate gaps in protection on an ongoing basis and either address these gaps or help the business determine mitigation priorities. And in some cases, a perfectly appropriate business decision is to accept a risk. It’s important to capture that acceptance formally, document why it was accepted and ensure that the acceptance is reviewed on an appropriate cadence so the level of risk over time doesn’t outpace a company’s appetite.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This will remove subjectivity and confusion from board reports. CISOs can show proof of readiness and effectiveness, and boards can interpret results in familiar business terms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="practical-steps-for-cisos-to-prove-resilience"&gt;Practical steps for CISOs to prove resilience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity deployment is critical, but insufficient. Every day, even organizations with robust cybersecurity investments fall victim to cyber attacks. Board and business leaders put the burden on cybersecurity leaders, but actually demand more: they want cyber resilience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cyber resilience is the ability to continue critical operations under degraded circumstances, like a cyber incident, and the agility to return to normal operations quickly and with minimal financial impact. It’s more than the deployment of cybersecurity tools. Backups must be recoverable, and cyber insurance policies need to pay claims. Ideally, the organization knows how long it takes to restart systems from backup and has all information at hand for claims to be paid fully and quickly. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, no single role owns cyber resilience, but different aspects are the purview of the CISO (safeguards), the CIO (backups) and the CFO (insurance). Collaboration between all three is required to assess that all safeguards are in place. It’s also time to upgrade manual tracking of safeguards to evidence-based, automated tracking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The next step is to shift from activity reporting to evidence sharing and decision support. This includes providing a clear view of the state of cybersecurity, which then surfaces risks that the business needs to make decisions on in terms of whether to mitigate or accept. To use evidence to demonstrate whether the business is meeting its goals for cyber resilience, data must replace prediction. Next, automate low-value work. Free teams from repetitive audit preparation by using tools to aggregate and provide tamper-proof evidence. Focus human expertise on strategy and decision-making for cyber resilience instead of administrative tasks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, educate and contextualize for the board. Deliver short, outcome-focused updates that tie cybersecurity performance to cyber resilience goals. Reinforce the point that business risk and continuity ultimately reside with the board, not the CISO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="better-language-stronger-trust"&gt;Better language, stronger trust&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber resilience is a business problem, not an IT and cybersecurity problem. The board will understand it when evidence-driven communication fosters transparency, trust and clarity of action. As they hear information relayed in language they can understand, boards gain confidence in investments and governance decisions. This results in fewer redlines on board reports, more meaningful conversations and longer CISO tenures. It moves cybersecurity from a reactive cost center to a proactive value driver. When CISOs can show proof tailored to the company’s own risk tolerance, the conversation changes from uncertainty to clarity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127327/building-trust-with-the-board-through-evidence-based-proof.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft develops a new scanner to detect hidden backdoors in LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127897/microsoft-develops-a-new-scanner-to-detect-hidden-backdoors-in-llms.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has developed a scanner designed to detect backdoors in open-weight AI models, addressing a critical blind spot for enterprises increasingly dependent on third-party LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a blog &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2026/02/04/detecting-backdoored-language-models-at-scale/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, the company said its research focused on identifying hidden triggers and malicious behaviors embedded during the training or fine-tuning of language models, which can remain dormant until activated by specific inputs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such backdoors can allow attackers to alter model behavior in subtle ways that enable data exposure or allow malicious activity to slip past traditional security controls unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As enterprises &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4123740/how-two-companies-are-moving-ai-prototypes-to-production.html"&gt;increasingly rely&lt;/a&gt; on third-party and open-source models for applications ranging from customer support to security operations, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4022073/ai-poisoning-and-the-cisos-crisis-of-trust.html"&gt;the integrity of those models&lt;/a&gt; is under scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Unlike traditional software, where scanners look for coding mistakes or known vulnerabilities, AI risks can include hidden behavior planted inside a model,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunilvarkey1/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sunil Varkey&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity analyst. “A model may work normally but respond in harmful ways when it sees a secret trigger.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That risk is more concerning because LLMs can be deployed without deep inspection, leaving security teams with limited visibility into their training or vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="signatures-that-suggest-backdoors"&gt;Signatures that suggest backdoors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s researchers identified three observable indicators, or “signatures,” that suggest the presence of backdoors in language models.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the strongest indicators is a shift in how a model pays attention to a prompt when a hidden trigger is present. In backdoored models, trigger tokens tend to dominate the model’s attention, effectively overriding the rest of the input.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We find that trigger tokens tend to ‘hijack’ the attention of backdoored models, creating a distinctive double triangle pattern,” Microsoft said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers also found that backdoored models may leak information about how they were poisoned. In some cases, specific prompts caused models to regurgitate fragments of the very training data used to insert the backdoor, including parts of the trigger itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another key finding is that language model backdoors behave differently from traditional software backdoors. Rather than responding only to an exact trigger string, many backdoored models react to partial or approximate versions of the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="effectiveness-of-the-scanner"&gt;Effectiveness of the scanner&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said the scanner does not require retraining models or prior knowledge of backdoor behavior and operates using forward passes only, avoiding gradient calculations or backpropagation to keep computing costs low.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company also said it works with most causal, GPT-style language models and can be used across a wide range of deployments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts say that while the approach improves visibility into language model poisoning, it is an incremental advance rather than a breakthrough, noting that several leading EDR platforms already claim the ability to detect backdoors in open-weight LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bigger question is how long such detection advantages will last.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While this new scanner will help counter real-world attacker techniques currently, adversaries will adapt quickly to outflank this scanner,” said &lt;a href="https://confidis.co/about/our-leadership-team/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keith Prabhu&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CEO of Confidis. “We are seeing a repeat of the ‘virus’ wars, where hackers kept evolving viruses to evade detection by using innovative techniques like polymorphic viruses.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That said, the scanner is essential for companies that download open-source models to use or customize in their own systems, according to Varkey.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For them, AI models become part of the supply chain, just like software libraries,” Varkey said. “The scanner is not a complete solution, but it is an important new layer of protection as AI adoption grows.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127897/microsoft-develops-a-new-scanner-to-detect-hidden-backdoors-in-llms.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The silent security gap in enterprise AI adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127334/the-silent-security-gap-in-enterprise-ai-adoption.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most security leaders believe they know where their sensitive data lives and how it is protected. That confidence is increasingly misplaced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As enterprises deploy AI across customer support, software development, legal analysis and internal operations, a new data exposure surface has quietly emerged. It does not sit in databases, file systems or network links. It lives inside AI inference traffic an area that falls outside most traditional security models and visibility frameworks, as &lt;em&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/em&gt; explains in its analysis of why&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4087007/ai-is-all-about-inference-now.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4087007/ai-is-all-about-inference-now.html"&gt;AI is all about inference now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This shift has happened quickly. In many organizations, AI systems have moved from pilot projects to core infrastructure in less than two years. Yet security architectures have not evolved at the same pace. The result is a widening gap between where sensitive data actually flows and where security teams are looking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This gap is rapidly becoming one of the most overlooked security risks in modern enterprise environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AI prompts are high-value targets&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI prompts are often dismissed as transient inputs temporary strings of text that exist only for the duration of a request. In reality, they frequently contain some of the most sensitive data an organization possesses:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proprietary source code and internal tooling&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Confidential documents and legal contracts&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Customer PII and financial records&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Strategic workflows and decision logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent industry analysis shows that enterprises are increasingly feeding sensitive proprietary data into generative AI systems to improve relevance and accuracy, particularly as organizations work to unlock internal data layers for AI-driven applications. &lt;em&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/em&gt; has documented this trend in its discussion of&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4094124/getting-the-enterprise-data-layer-unstuck-for-ai.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4094124/getting-the-enterprise-data-layer-unstuck-for-ai.html"&gt;getting the enterprise data layer unstuck for AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From a business perspective, this makes sense. AI systems perform best when they are grounded in real organizational knowledge. From a security perspective, however, it represents a fundamental change in how sensitive data is handled. Information that was once confined to controlled repositories is now being copied, transformed and transmitted as part of inference requests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional data flows, prompts are rarely classified, sanitized or monitored. They pass through application layers, middleware, logging systems, observability pipelines and third-party services with minimal scrutiny. In many cases, they are treated as operational exhaust rather than as high-value data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This creates a dangerous mismatch: some of the most sensitive data in the organization is flowing through one of the least protected pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why existing controls fall short&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional security architectures were not designed for AI workloads, and the limitations become clear at the inference layer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Encryption protects data only until it is decrypted for processing. At that point, prompts may be exposed to application memory, runtime environments, debugging tools, observability platforms and administrative access. While transport encryption remains essential, it does little to reduce exposure once data reaches the systems that actually perform inference.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data loss prevention tools also struggle in this context. Legacy DLP solutions were built around structured data, well-defined patterns and predictable storage locations. AI prompts are dynamic, unstructured and context dependent. As a result, DLP tools often lack the semantic understanding needed to determine whether a prompt contains sensitive material or whether its use is appropriate. These limitations are well documented in discussions around why&lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/k/dlp-to-modern-data-security.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/k/dlp-to-modern-data-security.html"&gt;legacy DLP approaches fall short in modern data security environments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Logging and observability introduce another layer of risk. To troubleshoot AI systems, teams often log prompts, responses and intermediate states. These logs are then shipped to centralized platforms, retained for long periods and accessed by broad groups of engineers. What begins as a debugging convenience can quickly become a repository of sensitive data stored far outside its original security perimeter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In many environments, trust effectively stops at the API gateway. Beyond that boundary, AI inference traffic is implicitly trusted, even though it frequently crosses internal and external trust zones. This implicit trust model may have worked for traditional application architectures, but it is poorly suited to AI systems that blur the line between user input, internal data and external services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Internal risk is the bigger threat&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While external attackers remain a concern, internal exposure is often the more likely and less visible risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over-permissioned service accounts, misconfigured logging pipelines, compromised credentials or legitimate insider access can all result in silent prompt leakage. Unlike traditional breaches, these exposures do not require exploitation of vulnerabilities. They occur as a byproduct of normal operations in complex environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI systems exacerbate this risk because of their scale and frequency of use. A single application may generate thousands or millions of inference requests per day, each potentially containing sensitive data. Within that volume, misuse or accidental exposure can easily blend into normal traffic patterns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Research into insider risk consistently shows that accidental exposure is far more common than malicious breach, particularly in cloud environments where ownership and responsibility are distributed across teams. AI systems add yet another layer of complexity, making it harder to answer basic questions about who can access inference data, where it is stored and how long it is retained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because AI usage is frequent and expected, abnormal access patterns may not trigger alarms. This makes AI inference an ideal low noise channel for data exposure one that does not resemble traditional indicators of compromise and is therefore difficult to detect with existing tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The quantum time bomb&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond immediate exposure, there is a longer term risk that security leaders can no longer afford to treat as theoretical: cryptographic durability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI prompts and responses often contain data that must remain confidential for many years source code that underpins competitive advantage, customer records subject to regulatory protection, proprietary processes and strategic decisions. Yet much of today’s AI inference traffic is protected using cryptographic methods designed primarily for short-term transport security, not long term confidentiality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This distinction matters. Advances in quantum computing threaten to weaken many of the cryptographic algorithms currently used to protect data in transit and at rest. While large-scale, fault-tolerant quantum computers are not yet widely available, the associated risk is already present. Adversaries can capture encrypted data today and decrypt it later, once cryptographic assumptions fail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security agencies and standards bodies have explicitly warned about these &lt;em&gt;“harvest now, decrypt later”&lt;/em&gt; threats. The National Institute of Standards and Technology has highlighted the need to assess which data assets require long-term protection in its&lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/pqcrypto"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/pqcrypto"&gt;post-quantum cryptography guidance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI significantly expands the volume of data that may fall into this category. Inference traffic often includes rich contextual information that would be highly valuable if decrypted in the future. Unlike traditional records, this data is frequently generated at scale and retained in logs, analytics systems or backups without clear lifecycle controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For regulated industries with long data-retention requirements such as finance, healthcare and critical infrastructure this creates a silent exposure window that extends far beyond current compliance cycles. Organizations may be meeting today’s regulatory requirements while unintentionally accumulating long-term cryptographic risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI has unintentionally expanded not just the amount of sensitive data in motion, but the amount of data that must remain secure well into a post-quantum future often without organizations realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The bottom line for security leaders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This gap exists not because teams are careless, but because AI inference does not fit cleanly into existing security models. It crosses trust boundaries that were never designed with AI in mind and introduces data flows that traditional controls were never built to govern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As AI becomes embedded in core enterprise workflows, the security implications of inference traffic can no longer be treated as an edge case. They represent a fundamental shift in how sensitive data is created, processed and exposed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is not a call for a specific solution, but a problem the industry can no longer afford to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127334/the-silent-security-gap-in-enterprise-ai-adoption.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attackers exploit decade‑old Windows driver flaw to shut down modern EDR defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127968/attackers-exploit-decade%e2%80%91old-windows-driver-flaw-to-shut-down-modern-edr-defenses.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a recent incident, attackers abused a legitimate but vulnerable Windows kernel driver to shut down endpoint security tools during an ongoing incident response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a Huntress report, the activity was observed during a customer investigation in early 2026 and involved the use of an old EnCase forensic driver (by Guidance Software) as part of the Bring Your Own Vulnerable Driver (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3600750/infostealers-are-using-byovd-to-steal-critical-system-data.html" target="_blank"&gt;BYOVD&lt;/a&gt;) technique to terminate Endpoint Detection and Response (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/568045/what-is-edr-endpoint-detection-and-response.html" target="_blank"&gt;EDR&lt;/a&gt;) processes from kernel mode.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The intrusion began with compromised SonicWall SSL VPN credentials, after which the attacker conducted internal reconnaissance and deployed a custom “EDR killer” binary.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The attack was disrupted before ransomware deployment, but the case highlights a growing trend: threat actors weaponizing signed, legitimate drivers to blind endpoint security,” Huntress researchers said in a blog post. “The EnCase driver’s certificate expired in 2010 and was subsequently revoked, yet Windows still loads it, a gap in Driver Signature Enforcement that attackers continue to exploit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft did not immediately respond to CSO’s request for comments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The BYOVD abuse&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the researchers, the attack used a common technique of abusing a legitimate signed driver that already has kernel-level privileges. This gave the attackers direct, high-privilege access to the kernel, effectively allowing them to terminate almost any process they want, including security tooling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Windows’ Driver Signature Enforcement, the policy requiring all kernel-mode drivers to be digitally signed by a trusted Certificate Authority (CA), doesn’t check certificate revocation lists at kernel load time. Researchers noted this to be a legacy behavior that remains exploitable because of backward compatibility features introduced years ago that allow an exception for drivers signed with certificates issued before July 29, 2015, that chain to a supported cross-signed CA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The EnCase driver contains a timestamp from a VeriSign service, which the authentication check still considers valid. “When code is signed with a timestamp, Windows validates the signature against the time the signature was created, not the current date,” the researchers noted. “Because the driver was timestamped while the certificate was still valid (&lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/install/deprecation-of-software-publisher-certificates-and-commercial-release-certificates" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;before January 31, 2010&lt;/a&gt;), the signature remains valid indefinitely, even though the certificate has since expired.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once in the kernel, the driver exposes an IOCTL interface that lets the malware terminate arbitrary processes with full system privileges. Among the functionality exposed are process termination commands that bypass user-mode safeguards for Protected Process Light (PPL) processes, the defenses EDR systems depend on to avoid tampering.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-kill-list-excluded-huntress"&gt;The kill list excluded Huntress&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The EDR killer binary used in the Huntress-observed attack packed a 64-bit Windows executable and a custom encoded kernel driver payload, which it decoded into OemHwUpd.sys and installed as a kernel-mode service. Because Windows still honors its cryptographic signature, the attackers were able to load the driver.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once the vulnerable driver was in place, the EDR killer compiled an internal list of 59 well-known security tool processes, hashing their names and continuously checking for their presence on the system. “The kill loop runs continuously with a 1-second sleep interval, ensuring any security process that restarts is immediately terminated again,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, Huntress said it wasn’t on the kill list. “While the EDR killer targets nearly every major EDR and AV vendor on the market, the Huntress agent was not among the 59 processes targeted for termination,” it added. Once the driver was written to disk, the binary established persistence by registering it as a Windows kernel service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress recommended enabling Microsoft’s Vulnerable Driver Blocklist on all supported Windows systems to prevent known abused drivers from loading. The researchers also advised enforcing strong access controls on remote access services, including MFA for VPNs such as SonicWall, and closely monitoring for suspicious driver installation activity. Where possible, organizations are also encouraged to enable virtualization-based security features like Hypervisor-protected Code Integrity (HVCI) to further restrict kernel-mode abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127968/attackers-exploit-decade%e2%80%91old-windows-driver-flaw-to-shut-down-modern-edr-defenses.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-072)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-073)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–074)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-075)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-076)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-077)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes security advisory (AV26-078)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-079)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-080)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-081)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-082)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-083)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django security advisory (AV26-084)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-085)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV26-086)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substack data breach leaks users’ email addresses and phone numbers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128287/substack-data-breach-leaks-users-email-addresses-and-phone-numbers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Substack, a high-profile publishing platform widely used by academics, journalists, subject matter experts, and controversialists, has suffered a data breach affecting an unknown number of its creators and subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to emails sent out this week to some users, on February 3 the company “identified evidence” that a third party had exploited an unspecified weakness in the company’s systems to gain access to user email addresses, phone numbers and, more vaguely, “other internal metadata.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The breach happened in October 2025, which means that data, which the company said did not include credit card numbers, passwords, or financial information, has been exposed for up to four months.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We have fixed the problem with our system that allowed this to happen. We are conducting a full investigation, and are taking steps to improve our systems and processes to prevent this type of issue from happening in the future,” &lt;a href="https://lorichristian.substack.com/p/notice-of-data-breach" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said the email&lt;/a&gt; from Substack CEO Chris Best.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We do not have evidence that this information is being misused, but we encourage you to take extra caution with any emails you receive that may be suspicious.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="no-passwords-to-lose"&gt;No passwords to lose&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the time of publication, Substack had not yet made a web announcement about the breach, limiting itself to sending emails to users. This implies that the breach only affects a subset of its estimated 35 million active users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the language of the email alert downplays the incident, describing the exposed data as merely being “shared without your permission.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the fact that the breach was only discovered this week, after a four-month delay, raises the possibility that its scope could yet grow as Substack conducts deeper forensics. A &lt;a href="https://dailydarkweb.net/substack-data-breach-leads-to-leak-of-nearly-700000-records/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;dark web source claimed&lt;/a&gt; the breach compromised 697,313 records, although this remains unconfirmed. It also reported that IDs from payment system Stripe, used by creators to receive payment from their subscribers, were compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on the wording of the email alert sent by the company, the breach only affects users who have Substack accounts; anyone who subscribes to a Substack creator’s newsletter directly using an email address shouldn’t be affected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The full extent of what was exposed is less clear. In addition to email addresses and phone numbers, the company mentioned “metadata,” a catch-all term. In its &lt;a href="https://substack.com/privacy#:~:text=What%20Information%20does%20Substack%20collect" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, Substack describes a wide range of data this might include, depending on how the site is used, including user IDs, profile pictures, biographies, and IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How should Substack users react? Normally, the advice after any data breach is to change the account password. However, Substack’s default access method is &lt;a href="https://faq.substack.com/p/logging-in-to-substack" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;via email address&lt;/a&gt;, with authentication confirmed by sending a “magic link” to the user’s email address. This removes the problem of password compromise and phishing attacks by not having a password to phish. If optional multi-factor authentication is turned on, the user must additionally enter a onetime code from an app.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Passwords are still possible — users who signed up before 2023 might have one — but in 2026, the user must actively choose to create one. The company doesn’t mention whether this subset of users should consider changing their passwords as a precaution, but did offer the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We cannot share specifics about our security systems and processes, but we can confirm that the issue has been resolved and safeguards have been put in place to help prevent this issue from happening again.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Substack’s only other known security incident happened in 2020 when it &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Substack#:~:text=On%20July%2028%2C%202020%2C" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;accidentally exposed&lt;/a&gt; user email addresses by adding them to the “cc” (carbon copy) field instead of the “bcc” (blind carbon copy) of an email when sending out a policy update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128287/substack-data-breach-leaks-users-email-addresses-and-phone-numbers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-087)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-088)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-089)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV26-090)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV26-091)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV26-092)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
