<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 23:20:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-671)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luxury hybrid car thieves taken down in Belgium, Italy and Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</link>
      <description>A highly specialised organised crime network responsible for the theft of more than 100 luxury hybrid cars has been dismantled in an international operation led by the Italian Carabinieri with support from Europol and Eurojust. The estimated value of all stolen cars is of at least EUR 3 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-672)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-014 Security Incident impacting F5</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serious vulnerability found in Rust library</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077445/serious-vulnerability-found-in-rust-library.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers creating projects in the Rust programming language, as well as IT leaders with Rust-based applications in their environments, should pay attention to a serious vulnerability found in one of the programming language’s libraries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Edera say they have uncovered a critical boundary-parsing bug, dubbed TARmageddon (&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-62518" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-62518&lt;/a&gt;), in the popular &lt;em&gt;async-tar&lt;/em&gt; Rust library. And not only is it in this library, but also in its many forks, including the widely used &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the worst-case scenario, this vulnerability has a severity of 8.1 (High) and can lead to Remote Code Execution (RCE) through file overwriting attacks, such as replacing configuration files or hijacking build backends,” &lt;a href="https://edera.dev/stories/tarmageddon" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the researchers say in a report. &lt;/a&gt;Among the other possible impacts is the spread of the infection via applications, also known as a supply chain attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first recommended action is to patch all active forks, since this vulnerability impacts major, widely-used projects, the researchers say, including &lt;em&gt;uv&lt;/em&gt; (Astral’s Python package manager), &lt;em&gt;testcontainers&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;wasmCloud&lt;/em&gt;. “Due to the widespread nature of &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; in various forms, it is not possible to truly quantify upfront the blast radius of this bug across the ecosystem,” they say.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, the researchers warn, the highly downloaded &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; remains unpatched, probably because it’s no longer actively maintained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Edera suggests that developers who rely on &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; consider migrating to an actively maintained fork such as &lt;em&gt;astral-tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; version 0.5.6 or later, which has been patched.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders also need to scan their applications to see if any were developed in Rust and are at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-is-it-critical"&gt;Why is it critical?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;TAR files are used in Unix and Linux systems for bundling multiple directories and files into an archive file that retains the full directory structure and metadata of the original information, explains Robert Beggs, head of Canadian incident response firm DigitalDefence. Archive files are commonly used in backups, or for packing software for purposes such as distributing source code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because of the way in which particular versions of the TAR libraries have been written, a potential vulnerability exists, he said in an email to &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt;, noting,  “In the worst case, it would allow an attacker to execute arbitrary code on a host system and engage in malicious actions, such as overwriting critical files (configuration files, build scripts), or gaining unauthorized filesystem access.” Exploitation could also result in the compromise of any system that extracts files from the malicious TAR.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The vulnerability is especially serious because the vulnerable TAR libraries are often present as part of applications that are not actively maintained, and may be missed when patching or otherwise mitigating the issue,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While there are as yet no known exploits of this vulnerability, Beggs said that can change quickly. “It is a high severity vulnerability  — 8.1 on a scale of 1 to 10 –,” he pointed out, “so it will likely attract the attention of attackers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="recommendations"&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He recommends infosec leaders: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;audit code to identify dependencies for forks or wrappers of &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar &lt;/em&gt;and ensure that they are also patched&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review usage of TAR files in continuous integration/continuous deployment environments as well as containers, and ensure that they are patched;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;isolate (sandbox) archives when processing, and avoid extracting TAR files from untrusted sources;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue to monitor for possible exploits or further vulnerabilities associated with the library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Admins may also be interested in &lt;a href="https://github.com/astral-sh/tokio-tar/security/advisories/GHSA-j5gw-2vrg-8fgx" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this advisory explaining the problem&lt;/a&gt; created by Astral Security, which maintains &lt;em&gt;astral-tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bug was discovered in July and disclosed that month to maintainers of all libraries, the Rust Foundation, and a certain number of projects. It was agreed details wouldn’t be released until this week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the most popular fork (&lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;, with over 5 million downloads on crates.io) appears to be no longer actively maintained, Edera co-ordinated a decentralized disclosure across the complex fork lineage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="possible-consequences"&gt;Possible consequences&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability is a desynchronization flaw that allows an attacker to ‘smuggle’ additional archive entries into TAR extractions, says Edera. It occurs when processing nested TAR files that exhibit a specific mismatch between their PAX extended headers and ustar headers. The flaw stems from the parser’s inconsistent logic when determining file data boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the possible infection scenarios painted by Edera are&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an attack on Python package managers using &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;. An attacker uploads a malicious package to the open source PyPI repository, from which developers download useful utilities. The package’s outer TAR container has a legitimate file but the hidden inner TAR contains a malicious one that hijacks the build backend. This hidden inner TAR introduces unexpected or overwritten files, which compromises the test environment and pollutes the supply chain;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;an attack on any system with separate ‘scan/approve’ phases.  A security scanner analyzes the outer, clean TAR and approves its limited file set. However, the extraction process using the vulnerable library pulls in additional, unapproved, and unscanned files from the inner TAR, resulting in a security control bypass and policy violation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rust developers say the language allows the creation of memory-safe applications, but, say Edera researchers, “the discovery of TARmageddon is an important reminder that Rust is not a silver bullet.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It does not eliminate logic bugs,” the report points out, “and this parsing inconsistency is fundamentally a logic flaw. Developers must remain vigilant against all classes of vulnerabilities, regardless of the language used.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report is also a reminder of the hazards of relying on unmaintained open source libraries in code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077445/serious-vulnerability-found-in-rust-library.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-673)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-674)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden hosts naval exercise with 200 special tactics operators</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</link>
      <description>Preparing to fight terrorism on land and seaThe exercise scenario focused on the deployment of special intervention units and naval assets during day- and night-time, simulating terrorist and hostage incidents on board of cruise liners and ferries. Day after day, the participants faced new challenges on the water and on some of the archipelago’s many islands, slowly preparing them for...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-675)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-676)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-677)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Risk-Assessment-Frameworks im Vergleich</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552765/6-risk-assessment-frameworks-im-vergleich.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="6 Risk-Assessment-Frameworks im Vergleich" class="wp-image-3552768" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/1200x.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Mit dem richtigen Framework lassen sich Risiken besser ergründen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;FOTOGRIN – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für viele Geschäftsprozesse ist Technologie inzwischen unverzichtbar. Deshalb zählt diese auch zu den wertvollsten Assets eines Unternehmens. Leider stellt sie gleichzeitig jedoch auch eines der größten Risiken dar – was Risk-Assessment-Frameworks auf den Plan ruft.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT-Risiken formal &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492180/cyber-risk-assessments-risikobewertung-hilft-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;zu bewerten&lt;/a&gt;, ermöglicht es Organisationen, besser einzuschätzen, zu welchem Grad ihre Systeme, Devices und Daten schädlichen Einflüssen ausgesetzt sind. Etwa in Form von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cyberbedrohungen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495375/third-party-risk-management-so-vermeiden-sie-compliance-unheil.html" target="_blank"&gt;Compliance-Verfehlungen&lt;/a&gt; oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/a/10-fakten-zu-datacenter-ausfaellen,3614299" target="_blank"&gt;Ausfällen&lt;/a&gt;. Zudem können IT- und Sicherheitsentscheider deren Folgen mit Hilfe von entsprechenden Rahmenwerken auch besser abzuschätzen. Das Ziel besteht am Ende darin, sämtliche identifizierten Risiken – und ihren Impact – zu minimieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In diesem Artikel stellen wir Ihnen (in aller Kürze) sechs populäre Risk-Assessment-Frameworks vor, die jeweils auf spezifische Risikobereiche abgestimmt sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-cobit"&gt;1. COBIT&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Hinter &lt;strong&gt;COBIT&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.isaca.org/resources/cobit" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Control Objectives for Information and Related Technology&lt;/a&gt;) steht der internationale IT-Berufsverband ISACA, der sich auf IT Governance fokussiert hat. Dieses sehr umfassende und breit angelegte Framework wurde entwickelt, um dabei zu unterstützen, Enterprise IT:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zu verstehen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu designen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu implementieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu managen und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu steuern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut ISACA definiert COBIT die Komponenten und Designfaktoren, ein optimales Governance-System aufzubauen und aufrechtzuerhalten. Die aktuelle Version, &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/a/was-ist-cobit,3614637" target="_blank"&gt;COBIT 2019&lt;/a&gt;, fußt auf einem Governance-Prinzipien-Sextett:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value für Stakeholder liefern&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ganzheitlichen Ansatz realisieren&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Governance-System dynamisch gestalten&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Management von Governance trennen&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;auf individuelle Unternehmensanforderungen abstimmen&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Ende-zu-Ende-Governance-System realisieren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das COBIT-Framework ist auf Business-Fokus konzipiert und definiert eine Reihe generischer Prozesse, um IT-Komponenten zu managen. Dabei werden außerdem auch Inputs und Outputs, Schlüsselaktivitäten, Zielsetzungen, Performance-&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492322/cybersecurity-messen-10-kennzahlen-die-cisos-weiterbringen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Metriken&lt;/a&gt; und ein grundlegendes Reifegradmodell festgelegt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut ISACA ist COBIT flexibel zu implementieren und ermöglicht Unternehmen, ihre Governance-Strategie anzupassen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-fair"&gt;2. FAIR&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das Framework &lt;strong&gt;FAIR&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.fairinstitute.org/what-is-fair" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Factor Analysis of Information Risk&lt;/a&gt;) bildet eine Methodik ab, um unternehmensbezogene Risiken zu quantifizieren und zu managen. Dahinter steht das Fair Institute, eine wissenschaftlich ausgerichtete Non-Profit-Organisation, die sich dem Management von betrieblichen und sicherheitstechnischen Risiken verschrieben hat. Laut den Machern ist FAIR das einzige, quantitative Standardmodell auf internationaler Ebene, um diese Art von Risiken zu erfassen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; FAIR bietet ein Modell, um die genannten Risiken in finanzieller Hinsicht zu verstehen, zu analysieren und zu quantifizieren. Laut dem Fair Institute unterscheidet es sich dabei insofern von anderen Risk-Assessment-Frameworks, als dass es seinen Fokus nicht auf qualitative Farbdiagramme oder numerisch gewichtete Skalen legt. Stattdessen will FAIR eine Grundlage liefern, um einen robusten Risikomanagement-Ansatz auszubilden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; FAIR ermittelt in erster Linie Wahrscheinlichkeiten mit Blick auf die Frequenz und das Ausmaß von &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/a/was-sie-ueber-dlp-wissen-muessen,3549370" target="_blank"&gt;Data-Loss-Ereignissen&lt;/a&gt;. Es handelt sich hierbei nicht um eine Methodik, um individuelle Risikobewertungen durchzuführen. Vielmehr will das Framework Unternehmen in die Lage versetzen, IT-Risiken zu verstehen, zu analysieren und zu messen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zu den Komponenten des FAIR-Frameworks gehören:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eine Taxonomie für IT-Risiken,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine standardisierte Nomenklatur für Risiken,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine Methode um Datenerfassungskriterien zu definieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Messskalen für Risikofaktoren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine Engine für Risikoberechnungen, sowie&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ein Modell, um komplexe Risikoszenarien zu analysieren.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Die quantitative Risk-Assessment-Ansatz von FAIR ist branchenübergreifend anwendbar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-iso-iec-27001"&gt;3. ISO/IEC 27001&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Bei &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/27001" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ISO/IEC 27001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; handelt es sich um einen internationalen Standard, der mit Leitlinien in Sachen IT-Security-Management unterstützt. Ursprünglich wurde er im Jahr 2005 gemeinschaftlich von der International Organization for Standardization (ISO) und der International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) veröffentlicht – und wird seither sukzessive überarbeitet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; ISO/IEC 27001 ist laut den Verantwortlichen ein Guide für Unternehmen jeder Größe und aus sämtlichen Branchen, um ein &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495288/isms-nach-iso-27001-anforderungen-und-umsetzung.html" target="_blank"&gt;Information-Security-Management-System&lt;/a&gt; (ISMS) aufzusetzen, zu implementieren, zu warten und fortlaufend zu verbessern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; ISO/IEC 27001 fördert einen ganzheitlichen Cybersicherheitsansatz, der Menschen, Richtlinien und Technologie auf den Prüfstand stellt. Ein auf dieser Grundlage erstelltes ISMS ist laut ISO ein Tool für Risikomanagement, Cyberresilienz und Operational Excellence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; ISO/IEC-27001-konform zu sein bedeutet, einem weltweit eingesetzten Standard zu genügen und Datensicherheitsrisiken aktiv zu managen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-nist-risk-management-framework"&gt;4. NIST Risk Management Framework&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/risk-management/about-rmf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Risk Management Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (RMF) wurde von der US-Behörde NIST (National Institute of Standards and Technology) entwickelt. Dieses Framework stellt einen umfassenden, wiederverwend- und messbaren, siebenstufigen Prozess in den Mittelpunkt, um IT- und Datenschutzrisiken zu managen. Dabei kommt eine ganze Reihe von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492240/nist-cybersecurity-framework-das-andert-sich-mit-csf-2-0.html" target="_blank"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt;-eigenen Standards und Guidelines zur Anwendung, um die Implementierung von Risikomanagement-Initiativen zu unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut NIST realisiert das RMF einen Prozess, der die Risikomanagementaktivitäten in den Bereichen Sicherheit, Datenschutz und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492023/supply-chain-risk-management-so-wird-ihre-lieferkette-resilient.html" target="_blank"&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/a&gt; in den Lebenszyklus der Systementwicklung integriert. Dabei berücksichtigt der Ansatz Effektivität, Effizienz und Einschränkungen durch geltende Gesetze, Direktiven, Anordnungen, Richtlinien, Standards oder Vorschriften.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Der siebenstufige Prozess des NIST RMF gliedert sich in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wesentliche Aktivitäten, um die Organisation auf den Umgang mit Sicherheits- und Datenschutzrisiken &lt;strong&gt;vorzubereiten&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Systeme und Daten, die verarbeitet, gespeichert und übertragen werden, auf der Grundlage einer Impact-Analyse &lt;strong&gt;kategorisieren&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine Reihe von Kontrollmaßnahmen &lt;strong&gt;auswählen&lt;/strong&gt;, um Systeme auf der Grundlage einer Risikobewertung zu schützen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Kontrollmaßnahmen &lt;strong&gt;implementieren&lt;/strong&gt; – und dokumentieren, wie das vonstattengeht.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Kontrollmaßnahmen überprüfen und &lt;strong&gt;bewerten&lt;/strong&gt;, ob diese wie gewünscht funktionieren.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Systembetrieb auf Grundlage einer risikobasierten Entscheidung &lt;strong&gt;autorisieren&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Implementierung und Systemrisiken kontinuierlich &lt;strong&gt;überwachen&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Das RMF bietet einen verfahrenstechnischen und geordneten Prozess, um Organisation dabei zu unterstützen, Security in ihre allgemeinen Risikomanagement-Prozesse einzubetten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-octave"&gt;5. OCTAVE&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;OCTAVE&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://insights.sei.cmu.edu/documents/1210/1999_005_001_16769.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Operationally Critical Threat, Asset, and Vulnerability Evaluation&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)) ist ein Framework, um Risiken im Bereich der Cybersicherheit zu identifizieren und zu managen. Es wurde vom CERT-Team der Carnegie Mellon University in den USA entwickelt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Dieses Risk-Assessment-Framework definiert eine umfassende Evaluierungsmethode. Diese ermöglicht Unternehmen nicht nur, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493004/report-von-xm-cyber-geschaftskritische-assets-in-gefahr.html" target="_blank"&gt;missionskritische IT-Assets&lt;/a&gt; zu identifizieren, sondern auch die Bedrohungen, die mit diesen in Zusammenhang stehen und die Schwachstellen, die das erst ermöglichen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut den Verantwortlichen ermöglicht die Zusammenstellung von IT-Assets, -Bedrohungen und –&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495294/schwachstellen-managen-die-6-besten-vulnerability-management-tools.html" target="_blank"&gt;Schwachstellen&lt;/a&gt; Unternehmen, zu durchdringen, welche Daten wirklich bedroht sind. Mit diesem Verständnis ausgestattet, können die Anwender eine Schutzstrategie entwickeln und implementieren, um diese nachhaltig zu schützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Das OCTAVE-Framework ist in zwei Versionen erhältlich.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OCTAVE-S bietet eine vereinfachte Methodik, die auf kleinere Unternehmen mit flachen hierarchischen Strukturen ausgerichtet ist.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;OCTAVE Allegro ist hingegen ein umfassenderes Framework, das sich in erster Linie für große Unternehmen oder solche mit komplexen Strukturen eignet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-tara"&gt;6. TARA&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;TARA&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.mitre.org/news-insights/publication/threat-assessment-and-remediation-analysis-tara" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Threat Assessment and Remediation Analysis&lt;/a&gt;) stellt eine Engineering-Methodik dar, mit deren Hilfe, Sicherheitslücken identifiziert, bewertet und behoben werden können. Dieses Framework wurde von der Non-Profit-Organisation MITRE entwickelt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das Framework ist Teil des MITRE-Systemportfolios, das darauf ausgerichtet ist, die Cybersicherheitshygiene sowie die Resilienz von IT-Systemen in einem möglichst frühen Stadium (innerhalb des Beschaffungsprozesses) zu adressieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das TARA-Framework nutzt einen Datenkatalog, um Angriffsvektoren zu identifizieren, die genutzt werden könnten, um Systemschwachstellen auszunutzen sowie potenzielle Gegenmaßnahmen einzuleiten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; TARA wurde ursprünglich im Jahr 2010 entwickelt und kam bereits in mehr als 30 Cyber-Risk-Assessments zum Einsatz. Dieses Framework eignet sich in besonderem Maße für Risikostudien, die sich auf Sicherheitsbedrohungen konzentrieren. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552765/6-risk-assessment-frameworks-im-vergleich.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-616) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfeit and substandard food worth EUR 95 million seized in global operation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</link>
      <description>Europol, OLAF, DG SANTE and 31 countries across Europe and beyond, together with food and beverage producers from the private sector, joined forces in the fourteenth edition of Operation OPSON. This yearly effort targets the criminals behind counterfeit and substandard food and beverages. Law enforcement, customs and food regulatory agencies seized 259 012 packages, 1 416 168 litres of beverages and 11 566 958 kilograms of food, including meat and seafood.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the meeting notetaker: The rise of AI summarization optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077438/manipulating-the-meeting-notetaker-the-rise-of-ai-summarization-optimization.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These days, the most important meeting attendee isn’t a person: It’s the AI notetaker.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This system assigns action items and determines the importance of what is said. If it becomes necessary to revisit the facts of the meeting, its summary is treated as impartial evidence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But clever meeting attendees can manipulate this system’s record by speaking more to what the underlying AI weights for summarization and importance than to their colleagues. As a result, you can expect some meeting attendees to use language more likely to be captured in summaries, timing their interventions strategically, repeating key points, and employing formulaic phrasing that AI models are more likely to pick up on. Welcome to the world of AI summarization optimization (AISO).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="optimizing-for-algorithmic-manipulation"&gt;Optimizing for algorithmic manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization has a well-known precursor: SEO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Search-engine optimization is as old as the World Wide Web. The idea is straightforward: Search engines scour the internet digesting every possible page, with the goal of serving the best results to every possible query. The objective for a content creator, company, or cause is to optimize for the algorithm search engines have developed to determine their webpage rankings for those queries. That requires writing for two audiences at once: human readers and the search-engine crawlers indexing content. Techniques to do this effectively are passed around like trade secrets, and a &lt;a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/seo-software-market-report#:~:text=The%20global%20SEO%20software%20market%20size%20was,and%20heightened%20competition%20in%20the%20digital%20landscape."&gt;$75 billion&lt;/a&gt; industry offers SEO services to organizations of all sizes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More recently, researchers have documented techniques for influencing AI responses, including &lt;a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2024/04/the-rise-of-large.html%22%3Elarge-language%20model%20optimization"&gt;large-language model optimization&lt;/a&gt; (LLMO) and &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09735"&gt;generative engine optimization&lt;/a&gt; (GEO). Tricks include content optimization — adding citations and statistics — and adversarial approaches: using specially crafted text sequences. These techniques often target sources that LLMs heavily reference, such as Reddit, which is claimed to be &lt;a href="https://www.visualcapitalist.com/ranked-the-most-cited-websites-by-ai-models/"&gt;cited in 40%&lt;/a&gt; of AI-generated responses. The effectiveness and real-world applicability of these methods remains limited and largely experimental, although there is substantial evidence that countries such as Russia are &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/new-atlanticist/exposing-pravda-how-pro-kremlin-forces-are-poisoning-ai-models-and-rewriting-wikipedia/"&gt;actively&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://thebulletin.org/2025/03/russian-networks-flood-the-internet-with-propaganda-aiming-to-corrupt-ai-chatbots/"&gt;pursuing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/04/17/llm-poisoning-grooming-chatbots-russia/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization follows the same logic on a smaller scale. Human participants in a meeting may want a certain fact highlighted in the record, or their perspective to be reflected as the authoritative one. Rather than persuading colleagues directly, they adapt their speech for the notetaker that will later define the “official” summary. For example:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The main factor in last quarter’s delay was supply chain disruption.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“The key outcome was overwhelmingly positive client feedback.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Our takeaway here is in alignment moving forward.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“What matters here is the efficiency gains, not the temporary cost overrun.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The techniques are subtle. They employ high-signal phrases such as “key takeaway” and “action item,” keep statements short and clear, and repeat them when possible. They also use contrastive framing (“this, not that”), and speak early in the meeting or at transition points.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once spoken words are transcribed, they enter the model’s input. Cue phrases — and even transcription errors — can steer what makes it into the summary. In many tools, the output format itself is also a signal: Summarizers often offer sections such as “Key Takeaways” or “Action Items,” so language that mirrors those headings is more likely to be included. In effect, well-chosen phrases function as implicit markers that guide the AI toward inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Research confirms this. Early AI summarization research &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1509.00685"&gt;showed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.08777"&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; models trained to reconstruct summary-style sentences systematically overweigh such content. Models over-rely on &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.11602"&gt;early-position&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1909.04028.pdf"&gt;content&lt;/a&gt; in news. And models often overweigh statements at the &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10570"&gt;start or end&lt;/a&gt; of a transcript, underweighting the middle. Recent work further confirms vulnerability to phrasing-based manipulation: models &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14197"&gt;cannot reliably&lt;/a&gt; distinguish embedded instructions from ordinary content, especially when phrasing mimics salient cues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-combat-aiso"&gt;How to combat AISO&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If AISO becomes common, three forms of defense will emerge. First, meeting participants will exert social pressure on one another. When researchers secretly deployed AI bots in Reddit’s r/changemyview community, users and moderators responded with&lt;a href="https://retractionwatch.com/2025/04/28/experiment-using-ai-generated-posts-on-reddit-draws-fire-for-ethics-concerns/"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://retractionwatch.com/2025/04/28/experiment-using-ai-generated-posts-on-reddit-draws-fire-for-ethics-concerns/"&gt;strong backlash&lt;/a&gt; calling it&lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/unethical-ai-research-reddit-under-fire"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;“&lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/unethical-ai-research-reddit-under-fire"&gt;psychological manipulation&lt;/a&gt;.” Anyone using obvious AI-gaming phrases may face similar disapproval.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second, organizations will start governing meeting behavior using AI: risk assessments and access restrictions before the meetings even start, detection of AISO techniques in meetings, and validation and auditing after the meetings.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Third, AI summarizers will have their own technical countermeasures. For example, the AI security company CloudSEK&lt;a href="https://www.cloudsek.com/blog/trusted-my-summarizer-now-my-fridge-is-encrypted----how-threat-actors-could-weaponize-ai-summarizers-with-css-based-clickfix-attacks"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cloudsek.com/blog/trusted-my-summarizer-now-my-fridge-is-encrypted----how-threat-actors-could-weaponize-ai-summarizers-with-css-based-clickfix-attacks"&gt;recommends&lt;/a&gt; content sanitization to strip suspicious inputs, prompt filtering to detect meta-instructions and excessive repetition, context window balancing to weight repeated content less heavily, and user warnings showing content provenance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Broader defenses could draw from security and AI safety research:&lt;a href="https://cheatsheetseries.owasp.org/cheatsheets/LLM_Prompt_Injection_Prevention_Cheat_Sheet.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://cheatsheetseries.owasp.org/cheatsheets/LLM_Prompt_Injection_Prevention_Cheat_Sheet.html"&gt;preprocessing content&lt;/a&gt; to detect dangerous patterns,&lt;a href="https://github.com/usefulmove/ConsensusLLM"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/usefulmove/ConsensusLLM"&gt;consensus approaches&lt;/a&gt; requiring consistency thresholds,&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02584"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02584"&gt;self-reflection techniques&lt;/a&gt; to detect manipulative content, and&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19098v1"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19098v1"&gt;human oversight protocols&lt;/a&gt; for critical decisions. Meeting-specific systems could implement additional defenses:&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/MeetingNet_EMNLP_full.pdf"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/MeetingNet_EMNLP_full.pdf"&gt;tagging inputs by provenance&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://aclanthology.org/2022.aacl-short.6.pdf"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://aclanthology.org/2022.aacl-short.6.pdf"&gt;weighting content&lt;/a&gt; by speaker role or centrality with sentence-level importance scoring, and discounting high-signal phrases while favoring consensus over fervor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="reshaping-human-behavior"&gt;Reshaping human behavior&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization is a small, subtle shift, but it illustrates how the adoption of AI is reshaping human behavior in unexpected ways. The potential implications are quietly profound.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Meetings — humanity’s most fundamental collaborative ritual — are being silently reengineered by those who understand the algorithm’s preferences. The articulate are gaining an invisible advantage over the wise. Adversarial thinking is becoming routine, embedded in the most ordinary workplace rituals, and, as AI becomes embedded in organizational life, strategic interactions with AI notetakers and summarizers may soon be a necessary executive skill for navigating corporate culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization illustrates how quickly humans adapt communication strategies to new technologies. As AI becomes more embedded in workplace communication, recognizing these emerging patterns may prove increasingly important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077438/manipulating-the-meeting-notetaker-the-rise-of-ai-summarization-optimization.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zimbra security advisory (AV25-678)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted five key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Microsoft WSUS flaw exploited in wild after insufficient patch</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078952/critical-microsoft-wsus-flaw-exploited-in-wild-after-insufficient-patch.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft released out-of-band patches on Thursday to “comprehensively” fix a critical vulnerability in the Windows Server Update Service (WSUS) after the first patches released on Oct. 14 proved insufficient. Attackers exploited the vulnerability in the wild after a detailed vulnerability analysis and proof-of-concept exploit were published this week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tracked as CVE-2025-59287, the vulnerability stems from an unsafe deserialization of the AuthorizationCookie object in WSUS environments. Successful exploitation enables remote code execution with SYSTEM privileges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;WSUS is commonly used in enterprise environments to deliver Microsoft updates to Windows systems in a controlled manner. The service is not enabled by default on Windows servers but can be turned on by enabling the WSUS Server Role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft included a patch for CVE-2025-59287 in its &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072485/october-2025-patch-tuesday-holes-in-windows-server-update-service-and-an-ancient-modem-driver.html"&gt;October Patch Tuesday release on Oct. 14&lt;/a&gt;. But the initial fix was apparently not complete and required a new round of updates for Windows Server 2012, Windows Server 2012 R2, Windows Server 2016, Windows Server 2019, Windows Server 2022, Windows Server 2022 (23H2 Edition, Server Core installation), and Windows Server 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the company’s &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-59287"&gt;updated advisory&lt;/a&gt;, organizations should deploy these updates as soon as possible. Work-arounds include disabling the WSUS Server Role or blocking inbound traffic to ports 8530 and 8531, but both these actions will render the service non-operational until the patches can be deployed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attacks-observed-in-the-wild"&gt;Attacks observed in the wild&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s advisory doesn’t mention in-the-wild exploitation, but researchers from cybersecurity firm Huntress and &lt;a href="https://advisories.ncsc.nl/2025/ncsc-2025-0310.html"&gt;the Dutch government’s National Cybersecurity Center&lt;/a&gt; separately reported evidence of attacks. This came after a detailed analysis and proof-of-concept exploit for the flaw &lt;a href="https://hawktrace.com/blog/CVE-2025-59287-UNAUTH"&gt;was posted by researchers from cybersecurity firm HawkTrace&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Starting around 2025-10-23 23:34 UTC, Huntress observed threat actors targeting WSUS instances publicly exposed on their default ports (8530/TCP and 8531/TCP),” the company wrote in &lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/blog/exploitation-of-windows-server-update-services-remote-code-execution-vulnerability"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; Friday. “Attackers leveraged exposed WSUS endpoints to send specially crafted requests (multiple POST calls to WSUS web services) that triggered a deserialization RCE against the update service.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The exploit activity resulted in the WSUS worker process spawning command prompt and PowerShell instances. A base64-encoded payload was downloaded and executed in PowerShell with the goal of discovering servers on the network and gathering user information which was then sent back to a remote attacker-controlled URL.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Huntress report includes detailed indicators of compromise, forensic artifacts, and detection rules in the open Sigma SIEM detection format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078952/critical-microsoft-wsus-flaw-exploited-in-wild-after-insufficient-patch.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI browsers can be abused by malicious AI sidebar extensions: Report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078306/ai-browsers-can-be-abused-by-malicious-ai-sidebar-extensions-report-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI browsers may be smart, but they’re not smart enough to block a common threat: Malicious extensions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the conclusion of researchers at SquareX, who on Thursday &lt;a href="https://labs.sqrx.com/ai-sidebar-spoofing-720e0c91d290" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;released a report&lt;/a&gt; showing how attackers can exploit AI sidebars through compromised browser extensions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This attack vector isn’t new. Malicious extensions have been &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4017474/verified-but-vulnerable-malicious-extensions-exploit-ide-trust-badges.html" target="_blank"&gt;inserted into browser web stores&lt;/a&gt; to infect standard browsers such as Chrome, Edge, Firefox, and others for years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What SquareX discovered are malicious extensions that can spoof the legitimate AI sidebars people use for queries. Their goal is to trick users into going to malicious websites, running data exfiltration commands, or installing backdoors. AI sidebar spoofing even works on the just-released OpenAI Atlas browser, SquareX says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One solution for CISOs and CIOs is to ban the use of AI browsers, it suggests. That assumes the IT department can manage which browsers staff are using, particularly if they are allowed to use their own internet-connected devices. At the very least, IT must audit all extensions installed by employees for AI and non-AI browsers, the report says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="treat-anything-ai-with-zero-trust-protocols"&gt;Treat anything AI with zero-trust protocols&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs and CIOs need to treat anything AI with the strongest zero-trust protocols available, commented &lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/ed-dubrovsky/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ed Dubrovsky&lt;/a&gt;, chief operating officer of incident response firm Cypfer, at least until some better functioning guardrails are established. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Establish a set of guardrails around AI use and functionality,” he said, “and if you are allowing AI vulnerable software into your corporate network, segment it into a place where it can’t get into the Digital Crown Jewels, or even have an awareness of them.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that AI is a completely different playing field, and CSOs are not yet prepared for it. The challenge is that IT leaders are trying to think of AI as a new tool or toolset and are trying to apply software development and maintenance methodologies to its management. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But in his view, AI is closer to “I just hired 100 new employees with very little vetting or appropriate security controls, how do I secure my assets in case some of them are malicious?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI is not only a language chatbot, but it also has agentic function where tasks are defined and deployed, and AI software can be written and deployed by AI,” he said. “This pushes the human away from the keyboard, in a way, and replaces it with a new software capability.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The risk is that AI is not, and likely never will be, completely foolproof, he added. There may come a day where AI will be powerful enough to avoid most human ability to fool it, but, he asked, can it avoid being manipulated by other AIs? &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dumpster-fires"&gt;‘Dumpster fires’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/?originalSubdomain=ca" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian employee security awareness training firm Beauceron Security, agrees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I think if CISOs are bored and want to spice up their lives with an incident, they should roll out these AI-powered hot messes to their users,” he said .&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“But, if they’re like most CISOs and they have lots of problems, but free time and boredom aren’t on that list, they should avoid these dumpster fires [AI browsers] at all costs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building and supporting a legitimate browser and extension ecosystem is difficult work, he argued, pointing out that even Apple, Google, and Microsoft still have issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I think it’s a mistake to think of the risk as just being about extensions,” he added. “It’s the fundamental DNA of these browsers that is bad; the companies aren’t incented to pay enough attention to the problems, and bad extensions are just the straw that breaks cybersecurity’s back.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-it-works"&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs have a tough challenge: It’s not hard to fool an employee into downloading and installing a malicious extension for any browser; browser extensions are supposed to be attractive add-on utilities such as password managers or AI productivity assistants. They are promoted in phishing and smishing messages, social media posts and, when threat actors are able, uploaded to marketplaces such as the Google Chrome Web Store. They can be malware disguised as a legitimate extension or can be a compromised version of one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In AI Sidebar Spoofing, says the SquareX report, once a victim opens a new AI browser tab, the malicious extension injects JavaScript into the web page to create a fake sidebar that looks exactly like a legitimate sidebar. When the user enters a prompt into the spoofed sidebar, the extension hooks into its AI engine. But if the prompt requests certain instructions or guides, the responses can be manipulated to include additional instructions to the user. So, for example, if the user asks for good file sharing sites, the malicious extension might provide a link to the attacker’s file sharing site that requests high risk OAuth permissions that it can harvest. In the hands of a hacker, they could allow access to the victim’s email.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one test, when a SquareX researcher asked a malicious sidebar extension how to install the Homebrew package manager for macOS or Linux, the instructions included an installation command line that executed a reverse shell command that would have connected the victim’s device to the attacker’s server. That would have given the attacker a system shell in which to execute commands on the victim’s machine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s critical that infosec leaders set granular browser-native policies that prevent users from carrying out malicious tasks as instructed by a fake AI sidebar, says the report. These would include a policy that blocks advanced phishing sites using advanced machine learning and page heuristic analysis, a policy that  blocks high risk permissions from being granted to non-allowlisted apps, and a policy that warns users about and blocks copies of malicious/risky Linux commands.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The research “is a warning shot for the early days of agentic browsing and [reminds users] that the implicit trust model of the UI needs rethinking,” said &lt;a href="https://www.exabeam.com/blog/incident-response/what-the-most-significant-government-collaboration-on-threat-detection-and-logging-got-right-and-wrong-and-what-you-should-know-about-it/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gabrielle Hempel&lt;/a&gt;, security operations strategist at Exabeam.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The main issue here is that agentic-AI browsers introduce an entirely new attack surface. This attack, a malicious extension injecting a fake AI sidebar overlay that looks like the real one, allows threat actors to hijack the ‘trusted’ AI assistant UI and trick users into executing dangerous operations,” she pointed out. “Organizations need to be taking this seriously, because when you delegate browsing and actions to an AI sidebar, you are elevating what previously might have been a minor risk into a material risk to cloud assets, credentials, and devices.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders should restrict AI browser use for high-risk functions until they are proven secure, she advised, adding that, because the attack uses an extension with host and storage permissions, organizations should revisit their extension approval workflows for those as well. In fact, any productivity tool that requests broad access should require scrutiny. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Segmentation is also important once these tools are implemented: least privilege applies here and AI interaction with certain tabs/services should be limited,” she said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4078274/ai-browsers-can-be-abused-by-malicious-ai-sidebar-extensions-report.html" target="_blank"&gt;Computerworld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078306/ai-browsers-can-be-abused-by-malicious-ai-sidebar-extensions-report-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Access Security Broker – ein Kaufratgeber</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494345/der-kaufratgeber-fur-cloud-access-security-broker.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CASB Kaufratgeber 16z9" class="wp-image-3622324" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/originalCSBKaufratgeber.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Lesen Sie, worauf es bei der Wahl eines Cloud Access Security Broker ankommt – und welche Anbieter was genau zu bieten haben.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Jack the sparow | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Cloud Access Security Broker (&lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2751631/mit-casb-sicher-in-die-wolke.html" target="_blank" title="CASB"&gt;CASB&lt;/a&gt;) sitzt zwischen Enterprise-Endpunkten und Cloud-Ressourcen und fungiert dabei als eine Art Monitoring-Gateway. Eine CASB-Lösung:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;gewährt Einblicke in Benutzeraktivitäten in der Cloud,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;setzt Access-Control-Richtlinien durch und&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;hält Ausschau nach Security-Bedrohungen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Standalone-Lösungen im Bereich Cloud Access Security Broker erfreuen sich wachsender Beliebtheit. Laut &lt;a href="https://www.mordorintelligence.com/industry-reports/cloud-access-security-brokers-market" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="den Analysten von Mordor Intelligence"&gt;den Analysten von Mordor Intelligence&lt;/a&gt; soll sich der CASB-Markt bis 2029 auf ein Volumen von 24,2 Milliarden Dollar aufblähen (2023: 11 Milliarden Dollar) – bei einer jährlichen Wachstumsrate von 17 Prozent. Den Research-Experten zufolge ist diese Entwicklung im Wesentlichen der zunehmenden Cloud-Akzeptanz, den wachsenden Sorgen in punkto Datensicherheit sowie der steigenden Nachfrage nach integrierten Security-Lösungen zuzuschreiben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus ist wichtig zu wissen, dass Cloud Access Security Broker auch eine Schlüsselkomponente umfassenderer Sicherheitsstrategien sind. Diese sind im Wesentlichen unter zweierlei Bezeichnungen bekannt:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der Begriff &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492817/security-service-edge-einfuhren-was-sse-anbieter-leisten-sollten.html" target="_blank" title="Secure Service Edge"&gt;Secure Service Edge&lt;/a&gt; (SSE) entstammt dem Analystenhaus &lt;strong&gt;Gartner&lt;/strong&gt; und hat sich inzwischen als De-Facto-Nomenklatur etabliert. SSE bezeichnet die Integration von CASB, Secure Web Gateway (SWG) und Zero Trust Network Access (&lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2826282/die-wichtigsten-ztna-anbieter-und-loesungen.html" target="_blank" title="ZTNA"&gt;ZTNA&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=US50723823" target="_blank" title="Network Edge Security as a Service"&gt;Network Edge Security as a Service&lt;/a&gt; (NESaaS) heißt dasselbe Konstrukt aus CASB, SWG und ZTNA bei den Marktforschern von &lt;strong&gt;IDC&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-5-wichtigsten-casb-anwendungsfalle"&gt;Die 5 wichtigsten CASB-Anwendungsfälle&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der ursprüngliche Use-Case für Cloud Access Security Broker war es, &lt;strong&gt;Schatten-IT-Instanzen zu bekämpfen&lt;/strong&gt;: CASB-Tools können Security-Teams dabei unterstützen, nicht autorisierte – oder nicht gemanagte – Cloud Services zu identifizieren und zu überwachen. Inzwischen hat sich das Use-Case-Portfolio von CASB jedoch erheblich erweitert:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datenschutz durchsetzen.&lt;/strong&gt; Die Pandemie ist vorbei, viele Mitarbeiter kehren zumindest teilweise ins Büro zurück – aber die Applikationen und Daten aus Remote-Work-Zeiten befinden sich weiterhin in der Cloud. Hybride Cloud-Umgebungen erfordern allerdings, sensible Daten &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494443/hybrid-work-sicherheit-so-arbeiten-sie-hybrid-und-sicher.html" target="_blank" title="angemessen zu schützen"&gt;angemessen zu schützen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance umsetzen.&lt;/strong&gt; In einem Umfeld sich stets verschärfender Datenschutzregularien sind CASB-Tools ein wichtiges Instrument, um entsprechende Richtlinien durchzusetzen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote-Arbeit absichern.&lt;/strong&gt; Unabhängig vom Standort der Mitarbeiter können Unternehmen mit einem Cloud Access Security Broker Sicherheitsstandards implementieren sowie den Remote-Zugriff auf Cloud-Ressourcen absichern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bedrohungen erkennen.&lt;/strong&gt; CASB-Lösungen können bösartige Aktivitäten und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank" title="Kompromittierungsversuche"&gt;Kompromittierungsversuche&lt;/a&gt; detektieren. Darüber hinaus sind die Tools in der Lage, Warnmeldungen in Echtzeit zu generieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="das-sollten-cloud-access-security-broker-leisten"&gt;Das sollten Cloud Access Security Broker leisten&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rein funktional betrachtet, zeichnen sich CASB-Lösungen hauptsächlich durch vier Features aus:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sichtbarkeit:&lt;/strong&gt; Sie bieten umfassende Einblicke in Cloud-Nutzung, Benutzeraktivitäten und Datenflüsse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kontrolle:&lt;/strong&gt; Sie bieten granulare Kontrollmöglichkeiten mit Blick auf User-Berechtigungen und Datenzugriff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datenschutz:&lt;/strong&gt; Sie bieten Funktionen, um sensible Informationen über mehrere Cloud-Dienste hinweg zu schützen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; Sie unterstützen dabei, Datenschutzbestimmungen einzuhalten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Von diesen Kernfunktionen abgesehen, sollten Unternehmen zudem sicherstellen, dass sich das CASB-Tool ihrer Wahl möglichst gut in bestehende Cloud Services, Applikationen und Security-Infrastrukturen &lt;strong&gt;integrieren lässt&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Sachen &lt;strong&gt;Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; stehen im Regelfall zwei Optionen zur Wahl – Proxy- oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2790525/was-sie-ueber-application-programming-interfaces-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank" title="API"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;-basiert. Die Mehrheit der Branchenkenner vertritt dabei die Meinung, dass letztgenannter Ansatz bessere Funktionalitäten bietet. Allerdings sollten Anwenderunternehmen auch sichergehen, dass die API Connections des Anbieters mit dem eigenen Cloud-App-Inventar in Einklang stehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-wichtigsten-casb-anbieter-und-losungen"&gt;Die wichtigsten CASB-Anbieter und -Lösungen&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die CASB-Anbieterlandschaft wird sowohl von IT-, beziehungsweise Technologie-Riesen als auch von traditionellen Sicherheitsanbietern bevölkert. Wir haben im Folgenden die wichtigsten Anbieter und ihre Angebote im Bereich Cloud Access Security Broker für Sie zusammengestellt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/de_de/products/security/cloudlock/index.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Cisco Cloudlock"&gt;Cisco Cloudlock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Netzwerkriese Cisco hat bereits im Jahr 2016 das CASB-Startup Cloudlock übernommen und dessen Technologie und Branding in sein Portfolio integriert. Bei Cisco Cloudlock handelt es sich um einen Cloud-nativen Cloud Access Security Broker, der Nutzer, Daten und Apps mit einem automatisierten Ansatz schützen soll und APIs nutzt, um Risiken im Cloud-Ökosystem zu managen. Laut Cisco setzt die Lösung auch fortschrittliche Machine-Learning-Algorithmen ein, um Anomalien zu erkennen und bietet Data-Loss-Prevention (&lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2797438/was-sie-ueber-dlp-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank" title="DLP"&gt;DLP&lt;/a&gt;)-Funktionalitäten. Richtlinienbasierte Kontrollen sollen dafür sorgen, dass gefährliche Aktivitäten je nach Berechtigung und Risikostufe blockiert werden können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.forcepoint.com/de/product/casb-cloud-access-security-broker" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Forcepoint One CASB"&gt;Forcepoint One CASB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch der Sicherheitsanbieter Forcepoint hat im Jahr 2021 mit Bitglass einen Standalone-CASB-Spezialisten übernommen, den Gartner bis dahin in seinem Magic Quadrant als “Leader” im Bereich CASB &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20201030005577/en/Bitglass-Named-a-Leader-in-Gartner%E2%80%99s-Magic-Quadrant-for-CASBs-for-Third-Consecutive-Year" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="einstufte"&gt;einstufte&lt;/a&gt;. In der Folge hat Forcepoint die Technologie von Bitglass mit seinen eigenen DLP-Funktionalitäten zu einer SSE-Lösung integriert. Forcepoint One CASB zeichnet sich vor allem durch sein Schatten-IT-Monitoring und -Reporting aus, bringt aber auch Funktionen im Bereich UEBA (&lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2788862/ist-uba-das-bessere-siem.html" target="_blank" title="User and Entity Behavior Analytics"&gt;User and Entity Behavior Analytics&lt;/a&gt;) mit. Die Software unterstützt darüber hinaus Zero-Trust-Architekturen und stellt hierfür Device und User-Authentifizierung zur Verfügung.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/de-de/security/business/siem-and-xdr/microsoft-defender-cloud-apps" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Microsoft Defender for Cloud Apps"&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft fokussiert sich mit seinem vollwertigen CASB-Angebot darauf, SaaS-Applikationen abzusichern. Defender for Cloud Apps kann laut den Redmondern Schatten-IT erkennen, gewährt Einblicke in die Cloud-App-Nutzung, schützt vor App-basierten Bedrohungen und liefert Compliance Assessments. Zu den erweiterten Funktionalitäten zählen SaaS Security Posture Management (SSPM), fortschrittlicher Bedrohungsschutz im Rahmen von Microsofts Extended Detection and Response (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492511/extended-detection-and-response-losungendie-11-besten-xdr-tools.html" target="_blank" title="XDR"&gt;XDR&lt;/a&gt;)-Lösung sowie eine App-Governance-Funktion, die zusätzlichen Bedrohungsschutz für kritische Daten und Ressourcen bieten soll.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.netskope.com/de/products/casb" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Netskope One CASB"&gt;Netskope One CASB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Netskope ist ein Pure-Play-CASB-Original und gilt sowohl im Bereich CASB als auch im Bereich SSE als führend. Laut Forrester Research zeichnet sich der Anbieter durch Innovationskraft über seinen gesamten Technologiestack aus und hat zudem bedeutende Investitionen in den Bereichen Private Global Network, künstliche Intelligenz und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493126/genai-security-als-checkliste.html" target="_blank" title="Generative AI Security"&gt;Generative AI Security&lt;/a&gt; getätigt. Vor kurzem hat der Anbieter sein CASB-Tool außerdem um eine SWG-Funktion erweitert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.de/network-security/next-gen-casb" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Palo Alto Next-Generation CASB"&gt;Palo Alto Next-Generation CASB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Basierend auf der Aussage, dass es sich weniger um ein eigenständiges Produkt als vielmehr um eine Reihe integrierter Lösungen wie Inline-Sicherheit, SSPM und Enterprise DLP handelt, bewirbt Palo Alto sein CASB-Offering offensiv als “Next Generation”. Die Lösung soll Anwendungen und Daten in Cloud- und hybriden Arbeitsumgebungen sichern, Daten im Transit zwischen Benutzern und &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2806737/die-30-wichtigsten-saas-anbieter.html" target="_blank" title="SaaS-Anbietern"&gt;SaaS-Anbietern&lt;/a&gt; sichern, Compliance gewährleisten und Schatten-IT-Risiken minimieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/de/products/cloud-security/cloud-app-security-broker" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Proofpoint Cloud App Security Broker"&gt;Proofpoint Cloud App Security Broker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Proofpoint konzentriert sich mit seinem CASB-Tool darauf, DLP-Funktionen zu erweitern sowie E-Mail- und Cloud-basierte Bedrohungen abzuwenden. Dabei verfolgt die Proofpoint-Lösung einen menschenzentrierten Ansatz: Sie liefert detaillierte Insights darüber, wer sensible Daten erstellt, diese besitzt, herunter- oder hochlädt, teilt und bearbeitet. Aber das Tool kann auch Benutzer identifizieren, bei denen Phishing-Angriffe erfolgreich verlaufen sind, oder die Personen, die am häufigsten angegriffen werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.skyhighsecurity.com/de/products/cloud-access-security-broker.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Skyhigh CASB"&gt;Skyhigh CASB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Durch seine Inline-Bereitstellungsmodi (Forward- und Reverse-Proxy) ermöglicht die CASB-Lösung von Skyhigh Security, den User Access zu genehmigten und nicht genehmigten Cloud-Diensten in Echtzeit zu kontrollieren. Dabei konzentriert sich der Sicherheitsanbieter Skyhigh (der zum indischen IT-Konzern Musarubra gehört) darauf, eine umfassende Abdeckung bereitzustellen. Dazu kombiniert die Software Security-Ereignisse und Machine-Learning-Systeme, um Sicherheitsteams dabei zu unterstützen, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493521/false-positives-reduzieren-5-tipps-fur-weniger-security-alerts.html" target="_blank" title="Fehlalarme"&gt;Fehlalarme&lt;/a&gt; von echten Alerts zu unterscheiden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.broadcom.com/products/cybersecurity/information-protection/data-loss-prevention-cloud/cloud-application-security-cloudsoc" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Symantec CloudSOC CASB"&gt;Symantec CloudSOC CASB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Symantec wurde 2019 bekanntermaßen von Broadcom übernommen. Die CloudSOC CASB-Lösung soll SaaS-Anwendungen über extensive API-Integrationen und Inline-Traffic-Analysen überwachen können. Dabei verspricht Symantec – respektive Broadcom – vollständige Transparenz und automatisierte Detektion von Hochrisiko-Benutzern, kompromittierten Konten und Insider-Aktivitäten. Individuelle, verhaltensbasierte Bedrohungs-Scores für Benutzer ermöglichen darüber hinaus, Risiken zeitnah zu identifizieren. Die Symantec-Lösung automatisiert darüber hinaus die Klassifizierung regulierter Daten, die in und aus Anwendungen fließen und setzt Richtlinien durch. DLP- und CSPM-Funktionen sind ebenfalls geboten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zscaler.de/technology/cloud-access-security-broker-casb" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Zscaler CASB"&gt;Zscaler CASB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das CASB-Tool von Zscaler bietet Inline-, Echtzeit- und Out-of-Band-Scanning-Funktionen, um Daten zu schützen, Bedrohungen zu blockieren, Compliance zu gewährleisten und Transparenz zu schaffen. Zu den wichtigsten Funktionen der Lösung zählen die “Agentless Cloud Browser Isolation” um BYOD- und Drittanbieter-Geräte abzusichern, Advanced Threat Protection um Malware von Cloud-Ressourcen fernzuhalten, Cloud Sandboxing, um Ransomware und &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2803863/was-ist-ein-zero-day-exploit.html" target="_blank" title="Zero-Day-Exploits"&gt;Zero-Day-Exploits&lt;/a&gt; Einhalt zu gebieten sowie Risk Scores für ungenehmigte Apps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="16-fragen-vor-dem-invest-in-cloud-access-security-broker"&gt;16 Fragen vor dem Invest in Cloud Access Security Broker&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Einen Cloud Access Security Broker anzuschaffen, kann ein komplexes Unterfangen darstellen: Die Liste möglicher Funktionen ist – je nach Definition – lang. Und CASB-Tools selbst sind Teil eines breiter angelegten Trends hin zu SSE- und SASE-Plattformen, die wiederum Funktionen wie ZTNA oder SD-WAN umfassen. Soll heißen: Unternehmen müssen ihre jeweiligen, spezifischen Probleme identifizieren – und anschließend einen Anbieter auswählen, der ihre unmittelbaren Anforderungen erfüllt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um Sie dabei zu unterstützen, haben wir einige wichtige Fragen zusammengestellt, die Sie sich selbst und dem Anbieter Ihrer Wahl &lt;strong&gt;vor dem Kauf&lt;/strong&gt; einer CASB-Lösung stellen sollten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 Fragen, die Sie sich stellen sollten&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Habe ich einen guten Überblick darüber, auf welche Cloud-Dienste meine Benutzer zugreifen – einschließlich Auftragnehmer und andere Drittanbieter?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verfüge ich über ein solides Datenklassifizierungssystem, um zu wissen, welche Art von Daten sensibel oder unternehmenskritisch sind?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verfüge ich über Richtlinien für die Zugriffskontrolle in On-Premise- und Cloud-Umgebungen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Habe ich klare Ziele? Wie sieht meine Prioritätensetzung bei der Suche nach einer CASB-Lösung aus?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie lässt sich eine CASB-Lösung in meine bestehende Sicherheitsinfrastruktur integrieren?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie fügt sich der Kauf eines CASB-Tools in meine Security-Roadmap ein? Welche Rolle könnten mit Blick auf die Zukunft SSE oder SASE spielen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verfüge ich über ausreichend Budget für ein neues Tool?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verfüge ich über das interne Personal, um das Tool vor Ort zu implementieren und zu managen? Ist ein Cloud-basierter Managed Service möglicherweise die bessere Option?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 Fragen, die Sie Ihrem CASB-Anbieter stellen sollten&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welche Funktionen sind in Ihrem CASB-Produkt enthalten? Sind DLP und SWG enthalten oder handelt es sich um zusätzliche Module?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie sieht Ihre Roadmap für SSE und SASE aus?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Viele Anbieter haben Standalone-CASB-Tools gekauft und sie in ihr Portfolio integriert. Welchen Grad der Integration haben Sie erreicht?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie passt dieses Tool jetzt und in Zukunft in meine bestehende Sicherheitsinfrastruktur, wenn ich mehr Sicherheitsfunktionen in die Cloud migriere?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welche geografischen Gebiete decken Sie ab?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decken Ihre APIs alle Cloud-Dienste ab, die wir nutzen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skaliert Ihr Produkt, wenn unser Unternehmen wächst?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie hoch sind die initialen sowie die längerfristigen Kosten? Wie steht es um die Total Cost of Ownership?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494345/der-kaufratgeber-fur-cloud-access-security-broker.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-679)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-679</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-679</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-680)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-680</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-680</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-681)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-681</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-681</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–682)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-682</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-682</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-683)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-683</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-683</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-485) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-485</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-485</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-684)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-684</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-684</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectWise security advisory (AV25-685)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-685</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-685</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware recovery perils: 40% of paying victims still lose their data</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077484/ransomware-recovery-perils-40-of-paying-victims-still-lose-their-data.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Two in five companies that pay cybercriminals for ransomware decryption fail to recover data as a result, according to a survey of 1,000s SMEs by insurance provider Hiscox.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The survey also revealed that ransomware remains a major threat, with 27% of businesses surveyed reporting an attack in the past year. Of those affected, 80% — which includes both insured and uninsured businesses — paid a ransom in an attempt to recover or protect critical data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But only 60% successfully recovered all or part of their data as a result, &lt;a href="https://www.hiscox.ie/sites/ireland-new/files/2025-09/Hiscox%20Cyber%20Readiness%20Report%202025.pdf"&gt;Hiscox’s Cyber Readiness Report&lt;/a&gt; found.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="https://qbeeurope.com/news-and-events/press-releases/ransomware-attacks-to-rise-by-40-by-2026-qbe-warns/"&gt;QBE Insurance report&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month on cybercrime and cloud-based threats revealed that ransomware incidents nearly tripled year-on-year in Q1 2025, reaching &lt;strong&gt;1,537 in Q1 2025&lt;/strong&gt; compared to 572 in the same quarter last year. CrowdStrike’s 2025 State of Ransomware Survey released this month also found that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4075912/ai-enabled-ransomware-attacks-cisos-top-security-concern-with-good-reason.html"&gt;93% of ransomware-paying victims had data stolen anyway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="flawed-ransomware-encryption-often-frustrates-recovery"&gt;Flawed ransomware encryption often frustrates recovery&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hiscox’s statistics on the plight of ransomware victims highlight just one of myriad difficulties organizations face when attempting to recover from &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563507/what-is-ransomware-how-it-works-and-how-to-remove-it.html"&gt;ransomware&lt;/a&gt; attacks, industry experts say.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The 60% recovery rate reflects several technical and operational realities encountered regularly in incident response,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-m-john/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;James John&lt;/a&gt;, incident response manager at cybersecurity firm Bridewell, tells CSO. “Firstly, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3838121/the-dirty-dozen-12-worst-ransomware-groups-active-today.html"&gt;ransomware operators&lt;/a&gt; vary significantly in sophistication. Whilst established groups like LockBit or ALPHV typically provide functional decryptors, as they have a ‘reputation’ to maintain, smaller operations often deploy flawed encryption implementations or simply disappear after payment.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Decryptors are frequently slow and unreliable, John adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Large-scale decryption across enterprise environments can take weeks and often fails on corrupted files or complex database systems,” he explains. “Cases exist where the decryption process itself causes additional data corruption.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even when decryptor tools are supplied, they may contain bugs, or leave files corrupted or inaccessible. Many organizations also rely on untested — and vulnerable — backups. Making matters still worse, many ransomware victims discover that their backups were also encrypted as part of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Criminals often use flawed or incompatible encryption tools, and many businesses lack the infrastructure to restore data cleanly, especially if backups are patchy or systems are still compromised,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/darylflack/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Daryl Flack&lt;/a&gt;, partner at UK-based managed security provider Avella Security and cybersecurity advisor to the UK Government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="additional-recovery-pressures"&gt;Additional recovery pressures&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern ransomware attacks now routinely involve double or triple extortion whereby attackers &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4032874/ransomware-attacks-the-evolving-extortion-threat-to-us-financial-institutions.html"&gt;threaten to leak stolen data&lt;/a&gt; or launch distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks even after payment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This fundamentally changes the calculus on what victims can expect in cases where they decide to make a ransomware payment, which more often than not fails to resolve many of the problems arising from a ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Paying only addresses the encryption element, not the broader compromise,” Bridewell’s John notes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, a ransomware incident puts an organization under enormous pressure, with legal, operational, and reputational issues all converging, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3825444/ransomware-gangs-extort-victims-17-hours-after-intrusion-on-average.html"&gt;often within a matter of hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These factors, combined with the inherent uncertainty of dealing with criminals, help explain why paying the ransom so often falls short of achieving full data recovery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://harperjames.co.uk/our-people/lillian-tsang/"&gt;Lillian Tsang&lt;/a&gt;, senior solicitor in Harper James’ data protection and privacy team, warns that even when a decryption key is received, some data may already be permanently damaged, altered, or stolen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That creates operational challenges but also raises data protection concerns, particularly where personal data is involved,” Tsang explains. “If records are lost or compromised, this can amount to a personal data breach under UK GDPR, which brings reporting obligations and the potential for regulatory scrutiny.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Paying a ransom doesn’t give a business any legal recourse if the criminals fail to deliver and, worse, “payment can create further risk if funds are unknowingly transferred to a sanctioned group,” Tsang warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="financial-resilience-and-legal-issues"&gt;Financial resilience and legal issues&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How a ransomware attack plays out in practice is illustrated by an account from an executive at Kantsu, a midsize Japanese logistics company. Kantsu President Hisahiro Tatsujo &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4036296/%E3%82%B5%E3%82%A4%E3%83%90%E3%83%BC%E6%94%BB%E6%92%83%E3%81%AB%E3%81%95%E3%82%89%E3%81%95%E3%82%8C%E3%81%9F%E4%BC%81%E6%A5%AD%E7%B5%8C%E5%96%B6%E8%80%85%E3%81%8C%E8%AA%9E%E3%82%8B%E5%AF%BE%E5%BF%9C.html"&gt;told CIO.com about the company’s efforts to restore operations following a ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kantsu — which did not pay a ransomware — was obliged to ask financial institutions for loans to cover the cost of recovering its operations because, although it was insured, its insurance firm had to go through a claims process before making a payout. The incident illustrated how enterprises need a financial as well as an operational plan to successfully recover from ransomware attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, when systems are disrupted by ransomware attacks, legal obligations kick in almost immediately with requirements to notify regulators and affected individuals, especially if personal data is affected by a breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“One of the biggest challenges is making rapid, high-stakes decisions with only fragments of information,” says Harper James’ Tsang. “Senior leaders have to weigh the legal risks of payment, the impact on business continuity, and the potential consequences for individuals, often with limited technical clarity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="forewarned-is-forearmed"&gt;Forewarned is forearmed&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some experts advise maintaining a retainer with an incident response firm as part of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/515730/business-continuity-and-disaster-recovery-planning-the-basics.html"&gt;disaster recovery plans&lt;/a&gt; that anticipate the all-too-real possibility of a ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Having a retainer with a reputable incident response or negotiation firm — one equipped to handle cryptocurrency transactions — is crucial,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremysamide/"&gt;Jeremy Samide&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at Blackwired, a cybersec company focused on direct threat intelligence. “Such firms manage &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3568817/the-ransomware-negotiation-playbook-adds-new-chapters.html"&gt;negotiations&lt;/a&gt;, have access to multiple crypto types (e.g., Bitcoin, Monero, Zcash), and can execute transfers securely if payment becomes the only path to recovery.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Samide adds: “Preparation doesn’t mean capitulation — it means being ready for every scenario.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Harper James’ Tsang cautions against setting aside funds to pay criminals in the event of ransomware attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Setting aside funds to pay a ransom is increasingly viewed as problematic,” Tsang says. “While payment isn’t illegal in itself, it may breach sanctions, it can fuel further criminal activity, and there is no guarantee of a positive outcome.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A more secure legal and strategic position comes from investing in resilience through strong security measures, well-tested recovery plans, clear reporting protocols, and cyber insurance, Tsang advises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cyber insurance is crucial for ransomware attacks because not only does it provide financial protection, but it can also give organizations access to specialized support that can significantly reduce damage and downtime,” Tsang explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571703/cyber-insurance-explained.html"&gt;Cyber insurance&lt;/a&gt; policies often offer active crisis management, with provisions that can cover:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immediate incident response and forensic investigation&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Containment and remediation of infected systems&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Negotiation and legal coordination with attackers&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Data recovery and business continuity support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Insurance can’t prevent an attack — but it can soften the blow, bring structure to chaos, and ensure that organizations don’t navigate ransomware crises alone,” says Blackwired’s Samide.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But cyber insurance still comes with caveats, other experts caution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Insurance premiums are rising, and insurers now expect a stronger baseline of cybersecurity measures — multi-factor authentication, patch management, and tested backups — before offering or renewing coverage,” says Avella Security’s Flack. “This shift encourages organizations to adopt better security practices as part of their risk management approach.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cyber-recovery"&gt;Cyber recovery&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber recovery following a ransomware attack needs to be treated similarly to disaster recovery with a fully defined, in-house recovery plan, fully documented, where uncompromised data can be restored confidently, experts advise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When enterprises are hit by ransomware, one of the first and most pressing challenges is assessing the full scope of the attack — identifying which data has been compromised, which systems are affected, and whether existing backups can be trusted,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mcgann/"&gt;Jim McGann&lt;/a&gt;, CMO at Index Engines, explains. “Even when backups are available, verifying their integrity is a major hurdle, as they may contain corrupted or altered files that could reintroduce the threat during recovery.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Enterprises now need in-house recovery plans that include forensic-level data validation of data, not just restoration,” McGann advises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077484/ransomware-recovery-perils-40-of-paying-victims-still-lose-their-data.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory (AV25-640) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lazarus group targets European drone makers in new espionage campaign</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078672/lazarus-group-targets-european-drone-makers-in-new-espionage-campaign.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity researchers from ESET have identified a new Lazarus Group campaign targeting European defense contractors, particularly those involved in unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to ESET findings, the threat actors used fake job offers and trojanized open-source software, as is customary in their Operation Dreamjob campaigns, to infiltrate their targets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Some of these are heavily involved in the unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) sector, suggesting that the operation may be linked to North Korea’s current efforts to scale up its drone program,” ESET researchers said in a blog post about the European firms targeted. The activity, observed since March 2025, marks another phase of Lazarus’ long-running espionage&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657312/north-koreas-state-hacking-program-is-varied-fluid-and-nimble.html" target="_blank"&gt; operations&lt;/a&gt; that align closely with North Korea’s strategic military objectives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operation Dreamjob is a series of campaigns where the Lazarus group &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3818521/lazarus-group-tricks-job-seekers-on-linkedin-with-crypto-stealer.html"&gt;poses as recruiters&lt;/a&gt; from well-known aerospace and defense firms and deploys malicious payloads to gain persistence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Attack chain built around fake job offers and tampered software&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The initial compromise begins with spear-phishing messages posing as job opportunities from reputable defense companies. These messages deliver malicious files disguised as PDF readers or installation packages. When executed, they load additional components through &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4038967/new-ransomware-charon-uses-dll-sideloading-to-breach-critical-infrastructure.html"&gt;DLL side-loading&lt;/a&gt;, a tactic Lazarus has used in several previous operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this campaign, ESET observed the use of “DroneEXEHijackingLoader.dll,” a loader specifically crafted to exploit legitimate executables, which then delivered “ScoringMathTea,” a custom remote-access trojan (RAT) used by the group for command execution, data exfiltration, and persistence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack also leveraged trojanized versions of open-source software such as WinMerge and Notepad++, embedding loaders and droppers into otherwise benign tools. “The attackers decided to incorporate their malicious loading routines into open-source projects available on GitHub,” the researchers &lt;a href="https://www.welivesecurity.com/en/eset-research/gotta-fly-lazarus-targets-uav-sector/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. “The choice of project varies from one attack to another.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While ScoringMathTea is the primary payload used in this UAV-focused campaign, ESET noted that Lazarus has, in past operations, frequently used LightlessCan and related families, including ImprudentCook, BlindingCan, miniBlindingCan, and SimplexTea.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Drone-component theft meets geopolitical ambition&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The targeting of firms linked to UAV design and manufacture is no coincidence. At least two of the companies compromised were tied to critical drone component supply chains and software systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The in-the-wild attacks successively targeted three European companies active in the defense sector,” researchers added. “Although their activities are somewhat diverse, these entities can be described as a metal engineering company (Southeastern Europe), a manufacturer of aircraft components (Central Europe), and a defense company (Central Europe).”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, imagery and reports indicate that North Korea is actively pursuing its own drone manufacturing capability–Saetbyol-4 and Saetboyl-9 models which bear more than a passing resemblance to US equivalents, the blog noted. The theft of design data, manufacturing process know-how, and supply chain intelligence could accelerate Pyongyang’s UAV push. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ESET has provided downloadable IoCs (SHA-1 hashes, C2 domains, and IPs) and a GitHub repo with the full artifact set and mapped the campaign to MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK techniques such as DLL side-loading (T1574.002), user execution (T1204.002), reflective code loading (T1620), process injection (T1055), and web protocol C2 (T1071.001). According to ESET researchers, defenders in the aerospace and UAV supply chain should ingest these IoCs, tune detections for the listed TTPs, and apply the containment and hunting steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078672/lazarus-group-targets-european-drone-makers-in-new-espionage-campaign.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 12:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agreement on cybercrime criticized over risks to cybersecurity researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078735/un-agreement-on-cybercrime-criticized-over-risks-to-cybersecurity-researchers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity researchers could face criminal charges for performing their legitimate work if the &lt;a href="https://www.unodc.org/unodc/en/cybercrime/convention/text/convention-full-text.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;United Nations Convention against Cybercrime&lt;/a&gt; is ratified in a process beginning in Hanoi, Vietnam, this weekend, critics say.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tech industry group &lt;a href="https://cybertechaccord.org/signatories/"&gt;Cybersecurity Tech Accord&lt;/a&gt; said today that little has changed since it presented &lt;a href="https://www.unodc.org/documents/Cybercrime/AdHocCommittee/Concluding_session/Submissions/Multi-Stakeholders/Cybersecurity_Tech_Accord_-_7th_AHC_session_submission.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a detailed critique of the UN Convention against Cybercrime&lt;/a&gt; more than a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group, comprising tech heavyweights Arm, Cisco, Cloudflare, Dell, Meta, Microsoft, Salesforce, SAP, and over 100 others, warned that the convention opens the door to criminalization of legitimate online activities, as well as making fighting cybercrime more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Accord said the Convention had an unclear and overly broad scope, vague criminalization provisions, missing protections for cybersecurity researchers, unnecessarily expansive data access provisions, and intrusive surveillance powers with no meaningful safeguards to protect individuals and victims of cybercrime from arbitrary abuse of executive authority. “As a result,” it said, “the latest draft reads more like a UN digital surveillance treaty than a targeted instrument to fight cybercrime.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consequently, it urged UN member-states not to ratify the Convention when the process begins this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-researchers-at-risk"&gt;Security researchers at risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Human Rights Watch, an organization that investigates and reports on abuses worldwide, is also opposed to the Convention. In a &lt;a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2024/12/30/new-un-cybercrime-treaty-primed-abuse" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post shortly after the UN adopted the Convention&lt;/a&gt;, it said that the treaty extends far beyond cybercrime to require states to establish “broad electronic surveillance powers” without adequate human rights safeguards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The convention will obligate governments to collect electronic evidence and share it with foreign authorities for any ‘serious crime,’ defined as an offense punishable by at least four years of imprisonment under domestic law,” wrote Deputy Director, Technology, Rights &amp;amp; Investigations, Deborah Brown, noting that many governments treat activities such as investigative journalism and the ordinary activities of security researchers as criminal offenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Human Rights Research Center is one of numerous other groups warning against the Convention. “The poor drafting of the UN Cybercrime Treaty demonstrates that a minimum threshold for activities constituting a cybercrime has not been established, illustrating a problematic line that Member States need to walk in upholding national and international justice,” it warned &lt;a href="https://www.humanrightsresearch.org/post/the-un-cybercrime-treaty-a-pandora-s-box-for-human-rights" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in a March 2025 post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/valence-howden" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Valence Howden&lt;/a&gt;, an advisory fellow at Info-Tech Research Group, said that the Convention had improved during the drafting process, particularly around the definition of what actions constitute cybercrimes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The current text of the agreement focused a lot more on ensuring that the action was taken with the intent to be malicious, so I see a lot of value in this moving forward,” he said. “I don’t believe it’s perfect, and we may need a bit more explicit protection for individuals who aren’t doing things with malicious intent. However, I believe the urge to make it hyper-specific will also allow nitpicking that will work to prevent this from moving forward at all. That approach favors the powerful companies and protects potential criminality on their part in accessing and leveraging data for AI.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, he added, “We need to see and understand the signatories and understand how they implement, because there is flexibility (read as vagueness) in the treaty. Much like global standards, it has to allow for flexibility to account for the variable approaches of different countries and regions. I suspect the debate that it’s driven by is beneficial as well.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Beauceron Security, also applauded facets of the Convention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The good news here is that after five long years of negotiation, certain basics like making sure countries that sign on and ratify this treaty all have criminal laws on the books for various digital crimes consistently is a huge win,” he said, recalling a case he assisted in where the perpetrator of a series of non-consensual intimate image distributions fled the country to a region where the act was not considered a crime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In this scenario, if this convention was in effect, if the country the suspect had fled to had signed on, they would have been required to treat what happened as a crime and hopefully would have cooperated in the investigatation and prosecution of the perpetrator,” he said. “And the victim may have had some measure of justice. Instead, they were left only with the trauma of what happened to them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He is pleased that the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071954/eu-to-sign-un-convention-on-cybercrime.html"&gt;European Union has decided to support the treaty&lt;/a&gt;, since it takes cybercrime seriously while still protecting the fundamental privacy and human rights of its citizens. However, he noted, “I think the key here is to remember each member state has to not just sign on, but has to ratify this treaty in their government and pass or amend laws as required. This is going to take quite some time. As well, nothing in this treaty compromises the judicial or policing processes, so if an authoritarian regime attempts to abuse this convention, western liberal democracies with strong foundations in the rule of law will have checks and balances.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="better-budapest-than-hanoi"&gt;Better Budapest than Hanoi?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the Cybersecurity Tech Accord’s &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashtonhart/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nick Ashton-Hart&lt;/a&gt;, who headed the group’s delegation to the UN committee creating the treaty, said that rather than implementing the Convention against Cybercrime, UN member states should look to another agreement: the Council of Europe’s &lt;a href="https://www.coe.int/en/web/cybercrime/the-budapest-convention" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Budapest Convention&lt;/a&gt;. It, he said, “is a much better agreement that is already in force with a critical mass of member-states as parties, a growing list of states who want to join it,  a proven track record, and extensive guidance in how to address the Convention in a rights respecting way.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He added, “I expect that the private sector will continue to focus its efforts on capacity building and technical assistance for Budapest and won’t prioritize the UN Convention – unless the protocol negotiations [described in Articles 61 and 62 of the Convention] address its problems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite these problems, Shipley thinks that the industry should now focus on proper implementation of the Convention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I understand the concerns that the cybersecurity industry has raised,” he said. “They’re not at the idea of greater cooperation in taking down gangs. They’re aimed at the conventions ambiguous language around unauthorized access and the potential for security researchers to be caught in the crosshairs for doing ethical research. But that ship has sailed and we’d be better off ensuring the application of the convention within states that choose to sign on, does include robust protections for security research.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Convention will come into force 90 days after it has been ratified by 40 member states or regional economic integration organizations; the ratification process extends until December 31, 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078735/un-agreement-on-cybercrime-criticized-over-risks-to-cybersecurity-researchers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-686)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-686</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-686</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-687)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-687</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-687</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-689)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-690)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ericsson security advisory (AV25-691)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-692)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV25-693)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-694)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-583) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-695)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-666) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-015 - Vulnerability impacting Microsoft Windows Server Update Services - CVE-2025-59287</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
