<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 23:19:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-667)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-propagating worm found in marketplaces for Visual Studio Code extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076718/self-propagating-worm-found-in-marketplaces-for-visual-studio-code-extensions-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A month after a self-propagating worm was &lt;a href="https://www.upguard.com/blog/the-shai-hulud-attack-explained" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;discovered in the open source NPM code repository&lt;/a&gt;, a similar worm has been found targeting Visual Studio Code extensions in open marketplaces.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.koi.ai/blog/glassworm-first-self-propagating-worm-using-invisible-code-hits-openvsx-marketplace" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Researchers at Israel-based Koi Security&lt;/a&gt; say the malware, which they dub GlassWorm, has been found in extensions in the OpenVSX and Microsoft VS Code marketplaces.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is one of the most sophisticated supply chain attacks we’ve ever analyzed,” the researchers warn. “And it’s spreading right now.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If the compromised extensions are folded into code, they harvest NPM, GitHub, and Git credentials left by developers in their work, drain funds from 49 cryptocurrency wallets, deploy SOCKS proxy servers on developer computers, install hidden VNX servers for remote access, and use stolen credentials to compromise additional packages and extensions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Seven OpenVSX extensions were compromised last week and were downloaded over 35,000 times, the report says. In addition, another infected extension was detected in the VS Code marketplace over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The worms in the extensions evade detection using an old technique: Including malware written with Unicode variation selectors. These are special characters that are part of the Unicode specification but don’t produce any visual output.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To a developer doing code review, it looks like blank lines or whitespace,” says Koi Security. “To static analysis tools scanning for suspicious code, it looks like nothing at all.” But to a JavaScript interpreter, it’s executable code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CISOs should treat this as an immediate security incident if their developers use VS Code,” says Tanya Janca, head of the Canadian secure coding training consultancy SheHacksPurple.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Because extensions inherit full VS Code permissions, once installed they can steal credentials, exfiltrate source code, and enable remote command and control (for example, via VNC and SOCKS proxies). Risk level: Very High.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should start their incident response processes immediately, she said, conducting an inventory to see which corporate applications use VS Code, which extensions they contain, and determining if any are on the known affected list.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They should also monitor for suspicious application behavior, she added, specifically strange outgoing connections and processes mentioned in the research, unapproved VNC servers, and long-lived SOCKS proxy processes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="educate-your-developers"&gt;Educate your developers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Janca recommends disabling all application auto-updates, and educating all developers about the situation and the extensions to watch for.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Block access to the OpenVSX registry and all other untrusted/unknown marketplaces, permanently,” she advises. “Have developers log out of their developer tools and reboot. Revoke and then rotate any credentials that might have been spilled before logging back into everything.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Follow normal practices for incident response, she concluded: Detect, contain, eradicate, recover.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="marketplaces-targeted"&gt;Marketplaces targeted&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Koi Security report is the latest in a series of warnings that threat actors are increasingly targeting VS Code marketplaces in supply chain attacks.  Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4072829/tigerjacks-malicious-vscode-extensions-mine-steal-and-stay-hidden.html" target="_blank"&gt;Koi Security exposed&lt;/a&gt; a threat actor dubbed TigerJack spreading malicious extensions. And &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4074939/threat-actors-are-spreading-malicious-extensions-via-vs-marketplaces.html" target="_blank"&gt;researchers at Wiz just published research&lt;/a&gt; showing the widespread abuse of the OpenVSX and VS Code marketplaces.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The use of Unicode to hide malware was &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4059606/meet-shadowleak-impossible-to-detect-data-theft-using-ai.html" target="_blank"&gt;exposed as recently as last month&lt;/a&gt; by researchers at Radware, who found it being used to compromise ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These reports should come as no surprise. Open code marketplaces, where developers can upload code for others to use in their applications, have long been targets for threat actors as vehicles for inserting malicious code into projects. The code then spreads into developer or customer environments to steal credentials and data. Collectively, these are known as supply chain attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the most targeted repositories are GitHub, GitLab and &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4060306/npm-attacks-and-the-security-of-software-supply-chains.html" target="_blank"&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft gives developers the ability to add extensions and themes to Visual Studio Code to make life easier for developers, as well as to enhance functionality. An extension can add features like debuggers, new languages, or other development tools, while a theme is a type of extension that changes the appearance of the editor, controlling things like colors and fonts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leverages-blockchain"&gt;Leverages blockchain&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Koi Security researchers came across the wormed extension in OpenVSX when their risk engine flagged suspicious activity in an update of an extension called CodeJoy. a developer productivity tool with hundreds of downloads. However, version 1.8.3 introduced some suspicious behavioural changes. The source code included what looked like massive gap between lines that was actually malicious code encoded in unprintable Unicode characters that can’t be viewed in a code editor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Worse, the malware uses the public &lt;a href="https://solana.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Solana blockchain&lt;/a&gt; as a command and control infrastructure (C2) for its goal of hunting for login credentials, especially those for crypto wallets. The malware also reaches out to a Google Calendar event as a backup C2 mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The stolen NPM, GitHub, Git, and OpenVSX credentials also help the malware spread as a worm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, the malware injects a remote access trojan onto the workstations of victim developers, turning them into SOCKS proxy servers. The workstations can then be used to access an organization’s IT systems, becoming internal network access points, persistent backdoors, proxies for attacking other internal systems and data exfiltration channels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="developers-are-prime-target"&gt;Developers are ‘prime target’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers are a prime target for attacks these days, pointed out &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute. What they often don’t realize is that any extension they install, even if it appears benign, has full access to their code and may make modifications without explicitly informing the developer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs must include developers in discussions about securing development tools, he advises. Limiting permitted tools is often counterproductive, as developers will identify workarounds to get work done. Security must cooperate with developers to assist them in using the tools they need securely, and any endpoint protection product needs to be tuned to support the unique usage patterns of developers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just a supply-chain problem, said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/will-baxter-1b350611/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Will Baxter&lt;/a&gt;, field CISO at Team Cymru, it’s a new infrastructure layer merging cyber-crime tooling, blockchain resilience, and developer-tooling pivoting. Registry operators, threat researchers and blockchain-monitoring partners need to share intelligence and work together more closely to flag these hybrid attacks, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="more-advice-to-csos"&gt;More advice to CSOs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Janca says to lower the risk of supply chain attacks, security leaders and application security professionals should:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reduce attack surface whenever possible: Only install features and other software that they use, for instance, uninstall any VS Code extensions that are not used, and remove all unused dependencies from code;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;monitor all employee workstations for anomalous behavior, with more focus on those who have privileged access, such as software developers.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;apply least privilege for identity and access management, especially for developer machines&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;implement a fast and efficient change management process that includes software supply chain changes;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;train developers on secure coding, protecting their supply chain, and their role during incident response, to help prevent issues like this in the future or to respond faster and more gracefully&lt;br /&gt;There are various security scanning tools that can be used to reduce risk and catch issues before they become security incidents, such as extension scanners, secret scanners, supply chain security tooling (SCA and SBOM), and endpoint protection;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;follow proper secret manage best practices, so that malicious packages like these cannot harvest credentials;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;only approved repositories, marketplaces, etc. should be used in an organizations. Block all unknown or untrusted places for downloading code, packages, images, and extensions;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;harden the entire software supply chain, not just third-party components and code. This includes regular updates and locking down access to the CI/CD, developer IDEs and workstations, artifacts, and more.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;push governments to provide a solution to the very insecure open source software ecosystem that so many of us rely on. Or, give preference closed-source development languages and frameworks, though this, she admits, wouldn’t have helped in this case, as .Net is closed source but VS Code Marketplace is not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4076668/self-propagating-worm-found-in-marketplaces-for-visual-studio-code-extensions.html" target="_blank"&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076718/self-propagating-worm-found-in-marketplaces-for-visual-studio-code-extensions-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 01:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-668)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV25-669)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-670)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-671)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-672)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-014 Security Incident impacting F5</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sendmarc appoints Dan Levinson as Customer Success Director in North America</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076877/sendmarc-appoints-dan-levinson-as-customer-success-director-in-north-america.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendmarc.com/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=dan-announcement-usa-appointment" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sendmarc&lt;/a&gt; has announced the appointment of &lt;strong&gt;Dan Levinson&lt;/strong&gt; as &lt;strong&gt;Customer Success Director – North America&lt;/strong&gt;, furthering the company’s regional expansion and commitment to providing expert, locally aligned support to organizations across the continent. Levinson will lead the development of customer success programs that help businesses strengthen their email security and achieve full compliance with Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance (&lt;a href="https://sendmarc.com/dmarc/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=dan-announcement-usa-appointment" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DMARC&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With over 15 years of experience spanning email security, email deliverability, account management, product management, and leadership, Levinson brings deep expertise in implementing and managing email authentication protocols, including Sender Policy Framework (&lt;a href="https://sendmarc.com/spf/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=dan-announcement-usa-appointment" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SPF&lt;/a&gt;), DomainKeys Identified Mail (&lt;a href="https://sendmarc.com/dkim/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=dan-announcement-usa-appointment" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DKIM&lt;/a&gt;), and DMARC. He has helped organizations apply these standards effectively to reduce impersonation risks and improve deliverability. His work has also driven measurable operational improvements, including a 25% reduction in support cases during a period of 20% year-over-year customer growth. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In his new role, Levinson will focus on building a customer success team designed to provide responsive, expert-level support to Sendmarc’s North American clients. His team will work closely with customers to strengthen the adoption of DMARC and related standards, enabling advanced protection and improved visibility across their email environments. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Joining Sendmarc has allowed me to continue an incredibly rewarding career in cybersecurity. The position affords me an opportunity to remain on the front lines, engaging directly with customers, as well as draw on my leadership experience to build a high-performing team to expand our North American presence,” said Levinson. “Sendmarc has built every capability modern DMARC users expect, without compromising on standards or email deliverability best practices that are often overlooked by other providers in the space. What I’m most impressed with, though, is the dedication and subject matter expertise across the global customer success team. Most team members have had successful careers in other areas of cybersecurity, which strengthens the care and support our customers receive. I honestly couldn’t ask for more when I consider the capabilities and sophistication of the platform, the dedicated staff, and the incredibly trusting leadership group here. Sendmarc is the DMARC solution that the North American market should be very excited about.” Rob Bowker, North America Region Lead at Sendmarc, commented: “The DMARC space is crowded with a lot of noise, but every now and then, you find the people who cut through it. I’ve had the good fortune of working alongside Dan not once, but twice – and this time, we’re doing it with the right platform and the right leadership. I’m very excited about this second chance to get it right.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Sendmarc &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sendmarc.com/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=dan-announcement-usa-appointment" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sendmarc&lt;/a&gt; is a global leader in safeguarding email communications through DMARC. Built with a partner-first approach, its platform empowers MSPs and VARs to deliver trusted protection against impersonation, phishing, and other email-based threats. In addition to preventing fraud, Sendmarc improves email deliverability, ensuring legitimate business communications reach their intended recipients. Trusted by enterprises and partners worldwide, Sendmarc provides the tools and expertise needed to help customers achieve full DMARC compliance quickly and effectively. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North America Customer Success Director&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Levinson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sendmarc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dan.levinson@sendmarc.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North America Region Lead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Bowker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sendmarc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rob.bowker@sendmarc.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076877/sendmarc-appoints-dan-levinson-as-customer-success-director-in-north-america.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfeit and substandard food worth EUR 95 million seized in global operation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</link>
      <description>Europol, OLAF, DG SANTE and 31 countries across Europe and beyond, together with food and beverage producers from the private sector, joined forces in the fourteenth edition of Operation OPSON. This yearly effort targets the criminals behind counterfeit and substandard food and beverages. Law enforcement, customs and food regulatory agencies seized 259 012 packages, 1 416 168 litres of beverages and 11 566 958 kilograms of food, including meat and seafood.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAASM and EASM: Top 12 attack surface discovery and management tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/574797/9-attack-surface-discovery-and-management-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber asset attack surface management (CAASM) or external attack surface management (EASM) solutions are designed to quantify the attack surface and minimize and harden it. The goal with CAASM tools is to give the adversary as little information about the security posture of the business as possible while still maintaining critical business services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever watched a heist film, step one in executing the score of the century is casing the place: observing security measures, measuring response times, and mapping out escape routes. This process is similar to both attacking and protecting enterprise IT resources: Gain knowledge of publicly visible resources on the internet, learn what makes up the technology stack, and find vulnerabilities and weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="basics-of-the-attack-surface-management"&gt;Basics of the attack surface management&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573661/top-5-attack-surface-challenges-related-to-security-operations.html"&gt;attack surface&lt;/a&gt; is the entirety of corporate resources – also known as assets – accessible from the internet in some form. This could be applications hosted on-premises with ports opened through the corporate firewall, SaaS applications hosted in the cloud, or any number of cloud-hosted resources with a public presence. The attack surface includes things like open ports and protocols, SSL and cryptographic standards being used, applications being hosted, and even the server platforms hosting the application.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The units that make up the attack surface are referred to as assets. They are the IP address or domain name, coupled with the technology stack that makes up the application or service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities are configuration deficiencies or unpatched software that leave the door open for an attack by malicious users to compromise one or more systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While attack surface management is primarily focused on assets on the public-facing internet, assets within the bounds of a corporate data center or cloud networks can also put a business at risk if not properly monitored and managed. Because these assets are not available to outside entities the ability to monitor them requires either a software agent or the ability for the monitoring service to reach into your network.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Servers and applications often have a soft underbelly when viewed from within the corporate network. Any monitoring tool must evaluate a wider range of services and, in many cases, test the services as both an anonymous user and one that’s authenticated to the network.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="caasm-and-easm-tools-for-attack-surface-discovery-and-management"&gt;CAASM and EASM tools for attack surface discovery and management&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Periodic scans of the network are no longer sufficient for maintaining a hardened attack surface. Continuous monitoring for new assets and configuration drift are critical to ensure the security of corporate resources and customer data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;New assets need to be identified and incorporated into the monitoring solution as these could potentially be part of a brand attack or shadow IT. Configuration drift could be benign and part of a design change, but also has the potential to be the result of human error or the early stages of an attack. Identifying these changes early allows for the cybersecurity team to react appropriately and mitigate any further damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are 12 tools to help discovering and managing risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="axonius-cyber-asset-attack-surface-management"&gt;Axonius Cyber Asset Attack Surface Management&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Axonius offers a robust &lt;a href="https://www.axonius.com/platform/cyber-asset-attack-surface-management-caasm"&gt;CAASM suite&lt;/a&gt; that touches all the key factors for monitoring the attack surface. It starts with an asset inventory which is updated automatically and fleshed out with context from both internal data sources and resources Axonius has access to outside a user’s network. It can also perform monitoring based on security controls from policy sets such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/569591/pci-dss-explained-requirements-fines-and-steps-to-compliance.html"&gt;PCI&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570241/hipaa-explained-definition-compliance-and-violations.html"&gt;HIPAA&lt;/a&gt;, identifying configurations or vulnerabilities that equate to policy violations, allowing the user to take action to resolve the finding. Pricing on AWS marketplace for the entire Axonius cloud starts at $90,000 per year for 500 assets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="bugcrowd-easm"&gt;Bugcrowd EASM&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bugcrowd acquired Informer’s &lt;a href="https://www.bugcrowd.com/products/attack-surface-management"&gt;EASM&lt;/a&gt; product in May 2024 and has integrated it into its security platform. It automates asset discovery across web applications, APIs, and other aspects of the public-facing business IT stack. These assets are monitored continuously, with any risks identified being prioritized in real time. Informer offers add-on services to perform manual risk validation and even pen testing. The workflow-based response system facilitates incorporating multiple teams into incident response by integrating with existing ticketing and communication applications. Once identified threats have been mitigated, retesting can be initiated immediately to validate the configuration change or system update has fully remediated the risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="crowdstrike-falcon-exposure-management"&gt;CrowdStrike Falcon Exposure Management&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CrowdStrike has transformed Falcon Surface from a standalone EASM tool into a core part of &lt;a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/en-us/platform/exposure-management"&gt;Falcon Exposure Management&lt;/a&gt;, adding AI-native code to proactively identify and eliminate enterprise risk. The software goes beyond alert identification to use adversary-driven AI to deliver real risk reduction. It can correlate exposures with business context, validating exploitability, and enabling direct remediation in Falcon. Enterprises can get an outside-in view of their attack surface and discover internet-connected assets using a variety of techniques, including active, passive, and API-based scans. Using a proprietary and continuously running internet mapping technology, its engine can determine location information and see real-time changes. Customers are seeing up to 98% fewer critical vulnerabilities and 75% smaller external attack surfaces. Specific pricing is not available, and this tool is not part of its enterprise software bundle. It can be purchased as a subscription license on a per managed endpoint basis, with unmanaged asset coverage included at each tier. The above link also has an interactive demo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cycognito-attack-surface-management"&gt;CyCognito Attack Surface Management&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CyCognito’s &lt;a href="https://www.cycognito.com/attack-surface-management"&gt;CAASM&lt;/a&gt; product provides continuous monitoring and inventory of assets whether they reside on-premises, in the cloud, with a third-party, or through a subsidiary. Business context such as ownership and relationships between assets can be added to facilitate the triage process and aid in prioritizing response to risk. This context and intelligent prioritization (evaluating things like ease of exploitation and asset classification) helps focus on the most critical risks to the network. CyCognito also tracks configuration drift on assets, enabling the view of change history and identifying new risks to the corporate infrastructure. Pricing on AWS marketplace is $30,000 per year for 250 assets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="jupiterone-cyber-asset-attack-surface-management"&gt;JupiterOne Cyber Asset Attack Surface Management&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JupiterOne bills its &lt;a href="https://www.jupiterone.com/cyber-asset-attack-surface-management"&gt;CAASM&lt;/a&gt; solution as a way to seamlessly aggregate cyber asset data into a unified view. Context is added automatically where appropriate, and asset relationships can be defined and optimized to enhance vulnerability analysis and incident response. Custom queries allow the cybersecurity team to answer complex questions, while asset inventory can be browsed using an interactive visual map, enabling evaluation of incident scope and prioritization of response. Your existing investments into security tools can be leveraged using integrations, turning JupiterOne into a holistic centralized view into your corporate security posture. Pricing on AWS marketplace is based on company size and starts at $24,000 per year for up to 500 employees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="microsoft-defender-external-attack-surface-management"&gt;Microsoft Defender External Attack Surface Management&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/business/cloud-security/microsoft-defender-external-attack-surface-management"&gt;Microsoft Defender EASM&lt;/a&gt; provides discovery of unmanaged assets and resources, including those deployed by shadow IT and assets residing in other cloud platforms. Once assets and resources are identified, Defender EASM probes for vulnerabilities at every layer of the technology stack, including the underlying platform, app frameworks, web applications, components, and core code. It can quickly remediate vulnerabilities in newly discovered resources by categorizing and prioritizing vulnerabilities in real time as they’re discovered. It integrates with Microsoft’s Security Copilot and Exposure Management to obtain snapshots of the attack surface. Defender EASM has enhanced and more actionable data dashboards. It is priced at a penny per month per managed asset.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="outpost24-easm"&gt;Outpost24 EASM&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Outpost24 acquired Belgian software company Sweepatic and has incorporated its &lt;a href="https://outpost24.com/products/external-attack-surface-management"&gt;EASM&lt;/a&gt; tool into its collection of threat intelligence, data leakage and pen testing modules. Its EASM software is available both directly or as a managed service and can collect data either passively using DNS and other TCP/IP details or with direct connections to cloud providers such as AWS and Azure along with other major software players such as ServiceNow, Slack, Axonius and Atlassian’s Jira. Pricing starts at $17,000 per year and is based on the number of assets under management and other factors such as integration with its other security modules.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="palo-alto-networks-cortex-xpanse"&gt;Palo Alto Networks Cortex Xpanse&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/cortex/cortex-xpanse"&gt;Xpanse&lt;/a&gt; is part of Palo Alto’s XSIAM product suite but can be purchased separately. There is a slightly smaller feature set on the standalone product. It came out of a 2020 acquisition, and it has been tightly integrated into the Palo Alto universe of XSOAR and other XSIAM modules, including playbook automations and remediations. It also &lt;a href="https://docs-cortex.paloaltonetworks.com/r/Cortex-XPANSE/2/Cortex-Xpanse-Expander-User-Guide/Integrations"&gt;supports integration with third-party tools&lt;/a&gt; such as Qualys, Jira, and ServiceNow. The product comes with an impressive array of pre-built detection rules, widgets to assist in constructing queries and discovery routines, and numerous data dashboards that can be customized for particular audiences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="rapid7-surface-command"&gt;Rapid7 Surface Command&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rapid7.com/products/command/attack-surface-management-asm"&gt;Surface Command&lt;/a&gt; is just one of numerous modules offered by Rapid7 that include vulnerability and incident management and cloud native security. It unifies threat exposure, detection, and response, designed to provide a continuous birds-eye view of vulnerabilities from endpoint to cloud to close security gaps and prevent attacks. It is designed to eliminate blind spots and to help accelerate response and remediation. It also includes agentic AI features that are designed for security operations staff to guide threat response. It is priced on a complex calculator based on the average number of monitored assets and free trials are available.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="riskprofiler-io-easm"&gt;RiskProfiler.io EASM&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://riskprofiler.io/"&gt;RiskProfiler uses a single platform&lt;/a&gt; that manages all external threats including dark web, digital monitoring, tracking emerging hacking campaigns, vulnerabilities and supply chain attacks. These threats are tied together with agentic AI tools to provide a unified threat corpus. The product has 13,000 rules pre-installed that bridges both open source and their own proprietary algorithms. One module analyzes vendor third-party risk assessments as part of its threat intelligence. It comes with a customizable management dashboard to show various views. Priced on the number of assets under management and which modules are deployed (such as choosing continuous assessments versus discrete scheduled ones) and whether it is purchased directly or through a managed services partner.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="socradar-attackmapper"&gt;SOCRadar AttackMapper&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SOCRadar is a general-purpose threat intelligence tool that attempts to give users an attacker’s-eye view of assets through &lt;a href="https://socradar.io/suites/attack-surface-management/"&gt;AttackMapper&lt;/a&gt;. It uses agentic-based threat intel to set up smart workflows, also performs dynamic monitoring against assets in real-time, identifying new or changed assets and analyzing those changes for potential vulnerabilities. SOCRadar correlates their findings with known vulnerabilities and attack methods to bring context to the decision making and triage process. AttackMapper does more than monitor endpoints and software vulnerabilities, as things like SSL weaknesses and certificate expiration, and even DNS records and configuration are fair game. Even website defacement can be identified by AttackMapper to protect brand reputation, and there are other modules for dark web and blockchain monitoring, data leak protection and domain takedowns. There is a free edition, and paid versions start at $8,000/year and are based on the size of the digital footprint.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="tenable-asm"&gt;Tenable ASM&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/products/attack-surface-management"&gt;Tenable’s ASM&lt;/a&gt; tool is part of its integrated One exposure management platform that can collect data to help visualize attack paths, evaluate vulnerabilities, and understand the larger threat landscape. Tenable’s unified approach provides security teams with an up-to-date inventory and exposure context needed to confidently identify, prioritize and eliminate risk. It can easily categorize assets using 200 fields of metadata, severity ranking and comprehensive filtering to make informed decisions. It can monitor infrastructure changes to gain an up-to-date view of your assets as your attack surface changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="questions-to-ask-potential-vendors"&gt;Questions to ask potential vendors:&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The days of imagining your attack surface as static and easily tracked are gone. The state of your attack surface changes in sometimes imperceptible ways,” wrote Palo Alto Networks’ &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/resources/research/2023-unit-42-attack-surface-threat-report"&gt;Unit42 in a 2023 threat report&lt;/a&gt;. This means potential ASM buyers need to understand how these changes happen and how they can neutralize them. Here are some questions to ask your team and the vendors about their ASM offerings:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we need a cyber or external-based ASM tool? It depends whether you are looking for the enemy within or without and the proportion of your on-premises infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How much automation is used and how effective is it? Does the ASM tool discover all your vulnerable assets, including digital certificates, exposed user credentials, and other internet-facing servers and services? What metadata and other details, such as open TCP/IP ports and network shares, are part of this discovery?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Once vulnerabilities are found, how are they remediated? Are they automatically fixed or is some human action required?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Does the ASM tool perform continuous monitoring, and how are these changes reported?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What vulnerabilities are shared and how are they shared or integrated with other SOC tools?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Are there different dashboards for management and other consumers of ASM results to make the tool more actionable and useful to these different audiences, such as the cloud security team and security auditors?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Finally, make sure you understand the vendor’s pricing. Most have complex usage-based pricing that is more of a custom quote and very few offer public and transparent pricing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/574797/9-attack-surface-discovery-and-management-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-673)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-674)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce’s glaring Dreamforce omission: Vital security lessons from Salesloft Drift</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076024/dreamforce-finds-salesforce-weathering-a-security-storm.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salesforce’s &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3516181/dreamforce-2024-latest-news-and-insights.html"&gt;2025 Dreamforce conference&lt;/a&gt; last week offered attendees a range of sessions on best practices for securing their Salesforce environments and AI agents, and about what Salesforce itself is doing with AI to improve security. The company even &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069285/salesforce-ai-agents-set-to-assist-enterprises-with-security-and-compliance.html"&gt;released two new agents aimed at CISOs ahead of the event&lt;/a&gt;, one to handle security issues and an agent for addressing privacy and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Overall, security as a shared responsibility was the theme: Salesforce is doing its part, and customers need to do theirs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But what the conference didn’t address were weaknesses exposed by the recent spate of Salesforce-related breaches that affected more than 700 companies and nearly 1.5 billion records, inspiring 70-plus lawsuits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I was at the event, and I talked to all the leadership, and this was not one of the topics,” says Chirag Mehta, a vice president at Constellation Research. “This didn’t come up.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The omission was a likely missed opportunity, given that the lessons of what has gone down in the Salesforce ecosystem over the past few months are significant for the increasingly connected and AI-infused future that is central to Salesforce’s agentic vision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="anatomy-of-a-third-party-cyber-disaster"&gt;Anatomy of a third-party cyber disaster&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At issue is one of the largest SaaS supply-chain breaches in recent years. According to the &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/data-theft-salesforce-instances-via-salesloft-drift"&gt;Google Threat Intelligence Group&lt;/a&gt;, over &lt;a href="https://cyberscoop.com/salesforce-salesloft-drift-attack-spree-google/"&gt;700 organizations&lt;/a&gt; were impacted by an August breach in which the “actor systematically exported large volumes of data from numerous corporate Salesforce instances.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Seeing as the data had been stored by Salesforce, non-cyber professionals might assume this was a Salesforce breach, but that was not the case, Mehta says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Yes, the breach happened in a Salesforce instance,” he explains. “But it was not caused by something Salesforce did. The people who understand what’s going on, they understand what Salesforce is supposed to do, and what the customers were supposed to do.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead, the breach occurred when a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4046407/attackers-steal-data-from-salesforce-instances-via-compromised-ai-live-chat-tool.html"&gt;threat actor obtained Salesforce OAuth tokens&lt;/a&gt; from third-party AI chat tool Salesloft Drift and used the tokens to download large volumes of data from Salesforce instances.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salesforce, which has attempted to minimize the breach’s severity by saying “&lt;a href="https://help.salesforce.com/s/articleView?id=005134951&amp;amp;type=1"&gt;a small number of customers&lt;/a&gt;” were affected, noted that when it detected the activity, it “invalidated active Access and Refresh Tokens, and removed Drift from AppExchange. We then notified affected customers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But according to Salesforce customer Cloudflare, the CDN giant saw the &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/response-to-salesloft-drift-incident/"&gt;first signs&lt;/a&gt; of reconnaissance related to the breach on Aug. 9, with an attacker gaining access to Cloudflare’s Salesforce tenant on Aug. 12. By Aug. 17, the attackers had analyzed Cloudflare’s Salesforce case workflows, derived insights into how Cloudflare’s team members handle various types of cases, and completed their exfiltration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Three days later, on Aug. 20, Salesforce revoked Salesloft Drift connections and published its notice on its website. “At that point, Cloudflare had not yet been notified, and we had no indication that this vendor action might relate to our environment,” Cloudflare’s security leaders stated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare wasn’t alone. Hundreds of companies were affected, including some of the biggest names in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mitiga.io/blog/shinyhunters-and-unc6395-inside-the-salesforce-and-salesloft-breaches"&gt;Mitiga Security researcher Idan Cohen wrote&lt;/a&gt;: “In the Drift case, customers weren’t careless. The attackers didn’t hack their way in. They logged in, pretending to be a trusted third-party service.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t the only case involving breached Salesforce accounts. In June, a different group of attackers, known as ShinyHunters, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4035701/we-too-were-breached-says-google-months-after-revealing-salesforce-attacks.html"&gt;pretended to be IT support personnel&lt;/a&gt;, in order to trick users into approving a connection to a malicious version of Salesforce’s Data Loader application that then exfiltrated data from Salesforce environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google, whose threat intelligence team described these attacks in a June report, itself fell victim to such an attack in August.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By October, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4067846/extortion-gang-opens-data-leak-site-to-squeeze-victims-of-its-salesforce-attacks.html"&gt;attackers claimed to have stolen more than 1.5 billion Salesforce records&lt;/a&gt; from 760 companies. They also launched an extortion campaign against Salesforce and its compromised enterprise customers, including Toyota, FedEx, Hulu, and UPS.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Multiple lawsuits have been filed against Salesforce, claiming the company didn’t do enough to vet third-party applications connected to its systems, or to monitor for signs of data exfiltration and other malicious activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Salesforce … had the duty and ability to control its software environment and prevent these attacks from succeeding through implementation of security protocols that other companies in Salesforce’s industry regularly and routinely implement. But Salesforce did not,” said one complaint in a &lt;a href="https://mdlcases.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/MDL-3164.pdf"&gt;class-action lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; filed on Aug. 29 in California.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The potential for OAuth exploitation “was a known risk” and Salesforce failed to vet third-party connections, build protections, or monitor its networks against this kind of malicious activity, another group of class-action claimants said in a &lt;a href="https://www.pacermonitor.com/public/filings/DM725Z2I/Johnson_v_Salesforce_Inc__candce-25-08011__0001.0.pdf"&gt;complaint&lt;/a&gt; filed in September.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to San Diego law firm CaseyGerry, there are now more than &lt;a href="https://caseygerry.com/blog/salesforce-data-breach-lawsuit/"&gt;70 cases filed&lt;/a&gt; across the country related to the Salesforce data breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-biggest-blind-spot"&gt;The biggest blind spot&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When companies delegate access to third parties via OAuth integrations, it creates a systemic security blind spot that spans all industries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By stealing those tokens, attackers can gain access to all connected systems. “Authorizing a malicious connected app bypasses many traditional defenses such as MFA, password resets and login monitoring, and because OAuth tokens are issued by Salesforce itself, activity coming from the malicious app can look like it’s from a trusted integration,” the FBI &lt;a href="https://www.ic3.gov/CSA/2025/250912.pdf"&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; in an alert released in September.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The exploitation of such weaknesses is only going to get worse — especially as AI-related integrations increasingly become the norm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whereas a traditional CRM integration might need contact data, “an AI sales assistant typically requires contacts, email histories, calendar information, deal pipeline data, conversation logs, and product catalogs,” noted Trend Micro AI security expert Fernando Tucci in a report on why the &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/i/ai-app-breach.html"&gt;breach of Salesloft Drift — an AI chatbot — hits differently&lt;/a&gt;. “This broader access pattern means a single compromised AI integration can expose significantly more sensitive information than traditional point solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Worse, because AI chatbots are specifically designed to access large data sets, when a malicious actor piggybacks on the same connection to steal data, the traffic pattern can look legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Understanding all these partnerships and connections requires close coordination with vendor management, says Steve Winterfeld, advisory CISO at Akamai. “Plus, understanding where your data is takes both culture-driven policies and technical controls,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With white-labeled services, APIs, and now LLMs, these two goals are much more complex. “If you haven’t conducted a supply chain breach exercise yet, now is the time,” Winterfeld says. “These recent events underscore the importance of validating your program.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ironically, many security firms were among the victims, including Zscaler, Cloudflare, Palo Alto Networks, Pager Duty, SpyCloud, Tenable, Proofpoint, Rubrik, BeyondTrust, Bugcrowd, JFrog, CyberArk, and Black Duck.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="one-company-who-didnt-fall-victim"&gt;One company who didn’t fall victim&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One company that wasn’t scathed by the breaches was cloud-based IAM vendor Okta. Why? It allowed connections only from authorized IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.okta.com/newsroom/articles/the-salesloft-incident--a-wake-up-call-for-saas-security-and-ips/"&gt;According to Okta&lt;/a&gt;, when the company learned of the compromise, it immediately reviewed its logs and found attempts to access resources with stolen tokens — but those attempts failed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The single most important control that prevented this breach was our enforcement of inbound IP restrictions,” the company said. “The threat actor attempted to use a compromised token to access our Salesforce instance, but the attack failed because the connection originated from an unauthorized IP address. This security layer proved essential, blocking the unauthorized attempt at the front door before any access could be gained.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This whitelisting approach to security is a powerful tactic, but it’s difficult to implement because it requires a great deal of discipline.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another challenge is that not all SaaS vendors support this capability. “Many providers in the cloud-first world do not offer this foundational security feature, creating a significant challenge for protecting interconnected systems,” Okta said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Foundational security benchmarks for SaaS providers are only now coming together, following the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4063383/cloud-security-alliance-launches-framework-to-improve-saas-security.html"&gt;Cloud Security Alliance’s recently launched SaaS Security Capability Framework (SSCF)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Okta noted that Salesforce already offers this functionality, but added that using it requires “significant effort,” given that restrictions have to be configured for APIs and users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another way to protect connections is to limit them to a specific client, using demonstrating proof of possession (DPoP), which prevents the reuse of stolen tokens, but this is even more difficult in practice because it requires changes to the authentication flow and adds new requirements for clients and servers. Another option is mutual TLS, which offers even stronger security, but at an even higher cost of complexity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the financial sector, for example, some regulators mandate DPoP or mTLS; while it isn’t mandated in healthcare, there’s a use case there as well, according to &lt;a href="https://tyk.io/blog/demonstrating-proof-of-possession-dpop-oauth2-security-for-fapi-2-0-and-open-banking/"&gt;Tyk Technologies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More companies should be looking at upgrading this as their use of interconnected SaaS apps and AI tools increases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Internet Engineering Task Force &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc9700#name-sender-constrained-access-t"&gt;included&lt;/a&gt; both DPoP and mTLS among its best practices for OAuth security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="compounding-risk-going-forward"&gt;Compounding risk going forward&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When companies allow connections to systems outside their perimeter, they need to understand the risks they are assuming and the security controls available to them, Constellation’s Mehta says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even a control as straightforward and common as multi-factor authentication can be difficult to implement for all employees, he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“From a solution provider perspective, they provide a specific set of security controls and features and it’s up to the customers to make sure they actually use them. In my view, it is a shared responsibility,” Mehta says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shared responsibility for security was an important part of the message of last week’s Dreamforce, but discussion of the Salesloft incident was conspicuously missing — a loss for attendees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because if anything can be taken away from the past few months of Salesforce-related cybersecurity, it’s that software supply-chain security is more important than ever. And it will only increase in importance as more systems get connected — a key tenet of &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4066640/salesforce-trusted-ai-foundation-provides-scaffolding-for-the-agentic-enterprise.html"&gt;Salesforce’s aim to power the agentic enterprise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Software supply-chain security is already not so easy to achieve, and, even as Salesforce promises to make this easier with the help of AI, it is AI itself that will make the problem that much harder to solve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;More &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3490106/salesforce-latest-news-and-insights.html"&gt;Salesforce news&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4071597/salesforce-updates-its-agentic-ai-pitch-with-agentforce-360.html"&gt;Salesforce updates its agentic AI pitch with Agentforce 360&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4070540/lessons-from-the-salesforce-breach.html"&gt;Lessons from the Salesforce breach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4069900/salesforce-brings-agentic-ai-to-it-service-management.html"&gt;Salesforce brings agentic AI to IT service management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4046713/salesforce-ai-research-unveils-new-tools-for-ai-agents.html"&gt;Salesforce AI Research unveils new tools for AI agents&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076024/dreamforce-finds-salesforce-weathering-a-security-storm.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-675)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-676)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-677)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 factors creating bottlenecks for enterprise GenAI adoption</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076511/4-factors-creating-bottlenecks-for-enterprise-genai-adoption.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There’s a significant gap between the potential value of AI and the measurable value that enterprises have only recently begun to experience. The launch of ChatGPT in 2022 triggered a massive shift in how companies perceive AI. Pilots were launched. Promises of high returns were made. Innovation skyrocketed. LLMs, retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipelines and multi-agent systems are being embedded into decision-critical workflows — from contract analysis to customer support to financial approvals. The pace of technological change has become so rapid that many companies are now struggling to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But here’s one hard truth: &lt;a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=US52838824&amp;amp;pageType=PRINTFRIENDLY" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;only 3 out of 37 GenAI pilots are actually successful&lt;/a&gt;. While data quality has emerged as a major concern, experts are also concerned about surrounding issues — including security, observability, evaluation and integration. These are non-negotiable for GenAI security and success.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-security-data-privacy-beyond-firewalls"&gt;1. Security &amp;amp; data privacy: Beyond firewalls&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/research/project-vend-1" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anthropic’s experiment with Claudius&lt;/a&gt; is an eye-opener. The experiment illuminates that security in generative AI isn’t about perimeter defenses — it’s about controlling what models and agents can &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;. Unlike traditional models, where erecting digital walls at the perimeter can secure the system, GenAI systems can be attacked with prompt injections, agentic manipulations or shadow models created by reverse engineering.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perimeter defenses — like firewalls, authentication and DDoS protection — are crucial, but they only control who can access the system or how much data can flow in or out. However, in recent times, multiple options have emerged to ensure what models can see or do, including running inference inside secure enclaves, dynamic PII scrubbing, role-based data filtering and least-privilege access controls for agents. From my experiments, I can say that two strategies stand out: Confidential compute with policy-driven PII protection and fine-grained agent permissions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="confidential-compute-policy-driven-pii-protection"&gt;Confidential compute + policy-driven PII protection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fintech, healthtech, regtech and other domains, LLMs often process sensitive data — contracts, patient records and financials. There, even if you trust the cloud, regulators may not. Confidential computing ensures data-in-use protection, even from cloud operators. It guarantees strong compliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But there is a trade-off. The technology is still in its early days and it can incur significant costs. That said, it can be used in narrow use cases with regulated data. It gives satisfactory results when paired with &lt;a href="https://www.talentica.com/blogs/privacy-by-design-safeguarding-pii-in-the-age-of-generative-ai/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;dynamic PII scrubbing tools&lt;/a&gt; like Presidio or Immuta for adaptive protection based on geography, user role or data classification.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="fine-grained-agent-permissions-zero-trust-for-llms"&gt;Fine-grained agent permissions (zero trust for LLMs)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Consider AI agents as &lt;em&gt;untrusted by default&lt;/em&gt; and only grant them the exact access they need—nothing more. Blanket access is dangerous, much like handing an intern unrestricted control of your ERP system. Agents work more securely when each agent-tool pair gets a scoped capability token that defines precisely what it’s allowed to do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, an &lt;em&gt;Invoice Extractor&lt;/em&gt; agent might parse PDF files but have &lt;a href="https://www.talentica.com/blogs/zero-knowledge-proofs-in-decentralized-blockchain-elevating-privacy-and-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;zero access&lt;/a&gt; to financial databases. Policy engines like OPA (Open Policy Agent) or Cerbos enforce these permissions at scale as centralized access managers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some teams experiment with blockchain-based audit trails for tamper-proof logging—useful in defense or supply chain scenarios, but typically unnecessary overhead for most enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-observability-taming-the-black-box"&gt;2. Observability: Taming the black box&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Debugging autonomous agents is exponentially harder than debugging chatbots. If you don’t have enough observability, you risk “black box chaos.” Without transparency, it will be really difficult for teams to understand, trust or improve the system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Observability in GenAI means more than logging. You need to trace, debug, replay and validate agent decisions across unpredictable workflows. Implement early to move from firefighting to proactive reliability. I go ahead with two solutions-&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="distributed-tracing-with-agent-graphs"&gt;Distributed tracing with agent graphs&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Debugging and optimization are tricky in multi-agent systems as tasks are often delegated in unpredictable ways. Tools like OpenTelemetry, LangSmith and Grafana help in visualizing how agents make decisions, track their task flows and measure latency at each step.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These tools create clear interaction graphs and identify bottlenecks by explaining system behavior and speeding root cause analysis. However, detailed traces create storage overhead and data leakage risks if sensitive prompts or outputs aren’t properly safeguarded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="replay-simulation-environments"&gt;Replay &amp;amp; simulation environments&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many production issues in agentic systems are “one-off” bugs caused by unusual input or timing. Replay environments allow teams to re-run prompt chains and simulate edge cases, which is crucial for diagnosing failures and preventing regressions. Such setups ensure robust deployments and support more rigorous testing before pushing changes live.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, don’t expect this solution to replicate a real-life scenario. The complexity and unpredictability of a real production environment is a completely different ball game. Use this solution as a complement to, rather than a substitute for, live monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-evaluation-model-migration-readiness"&gt;3. Evaluation &amp;amp; model migration readiness&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional enterprise release cycles are no match for the rapidly evolving LLM landscape. The pace at which new models emerge puts the LLM ecosystem several steps ahead. If enterprises fail to keep up, they risk falling behind in innovation or incurring costly technical debt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Switching to a new model or framework without a structured approach can cause performance regressions or unexpected behavior in production environments. Every time you switch models, there is a risk. LLMs don’t behave in the same way as other normal software upgrades. A new model might give different answers, miss compliance rules or fail in niche use cases your business depends on. Add to that, vendors change pricing often, APIs get deprecated and leadership often pushes for cost savings or better accuracy. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Continuous evaluation and safe model migration are two possible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="continuous-evaluation-pipelines"&gt;Continuous evaluation pipelines&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Treat model evaluation in the context of large language models (LLMs) like CI/CD pipelines in software development. Test LLMs like you test code—continuously. Use curated test sets with domain Q&amp;amp;A, edge cases and red-team prompts to ensure models stay aligned with business goals and catch potential issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Weekly evaluations let teams catch regressions before they hit production or affect users. This proactive approach keeps models robust against evolving data and changing user needs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, frequent evaluation brings significant costs—token usage, infrastructure and human effort to maintain test sets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Balance cost and evaluation by rotating test sets quarterly and incorporating anonymized real user data. This optimizes the process while simulating real-world scenarios and preserving privacy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="dual-run-migration-strategy"&gt;Dual-run migration strategy&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Migrating to a new model in production demands precision and caution. Deploy a dual-run strategy to allow both the old and new models to operate in parallel. You can then compare their outputs in real-time, and make the final switch gated by predefined evaluation thresholds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let me explain this with an example. Financial services companies are very specific about their requirements, such as privacy, observability and other features. We dual-ran GPT-4 and Mistral for one such company for six weeks before making the switch to understand the pros and cons. This ensured a smooth transition as we monitored their outputs and only cut over when the new model consistently met or exceeded performance benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note: Treat LLMs as modular infrastructure components — not monolithic systems that are too risky to touch. With the right evaluation and migration strategies, enterprises can stay agile, reduce risk and continuously improve their AI capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-secure-business-integration-from-poc-to-production"&gt;4. Secure business integration: From POC to production&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most enterprises plug GenAI into workflows through basic APIs or chat interfaces. This works for prototypes but lacks enterprise-grade guardrails. Security, governance and accountability concerns quickly derail adoption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;True enterprise AI requires deep integration with robust security, governance and accountability built in. AI must be embedded within systems that enforce organizational policies, monitor behavior and ensure traceability. This means pairing AI capabilities with business rules, compliance requirements and operational standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without proper integration, even high-performing models become liabilities—causing data leaks, unauthorized actions or biased decisions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="policy-aware-integration-with-enterprise-systems"&gt;Policy-aware integration with enterprise systems&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Guardrails are essential when integrating GenAI with core enterprise platforms like SAP, Salesforce or ServiceNow. These systems handle sensitive data and critical operations — unconstrained AI access dramatically increases risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implement policy enforcement points (PEPs) as a compliance layer for AI actions. For example, an AI drafting sales proposals needs managerial oversight for approvals over $50,000. Without this guardrail, the system might approve controversial deals autonomously. The case of Air Canada is a great example where &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/travel/article/20240222-air-canada-chatbot-misinformation-what-travellers-should-know" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the bot gave the customer wrong information and the court found the company liable for it&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This system can further be strengthened with a role-based data filtering. The system can ensure that the AI gets access to data that the human user is authorized to see. This would prevent inadvertent exposure of confidential information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="impact-analytics-risk-dashboards"&gt;Impact analytics &amp;amp; risk dashboards&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional security logs are insufficient for understanding the real-world impact of GenAI applications. Businesses need visibility into how AI affects outcomes — such as whether it reduces escalation rates, flags problematic contracts or improves operational efficiency. For this, you need impact analytics dashboards to track both operational metrics and business KPIs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, there’s a risk that AI may optimize for the wrong metrics, such as approving borderline cases to reduce turnaround time. This might compromise quality or compliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now this solution is probably the most advised. Organizations must implement human-in-the-loop checkpoints and conduct periodic audits to ensure AI decisions align with strategic goals and ethical standards. I would like to suggest one extra step. Create tiered thresholds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For a low-risk action like drafting internal emails is a low-risk action, let the GenAI act autonomously. But from there onwards, you have to be extra careful. For a medium-risk action like customer responses, route a random sample for human review. For high-risk actions like contract approvals and financial changes, there are no shortcuts. You must enforce mandatory sign-off.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="where-compromise-leads-to-catastrophe"&gt;Where compromise leads to catastrophe&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security, observability, evaluation and integration are four crucial factors creating bottlenecks for enterprise AI adoption. Enterprises operate with huge datasets that are sensitive in nature. Any compromise there could be catastrophic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controlling what models and agents can see and do is crucial.&lt;/strong&gt; Confidential computing with policy-driven PII protection and zero-trust safeguards for LLMs has emerged as two effective measures.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observability can negate ‘black box chaos’.&lt;/strong&gt; Distributed tracing with agent graphs, along with replay and simulation environments, has proven its worth as an efficient method. But don’t expect the second method to mimic a perfect real-life scenario.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation and model migration help enterprises avoid tech debt and streamline innovation.&lt;/strong&gt; Continuous evaluation pipelines and a dual-run migration strategy can keep them abreast of the market. But enterprises must also factor in the cost. A spike in evaluation frequency could impact ROI.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://mlq.ai/media/quarterly_decks/v0.1_State_of_AI_in_Business_2025_Report.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;95% of POCs fail to move to production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is because POC guardrails are no match for real-world security risks. Policy-aware integration and impact analytics with risk dashboards can ensure a smoother transition. A tiered threshold can improve performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076511/4-factors-creating-bottlenecks-for-enterprise-genai-adoption.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted five key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I am not a robot’: Russian hackers use fake CAPTCHA lures to deploy espionage tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077031/i-am-not-a-robot-russian-hackers-use-fake-captcha-lures-to-deploy-espionage-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Russian state-backed hackers are using fake “I am not a robot” CAPTCHA pages to deliver new strains of espionage malware, according to Google Cloud’s Threat Intelligence Group (GTIG), marking a fresh evolution in tactics by the ColdRiver group that has long targeted Western governments, think tanks, and media organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group, also known as Star Blizzard, UNC4057, or Callisto, has replaced its previously exposed LostKeys malware with a new suite of tools, including NOROBOT, YESROBOT, and MAYBEROBOT.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These programs can evade detection through multi-stage delivery chains and encrypted payloads. Google said the shift came just days after the company published technical details on LostKeys earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1294806/russian-hacker-coldriver-extends-tactics-to-include-custom-malware.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;ColdRiver&lt;/a&gt;’s latest campaign uses social engineering tactics known as “ClickFix,” tricking victims into running malicious code disguised as CAPTCHA verification steps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“NOROBOT and its preceding infection chain have been subject to constant evolution — initially simplified to increase chances of successful deployment, before re-introducing complexity by splitting cryptography keys,” &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/new-malware-russia-coldriver" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GTIG said&lt;/a&gt;. “The shift back to more complex delivery chains increases the difficulty of tracking their campaigns. This constant development highlights the group’s efforts to evade detection systems for their delivery mechanism for continued intelligence collection against high-value targets.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The technique shows a growing trend in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3546864/doj-seizes-41-russian-controlled-domains-in-cyber-espionage-crackdown.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;state-sponsored operations&lt;/a&gt; that combine psychological manipulation with stealthy modular malware to bypass enterprise defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“ColdRiver’s quick pivot from exposed infrastructure to new delivery methods like fake CAPTCHAs reveals a lot about their capabilities,” said &lt;a href="https://www.hfsresearch.com/team/akshat-tyagi/"&gt;Akshat Tyagi&lt;/a&gt;, associate practice leader at HFS Research. “They are operationally very agile because, practically within weeks, they shifted infrastructure, rewrote delivery mechanisms, and deployed new payloads. It seems they are a well-funded and well-resourced team. They likely have a modular architecture allowing them to replace components, and they also have access to global engineering talent.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="inside-the-findings"&gt;Inside the findings&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google said the new malware families have been in active development from May through September 2025, with the attackers repeatedly refining their tools to evade detection. The pace of updates shows ColdRiver’s ability to rebuild its toolset almost immediately after public exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The earliest NOROBOT sample used a cryptographic scheme that split the decryption key across multiple components that had to be recombined in a specific order to decrypt the final payload.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;YESROBOT is described in Google’s report as a minimal Python backdoor that requires every command to be valid Python, making basic functions such as downloading files or retrieving documents more cumbersome to implement. The latter NOROBOT build was drastically simplified, fetching a single file that, in observed cases, installed a logon script to establish persistence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“The specific changes made between NOROBOT variants highlight the group’s persistent effort to evade detection systems while ensuring continued intelligence collection against high-value targets,” the report said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="evolving-tactics-and-strategies"&gt;Evolving tactics and strategies&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts said ColdRiver, which for years focused on credential theft and email account compromise, is shifting toward multi-stage intrusions that rely on users to execute malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By using ClickFix pages that mimic CAPTCHA verification screens, the group can bypass email security filters and deliver malware directly to victims’ devices, increasing the likelihood of infection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“At this stage, it is difficult to expect end users to identify and discard fraudulent CAPTCHA, since CAPTCHA is part of the standard access process,” said cybersecurity analyst &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sunilvarkey1/"&gt;Sunil Varkey&lt;/a&gt;. “The only option is to monitor behavioral changes, living-off-the-land telemetry, and abnormal activity through tools such as EDR and NDR. Organizations need to understand how users and hosts behave in specific scenarios and monitor deviations, which requires having a strong baseline and enforcing it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This shift from simple phishing to multi-stage, interactive attacks shows ColdRiver’s ability to adapt to improved cyber awareness among users. Traditional lures are less effective as people become cautious about clicking suspicious links, but CAPTCHA pages still feel familiar and safe, a trust ColdRiver has learned to exploit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Tactically, it indicates ColdRiver’s focus on operational security (OPSEC) and stealth,” said &lt;a href="https://sure-shield.com/our-teams/sanjaya-kumar/"&gt;Sanjaya Kumar&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of SureShield. “The malware uses encrypted communications and anti-analysis techniques, allowing prolonged access for months without detection. Target selection remains high value, including NGOs, dissidents, policy advisors, and Western officials, but the CAPTCHA method also extends to softer targets in think tanks and academia, where quick credential theft can lead to espionage chains.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For defenders, it underscores the need to move beyond traditional two-factor authentication and adopt behavioral and context-aware monitoring to identify stealthy, user-assisted intrusions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="defense-options-for-enterprises"&gt;Defense options for enterprises&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the attackers target specific organizations and individuals, they can use server-side filtering to deliver malware only to selected victims, making large-scale detection difficult, analysts said. Detection is further complicated when global security vendors have not yet developed or prioritized signatures for the new attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Defenders need to be fully aware that this isn’t a basic phishing gang using off-the-shelf malware,” Varkey said. “It appears to be state-linked or state-sponsored, with significant resources and the ability to pivot to new tools and delivery methods rapidly. Defenders cannot depend solely on IOCs, and organizations may need to strengthen their security posture to protect high-value assets significantly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kumar added that effective defense requires a layered and behavior-focused approach that uses tools to monitor anomalous PowerShell execution, unusual network calls to command-and-control servers, or fileless malware patterns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams should establish baselines for normal activity and generate alerts when deviations occur, such as unexpected login attempts from foreign IP addresses or rapid data exfiltration. “Focus on building a zero-trust architecture and enforce least-privilege access and micro-segmentation to limit lateral movement,” Kumar said. “Continuous vulnerability management scans to patch endpoints before exploitation, combined with security awareness training on interactive phishing (e.g., simulated CAPTCHA attacks), to cut success rates. Incident Responses need to be solidified, so simulate multi-stage attacks to test containment. Proactive cyber hygiene – regular patching, endpoint hardening, and threat hunting is essential.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077031/i-am-not-a-robot-russian-hackers-use-fake-captcha-lures-to-deploy-espionage-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-616) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zimbra security advisory (AV25-678)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serious vulnerability found in Rust library</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077445/serious-vulnerability-found-in-rust-library.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers creating projects in the Rust programming language, as well as IT leaders with Rust-based applications in their environments, should pay attention to a serious vulnerability found in one of the programming language’s libraries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Edera say they have uncovered a critical boundary-parsing bug, dubbed TARmageddon (&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-62518" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-62518&lt;/a&gt;), in the popular &lt;em&gt;async-tar&lt;/em&gt; Rust library. And not only is it in this library, but also in its many forks, including the widely used &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the worst-case scenario, this vulnerability has a severity of 8.1 (High) and can lead to Remote Code Execution (RCE) through file overwriting attacks, such as replacing configuration files or hijacking build backends,” &lt;a href="https://edera.dev/stories/tarmageddon" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the researchers say in a report. &lt;/a&gt;Among the other possible impacts is the spread of the infection via applications, also known as a supply chain attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first recommended action is to patch all active forks, since this vulnerability impacts major, widely-used projects, the researchers say, including &lt;em&gt;uv&lt;/em&gt; (Astral’s Python package manager), &lt;em&gt;testcontainers&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;wasmCloud&lt;/em&gt;. “Due to the widespread nature of &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; in various forms, it is not possible to truly quantify upfront the blast radius of this bug across the ecosystem,” they say.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, the researchers warn, the highly downloaded &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; remains unpatched, probably because it’s no longer actively maintained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Edera suggests that developers who rely on &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; consider migrating to an actively maintained fork such as &lt;em&gt;astral-tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt; version 0.5.6 or later, which has been patched.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders also need to scan their applications to see if any were developed in Rust and are at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-is-it-critical"&gt;Why is it critical?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;TAR files are used in Unix and Linux systems for bundling multiple directories and files into an archive file that retains the full directory structure and metadata of the original information, explains Robert Beggs, head of Canadian incident response firm DigitalDefence. Archive files are commonly used in backups, or for packing software for purposes such as distributing source code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because of the way in which particular versions of the TAR libraries have been written, a potential vulnerability exists, he said in an email to &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt;, noting,  “In the worst case, it would allow an attacker to execute arbitrary code on a host system and engage in malicious actions, such as overwriting critical files (configuration files, build scripts), or gaining unauthorized filesystem access.” Exploitation could also result in the compromise of any system that extracts files from the malicious TAR.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The vulnerability is especially serious because the vulnerable TAR libraries are often present as part of applications that are not actively maintained, and may be missed when patching or otherwise mitigating the issue,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While there are as yet no known exploits of this vulnerability, Beggs said that can change quickly. “It is a high severity vulnerability  — 8.1 on a scale of 1 to 10 –,” he pointed out, “so it will likely attract the attention of attackers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="recommendations"&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He recommends infosec leaders: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;audit code to identify dependencies for forks or wrappers of &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar &lt;/em&gt;and ensure that they are also patched&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review usage of TAR files in continuous integration/continuous deployment environments as well as containers, and ensure that they are patched;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;isolate (sandbox) archives when processing, and avoid extracting TAR files from untrusted sources;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue to monitor for possible exploits or further vulnerabilities associated with the library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Admins may also be interested in &lt;a href="https://github.com/astral-sh/tokio-tar/security/advisories/GHSA-j5gw-2vrg-8fgx" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this advisory explaining the problem&lt;/a&gt; created by Astral Security, which maintains &lt;em&gt;astral-tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The bug was discovered in July and disclosed that month to maintainers of all libraries, the Rust Foundation, and a certain number of projects. It was agreed details wouldn’t be released until this week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the most popular fork (&lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;, with over 5 million downloads on crates.io) appears to be no longer actively maintained, Edera co-ordinated a decentralized disclosure across the complex fork lineage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="possible-consequences"&gt;Possible consequences&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability is a desynchronization flaw that allows an attacker to ‘smuggle’ additional archive entries into TAR extractions, says Edera. It occurs when processing nested TAR files that exhibit a specific mismatch between their PAX extended headers and ustar headers. The flaw stems from the parser’s inconsistent logic when determining file data boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the possible infection scenarios painted by Edera are&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an attack on Python package managers using &lt;em&gt;tokio-tar&lt;/em&gt;. An attacker uploads a malicious package to the open source PyPI repository, from which developers download useful utilities. The package’s outer TAR container has a legitimate file but the hidden inner TAR contains a malicious one that hijacks the build backend. This hidden inner TAR introduces unexpected or overwritten files, which compromises the test environment and pollutes the supply chain;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;an attack on any system with separate ‘scan/approve’ phases.  A security scanner analyzes the outer, clean TAR and approves its limited file set. However, the extraction process using the vulnerable library pulls in additional, unapproved, and unscanned files from the inner TAR, resulting in a security control bypass and policy violation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rust developers say the language allows the creation of memory-safe applications, but, say Edera researchers, “the discovery of TARmageddon is an important reminder that Rust is not a silver bullet.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It does not eliminate logic bugs,” the report points out, “and this parsing inconsistency is fundamentally a logic flaw. Developers must remain vigilant against all classes of vulnerabilities, regardless of the language used.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report is also a reminder of the hazards of relying on unmaintained open source libraries in code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077445/serious-vulnerability-found-in-rust-library.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 21:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Risk-Assessment-Frameworks im Vergleich</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552765/6-risk-assessment-frameworks-im-vergleich.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="6 Risk-Assessment-Frameworks im Vergleich" class="wp-image-3552768" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/1200x.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Mit dem richtigen Framework lassen sich Risiken besser ergründen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;FOTOGRIN – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für viele Geschäftsprozesse ist Technologie inzwischen unverzichtbar. Deshalb zählt diese auch zu den wertvollsten Assets eines Unternehmens. Leider stellt sie gleichzeitig jedoch auch eines der größten Risiken dar – was Risk-Assessment-Frameworks auf den Plan ruft.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT-Risiken formal &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492180/cyber-risk-assessments-risikobewertung-hilft-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;zu bewerten&lt;/a&gt;, ermöglicht es Organisationen, besser einzuschätzen, zu welchem Grad ihre Systeme, Devices und Daten schädlichen Einflüssen ausgesetzt sind. Etwa in Form von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cyberbedrohungen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495375/third-party-risk-management-so-vermeiden-sie-compliance-unheil.html" target="_blank"&gt;Compliance-Verfehlungen&lt;/a&gt; oder &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/a/10-fakten-zu-datacenter-ausfaellen,3614299" target="_blank"&gt;Ausfällen&lt;/a&gt;. Zudem können IT- und Sicherheitsentscheider deren Folgen mit Hilfe von entsprechenden Rahmenwerken auch besser abzuschätzen. Das Ziel besteht am Ende darin, sämtliche identifizierten Risiken – und ihren Impact – zu minimieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In diesem Artikel stellen wir Ihnen (in aller Kürze) sechs populäre Risk-Assessment-Frameworks vor, die jeweils auf spezifische Risikobereiche abgestimmt sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-cobit"&gt;1. COBIT&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Hinter &lt;strong&gt;COBIT&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.isaca.org/resources/cobit" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Control Objectives for Information and Related Technology&lt;/a&gt;) steht der internationale IT-Berufsverband ISACA, der sich auf IT Governance fokussiert hat. Dieses sehr umfassende und breit angelegte Framework wurde entwickelt, um dabei zu unterstützen, Enterprise IT:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zu verstehen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu designen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu implementieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu managen und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;zu steuern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut ISACA definiert COBIT die Komponenten und Designfaktoren, ein optimales Governance-System aufzubauen und aufrechtzuerhalten. Die aktuelle Version, &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/a/was-ist-cobit,3614637" target="_blank"&gt;COBIT 2019&lt;/a&gt;, fußt auf einem Governance-Prinzipien-Sextett:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value für Stakeholder liefern&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ganzheitlichen Ansatz realisieren&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Governance-System dynamisch gestalten&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Management von Governance trennen&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;auf individuelle Unternehmensanforderungen abstimmen&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Ende-zu-Ende-Governance-System realisieren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das COBIT-Framework ist auf Business-Fokus konzipiert und definiert eine Reihe generischer Prozesse, um IT-Komponenten zu managen. Dabei werden außerdem auch Inputs und Outputs, Schlüsselaktivitäten, Zielsetzungen, Performance-&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492322/cybersecurity-messen-10-kennzahlen-die-cisos-weiterbringen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Metriken&lt;/a&gt; und ein grundlegendes Reifegradmodell festgelegt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut ISACA ist COBIT flexibel zu implementieren und ermöglicht Unternehmen, ihre Governance-Strategie anzupassen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-fair"&gt;2. FAIR&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das Framework &lt;strong&gt;FAIR&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.fairinstitute.org/what-is-fair" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Factor Analysis of Information Risk&lt;/a&gt;) bildet eine Methodik ab, um unternehmensbezogene Risiken zu quantifizieren und zu managen. Dahinter steht das Fair Institute, eine wissenschaftlich ausgerichtete Non-Profit-Organisation, die sich dem Management von betrieblichen und sicherheitstechnischen Risiken verschrieben hat. Laut den Machern ist FAIR das einzige, quantitative Standardmodell auf internationaler Ebene, um diese Art von Risiken zu erfassen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; FAIR bietet ein Modell, um die genannten Risiken in finanzieller Hinsicht zu verstehen, zu analysieren und zu quantifizieren. Laut dem Fair Institute unterscheidet es sich dabei insofern von anderen Risk-Assessment-Frameworks, als dass es seinen Fokus nicht auf qualitative Farbdiagramme oder numerisch gewichtete Skalen legt. Stattdessen will FAIR eine Grundlage liefern, um einen robusten Risikomanagement-Ansatz auszubilden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; FAIR ermittelt in erster Linie Wahrscheinlichkeiten mit Blick auf die Frequenz und das Ausmaß von &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/a/was-sie-ueber-dlp-wissen-muessen,3549370" target="_blank"&gt;Data-Loss-Ereignissen&lt;/a&gt;. Es handelt sich hierbei nicht um eine Methodik, um individuelle Risikobewertungen durchzuführen. Vielmehr will das Framework Unternehmen in die Lage versetzen, IT-Risiken zu verstehen, zu analysieren und zu messen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zu den Komponenten des FAIR-Frameworks gehören:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eine Taxonomie für IT-Risiken,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine standardisierte Nomenklatur für Risiken,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine Methode um Datenerfassungskriterien zu definieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Messskalen für Risikofaktoren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine Engine für Risikoberechnungen, sowie&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;ein Modell, um komplexe Risikoszenarien zu analysieren.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Die quantitative Risk-Assessment-Ansatz von FAIR ist branchenübergreifend anwendbar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-iso-iec-27001"&gt;3. ISO/IEC 27001&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Bei &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/27001" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ISO/IEC 27001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; handelt es sich um einen internationalen Standard, der mit Leitlinien in Sachen IT-Security-Management unterstützt. Ursprünglich wurde er im Jahr 2005 gemeinschaftlich von der International Organization for Standardization (ISO) und der International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) veröffentlicht – und wird seither sukzessive überarbeitet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; ISO/IEC 27001 ist laut den Verantwortlichen ein Guide für Unternehmen jeder Größe und aus sämtlichen Branchen, um ein &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495288/isms-nach-iso-27001-anforderungen-und-umsetzung.html" target="_blank"&gt;Information-Security-Management-System&lt;/a&gt; (ISMS) aufzusetzen, zu implementieren, zu warten und fortlaufend zu verbessern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; ISO/IEC 27001 fördert einen ganzheitlichen Cybersicherheitsansatz, der Menschen, Richtlinien und Technologie auf den Prüfstand stellt. Ein auf dieser Grundlage erstelltes ISMS ist laut ISO ein Tool für Risikomanagement, Cyberresilienz und Operational Excellence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; ISO/IEC-27001-konform zu sein bedeutet, einem weltweit eingesetzten Standard zu genügen und Datensicherheitsrisiken aktiv zu managen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-nist-risk-management-framework"&gt;4. NIST Risk Management Framework&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/risk-management/about-rmf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Risk Management Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (RMF) wurde von der US-Behörde NIST (National Institute of Standards and Technology) entwickelt. Dieses Framework stellt einen umfassenden, wiederverwend- und messbaren, siebenstufigen Prozess in den Mittelpunkt, um IT- und Datenschutzrisiken zu managen. Dabei kommt eine ganze Reihe von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492240/nist-cybersecurity-framework-das-andert-sich-mit-csf-2-0.html" target="_blank"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt;-eigenen Standards und Guidelines zur Anwendung, um die Implementierung von Risikomanagement-Initiativen zu unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut NIST realisiert das RMF einen Prozess, der die Risikomanagementaktivitäten in den Bereichen Sicherheit, Datenschutz und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492023/supply-chain-risk-management-so-wird-ihre-lieferkette-resilient.html" target="_blank"&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/a&gt; in den Lebenszyklus der Systementwicklung integriert. Dabei berücksichtigt der Ansatz Effektivität, Effizienz und Einschränkungen durch geltende Gesetze, Direktiven, Anordnungen, Richtlinien, Standards oder Vorschriften.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Der siebenstufige Prozess des NIST RMF gliedert sich in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wesentliche Aktivitäten, um die Organisation auf den Umgang mit Sicherheits- und Datenschutzrisiken &lt;strong&gt;vorzubereiten&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Systeme und Daten, die verarbeitet, gespeichert und übertragen werden, auf der Grundlage einer Impact-Analyse &lt;strong&gt;kategorisieren&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine Reihe von Kontrollmaßnahmen &lt;strong&gt;auswählen&lt;/strong&gt;, um Systeme auf der Grundlage einer Risikobewertung zu schützen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Kontrollmaßnahmen &lt;strong&gt;implementieren&lt;/strong&gt; – und dokumentieren, wie das vonstattengeht.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Kontrollmaßnahmen überprüfen und &lt;strong&gt;bewerten&lt;/strong&gt;, ob diese wie gewünscht funktionieren.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Systembetrieb auf Grundlage einer risikobasierten Entscheidung &lt;strong&gt;autorisieren&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Implementierung und Systemrisiken kontinuierlich &lt;strong&gt;überwachen&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Das RMF bietet einen verfahrenstechnischen und geordneten Prozess, um Organisation dabei zu unterstützen, Security in ihre allgemeinen Risikomanagement-Prozesse einzubetten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-octave"&gt;5. OCTAVE&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;OCTAVE&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://insights.sei.cmu.edu/documents/1210/1999_005_001_16769.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Operationally Critical Threat, Asset, and Vulnerability Evaluation&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)) ist ein Framework, um Risiken im Bereich der Cybersicherheit zu identifizieren und zu managen. Es wurde vom CERT-Team der Carnegie Mellon University in den USA entwickelt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Dieses Risk-Assessment-Framework definiert eine umfassende Evaluierungsmethode. Diese ermöglicht Unternehmen nicht nur, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493004/report-von-xm-cyber-geschaftskritische-assets-in-gefahr.html" target="_blank"&gt;missionskritische IT-Assets&lt;/a&gt; zu identifizieren, sondern auch die Bedrohungen, die mit diesen in Zusammenhang stehen und die Schwachstellen, die das erst ermöglichen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Laut den Verantwortlichen ermöglicht die Zusammenstellung von IT-Assets, -Bedrohungen und –&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495294/schwachstellen-managen-die-6-besten-vulnerability-management-tools.html" target="_blank"&gt;Schwachstellen&lt;/a&gt; Unternehmen, zu durchdringen, welche Daten wirklich bedroht sind. Mit diesem Verständnis ausgestattet, können die Anwender eine Schutzstrategie entwickeln und implementieren, um diese nachhaltig zu schützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; Das OCTAVE-Framework ist in zwei Versionen erhältlich.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OCTAVE-S bietet eine vereinfachte Methodik, die auf kleinere Unternehmen mit flachen hierarchischen Strukturen ausgerichtet ist.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;OCTAVE Allegro ist hingegen ein umfassenderes Framework, das sich in erster Linie für große Unternehmen oder solche mit komplexen Strukturen eignet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-tara"&gt;6. TARA&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das ist es:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;TARA&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.mitre.org/news-insights/publication/threat-assessment-and-remediation-analysis-tara" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Threat Assessment and Remediation Analysis&lt;/a&gt;) stellt eine Engineering-Methodik dar, mit deren Hilfe, Sicherheitslücken identifiziert, bewertet und behoben werden können. Dieses Framework wurde von der Non-Profit-Organisation MITRE entwickelt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Das kann es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das Framework ist Teil des MITRE-Systemportfolios, das darauf ausgerichtet ist, die Cybersicherheitshygiene sowie die Resilienz von IT-Systemen in einem möglichst frühen Stadium (innerhalb des Beschaffungsprozesses) zu adressieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So funktioniert es:&lt;/strong&gt; Das TARA-Framework nutzt einen Datenkatalog, um Angriffsvektoren zu identifizieren, die genutzt werden könnten, um Systemschwachstellen auszunutzen sowie potenzielle Gegenmaßnahmen einzuleiten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gut zu wissen:&lt;/strong&gt; TARA wurde ursprünglich im Jahr 2010 entwickelt und kam bereits in mehr als 30 Cyber-Risk-Assessments zum Einsatz. Dieses Framework eignet sich in besonderem Maße für Risikostudien, die sich auf Sicherheitsbedrohungen konzentrieren. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552765/6-risk-assessment-frameworks-im-vergleich.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the meeting notetaker: The rise of AI summarization optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077438/manipulating-the-meeting-notetaker-the-rise-of-ai-summarization-optimization.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These days, the most important meeting attendee isn’t a person: It’s the AI notetaker.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This system assigns action items and determines the importance of what is said. If it becomes necessary to revisit the facts of the meeting, its summary is treated as impartial evidence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But clever meeting attendees can manipulate this system’s record by speaking more to what the underlying AI weights for summarization and importance than to their colleagues. As a result, you can expect some meeting attendees to use language more likely to be captured in summaries, timing their interventions strategically, repeating key points, and employing formulaic phrasing that AI models are more likely to pick up on. Welcome to the world of AI summarization optimization (AISO).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="optimizing-for-algorithmic-manipulation"&gt;Optimizing for algorithmic manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization has a well-known precursor: SEO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Search-engine optimization is as old as the World Wide Web. The idea is straightforward: Search engines scour the internet digesting every possible page, with the goal of serving the best results to every possible query. The objective for a content creator, company, or cause is to optimize for the algorithm search engines have developed to determine their webpage rankings for those queries. That requires writing for two audiences at once: human readers and the search-engine crawlers indexing content. Techniques to do this effectively are passed around like trade secrets, and a &lt;a href="https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/seo-software-market-report#:~:text=The%20global%20SEO%20software%20market%20size%20was,and%20heightened%20competition%20in%20the%20digital%20landscape."&gt;$75 billion&lt;/a&gt; industry offers SEO services to organizations of all sizes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More recently, researchers have documented techniques for influencing AI responses, including &lt;a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2024/04/the-rise-of-large.html%22%3Elarge-language%20model%20optimization"&gt;large-language model optimization&lt;/a&gt; (LLMO) and &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.09735"&gt;generative engine optimization&lt;/a&gt; (GEO). Tricks include content optimization — adding citations and statistics — and adversarial approaches: using specially crafted text sequences. These techniques often target sources that LLMs heavily reference, such as Reddit, which is claimed to be &lt;a href="https://www.visualcapitalist.com/ranked-the-most-cited-websites-by-ai-models/"&gt;cited in 40%&lt;/a&gt; of AI-generated responses. The effectiveness and real-world applicability of these methods remains limited and largely experimental, although there is substantial evidence that countries such as Russia are &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/new-atlanticist/exposing-pravda-how-pro-kremlin-forces-are-poisoning-ai-models-and-rewriting-wikipedia/"&gt;actively&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://thebulletin.org/2025/03/russian-networks-flood-the-internet-with-propaganda-aiming-to-corrupt-ai-chatbots/"&gt;pursuing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/04/17/llm-poisoning-grooming-chatbots-russia/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization follows the same logic on a smaller scale. Human participants in a meeting may want a certain fact highlighted in the record, or their perspective to be reflected as the authoritative one. Rather than persuading colleagues directly, they adapt their speech for the notetaker that will later define the “official” summary. For example:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The main factor in last quarter’s delay was supply chain disruption.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“The key outcome was overwhelmingly positive client feedback.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Our takeaway here is in alignment moving forward.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“What matters here is the efficiency gains, not the temporary cost overrun.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The techniques are subtle. They employ high-signal phrases such as “key takeaway” and “action item,” keep statements short and clear, and repeat them when possible. They also use contrastive framing (“this, not that”), and speak early in the meeting or at transition points.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once spoken words are transcribed, they enter the model’s input. Cue phrases — and even transcription errors — can steer what makes it into the summary. In many tools, the output format itself is also a signal: Summarizers often offer sections such as “Key Takeaways” or “Action Items,” so language that mirrors those headings is more likely to be included. In effect, well-chosen phrases function as implicit markers that guide the AI toward inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Research confirms this. Early AI summarization research &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1509.00685"&gt;showed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.08777"&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; models trained to reconstruct summary-style sentences systematically overweigh such content. Models over-rely on &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.11602"&gt;early-position&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1909.04028.pdf"&gt;content&lt;/a&gt; in news. And models often overweigh statements at the &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10570"&gt;start or end&lt;/a&gt; of a transcript, underweighting the middle. Recent work further confirms vulnerability to phrasing-based manipulation: models &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14197"&gt;cannot reliably&lt;/a&gt; distinguish embedded instructions from ordinary content, especially when phrasing mimics salient cues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-combat-aiso"&gt;How to combat AISO&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If AISO becomes common, three forms of defense will emerge. First, meeting participants will exert social pressure on one another. When researchers secretly deployed AI bots in Reddit’s r/changemyview community, users and moderators responded with&lt;a href="https://retractionwatch.com/2025/04/28/experiment-using-ai-generated-posts-on-reddit-draws-fire-for-ethics-concerns/"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://retractionwatch.com/2025/04/28/experiment-using-ai-generated-posts-on-reddit-draws-fire-for-ethics-concerns/"&gt;strong backlash&lt;/a&gt; calling it&lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/unethical-ai-research-reddit-under-fire"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;“&lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/unethical-ai-research-reddit-under-fire"&gt;psychological manipulation&lt;/a&gt;.” Anyone using obvious AI-gaming phrases may face similar disapproval.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second, organizations will start governing meeting behavior using AI: risk assessments and access restrictions before the meetings even start, detection of AISO techniques in meetings, and validation and auditing after the meetings.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Third, AI summarizers will have their own technical countermeasures. For example, the AI security company CloudSEK&lt;a href="https://www.cloudsek.com/blog/trusted-my-summarizer-now-my-fridge-is-encrypted----how-threat-actors-could-weaponize-ai-summarizers-with-css-based-clickfix-attacks"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cloudsek.com/blog/trusted-my-summarizer-now-my-fridge-is-encrypted----how-threat-actors-could-weaponize-ai-summarizers-with-css-based-clickfix-attacks"&gt;recommends&lt;/a&gt; content sanitization to strip suspicious inputs, prompt filtering to detect meta-instructions and excessive repetition, context window balancing to weight repeated content less heavily, and user warnings showing content provenance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Broader defenses could draw from security and AI safety research:&lt;a href="https://cheatsheetseries.owasp.org/cheatsheets/LLM_Prompt_Injection_Prevention_Cheat_Sheet.html"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://cheatsheetseries.owasp.org/cheatsheets/LLM_Prompt_Injection_Prevention_Cheat_Sheet.html"&gt;preprocessing content&lt;/a&gt; to detect dangerous patterns,&lt;a href="https://github.com/usefulmove/ConsensusLLM"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/usefulmove/ConsensusLLM"&gt;consensus approaches&lt;/a&gt; requiring consistency thresholds,&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02584"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.02584"&gt;self-reflection techniques&lt;/a&gt; to detect manipulative content, and&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19098v1"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/html/2407.19098v1"&gt;human oversight protocols&lt;/a&gt; for critical decisions. Meeting-specific systems could implement additional defenses:&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/MeetingNet_EMNLP_full.pdf"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/MeetingNet_EMNLP_full.pdf"&gt;tagging inputs by provenance&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://aclanthology.org/2022.aacl-short.6.pdf"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://aclanthology.org/2022.aacl-short.6.pdf"&gt;weighting content&lt;/a&gt; by speaker role or centrality with sentence-level importance scoring, and discounting high-signal phrases while favoring consensus over fervor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="reshaping-human-behavior"&gt;Reshaping human behavior&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization is a small, subtle shift, but it illustrates how the adoption of AI is reshaping human behavior in unexpected ways. The potential implications are quietly profound.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Meetings — humanity’s most fundamental collaborative ritual — are being silently reengineered by those who understand the algorithm’s preferences. The articulate are gaining an invisible advantage over the wise. Adversarial thinking is becoming routine, embedded in the most ordinary workplace rituals, and, as AI becomes embedded in organizational life, strategic interactions with AI notetakers and summarizers may soon be a necessary executive skill for navigating corporate culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI summarization optimization illustrates how quickly humans adapt communication strategies to new technologies. As AI becomes more embedded in workplace communication, recognizing these emerging patterns may prove increasingly important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077438/manipulating-the-meeting-notetaker-the-rise-of-ai-summarization-optimization.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-679)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-679</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-679</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-680)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-680</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-680</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-681)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-681</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-681</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–682)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-682</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-682</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-683)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-683</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-683</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-485) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-485</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-485</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-684)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-684</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-684</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectWise security advisory (AV25-685)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-685</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-685</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory (AV25-640) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-686)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-686</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-686</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-687)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-687</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-687</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-689)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-690)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ericsson security advisory (AV25-691)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-692)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV25-693)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-694)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-583) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-695)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
