<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 03:04:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-706)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-016 Internet-accessible industrial control systems (ICS) abused by hacktivists</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-707)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker security advisory (AV25–708)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV25-693) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-709)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-710)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-629) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global experts advance the joint fight against crypto-enabled crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</link>
      <description>The criminal use of cryptocurrency is becoming increasingly professionalised, but so too is the global response. Participants at the 9th Global Conference on Criminal Finances and Cryptoassets emphasised three priorities: developing common standards, deepening cooperation and investing in capacity. These are essential if authorities and industry are to keep pace with evolving threats and recover illicit cryptoassets at scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 top bug bounty programs launched in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/657751/top-bug-bounty-programs.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/560279/why-you-need-a-bug-bounty-program.html"&gt;Bug bounty programs&lt;/a&gt; remain a crucial component of cybersecurity strategies in 2025, offering organizations the ability to draw in help from a diverse pool of cybersecurity professionals and researchers. The schemes offer continuous testing against emerging threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What are bug bounty programs?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bug bounty programs are structured systems for individuals to identify and report &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/1619312/software-bugs-that-bug-me-and-how-to-swat-them-down.html"&gt;security vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; and other bugs. They are offered by organizations, websites, and software developers. These programs are designed to leverage the skills of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/644922/hackrate-releases-ethical-hacking-monitoring-platform-hackgate.html"&gt;ethical hackers&lt;/a&gt; to enhance the security of software and systems before malicious parties can exploit these vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Participants, often referred to as bug bounty hunters, earn financial rewards or other forms of recognition for successfully reporting vulnerabilities in assets covered by bug bounty programs. Exploits achieved through social engineering trickery such as phishing are typically excluded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Bug bounty programs focus in 2025&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For ethical hackers, best practice for bug bounty hunting in 2025 involves thorough reconnaissance of a target organization’s technology stack, rather than just running automated tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Leading bug bounty platforms such as Bugcrowd, HackerOne, Synack, YesWeHack, and Intigriti offer rewards for identifying and reporting security vulnerabilities. Platforms connect ethical hackers with organizations, providing a structured framework for vulnerability disclosure and resolution — managing bug bounty rewards on behalf of their corporate clients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Technology providers and government organizations run stand-alone bug bounty programs as part of a broader security testing strategy that also includes penetration tests.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the past 12 months bug bounties have begun offering increased payouts and broader scope. Traditional web and mobile categories are being supplemented by an &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082265/ai-powered-bug-hunting-shakes-up-bounty-industry-for-better-or-worse.html"&gt;increased focus on AI systems&lt;/a&gt; and critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the past year, Accenture has seen bug bounty go AI-assisted at scale: Researchers lean on AI, programs incorporate AI systems in bounty scope, and prompt-injection findings have surged,” Ryan Whelan, Accenture global cyber intelligence lead, tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Vendors now pay for full exploit chains, not one-off bugs,” Whelan says, adding that this shows how the bug bounty market has matured to reward researchers for vulnerabilities that have “real-world impact and reproducibility.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are the notable programs launched or expanded in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="apple-increases-rewards-and-expands-bounty-program"&gt;Apple increases rewards and expands bounty program&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4071044/apple-bumps-rce-bug-bounties-to-2m-to-counter-commercial-spyware-vendors.html"&gt;Apple doubled the maximum reward for zero-click iPhone remote exploits&lt;/a&gt; from $1 million to $2 million, with additional bonuses for uncovering complex exploit chains pushing potential payouts up to $5 million or more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Apple also significantly increased rewards in other categories to encourage more intensive research. This includes $100,000 for a complete macOS Gatekeeper bypass, and $1 million for broad unauthorized iCloud access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vendor also added WebKit browser and wireless proximity exploits into the scope of its revamped Apple Security Bounty program. The most severe One-click WebKit sandbox escapes can earn up to $300,000. Payouts of up $1 million are payable for wireless proximity exploits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The updates — which come into effect in November 2025 — are in response to a febrile threat environment, exemplified by sophisticated exploit chains historically associated with state actors that are being harnessed by spyware vendors in targeted attacks, &lt;a href="https://security.apple.com/blog/apple-security-bounty-evolved/"&gt;Apple warns in a blog post on its revamped program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="google-launches-dedicated-ai-related-bug-bounty-program"&gt;Google launches dedicated AI-related bug bounty program&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bughunters.google.com/blog/6116887259840512/announcing-google-s-new-ai-vulnerability-reward-program"&gt;Google launched a dedicated AI Vulnerability Reward Program in October 2025&lt;/a&gt;. The scheme aims to incentivize security researchers to focus on uncovering previously undiscovered flaws in the vendor’s AI-based product and services, such as Gemini.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eligible exploits include those that lead to unauthorized account or data modifications, data exfiltration, model theft, or phishing enablement. Rewards operate in tiers from $5,000 up to $30,000. Prompt injections or jailbreaks are out of scope and not eligible for any rewards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The tech giant also increased the rewards offered through its core bug bounty program, increasing the highest category rewards for researchers who discover flaws in Google Chrome to $250,000. Expanded categories and higher rewards pushed the total amount paid out by &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2025/03/vulnerability-reward-program-2024-in.html"&gt;Google’s Vulnerability Reward Program&lt;/a&gt; to $12 million throughout 2024.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="microsoft-continues-zero-day-quest"&gt;Microsoft continues Zero Day Quest&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/bounty-ai"&gt;Microsoft expanded its AI Copilot bug bounty&lt;/a&gt;, with rewards up to $30,000 for code injection and other severe vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The technology giant also announced plans for its largest hacking event, “&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/blog/2025/08/zero-day-quest-join-the-largest-hacking-event-with-up-to-5-million-in-total-bounty-awards/"&gt;Zero Day Quest&lt;/a&gt;,” due to take place in spring 2026 and focused on uncovering cloud and AI vulnerabilities in products such as Microsoft Azure, Copilot, Identity, and M365.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Next year’s event follows the successful conclusion of an inaugural event in April, which focused on high impact vulnerabilities in Copilot and cloud and led to payouts of more than $1.6 million.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/blog/2025/08/microsoft-bounty-program-year-in-review-17-million-in-rewards"&gt;Microsoft paid out a total of $17 million&lt;/a&gt; to 344 security researchers this year, the company announced in August.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="samsung-puts-a-premium-on-mobile-security"&gt;Samsung puts a premium on mobile security&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://security.samsungmobile.com/rewardsProgram.smsb"&gt;Samsung launched a new bug bounty for mobile devices&lt;/a&gt;, offering up to $1 million for ethical hackers who discover and report critical flaws in core mobile systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The highest awards are on offer for high-impact bugs that present an arbitrary code execution risk on highly privileged targets or that bypass in-built security protections such as the Knox Vault or the TEEGRIS OS security platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The program covers vulnerabilities in Samsung’s smartphones, tablets, wearable devices, personal computers, services, and applications. Potential rewards vary depending on product as well as the severity of uncovered flaws.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="anthropic-offers-rewards-for-jailbreaking-claude"&gt;Anthropic offers rewards for jailbreaking Claude&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In May 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/testing-our-safety-defenses-with-a-new-bug-bounty-program"&gt;Anthropic launched a new bug bounty initiative&lt;/a&gt;, run through HackerOne, to stress-test advanced safety classifiers protecting Claude models. The invite-only trial program offered rewards of up to $25,0000 for vulnerabilities that reliably bypass AI safety constraints.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The scheme ran for a few weeks before it was replaced by a &lt;a href="https://hackerone.com/anthropic-vdp/policy_scopes"&gt;program&lt;/a&gt; focused on stress-testing &lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/constitutional-classifiers"&gt;Constitutional Classifiers system&lt;/a&gt; on the new Claude Opus 4 model. In August the scheme was further refined to offer &lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/model-safety-bug-bounty"&gt;rewards of up to $15,000 to pre-invited researchers who identify AI safety mitigation shortcomings&lt;/a&gt; in early pre-release versions of Anthropic’s Claude AI assistant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="openai-levels-up-bug-bounty-reward-program"&gt;OpenAI levels up bug bounty reward program&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In March, &lt;a href="https://opentools.ai/news/openai-cranks-up-bug-bounty-rewards-to-dollar100k-why-its-a-winning-move-for-ai-security"&gt;OpenAI dramatically increased the potential payouts for those who discovered critical vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; in its AI models and infrastructure from $20,000 to $100,000.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Assets that are in scope include ChatGPT, Open AI’s APIs, Open API corporate information and website, as explained in much more depth in &lt;a href="https://bugcrowd.com/engagements/openai"&gt;Open AI’s program page on Bugcrowd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nvidia-scales-up-security-defenses"&gt;Nvidia scales up security defenses&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chip giant &lt;a href="https://www.intigriti.com/blog/business-insights/intigriti-teams-with-nvidia-to-launch-bug-bounty-vulnerability-disclosure-program"&gt;Nvidia has teamed up with bug bounty platform Intigriti&lt;/a&gt; to launch a bug bounty and no financial reward vulnerability disclosure program (VDP), which went live this summer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nvidia products will be covered by a private bug bounty program. An additional private bug bounty package will cover core AI assets. The VDP extends to all other Nvidia assets, such as its website.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="shields-up"&gt;Shields up&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Belgian higher eduction and healthcare tech provider &lt;a href="https://www.intigriti.com/blog/news/intigriti-partners-with-shield-to-empower-security-within-healthcare"&gt;Shield has partnered with Intigriti to launch a vulnerability disclosure program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“[The] partnership provides essential support and services on vulnerability disclosure programs for critical national infrastructure (CNI) organizations such as hospitals, that now need to comply with NIS2 [EU cybersecurity regulation],” Intigriti said in a statement about the deal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cryptonomicon"&gt;Cryptonomicon&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last December virtual assets platform &lt;a href="https://www.hackerone.com/press-release/cryptocom-launches-landmark-usd-2-million-bug-bounty-program-hackerone"&gt;Crypto.com upgraded its existing bug bounty program&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://hackerone.com/crypto?type=team"&gt;HackerOne&lt;/a&gt;, providing up to $2 million in rewards for the reporting of critical security vulnerabilities. The boost made the vendor’s technology the most lucrative target for bug bounty hunters before recent enhancement to Apple’s program.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[For a look at last year’s top announcements, see “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4085288"&gt;12 notable bug bounty programs launched in 2024&lt;/a&gt;.”]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/657751/top-bug-bounty-programs.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and UEFA united for fair and safe football</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</link>
      <description>Today, 5 November 2025, Europol and UEFA have renewed and extended their Memorandum of Understanding, focused on preventing and combating crime while protecting the integrity of European football. The memorandum was signed at UEFA headquarters in Nyon by the Executive Director of Europol, Catherine De Bolle, and by the President of UEFA, Aleksander Čeferin. Europol and UEFA committed to cooperate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-uefa-united-for-fair-and-safe-football</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden hosts naval exercise with 200 special tactics operators</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</link>
      <description>Preparing to fight terrorism on land and seaThe exercise scenario focused on the deployment of special intervention units and naval assets during day- and night-time, simulating terrorist and hostage incidents on board of cruise liners and ferries. Day after day, the participants faced new challenges on the water and on some of the archipelago’s many islands, slowly preparing them for...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What past ERP mishaps can teach CISOs about security platformization</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080709/what-past-erp-mishaps-can-teach-cisos-about-security-platformization.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Research studies indicate that the average enterprise has between 40 and 80 separate security tools, a broad inventory that often leads to multiple security data silos, integration challenges, constant maintenance and tuning, and alert fatigue. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recognizing the challenges of this situation and the potential market for unified solutions, cybersecurity technology vendors like Cisco, CrowdStrike, Fortinet, Microsoft, Palo Alto Networks, and Trend Micro have been cobbling together security technology “platforms” —integrated product bundles that aggregate areas such as cloud security, email security, endpoint security, network security, SIEM, threat intelligence, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hmm. Moving from independent tools to an integrated architecture with a centralized database acting as the single point of truth. Where have we heard this before?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="erp-migrations-set-the-stage-for-platform-challenges"&gt;ERP migrations set the stage for platform challenges&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We older technologists may remember a similar migration to &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272362/what-is-erp-key-features-of-top-enterprise-resource-planning-systems.html"&gt;enterprise resource planning (ERP)&lt;/a&gt; in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the time, large organizations had independent departmental applications in areas such as finance, inventory management, supply chain management, HR, and manufacturing, resulting in disparate processes, separate teams, and no centralized view of the business.  ERP systems promised a “central nervous system” for the business, aggregating departmental data into a single, shared database and providing a unified, real-time view of the company’s operations. Driven by Y2K, enterprises raced toward ERP nirvana throughout the decade.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alas, it wasn’t so easy. ERP migrations were fraught with challenges like incompatible data formats requiring massive ETL and data transformation efforts. Many firms faced long and arduous efforts to customize ERP for their industry and organizational needs. Some organizations &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/284312/10-common-erp-mistakes-to-avoid.html"&gt;botched project planning&lt;/a&gt; leading to lengthy implementations and cost overruns. And in their focus on a hasty technology transition, many firms forgot to execute necessary &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272222/change-management-change-management-definition-and-solutions.html"&gt;organizational changes&lt;/a&gt; like gaining employee buy-in, modifying processes, and training technicians. This led to political strife and even outright project sabotage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While there’s no Y2K-like sword of Damocles hanging over CISOs’ heads, many security executives are considering security platforms for security efficacy, operational efficiency, and/or financial rationalization. Those still sitting on the fence are frequently persuaded by CFOs to at least consider this option. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-tips-for-getting-security-platformization-right"&gt;5 tips for getting security platformization right&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Current trending suggests that in many enterprises, security platform migration is inevitable in the short- or long-term. Given this, CISOs would be well served by carefully studying the mistakes made with ERP and plan accordingly with proven best practices. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Based on my research, here are a few suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get executive buy-in and vocal leadership.&lt;/strong&gt; Successful ERP migrations were driven by clearly defined business goals and passionate executive teams. Similarly, security platform migration should go beyond limited security and/or financial benefits alone. CISOs should prepare a business case demonstrating how a security platform will improve business-critical system protection and deliver cyber resilience to the organization. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once the board of directors and executives are committed, they should oversee project implementation objectives, provide organizational and employee incentives for meeting success metrics, and visibly cheerlead the effort. For their part, CISOs should continually communicate project progress in business — not just technical — terms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus first on the security team, not the technology.&lt;/strong&gt; ERP migrations were often impaired by doubtful IT employees myopically focused on their pet technologies or limited responsibilities. Correspondingly, some security professionals will be reluctant to give up their favored tools (i.e., “server huggers”) and individual tasks. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs must win over these naysayers by refocusing them on the overall mission of protecting the organization, and then carefully educate them on how a security platform aligns with this objective. Make sure to support the team with the services and training they’ll need for a successful technology transition and offer team and individual incentives to do so. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs would also be wise to think about folding career development opportunities into their security platform planning. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for project phases, not ‘big bang’ implementations.&lt;/strong&gt; ERP implementation challenges were often associated with overly aggressive project timelines. This led to project delays, cost overruns, and ultimately business impact. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one famous example, &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/284312/10-common-erp-mistakes-to-avoid.html"&gt;Hershey’s had an ERP-related system outage&lt;/a&gt; during the Halloween season and couldn’t ship products to its distributors. This led to lost market share, quarterly revenue impact, and a decrease in its share price. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To deliver value through a phased approach, organizations should start with a dependency map to understand &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2515727/6-tips-for-consolidating-your-it-security-tool-set.html"&gt;all the idiosyncrasies and connections of the existing architecture&lt;/a&gt;.  Clearly map out the future state, including data and workflows, and use this to determine how and where to start replacing tools. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Build an overlay implementation that mirrors the existing infrastructure. Create a test and rollback plan. Determine technical and business metrics — and executive reports — for each phase of the project.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should follow the adage and consider patience a virtue throughout the project. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start the technology journey with a modern data pipeline.&lt;/strong&gt; Once IT teams rolled up their sleeves toward ERP projects, they discovered data inconsistency everywhere. Finance systems referred to a major supplier as Acme Inc., CRM systems used ACME Incorporated, and each system used different customer numbers and billing addresses. This led to lengthy ETL processes to gain data reliability. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should overcome similar issues by focusing on data pipelining for achieving data quality, consistency, and accessibility. This will help break down data silos and build a single source of cybersecurity truth. A scalable data pipeline will ultimately accelerate the delivery of trustworthy data for analytics and decision-making. Again, this will deliver security &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; business benefits. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the transition for process re-engineering.&lt;/strong&gt; Too often, organizations tried to force fit existing business and technology processes into new ERP systems, leading to complex customization and political dissent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To avoid a similar fate, CISOs should use platformization as an opportunity to modernize and automate inefficient and/or manual processes using baked-in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567745/soapa-vs-soar-how-these-security-terms-differ.html"&gt;security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR)&lt;/a&gt; and AI functionality. Make sure to find ways for removing security bottlenecks to business processes, such as onboarding new users or providing timely reports to business managers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Overall, CISOs should make process re-engineering part of the planning, testing, and implementation aspects of the project. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="inflection-point-for-cisos"&gt;Inflection point for CISOs?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that the migration to ERP systems is often cited as an inflection point, when CIOs went from technical administrators to critical business executives. Prudent CISOs may benefit from platformization in a similar manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080709/what-past-erp-mishaps-can-teach-cisos-about-security-platformization.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake number, real damage: Europol urges action against caller ID spoofing</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</link>
      <description>Europol is calling for a coordinated European response to tackle caller ID spoofing, an in increasingly common tool, used for online fraud and social engineering scams. Caller ID spoofing occurs when criminals falsify the information displayed on phones, making numbers appear legitimate to deceive victims. This practice is driving substantial financial and societal harm, with an estimated EUR 850 million lost worldwide each year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese hackers target Western diplomats using hard-to-patch Windows shortcut flaw</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082701/chinese-hackers-target-western-diplomats-using-hard-to-patch-windows-shortcut-flaw.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chinese hackers have been spotted targeting European diplomats using a longstanding Windows shortcut vulnerability that’s been popular with threat groups as far back as 2017.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to security company &lt;a href="https://arcticwolf.com/resources/blog/unc6384-weaponizes-zdi-can-25373-vulnerability-to-deploy-plugx/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Arctic Wolf&lt;/a&gt;, whose researchers uncovered the latest campaign, the latest attacks saw spear phishing emails sent to officials working for the governments of Hungary, Belgium, Serbia, Italy, and The Netherlands during September and October.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Chinese government-operated group suspected of being behind the campaign is named UNC6384 by the Google Threat Intelligence Group (GTIG). The same group is believed to have targeted diplomats of several Asian countries earlier in 2025, which might give the impression that UNC6384 is a recently discovered threat actor, hence its UNC (“uncategorized”) status.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, Arctic Wolf said it believed the group’s tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) strongly resemble those of a known Chinese threat group, “Mustang Panda,” which has been around since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the face of it, this looks like just another Chinese cyber-espionage campaign against foreign governments. But there is a deeper story: the Windows vulnerability used in the campaign, which Microsoft has so far been unwilling — or unable — to patch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ghost-flaw"&gt;Ghost flaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Arctic Wolf, the latest campaign used spear phishing emails with diplomatic themes to lure targets into executing malicious Windows .LNK shortcut files. The vulnerability stems from a flaw in Windows UI parsing that allows command-line instructions to be hidden in &lt;a href="https://detection.fyi/sigmahq/sigma/windows/process_creation/proc_creation_win_susp_lnk_exec_hidden_cmd/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;.LNK format whitespace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This allows the attackers to launch a sequence of malicious actions while displaying a decoy PDF showing the agenda for a genuine European Commission meeting scheduled to have been held in Brussels on September 26. The result is the deployment of the PlugX remote access Trojan, which has been popular since 2008 as a tool for opening backdoors into Windows systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trend Micro told Microsoft about the weakness in September 2024, after which it was given a &lt;a href="https://cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-9491" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-9491&lt;/a&gt; identifier. However, it turns out that the company’s Zero Day Initiative (ZDI) had noticed the same issue in 2017, when it was given a separate internal ‘candidate’ identifier, &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/c/windows-shortcut-zero-day-exploit.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ZDI-CAN-25373&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The vulnerability has been exploited by state-sponsored APT groups from North Korea, Iran, Russia, and China,” said Trend Micro in a &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en/research/25/c/windows-shortcut-zero-day-exploit.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;March 2018 blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite there being a formal CVE, Microsoft appears reluctant to address the issue. As Trend Micro noted in a more recent blog from 2025, “We submitted a proof-of-concept exploit through Trend ZDI’s bug bounty program to Microsoft, who declined to address this vulnerability with a security patch.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That reluctance probably stems from the fact that CVE-2025-9491/ZDI-CAN-25373 would be difficult to patch without breaking legacy applications that depend on its current design.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On November 1, the day after this article was first published, Microsoft released an &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/advisory/ADV25258226" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;advisory notice on Windows LNK file UI behavior&lt;/a&gt;. In it, the company reiterated that it does not consider this a vulnerability. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The advisory noted that .lnk files cannot be delivered via browser unless packaged in a .zip file that is then opened by the user. “Attempting to open a .lnk file downloaded from the Internet automatically triggers a security warning advising users not to open files from unknown sources, and we strongly recommend heeding this warning,” Microsoft said in the advisory. “Double-clicking on a .lnk file produces a warning stating that the file format is not trusted; a victim must click through this prompt,” it added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Due to the user interaction involved and the fact that the system already warns users that this format is untrusted, Microsoft does not consider this a vulnerability” it concluded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mitigation"&gt;Mitigation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the absence of a patch, organizations worried about .LNK attacks should consider blocking .LNK files or disabling their execution in Windows Explorer, Arctic Wolf advised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This should be put in place across all Windows systems, prioritizing endpoints used by personnel with access to sensitive diplomatic or policy information. While this vulnerability was disclosed in March 2025, adoption by threat actors within months of disclosure necessitates urgent monitoring and countermeasures,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations could also block the command and control (C2) domains used by attackers, although these will change over time. In addition, Arctic Wolf recommends that IT teams search for the presence of Canon printer assistant utilities such as &lt;em&gt;cnmpaui.exe&lt;/em&gt;, which are part of the campaign’s exploit chain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; “The breadth of targeting across multiple European nations within a condensed timeframe suggests either a large-scale coordinated intelligence collection operation or deployment of multiple parallel operational teams with shared tooling but independent targeting,” Arctic Wolf noted, adding that the fact that UNC6384 had jumped on the flaw so quickly since it was made public earlier in 2025 suggested that the group had access to advanced capabilities and resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s not as if attacks exploiting Windows shortcut files in different ways are terribly new or innovative. During 2025, they’ve been abused in different ways by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3987073/after-helping-russia-on-the-ground-north-korea-targets-ukraine-with-cyberespionage.html" target="_blank"&gt;Russian cyber-campaigns&lt;/a&gt; against Ukraine, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3986671/stealth-rat-uses-a-powershell-loader-for-fileless-attacks.html" target="_blank"&gt;Chinese attacks&lt;/a&gt; using the Remcos RAT, and to target companies in the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3837964/polyglot-files-used-to-spread-new-backdoor.html" target="_blank"&gt;United Arab Emirates (UAE)&lt;/a&gt;. In June the technique was used to hide payloads in attacks abusing the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4009636/phishing-campaign-abuses-cloudflare-tunnels-to-sneak-malware-past-firewalls.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cloudflare Tunnel service&lt;/a&gt;. The issue is really that this type of flaw, which exploits an otherwise useful feature, is simply difficult to patch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was updated on November 6 with information about a new advisory notice from Microsoft.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082701/chinese-hackers-target-western-diplomats-using-hard-to-patch-windows-shortcut-flaw.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 08:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital health can’t scale if cybersecurity falls behind</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4085072/digital-health-cant-scale-if-cybersecurity-falls-behind.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When the world faced COVID-19, I watched something remarkable happen. Artificial intelligence (AI) systems, which I had once viewed as tools of research and efficiency, suddenly became instruments of survival. They modelled outbreaks, predicted surges and accelerated vaccine research. Yet at the same time, I witnessed another silent battle unfold a digital one. Health organizations, research institutions and even vaccine supply chains became targets of cyberattacks. For me, it was a turning point that reinforced a simple truth: AI cannot strengthen public health without cybersecurity at its core&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the years, working at the intersection of data, AI and cloud security for healthcare and life sciences organizations, I’ve seen how transformative intelligent systems can be. But I’ve also seen how fragile they are when trust, data integrity and governance are not built into their foundation. Today, as countries prepare for future pandemics, we must treat cybersecurity not as a support function but as a critical enabler of readiness.  The success of future pandemic preparedness will depend on whether we build trustworthy, secure and ethical AI systems from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-expanding-digital-frontline"&gt;The expanding digital frontline&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-driven pandemic preparedness depends on vast data ecosystems from genomic sequencing labs and hospital networks to connected sensors that monitor population health trends. These systems exchange millions of data points each hour, enabling faster decisions. But every connected device, every model training pipeline and every data integration point expands the attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one of my engagements, public health models were trained using de-identified patient data, IoT feeds and cloud-based analytics. The security challenge was immediate: multiple entry points, distributed teams and differing compliance standards. In such ecosystems, a small misconfiguration an unsecured API or an outdated firmware could expose entire datasets. During the pandemic, these vulnerabilities were exploited at scale. Cybercriminals targeted vaccine research, contact tracing platforms and national health dashboards. It became clear that pandemic preparedness now has a digital dimension as critical as epidemiological preparedness itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-unique-vulnerabilities-of-ai-systems"&gt;The unique vulnerabilities of AI systems&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional security frameworks are not enough for AI. Attacks on algorithms take subtler forms. I often explain to my clients that when you corrupt data, you corrupt intelligence. Data poisoning occurs when malicious data is inserted into the training process, teaching the AI to make wrong decisions later. Imagine an outbreak prediction model fed with falsified data that underestimates transmission in one region, this could delay interventions and cost lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another subtle but dangerous threat is model inversion, where attackers reverse-engineer AI outputs to infer private information about patients or study participants. In healthcare, this isn’t just a technical issue, it’s an ethical one. People trust that their health data will never re-identify them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And then there are adversarial attacks carefully crafted manipulations that cause AI models to misclassify or ignore patterns. A small perturbation in sensor data could make an outbreak detection algorithm miss early warning signals. These are not theoretical risks, they are realities that cybersecurity teams are already mitigating daily.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="designing-trustworthy-ai-ecosystems"&gt;Designing trustworthy AI ecosystems&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The systems I help design today for pharmaceutical analytics or public health modeling follow one guiding principle: security by design, not as an afterthought. This begins with a zero-trust architecture assuming every connection, user or system could be compromised until proven otherwise. Role-based access controls, network segmentation and identity verification are now foundational practices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I also emphasize data provenance, maintaining a traceable chain of custody for every piece of data that enters or leaves a pipeline. This allows us to validate sources, detect tampering and maintain confidence in the insights AI produces. Encryption (both at rest and in transit) is standard, but we also implement differential privacy and homomorphic encryption when dealing with highly sensitive medical or genomic data. These methods allow analysis without exposing personal details an elegant balance between innovation and ethics.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Model governance is another pillar. Every AI model must have version control, validation sandboxes and rollback capabilities. Before any deployment, we simulate possible adversarial attacks and test recovery procedures. I’ve learned that cybersecurity in AI is not just about defense; it’s about resilience, the ability to detect, isolate and recover without losing functionality during crises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ethics-governance-and-the-elements-of-human-trust"&gt;Ethics, governance and the elements of human trust&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Technology alone cannot protect public health. Trust is built through ethics and transparency. I often remind data teams that behind every dataset lies a patient, a family or a community. In pandemic situations, public trust determines whether people comply with digital contact tracing, share health information or follow AI-guided advisories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why ethical governance must go hand-in-hand with cybersecurity. AI systems should be explainable, auditable and accountable. Stakeholders from governments to citizens deserve to know how models make decisions, how data is protected and who has access. Regulations such as HIPAA, GDPR and emerging AI governance frameworks are not hurdles; they are guardrails that preserve integrity in moments of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;International cooperation also plays a defining role. The &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/ehealth/en/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;WHO’s Global Strategy on Digital Health&lt;/a&gt; calls for digital solidarity, while the &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST AI Risk Management Framework&lt;/a&gt; offers a structured approach to assessing and mitigating AI-related risks. Aligning with these standards helps harmonize cybersecurity practices across borders a necessity, since pandemics and cyber threats recognize none.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="lessons-from-the-pandemic-era-cybersecurity-as-preparedness"&gt;Lessons from the pandemic era: Cybersecurity as preparedness&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 was a wake-up call in more ways than one. Alongside the biological virus, we faced a wave of ransomware, phishing and misinformation attacks that disrupted hospitals and vaccine logistics. I remember reviewing security reports where health data breaches increased by nearly 50% in the early months of 2021. Those of us working on cloud architecture and analytics pipelines suddenly had to think beyond performance, we had to think about resilience under attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The experience reshaped my approach to digital health. We now conduct joint drills between epidemiology teams and cybersecurity engineers, simulating not only outbreak scenarios but also cyber incidents. This multidisciplinary collaboration ensures that both biological and digital emergencies are met with preparedness, not panic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts at the &lt;a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/06/covid-19-pandemic-teaches-us-about-cybersecurity-cyberattack-cyber-pandemic-risk-virus/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;World Economic Forum&lt;/a&gt; describe the growing risk of a “cyber pandemic,” where digital contagion spreads faster than any biological one. I share this concern. Our increasing dependence on AI-based systems means a well-coordinated cyberattack could paralyze response operations during an actual health emergency. It is not enough to develop smart systems; we must make them secure and adaptable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="moving-forward-the-road-ahead-security-by-intelligence"&gt;Moving forward: The road ahead – security by intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, I believe the next phase of pandemic preparedness must embrace a security-by-intelligence mindset where AI protects itself using AI. Machine learning can detect anomalies, identify suspicious access patterns and predict potential vulnerabilities before exploitation. We are beginning to see cybersecurity evolve from a reactive function into an intelligent, adaptive shield for public health infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yet technology is only as effective as the people behind it. Training healthcare professionals to recognize phishing attempts, securing endpoint devices and conducting cyber hygiene education must become as routine as infection-control drills. Every clinician, data engineer and policymaker has a role to play.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My advice to organizations embarking on digital health transformation is simple: embed cybersecurity from day one. Treat your data pipeline as a clinical asset, it deserves the same rigor as a vaccine trial or a diagnostic protocol. The systems that save lives must be resilient against those who would exploit them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="resilience-as-the-true-measure-of-readiness"&gt;Resilience as the true measure of readiness&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pandemic preparedness in the age of AI is no longer about who develops the fastest algorithm but who builds the most trustworthy ecosystem. As a data and cybersecurity architect in healthcare, I have witnessed that true innovation lies in resilience systems that continue to protect and perform even when threatened.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The next global health emergency will test not only our biological defences but also our digital fortifications. To succeed, cybersecurity must evolve from being a compliance checkbox to becoming the moral and operational foundation of digital health.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When the next outbreak comes and it will, our response must be dual: biological immunity and digital integrity. The AI that protects humanity must never be turned against it. That is the essence of preparedness — and the promise of a safer, smarter and more secure future for global health.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4085072/digital-health-cant-scale-if-cybersecurity-falls-behind.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-711)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress security advisory (AV25-712)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-713)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyberattacks surge against IoT, mobile devices in critical infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/mobile-iot-attacks-surge-critical-infrastructure-zscaler/805008/</link>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgproxy.divecdn.com/4sXKvGIHbz-z0PSL3BRdJQrD3m2pfJqLAES5d7CTXNY/g:nowe:0:42/c:2500:1412/rs:fill:1600:900:1/Z3M6Ly9kaXZlc2l0ZS1zdG9yYWdlL2RpdmVpbWFnZS9HZXR0eUltYWdlcy0yMjI1NzEyNDYxLmpwZw==.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manufacturing and energy firms saw some of the biggest increases in malware activity targeting connected devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/mobile-iot-attacks-surge-critical-infrastructure-zscaler/805008/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:58:55 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ID verification laws are fueling the next wave of breaches</title>
      <link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/id-verification-laws-are-fueling-the-next-wave-of-breaches/</link>
      <description>ID laws are forcing companies to store massive amounts of sensitive data, turning compliance into a security risk. Acronis explains how integrated backup and cybersecurity platforms help MSPs reduce complexity and close the gaps attackers exploit. [...]</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/id-verification-laws-are-fueling-the-next-wave-of-breaches/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:05:15 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Chargeback: 4.3 million cardholders affected, EUR 300 million in damages</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</link>
      <description>On 4 November 2025, an international coordinated action day targeted three major fraud and money laundering networks as part of Operation “Chargeback.” Led by the Cybercrime Department (Landeszentralstelle Cybercrime) of the General Prosecutor's Office (Generalstaatsanwaltschaft) in Koblenz, Germany, and the German Federal Criminal Police Office (Bundeskriminalamt), the operation has been investigating these networks since December 2020. More than 60 house searches were conducted and a total of 18 arrest warrants executed. The criminal networks are suspected of misusing credit card data from over 4.3 million cardholders across 193 countries. In total, the estimated damage from the fraud scheme exceeds EUR 300 million, with attempted damages amounting to over EUR 750 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operation-chargeback-43-million-cardholders-affected-eur-300-million-in-damages</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>54 individuals arrested in action against labour exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</link>
      <description>Over the last weeks, law enforcement, border guards and labour and tax authorities across Europe joined forces to identify and tackle labour exploitation. This recent edition of the EMPACT Joint Action Days targeted trafficking in human beings for labour exploitation purposes, with a special emphasis on the agricultural sector, gastronomy, and temporary work agencies. In particular, the involved authorities also took measures against the exploitation of non-EU nationals and refugees. Led by France and the Netherlands, and carried out by authorities from 32 countries with support from Europol and the European Labour Authority (ELA), the action days resulted in the arrest of 54 individuals and identification of 404 potential victims of human trafficking.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/54-individuals-arrested-in-action-against-labour-exploitation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malicious npm packages contain Vidar infostealer</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086415/malicious-npm-packages-contain-vidar-infostealer-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Malicious code continues to be uploaded to open source repositories, making it a challenge for responsible developers to trust what’s there, and for CISOs to trust applications that include open source code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest example comes from researchers at Datadog Security, who said that last month they found 17 packages (23 releases) in the &lt;a href="https://securitylabs.datadoghq.com/articles/mut-4831-trojanized-npm-packages-vidar/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;npm repository that contained downloader malware&lt;/a&gt; for Windows systems that executes via a postinstall script.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The associated packages masquerade as Telegram bot helper packages, icon libraries, or legitimate-seeming forks of preexisting projects such as Cursor and React. They provide legitimate functionality, but their actual goal is to execute the Vidar infostealer malware on the victim system. Datadog believes this is the first public disclosure of Vidar malware being delivered via npm packages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both of the accounts offering these packages (aartje and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;saliii229911 ) have since been banned. However, they were on the registry for about two weeks, and the malicious packages were downloaded at least 2,240 times. However, the researchers believe many of those downloads were likely by automated scrapers, with some occurring after the packages had been removed and replaced with empty security holding packages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="all-sorts-of-nasty-things"&gt;All sorts of nasty things&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Malicious compromise of open source components can lead to all sorts of nasty things. First, threat actors can steal developers’ credentials and insert backdoors into their code. Second, the malicious code in the downloaded component itself could spread around the world to the developer’s customers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Datadog discovery is just another in a long list of malicious code uploaded to npm, PyPI, GitHub, and other open source repositories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082195/malicious-packages-in-npm-evade-dependency-detection-through-invisible-url-links-report.html" target="_blank"&gt;Last week, Koi Security reported&lt;/a&gt; finding 126 malicious packages in npm, and in September, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4058059/warning-hackers-have-inserted-credential-stealing-code-into-some-npm-libraries.html" target="_blank"&gt;researchers at Step Security reported&lt;/a&gt; that dozens of npm libraries had been replaced with credential stealing code. The same month, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053725/massive-npm-supply-chain-attack-hits-18-popular-packages-with-2b-weekly-downloads.html" target="_blank"&gt;researchers at Aikido reported&lt;/a&gt; that 18 highly popular and highly downloaded npm packages had been contaminated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know how to easily solve this problem without requiring a full security view of any newly submitted code, and that’s not fast, cheap, or easy,” commented &lt;a href="https://www.knowbe4.com/press/roger-grimes-joins-knowbe4-as-data-driven-defense-evangelist" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Roger Grimes&lt;/a&gt;, digital defence CISO advisor at KnowBe4.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“But it really is the only answer if you want reliable, safe, open source code.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ironically, he said, one of the biggest reasons given for the world to use open source code is that it’s readily reviewable, so anyone can look at it to see and stop vulnerabilities. “But the reality is that almost no one security reviews any of the tens of millions of lines of open source code,” he pointed out. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There have been dozens of open source projects that attempted to implement more default code review and all have failed,” he said. “One of my favorite related quotes of all time is, ‘Asking for users to review open source code before using is like asking passengers of an airliner to step outside the jet and review it for flight safety before they fly.’ I’m not sure who said that first, but it’s a brilliant summary of why volunteer open source code review really doesn’t work.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="typosquatting"&gt;Typosquatting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One favorite tactic of threat actors trying to infect the open source software supply chain is typosquatting, the creation of packages with names similar to those of legitimate ones to trick unwitting developers searching for a particular library. For example, in 2018 a researcher found that &lt;a href="https://bertusk.medium.com/detecting-cyber-attacks-in-the-python-package-index-pypi-61ab2b585c67" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;threat actors had created phony libraries in the Python repository&lt;/a&gt; called ‘diango,’ ‘djago,’ ‘dajngo,’ to dupe developers seeking the popular ‘django’ Python library.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should ensure that employees are educated about the issue of typosquatting and learn what to look for. IT departments should keep a comprehensive inventory of what components are used by all approved software against which audits can be conducted, to ensure only approved components are in place. This inventory and audit should be performed to validate any new components that are introduced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-more-to-do"&gt;What more to do?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There’s no shortage of advice for developers and IT and infosec leaders to help them avoid being victimized by malicious packages in open source repositories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One tactic is to include a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573185/what-is-an-sbom-software-bill-of-materials-explained.html" target="_blank"&gt;software bill of materials&lt;/a&gt; in every application an IT department acquires. With it, the DevOps/DevSecOps teams can track software components, identify vulnerabilities, and ensure compliance. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2021, the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) and the US National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) published an advisory, &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/publications/defending_against_software_supply_chain_attacks_508.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Defending Against Software Supply Chain Attacks&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;/a&gt;providing advice for creating secure open source apps. It starts with the creation of a formal supply chain risk management program to ensure that supply chain risk receives attention across the organization, even among executives and managers within operations and personnel across supporting roles, such as IT, acquisitions, legal, risk management, and security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An organization can reduce its software attack surface through configuration management, the advisory says, which includes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;placing configurations under change control;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;conducting security impact analyses;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;implementing manufacturer-provided guidelines to harden software, operating systems, and firmware;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;• maintaining an information system component inventory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Open Source Web Application Security Project (OWASP) offers this advice to developers using npm:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;always vet and perform due diligence on third-party modules that you install to confirm their health and credibility;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;hold off on immediate upgrades to new versions; allow new package versions some time to circulate before trying them out.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;before upgrading, make sure to review changelogs and release notes for the upgraded version.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;when installing packages, make sure to add the &lt;em&gt;ignore-scripts&lt;/em&gt; suffix to disable the execution of any scripts by third-party packages.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;consider adding &lt;em&gt;ignore-scripts&lt;/em&gt; to the .npmrc project file, or to the global npm configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href="https://www.andrewkrug.com/bio/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Andrew Krug&lt;/a&gt;, Datadog’s head of security advocacy, offered these additional tips:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;give developers the ability to install real-time package scanning at installation;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;guard against typosquatting and dependency confusion by prioritizing the use of internal package repositories as a guardrail for approved packages;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;maintain software bills of materials;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Deploy SCA (software composition analysis) at every phase of the software development lifecycle. Traditional SCA tools only periodically analyze code snapshots, he said, but effective detection must be complemented with real-time visibility into deployed services, including production, to reprioritize issues and focus on those exposed in sensitive environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4086337/malicious-npm-packages-contain-vidar-infostealer.html" target="_blank"&gt;InfoWorld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086415/malicious-npm-packages-contain-vidar-infostealer-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Security Posture Management: Die besten DSPM-Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493645/data-security-posture-management-die-besten-dspm-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Data Security Posture Management erfordert nicht nur die richtigen Tools, sondern auch eine entsprechende Vorbereitung." src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3376718/1200x.jpg" title="Data Security Posture Management erfordert nicht nur die richtigen Tools, sondern auch eine entsprechende Vorbereitung." width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Data Security Posture Management erfordert nicht nur die richtigen Tools, sondern auch eine entsprechende Vorbereitung.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Rawpixel.com | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cloud Computing ist von Natur aus dynamisch und flüchtig: Daten können schnell und einfach erstellt, gelöscht oder verschoben werden. Das sorgt dafür, dass auch die Cloud-Angriffsfläche sehr dynamisch ist – was &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495736/cloud-security-strategie-in-die-cloud-aber-mit-sicherheit.html" target="_blank" title="Schutzmaßnahmen erschwert"&gt;Schutzmaßnahmen erschwert&lt;/a&gt;. Ein lästiges Problem stellt dabei insbesondere dar, sensible Daten innerhalb von Cloud-Umgebungen aufzuspüren. An dieser Stelle kommt Data Security Posture Management – kurz DSPM – ins Spiel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="was-ist-data-security-posture-management"&gt;Was ist Data Security Posture Management?&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Bereich DSPM wurden in den vergangenen Jahren diverse Tools entwickelt, die dabei unterstützen, sowohl bekannte als auch unbekannte Daten zu erkennen, zu strukturieren und mit Blick auf Security und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494359/der-grose-ki-risiko-guide.html" target="_blank" title="Datenschutzrisiken"&gt;Datenschutzrisiken&lt;/a&gt; zu managen. Data Security Posture Management Tools können Sicherheitsentscheidern und ihren Teams dabei einen umfassenden Blick auf den Datenbestand des Unternehmens ermöglichen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das könnte Ihnen eventuell bekannt vorkommen – dennoch handelt es sich bei DSPM nicht um einen Abkömmling von &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2797438/was-sie-ueber-dlp-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank" title="Data Loss Prevention"&gt;Data Loss Prevention&lt;/a&gt; (DLP). Der wesentliche Unterschied besteht darin, dass DSPM-Tools nicht darauf “warten”, dass Daten gestohlen oder exfiltriert werden. DSPM-Produkte sind darauf ausgerichtet, Daten zu finden – unabhängig davon, wo sie sich befinden und ob diese Speicherorte gut dokumentiert oder unstrukturiert sind. Dabei zielen Data Security Posture Management Tools insbesondere darauf ab, sogenannte “Schattendaten” aufzuspüren. Dabei handelt es sich zum Beispiel um Datenelemente, die von Entwicklern oder Backup-Prozessen erstellt wurden oder veraltete &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492659/datenlecks-finden-so-verhindern-sie-repository-leaks.html" target="_blank" title="Repositories"&gt;Repositories&lt;/a&gt;, die in längst vergessenen, nicht mehr aktualisierten Cloud-Containern schlummern. DSPM-Tools übernehmen dabei eine “Locator”-Funktion. Gefundene Probleme zu beheben, fällt eigentlich in den Bereich traditionellerer Toolsets – beispielsweise &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494258/threat-intelligence-datenbanken-in-einem-soar-die-richtigen-spielzuge-gegen-hacker.html" target="_blank" title="SOAR"&gt;SOAR&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492608/was-ist-siem.html" target="_blank" title="SIEM"&gt;SIEM&lt;/a&gt; oder &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/de_de/what-is/cloud-native/cnapp.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="CNAPP"&gt;CNAPP&lt;/a&gt;. Inzwischen werden solche “Fix it”-Tools jedoch zunehmend von den Anbietern im Bereich Data Security Posture Management integriert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Daten aufzuspüren, ist allerdings nur der erste Schritt des DSPM-Prozesses: Sobald diese gefunden sind, müssen sie katalogisiert, ausgewertet und in verschiedenen Dashboards zusammengefasst werden. Das kann schwierig sein, wenn keine strikten Sicherheitskontrollen vorhanden sind. Deshalb werben die meisten DSPM-Anbieter auch damit, dass Kundendaten immer in der Umgebung des Kunden bleiben – was in der Regel bedeutet, dass nicht die eigentlichen Daten, sondern Metadaten gesammelt werden. Das heißt bei den Anbietern “agentenloser” oder API-Zugriff und hat den Vorteil, dass große Datenmengen schnell gescannt werden können, um die Art ihrer Nutzung und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495397/gehackte-konten-verlorene-datendie-15-dicksten-datenschutzverletzungen-unseres-jahrhunderts.html" target="_blank" title="potenzielle Risikofaktoren"&gt;potenzielle Risikofaktoren&lt;/a&gt; zu verstehen. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sobald die Daten entdeckt und die Metadaten gesammelt sind, besteht der nächste Schritt darin, regelmäßige Scans durchzuführen, um festzustellen, welche Änderungen vorgenommen werden. Die Betonung liegt dabei auf “regelmäßig”. Ergänzend hinzu kommt schließlich auch noch das Thema &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2803961/was-ist-data-governance.html" target="_blank" title="Data Governance"&gt;Data Governance&lt;/a&gt;: DSPM-Tools klassifizieren nach Risiken und können im Zusammenspiel mit anderen Security-Tools Richtlinien durchsetzen und Probleme beheben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Grundsätzlich bestehen DSPM-Tools aus mehreren Komponenten, darunter:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agenten und “agentless Collectors” (nützlich, um On-Premises-Daten zu tracken),&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ein zentralisiertes Management-Dashboard,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scanner, die Datensammlungen erkennen und priorisieren,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data-Lineage- und Usage-Karten sowie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compliance Assessments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das übergeordnete Ziel von DSPM-Produkten besteht darin, umfassendere &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495818/cloud-risiken-verwalten-so-wahlen-sie-das-passende-cspm-tool-aus.html" target="_blank" title="Cloud Security Posture Management"&gt;Cloud Security Posture Management&lt;/a&gt; (CSPM)-Tools zu ergänzen. Dabei fokussieren die DSPM-Werkzeuge jedoch nicht auf Cloud-Infrastrukturen selbst, sondern ausschließlich auf Daten sowie darauf, wie diese durch die verschiedenen Services genutzt werden. In vielen Fällen haben DSPM-Anbieter deswegen auch CSPM-Offerings im Portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="dspm-produkte-evaluieren"&gt;DSPM-Produkte evaluieren&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tools im Bereich Data Security Posture Management zu evaluieren, erfordert erheblichen Personalaufwand, da viele verschiedene Aspekte der IT-Infrastruktur eines Unternehmens davon betroffen sind. Das ist allerdings auch gut so, schließlich wollen Sie ja auch alle relevanten Daten identifizieren. Hilfreich ist zu diesem Zweck insbesondere ein Plan, der die wichtigsten Daten nach Priorität ordnet. Ein weiterer Tipp: Dokumentieren Sie, wie die einzelnen DSPM-Tools ihre Data Map erstellen und wie diese – und die darauf basierenden Dashboards – zu interpretieren sind. Schließlich ist es bei der Entscheidung über ein DSPM-Tool essenziell zu wissen, welche spezifischen Cloud Services abgedeckt sind und welche (noch) nicht.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Was die Preisgestaltung von DSPM-Tools angeht, ist diese im Regelfall flexibel gestaltet und hängt von diversen Faktoren ab. Das Gros der Anbieter setzt auf entsprechende Abo-Modelle. Sicher ist, dass das teuer wird: Sie dürfen pro Jahr mit einer sechsstelligen Summe rechnen. Eine weitere Vorwarnung: Es wird Sie einiges an Zeit und Mühe kosten, den Umfang, das Integrationsniveau und die enthaltenen Schutzfunktionen der einzelnen DSPM-Angebote bis ins letzte Detail zu durchdringen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-besten-dspm-tools"&gt;Die besten DSPM-Tools&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Folgenden haben wir die aktuell wichtigsten DSPM-Anbieter und ihre Offerings für Sie zusammengestellt. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://concentric.ai/product-overview/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Concentric Semantic Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cyera.io/platform" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cyera Data Security Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/guardium" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;IBM Guardium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.onetrust.com/platform/data-discovery-and-security/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Onetrust Data Use Governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.prismacloud.io/prisma/cloud/cloud-data-security" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Palo Alto Networks Prisma Cloud DSPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/de/products/data-security-posture-management" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Proofpoint DSPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://securiti.ai/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Securiti Data Command Center DSPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sentra.io/product" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sentra Cloud-Native Data Security Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.symmetry-systems.com/dataguard-dspm/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Symmetry Modern Data Security Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/cloud-security/solutions/dspm" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Tenable DSPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.varonis.com/products/data-security-platform" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Varonis Data Security Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/solutions/dspm" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Wiz DSPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493645/data-security-posture-management-die-besten-dspm-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 04:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 01:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why can’t enterprises get a handle on the cloud misconfiguration problem?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4083736/why-cant-enterprises-get-a-handle-on-the-cloud-misconfiguration-problem.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Seven years ago, I wrote about how &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564399/cloud-security-configuration-errors-put-data-at-risk-new-tools-can-help.html"&gt;cloud security configuration errors&lt;/a&gt; were putting enterprise data at risk. Amazon storage buckets were being left open to the public left and right, with millions of sensitive records exposed. Companies were new to the whole cloud thing, and cloud providers weren’t making it easy to lock everything down the way it should be.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’d think that by now enterprises should have their cloud assets locked down. Shouldn’t they?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, they still don’t.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to an April &lt;a href="https://blog.qualys.com/vulnerabilities-threat-research/2025/04/03/the-state-of-cloud-saas-security-essential-statistics-and-insights"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by Qualys, 28% of organizations surveyed had a cloud or SaaS-related breach in the past year, 24% said that misconfigured services posed the biggest risk to their cloud environments in third place after human error and targeted cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Qualys also looked at 44 million virtual machines hosted in the public clouds, and found that, on AWS 45% had misconfigured resources, on Google Cloud Platform (GCP) 63% had misconfigured resources, and 70% had misconfigured resources on Azure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity company also found that 63% of publicly accessible VMs had no encryption on attached EBS storage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="more-tools-more-opportunities-for-misconfiguration"&gt;More tools, more opportunities for misconfiguration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proliferation of SaaS tools that companies are using just expands the opportunities to make configuration mistakes. Data on 4.7 million Blue Shield California members was recently &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3970155/lesson-from-huge-blue-shield-california-data-breach-read-the-manual.html"&gt;exposed&lt;/a&gt; due to a misconfiguration in Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Microsoft, Google, and Amazon have handed us a problem,” says Andrew Wilder, CSO at Vetcor, a national network of more than 900 veterinary hospitals. “By default, everything is insecure, and you have to put security on top of it. It would be much better if they just gave us out-of-the-box secure stuff. Would you buy a car that doesn’t have locks? They wouldn’t even sell that car.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This security gap is what allows third-party vendors to exist, he says. “You should be building products — and I’m talking to you, Google, Microsoft, and Amazon — that are secure by design, so you don’t have to get a third-party tool. They should be out of the box secure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building an in-house security is not an option at Vetcor and the company is using the native tools provided by the hyperscalers. “And for us, right now, that’s good enough.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="stop-reassess-reconfigure"&gt;Stop. Reassess. Reconfigure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last year, according to Ayan Roy, EY Americas cybersecurity competency leader, the highest number of breaches were caused by shared cloud repositories. “That’s where we saw the maximum amount of data exfiltration,” he says. “A lot was from shared cloud stores and SaaS applications.” That’s despite the fact that the clients have cloud security blueprints and governance processes and it is because of shadow IT, he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations are turning something on but not configuring all the security features, not turning on all the logging and monitoring, not turning on MFA, not locking down access. “Business wants to go quickly and time to value is absolutely important.” But they do not include the cybersecurity teams on these decisions and that is where the problem begins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cyber becomes an afterthought. If they’re in the right conversation, they can do things more proactively instead of doing things retroactively.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One proactive measure that any company can take is to drive more awareness of enterprise-approved, secure platforms. That might require better communication or additional training to ensure that employees don’t go off and use insecure systems when secure options are available.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another blind spot comes up during mergers and acquisitions, he says. “Be proactive in acquisitions,” says Roy. “Do the due diligence and account for that, and make sure you have the right investment plan for cybersecurity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="top-cloud-configuration-mistakes"&gt;Top cloud configuration mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Scott Wheeler, cloud practice lead at Asperitas, the bigger the organization or the more regulatory oversight it faces, the fewer cloud configuration errors it will see. “But if you get to the bottom of the Fortune 1000, say, if you’re a manufacturing company and the implications of making a mistake are perceived not to be so huge, and they don’t have regulators hovering over them, they might be fast and loose. That’s where you see errors happening.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And the smallest organizations have tremendous problems since they don’t have the staff or the tools to manage configuration risks. This includes exposed storage buckets or web services, excessive privileges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The whole concept of zero trust is predicated on the fact that you can lock down access to the minimum of what you need,” says Wheeler. “But that’s hard to do.” People often increase permissions during development and don’t put them back when things go into production.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake that Wheeler sees is that databases or other cloud assets don’t communicate over secure private networks. “A lot of times, out of the box, those services don’t have that,” he says. “It takes some work to configure it so that it’s strictly private network traffic to my private cloud environment or my on-prem environment. That’s a huge one, and we see a lot of hacks with that — and a lot of compromises on internal environments.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lack of multi-factor authentication is another risk as MFA helps protect cloud environments against risks such as leaked credentials. Lack of encryption is another concern, according to &lt;a href="https://www.thalesgroup.com/en/news-centre/press-releases/thales-2025-global-cloud-security-study-reveals-organizations-struggle" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Thales&lt;/a&gt;, only 51% of sensitive cloud data is encrypted, and only 8% of enterprises encrypt 80% or more of their cloud data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="9-tips-for-cloud-configurations-to-reduce-data-exposure"&gt;9 tips for cloud configurations to reduce data exposure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-implement-multi-factor-authentication-everywhere"&gt;1. Implement multi-factor authentication everywhere&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Require MFA for all cloud access, not just some users. The reason that so many companies are reporting data breaches involving their Salesforce instances is that they didn’t have MFA properly set up and configured for their user accounts, allowing adversaries to take over user accounts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-default-to-private-networks-for-all-services"&gt;2. Default to private networks for all services&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Configure databases and cloud services to communicate only over private networks, not the public internet. According to Scott Wheeler at Asperitas, many services don’t default to this option and is the top misconfiguration that he sees in data breach investigations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-encrypt-sensitive-data-at-rest-and-in-transit"&gt;3. Encrypt sensitive data at rest and in transit&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only 51% of sensitive cloud data is encrypted, according to Thales. Today, encryption should be the default for all new and existing resources. And with quantum computing on the horizon, enterprises should already be using quantum-proof encryption algorithms to defend against harvest-now, decrypt-later attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-apply-least-privilege-access-controls"&gt;4. Apply least-privilege access controls&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Giving users and systems access to the minimum possible resources is a massive headache. And when additional privileges are granted for a particular reason, they’re often not downgraded again when the need passes. But least privilege is a cornerstone of modern zero trust security principles, and overprivileged accounts can easily lead to data losses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-use-infrastructure-as-code-for-all-changes"&gt;5. Use infrastructure as code for all changes&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When administrators or users make changes to cloud configurations in the cloud management consoles, it’s difficult to track those changes and to revert them if something goes wrong. Plus, humans can easily make mistakes. The solution experts advise is to adopt the principle of “infrastructure as code” and use configuration management tools so that all changes are checked against policies, tracked and audited, and can easily be rolled back.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-scan-for-misconfigurations-continuously"&gt;6. Scan for misconfigurations continuously&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And it’s not enough to check that configurations are set currently when the cloud assets are first set up. Companies need to make sure that they don’t change. Cloud providers offer some native tools to help with this, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;cloud security posture management&lt;/a&gt; tools can fill in the gaps or provide multi-cloud monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-lock-down-storage-buckets-and-disable-public-access"&gt;7. Lock down storage buckets and disable public access&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unsecured Amazon S3 buckets were all the rage with hackers a few years ago — and they are still a problem for companies. According to Tenable’s analysis of cloud environments, 9% of publicly accessible cloud storage contains sensitive data. Use bucket policies and access controls to ensure storage is private by default, and if you change its availability to public for testing or some other reason, make sure to make it private again when you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="8-enable-comprehensive-logging-and-monitoring-for-all-deployments"&gt;8. Enable comprehensive logging and monitoring for all deployments&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies will often have monitoring for major cloud services, but shadow IT deployments are left in the dark. This is less a technology problem than a management one and can be addressed by better communications with business units and a more disciplined approach to deploying technology on an enterprise-wide level. With the rapid pace of technological change, this is harder to do but also more important, as AI and other new cloud services may touch sensitive data and processes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="9-start-secure-from-day-one"&gt;9. Start secure from day one&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Build security into your cloud architecture from the beginning — it’s much harder to retrofit later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="will-ai-solve-every-problem"&gt;Will AI solve every problem?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vendors are promising that AI will make security easier, cheaper, and more effective.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But will generative AI really solve the cloud configuration problem?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It could, says Vetcor’s Wilder. “But it’s not going to happen as quickly as people are saying. I really think agentic AI has the possibility to enhance what security teams are doing, to alleviate the lack of resources we have. But there’s a lot of organizational change management that goes into that as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4083736/why-cant-enterprises-get-a-handle-on-the-cloud-misconfiguration-problem.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-714)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-714</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-714</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-715)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-715</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-715</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-716)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-716</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-716</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-717)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-717</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-717</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–718)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-718</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-718</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-719)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-720)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-720</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-720</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquiti security advisory (AV25-721)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubiquiti-security-advisory-av25-721</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubiquiti-security-advisory-av25-721</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business continuity and cybersecurity: Two sides of the same coin</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086135/business-continuity-and-cybersecurity-two-sides-of-the-same-coin.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As someone who has spent over six years in the trenches of IT operations at Amazon, managing critical infrastructure that cannot afford downtime, I’ve witnessed firsthand how the convergence of cyberthreats and business continuity has fundamentally changed the game for executives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 3 am call that every CISO and CIO dreads isn’t just about a server crash anymore. It’s about sophisticated threat actors who understand that disrupting your operations can be more profitable than stealing your data. After managing IT infrastructure for one of the world’s largest companies and responding to countless incidents, I can tell you that the traditional approach to business continuity planning is dangerously outdated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-5-4-million-question-every-executive-must-answer"&gt;The $5.4 million question every executive must answer&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to IBM’s 2024 Cost of a Data Breach report, the &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/reports/data-breach" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;average cost of a data breach has reached $4.88 million globally&lt;/a&gt;, with business disruption accounting for the largest portion of these costs. But here’s what keeps me up at night: These figures don’t capture the full picture of what happens when cybercriminals specifically target your business continuity infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During my tenure as an IT support engineer at Amazon, I’ve seen how quickly operational disruptions cascade through interconnected systems. When attackers target your disaster recovery sites, backup systems and the very tools you rely on to restore operations, the financial impact multiplies exponentially. The question isn’t whether your organization will face a cyber-induced business disruption; it’s whether you’ll survive it with your reputation and market position intact.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-traditional-business-continuity-plans-fail-against-modern-threats"&gt;Why traditional business continuity plans fail against modern threats&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’ve implemented change management processes in environments requiring 99.99% uptime and I can tell you that most business continuity plans were designed for a different era. They assume that your backup systems, communication channels and recovery procedures will be available when you need them. Today’s threat actors specifically target these assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2023 Veeam Ransomware Trends Report revealed that &lt;a href="https://www.veeam.com/ransomware-trends-report-2023?ad=in-text-link" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;93% of ransomware attacks target backup repositories&lt;/a&gt;. This isn’t coincidental. Cybercriminals understand that by compromising your recovery infrastructure, they maximize their leverage and your desperation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From my experience managing IT assets and coordinating incident responses, I’ve learned that the most dangerous assumption executives make is that cybersecurity and business continuity are separate disciplines. They’re not. They’re two sides of the same operational coin and treating them separately creates the vulnerabilities that sophisticated attackers exploit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-human-factor-your-biggest-asset-and-greatest-risk"&gt;The human factor: Your biggest asset and greatest risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Having trained numerous engineers and served as an escalation point for complex technical challenges, I’ve observed a critical pattern: human behavior under pressure consistently undermines even the most sophisticated technical controls. When your primary systems are down and executives are demanding immediate restoration, your team will take shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They’ll use personal devices to access company systems. They’ll share credentials to speed up recovery processes. They’ll bypass security protocols to restore operations quickly. This isn’t a training problem; it’s a human nature problem that requires systematic solutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2024 Verizon Data Breach Investigations Report confirms that &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;68% of breaches involve a human element&lt;/a&gt;. During crisis situations, this percentage increases dramatically as stress and urgency override security awareness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-resilient-infrastructure-lessons-from-high-availability-environments"&gt;Building resilient infrastructure: Lessons from high-availability environments&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implementing network security protocols and backup solutions in Amazon’s demanding environment has taught me that resilience requires a fundamental shift in thinking. You cannot simply add cybersecurity measures to existing business continuity plans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You must architect your entire continuity strategy around the assumption that your primary systems will be compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This means implementing network segmentation that isolates critical business functions from general corporate networks. When attackers gain access to email systems or file shares, they shouldn’t automatically have pathways to manufacturing controls or financial systems. &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/publications/zero-trust-architecture" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST’s Zero Trust Architecture guidelines&lt;/a&gt; provide a framework, but implementation requires deep understanding of your operational dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Your backup and recovery systems need their own security considerations. I’ve seen organizations invest millions in backup infrastructure only to discover that attackers had persistent access to their recovery environments for months. This requires implementing offline backup strategies, maintaining air-gapped recovery environments and regularly testing restoration procedures under simulated attack conditions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cloud-paradox-opportunity-and-vulnerability"&gt;The cloud paradox: Opportunity and vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud services present both opportunities and challenges for business continuity planning. While platforms like AWS, Azure and Google Cloud offer geographic redundancy and professional security management, they also create dependencies on external providers and internet connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2023 Uptime Institute Global Data Center Survey found that &lt;a href="https://uptimeinstitute.com/resources/research-and-reports/uptime-institute-global-data-center-survey-results-2023" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;80% of data center outages could have been prevented through better processes and training&lt;/a&gt;. In cloud environments, you’re dependent on your provider’s processes and training, which creates a different risk profile that many executives underestimate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="integration-where-most-organizations-fail"&gt;Integration: Where most organizations fail&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effective business continuity planning must integrate cybersecurity incident response from the very beginning. This means having communication protocols that work even when primary networks are compromised, decision-making processes that account for ongoing security threats and recovery procedures that don’t inadvertently reintroduce vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The traditional approach of focusing on restoring operations first and investigating security issues later is no longer viable. Organizations need to be able to conduct forensic analysis while simultaneously working to restore services. This requires specialized tools, trained personnel and procedures that balance the urgency of business recovery with the need to preserve evidence and prevent further compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="testing-the-reality-check-most-executives-avoid"&gt;Testing: The reality check most executives avoid&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regular testing becomes even more critical when cybersecurity threats are factored into the equation. Organizations need to conduct exercises that simulate not just technical failures, but active attacks on their recovery infrastructure. These tests should include scenarios where primary communication channels are compromised, key personnel are unavailable and recovery systems themselves are under attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/white-papers/sans-2024-detection-response-survey" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SANS 2024 Detection and Response Survey&lt;/a&gt; revealed that organizations that conduct regular tabletop exercises recover 50% faster from actual incidents. But tabletop exercises aren’t enough. You need red team exercises where security professionals attempt to disrupt business continuity procedures using the same tactics that real attackers might employ.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-executive-imperative-act-before-the-crisis"&gt;The executive imperative: Act before the crisis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The integration of cybersecurity and business continuity planning will only become more important as organizations become increasingly dependent on digital infrastructure. Emerging technologies like artificial intelligence and internet of things devices create new attack surfaces that must be considered in continuity planning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The key to success lies in recognizing that cybersecurity and business continuity are not separate disciplines that occasionally overlap. They are fundamentally interconnected aspects of organizational resilience that must be planned, implemented and managed as a unified strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As executives, you have a choice: Invest in integrated cyber-resilient business continuity now or explain to your board, customers and shareholders why your organization couldn’t maintain operations when it mattered most. The threat actors are already making their choice. The question is, what’s yours?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086135/business-continuity-and-cybersecurity-two-sides-of-the-same-coin.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-722)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-722</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-722</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-723)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-723</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-723</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV25-725)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av25-725</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nikkei’s Slack breach leaks sensitive data from more than 17,000 users</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086100/nikkeis-slack-breach-leaks-sensitive-data-from-more-than-17000-users.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Japanese media company Nikkei has confirmed that a security breach of its Slack accounts has potentially leaked highly sensitive information from more than 17,000 of its users. Consultants point to the incident as yet another reminder of the dangers when non-corporate devices are allowed to access confidential corporate data. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“An employee’s personal computer was infected with a virus, leading to the leakage of Slack authentication credentials. It is believed that this information was used to gain unauthorized access to employee accounts,” Nikkei said in &lt;a href="https://www.nikkei.co.jp/nikkeiinfo/en/news/announcements/1394.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a published statement&lt;/a&gt;. “The incident was identified in September and countermeasures such as changing passwords were implemented. Potentially leaked information includes the names, email addresses, and chat histories for 17,368 individuals registered on Slack.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Nikkei statement added “Considering the incident’s significance and to ensure transparency, we voluntarily reported it to [Japan’s] &lt;a href="https://www.ppc.go.jp/en/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Personal Information Protection Commission&lt;/a&gt;. No leakage of information related to sources or reporting activities has been confirmed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, a directory of former government and military specialists, stressed that this is part of an ongoing trend of Slack breaches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There is often increased risk when employees or contractors access company resources from non-company-managed devices. Recent attacks against Okta, MGM Resorts, and others have been linked to such unmanaged access,” Levine said, adding that last year, “an attacker exfiltrated more than [1 terabyte] of internal data from Disney’s Slack environment when a contractor had accessed Slack from an unmanaged device, bypassing monitoring tools.”  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/erik-avakian" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Erik Avakian&lt;/a&gt;, technical counselor at Info-Tech Research Group, noted that one of the most concerning things about attacks similar to the Nikkei breach is that the attackers are often able to easily bypass MFA defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“An employee’s computer gets hit by malware designed to steal credentials. The malware grabs Slack session tokens and cookies, then sends them to attacker command and control servers,” Avakian said. “With those stolen and likely active tokens, the attacker is able to log into Slack from their own device and access private channels and chat history without even triggering a multi-factor authentication prompt, since they reused an already-authenticated session.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Avakian said that the nature of these attacks suggests that enterprise CISOs should consider procedural changes. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This kind of attack would give threat actors “broad access to channels and integrations, which made the impact worse. Weaknesses around this incident shine a light on unmanaged or poorly protected devices, long-lived tokens, and not enough logging or alerts for suspicious sessions,” Avakian said. “Organizations can learn from these types of incident, and those using Slack, or any other widely used communications platform similar to Slack, should maintain a policy for revoking active sessions and refreshing tokens for affected users routinely, forcing password resets and rotating API tokens.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffreyeman/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jeff Man&lt;/a&gt;, a senior information security consultant with Online Business Systems, pointed out, “the larger discussion should be on the failings of the Nikkei IT/IS program to protect against some sort of attack that targeted its employees. Why are employees allowed to use Slack on personal devices?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“So this is really an issue of risk management,” Man said. “In the case of Nikkei, it appears the exploitation was elsewhere [on the system]. The initial access allowed the miscreants to use credentials to gain access to Slack. That’s not a compromise of Slack itself, that’s a compromise of employee account authentication.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://thecyberdr.com/#about" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Stephen Boyce&lt;/a&gt;, security consultant and CEO of The Cyber Dr., said the Nikkei incident represents “what happens when someone uses a personal device to get into work systems. Once that device gets hit with malware, it’s game over for the credentials. The part that worries me is this could happen anywhere. People forget how much sensitive stuff ends up in Slack: messages, files, links, sometimes even credentials. Once someone has that, they can poke around pretty freely.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To me, it’s just another reminder that zero trust has to go all the way out to the edge, not just the network. You’ve got to know the device, use MFA tied to managed hardware, and control what data lives in those SaaS tools,” Boyce said. “You may be also asking ‘Well, do we do away with BYOD all together?’ And the short answer is ‘no’ but we do need to look at ways we can secure the workforce beyond company issued assets.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086100/nikkeis-slack-breach-leaks-sensitive-data-from-more-than-17000-users.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-724) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-724</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-726)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-726</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-619) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-619</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV25-727)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av25-727</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-728)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-728</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-729)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-729</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-730)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-730</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – November 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-731)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-november-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-731</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
