<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 22:39:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>New APT group breached gov and critical infrastructure orgs in 37 countries</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128378/new-apt-group-breached-gov-and-critical-infrastructure-orgs-in-37-countries.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new cyberespionage group that operates out of Asia has compromised 70 government and critical infrastructure organizations across 37 countries over the past year using a sophisticated toolset that combines phishing, exploitation kits, custom malware, Linux rootkits, web shells, and a variety of other tunneling and proxy tools. Researchers believe the group is expanding its activities and is conducting active reconnaissance on even more targets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Between November and December 2025, we observed the group conducting active reconnaissance against government infrastructure associated with 155 countries,” researchers from security firm Palo Alto Networks said in &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/shadow-campaigns-uncovering-global-espionage/"&gt;a new report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto tracks the group as TGR-STA-1030 (aka UNC6619) and believes it is based in Asia based on language settings, its preference for regional tooling, GMT+8 operating hours, and targeting that aligns with events in the region. The researchers, who have been tracking the group since February 2025, believe it has ties to a nation state.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group’s confirmed victims include national-level law enforcement and border control entities; ministries and departments of interior, foreign affairs, finance, trade, economy, immigration, mining, justice, and energy; elected officials and even a parliament’s infrastructure. The group has also targeted national telecommunications companies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While this group might be pursuing espionage objectives, its methods, targets, and scale of operations are alarming, with potential long-term consequences for national security and key services,” Palo Alto’s researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-phishing-to-exploits"&gt;From phishing to exploits&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto started tracking the group a year ago following a series of phishing campaigns directed at European governments that the company dubbed the Shadow Campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The phishing emails posed as announcements about organizational changes in official institutions and were written in the language of their intended targets. The messages contained links that led to the download of a ZIP archive with a custom malware loader the researchers now call Diaoyu.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This loader performs various checks to detect the presence of certain antivirus programs and to ascertain whether it is running in a sandbox. It then proceeds to download the Cobalt Strike implant from a GitHub repository. Cobalt Strike is a commercial penetration testing tool that has grown popular among attackers over the years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although the group hasn’t been observed exploiting previously unknown vulnerabilities to gain access to networks, it has used exploits for known vulnerabilities (N-days) in a large number of software products, operating systems, and libraries, including: SAP Solution Manager, Microsoft Open Management Infrastructure, Microsoft Exchange Server, Pivotal Spring Data Commons, Struts2, Eyou Email System, Beijing Grandview Century eHR Software, Weaver Ecology-OA, Commvault CommCell CVSearchService, Zhiyuan OA, Microsoft Windows, networking products from Ruijieyi Networks and D-Link, and more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“On one occasion, we observed the actor connecting to e-passport and e-visa services associated with a ministry of foreign affairs,” the researchers said. “Because the server for these services was configured with Atlassian Crowd software, the actor attempted to exploit CVE-2019-11580, uploading a payload named rce.jar.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-complex-toolset-of-implants"&gt;A complex toolset of implants&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to Cobalt Strike, the group uses various other malware payloads and command-and-control (C2) frameworks, including VShell, Havoc, SparkRat, and Sliver. On compromised web servers, the attackers deploy a variety of web shells, including Behinder, Neo-reGeorg, and Godzilla.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On Linux servers the group has been seen deploying a rootkit dubbed ShadowGuard, which leverages the Extended Berkeley Packet Filter (eBPF), a powerful feature for running sandboxed code inside the Linux kernel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“eBPF backdoors are notoriously difficult to detect because they operate entirely within the highly trusted kernel space,” the researchers said. “eBPF programs do not appear as separate modules. Instead, they execute inside the kernel’s BPF virtual machine, making them inherently stealthy. This allows them to manipulate core system functions and audit logs before security tools or system monitoring applications can see the true data.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ShadowGuard appears to be a tool that’s unique to this group and allows them to hide processes, files, and directories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To conceal outgoing network traffic from victim networks, the attackers use a variety of relay and proxy servers running tunneling software like the GO Simple Tunnel (GOST), Fast Reverse Proxy Server (FRPS), and IOX, but their C2 servers are typically hosted on virtual private servers (VPS) from the US, UK, and Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="increase-in-targeting"&gt;Increase in targeting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto believes the group is expanding its operations because it has scanned networks of organizations from 155 countries for known vulnerabilities since October. The scans appear to be targeted on IP addresses belonging to government infrastructure and specific targets of interest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, during the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4066008/government-shutdown-deepens-us-cyber-risk-exposing-networks-to-threat-actors.html"&gt;US government shutdown that began in October&lt;/a&gt;, the group started scanning the infrastructure of governments in the Americas, including in Brazil, Canada, Dominican Republic, Guatemala, Honduras, Jamaica, Mexico, Panama, and Trinidad and Tobago. The researchers believe the group has already compromised entities in Bolivia, Brazil, Mexico, Panama, and Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The group seems to time its targeting to certain events. For example, when the president of Czechia met with the Dalai Lama in August, the group immediately started scanning the computer infrastructure belonging to the Czech Army, police, parliament, and presidency, as well as its ministries of interior, finance, and foreign affairs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“TGR-STA-1030 remains an active threat to government and critical infrastructure worldwide,” Palo Alto said. “The group primarily targets government ministries and departments for espionage purposes. We assess that it prioritizes efforts against countries that have established or are exploring certain economic partnerships.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company’s report includes indicators of compromise, including IP addresses, domain names, and file hashes for the implants used by the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128378/new-apt-group-breached-gov-and-critical-infrastructure-orgs-in-37-countries.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol supports French investigation into alleged criminal activity linked to platform X</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</link>
      <description>The investigation is conducted by the Paris Public Prosecutor’s Office with the support of the French Gendarmerie’s cybercrime unit (UNCyber) and Europol.On the action day, French authorities carried out investigative measures in the offices of the platform in France. Europol supported the investigation through its European Cybercrime Centre (EC3), providing specialised cybercrime expertise and deploying an analyst on the ground...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supports-french-investigation-alleged-criminal-activity-linked-to-platform-x</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-072)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-072</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-073)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-073</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–074)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-074</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-075)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-075</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-076)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-076</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-077)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-077</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes security advisory (AV26-078)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-079)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-080)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-081)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-082)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-083)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django security advisory (AV26-084)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-085)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV26-086)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-087)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-088)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customer Identity &amp; Access Management: Die besten CIAM-Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492789/customer-identity-access-management-die-6-besten-ciam-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Digital Key 16z9 DE Only" class="wp-image-3816426" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/original_Jackie-Niam.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Wir haben die besten Lösungen in Sachen Customer Identity &amp;amp; Access Management für Sie zusammengestellt.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Jackie Niam | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Customer Identity &amp;amp; Access Management (CIAM) bildet eine Unterkategorie von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495114/identity-access-managementdie-9-besten-iam-tools.html" target="_blank" title="Identity &amp;amp; Access Management"&gt;Identity &amp;amp; Access Management&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495781/identity-access-management-umsetzen-6-anzeichen-dass-ihre-iam-strategie-nichts-taugt.html" target="_blank" title="IAM"&gt;IAM&lt;/a&gt;). CIAM wird dazu eingesetzt, die Authentifizierungs- und Autorisierungsprozesse von Applikationen zu managen, die öffentlich zugänglich sind, beziehungsweise von Kunden bedient werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geht es darum, die für Ihr Unternehmen passende CIAM-Lösung zu ermitteln, gilt es, die Benutzerfreundlichkeit mit einer langen Liste von Geschäftszielen und -anforderungen ins Gleichgewicht zu bringen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketingverantwortliche&lt;/strong&gt; wollen Daten über Kunden und deren Geräte sammeln.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datenschutzbeauftragte&lt;/strong&gt; wollen sicherstellen, dass alle Prozesse mit den Datenschutzbestimmungen in Einklang stehen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security- und Risiko-Entscheider&lt;/strong&gt; wollen die Integrität der Konten sicherstellen und die betrügerische Nutzung von Anmeldedaten so weit wie möglich verhindern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um Sie bei diesem heiklen Balanceakt zu unterstützen, haben wir die derzeit besten Lösungen, die der Markt für Customer Identity &amp;amp; Access Management zu bieten hat, für Sie zusammengestellt. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="empfehlenswerte-customer-identity-access-management-tools"&gt;Empfehlenswerte Customer Identity &amp;amp; Access Management Tools&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die folgenden CIAM-Plattformen und -Lösungen werden von Analysten und Kunden aufgrund ihres Funktionsumfangs, ihrer Erweiterbarkeit und ihrer Benutzerfreundlichkeit bevorzugt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/verify-identity" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="IBM Security Verify"&gt;IBM Security Verify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Enterprise-Bereich erhält IBMs Security Verify gute Noten für seine robuste Infrastruktur, die durch eine containersierte Multi-Cloud-Architektur gestützt wird. Diese ist nicht nur skalierbar, sondern bietet Unternehmen auch die Möglichkeit, isolierte Kundeninstanzen zu managen. Dabei bietet die IBM-Lösung Support für eine Vielzahl von Authentifizierungsstandards, inklusive FIDO 2 Server-Zertifizierung. Um Marketing-Analysen oder BI-Funktionen zu integrieren, können die Kunden entweder das IBM-eigene Ökosystem oder Drittanbieter über ein ausgedehntes Konnektoren-Portfolio ins Boot holen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein wichtiges Alleinstellungsmerkmal des IBM-Produkts: Während viele andere CIAM-Produkte in Sachen risikobasierte Authentifizierung und Betrugsbekämpfung nur Integrationsoptionen anbieten können, bringt Security Verify diese Funktionen nativ mit: Die “Trusteer”-Funktionen nutzen Analysefunktionen, um Betrug mit Hilfe von KI-gestütztem, adaptivem Zugriff zu reduzieren. Das System nutzt eine Kombination aus Anomalieerkennung, Erkennung von Betrugsmustern und anderen passiven Verhaltensanalysen, um die Vertrauenswürdigkeit eines Kontos zu bewerten und die Authentifizierungsanforderungen entsprechend anzupassen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus bietet die IBM-Lösung auch ein Self-Service-Portal für die Benutzer, um Einwilligungen zu managen sowie eine &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495562/4-security-aspekte-low-code-heist-nicht-low-risk.html" target="_blank" title="Low-Code/No-Code"&gt;Low-Code/No-Code&lt;/a&gt;-Management-Funktion, die Datenschutzbeauftrage und Business-Entscheidern ermöglicht, Datenschutzrichtlinien und -anforderungen ohne die Hilfe von Softwareentwicklern festzulegen und zu optimieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.loginradius.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="LoginRadius"&gt;LoginRadius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn Sie in Sachen CIAM eine schlüsselfertige Lösung suchen, die für ihre einfache Implementierung und Bedienung bekannt ist, sollten Sie einen Blick auf das Angebot von LoginRadius werfen: Sie bringt umfassenden API-Support mit und lässt sich in vielfacher Hinsicht an ihre Bedürfnisse anpassen. Allerdings handelt es sich hierbei nicht um eine Plattform, die für umfangreiche Code-Anpassungen unter der Haube gedacht ist. Vielmehr adressiert sie als &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2802722/was-sie-ueber-no-code-plattformen-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank" title="No-Code-Lösung"&gt;No-Code-Lösung&lt;/a&gt; Unternehmen, die wenig bis gar keine Entwicklungsarbeit leisten wollen oder können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Onboarding-Workflows werden über eine grafische Benutzeroberfläche abgewickelt, Richtlinien über Dropdown-Listen erstellt. Zu Integrationszwecken steht ein Marktplatz mit vordefinierten Konnektoren zur Verfügung. Darüber hinaus enthält die CIAM-Plattform auch eine integrierte Analyse-Engine mit Dutzenden von Reportings für Marketing- und Identitätsanalysen. Um Datenschutz- und Compliance-Anforderungen gerecht zu werden, stehen grundlegende Consent-Management- und Self-Service-Funktionen zur Verfügung – zudem wird etwa Social Login unterstützt. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für die einfache Bedienung und die Deployment-Vorzüge opfern Unternehmen ein gewisses Maß an Kontrolle: So verfügt das Tool zwar über eine Authentifizierungs-Risiko-Engine, bietet aber nur wenig Kontrolle über dessen Priorisierung. Für Betrugserkennungs-Funktionen von Drittanbietern stehen nicht besonders viele Konnektoren zur Verfügung und Geräteattribute werden für Risikobewertungen und -analysen zwar untersucht, allerdings nur in begrenztem Umfang.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/de-de/security/business/microsoft-entra" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Microsoft Entra"&gt;Microsoft Entra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft ist zwar ein wichtiger Akteur auf dem breiteren IAM-Markt, arbeitet sich in Sachen CIAM aber immer noch auf der Reifegradskala nach oben. Im Rahmen ihrer letzten großen Access-Management-Analyse argumentierten die Marktforscher von Gartner, die CIAM-Funktionen von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495134/neue-angriffsmoglichkeitenwie-azure-ad-neue-authentifizierungsrisiken-eroffnet.html" target="_blank" title="Azure AD"&gt;Azure AD&lt;/a&gt; seien im Vergleich zu den Konkurrenzangeboten unausgereift, weswegen die meisten Kunden das Produkt nur für Workforce-Szenarien verwendeten. Seitdem ist allerdings viel passiert: Microsoft hat mit Nachdruck in sein gesamtes Identity-Portfolio investiert und sich mit einer neuen Produktlinie namens Entra positioniert. Diese umfasst nun das komplette Azure-AD-Paket, inklusive der CIAM-Funktionalitäten von Azure AD External Identities – zudem wurde auch die Open-Standard-Plattform Verified ID in den Mix aufgenommen. Microsoft setzt auf dieses dezentrale Identitätsnachweis-Ökosystem in erster Linie für Mitarbeiterszenarien und setzt damit einen langfristigen strategischen Schwerpunkt, der sich vermutlich auch auf externe Anwendungsfälle erstrecken wird.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trotz einiger großer Funktionslücken – etwa fehlende Consumer Privacy Dashboards oder der eher rudimentären Adaptive-Authentication-Policy-Konstruktion – hat Azure AD External Identities Vorteile: Es ist extrem skalierbar, einfach zu bedienen und verfügt über einige starke Account-Takeover-Schutzmechanismen. Zudem lässt es sich gut mit Microsofts BI- und CRM-Plattformen für erweiterte Analysen integrieren und bietet ein kontinuierlich wachsendes Integrations-Ökosystem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://auth0.com/ciam" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Okta / Auth0"&gt;Okta / Auth0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nach der Übernahme von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492807/interview-mit-jameeka-green-aarondie-gefahrenlage-aus-sicht-einer-ciso.html" target="_blank" title="Auth0"&gt;Auth0&lt;/a&gt; will Okta das CIAM-Produkt von Auth0 als eigenständiges Angebot neben den hauseigenen CIAM-Funktionen beibehalten, um Kunden maximale Flexibilität bei der Implementierung zu bieten. Nichtsdestotrotz wird es zu Überschneidungen und Integrationen kommen – Okta hat bereits mehrere Funktionen kombiniert, um die Fähigkeit zu Zusammenarbeit und Innovation zu beschleunigen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auth0 bietet zwar einige Workforce-IAM-Funktionen an, aber diese Plattform ist mit CIAM-Anwendungsfällen groß geworden – entsprechend stark ausgeprägt ist der Fokus auf diesen Bereich. Laut den Analysten von Gartner eignet sich die CIAM-Lösung von Auth0 vor allem dann, wenn Entwickler Access Management für Verbraucher in individuell entwickelte, API-lastige Anwendungen einbauen müssen. Dazu kombiniert die Plattform “großartige UX-Flows und UI-Anpassungsfähigkeiten” mit “umfassenden Entwickler-Tools und vollständiger API-Unterstützung”, heißt es in Gartners Magic Quadrant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das gesamte Okta-CIAM-Portfolio verfügt über eine Reihe von Konnektoren für Business Intelligence, CRM, Marketing-Analytics und -Automatisierung, andere IAM-Plattformen, beliebte SaaS-Anwendungen und Plattformen zur Betrugsbekämpfung. Raum nach oben gibt es bei diesem Produkt, wenn es darum geht, Geräteintelligenz und Verhaltensbiometrie in die nativen Funktionen der Plattform zu integrieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.onelogin.com/solutions/ciam" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="OneLogin"&gt;OneLogin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Identity-as-a-Service (IdaaS)-Anbieter OneLogin gehört in Gartners Magic Quadrant für Access Management zur Spitzengruppe und bietet einige abgespeckte, entwicklerfreundliche CIAM-Funktionen. Die könnten speziell für Unternehmen, die eine erschwingliche Option für den Aufbau einer stärkeren Kundenauthentifizierung suchen, hilfreich sein. Laut Gartner liegt die Stärke von OneLogin auch in den erschwinglichen Preisen, die das Unternehmen für externe Zugriffsmanagement-Anwendungen aufruft.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Lösung selbst zeichnet sich dabei durch seine flexible Erweiterbarkeit mit umfangreicher Entwicklerunterstützung und seine robusten APIs aus. Die Serverless Smart-Hooks-&lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2790525/was-sie-ueber-application-programming-interfaces-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank" title="API"&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;-Funktion soll Entwickler dabei unterstützen, CIAM-Workflows und -Richtlinien anzupassen, um möglichst nahtlose und sichere Benutzererfahrungen während der Anmeldung zu gewährleisten. Entlastung gibt es auch, wenn es um Single-Sign-On geht – auch hier unterstützt das Tool dabei, entsprechende Funktionen in Consumer-Apps einzubauen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Gegensatz zu vielen anderen CIAM-Lösungen in dieser Übersicht, gehören allerdings keine Out-of-the-Box-Funktionen für Consent Management oder geschäftsorientierte Funktionen wie Marketing-Analysen und Automatisierung zum Paket – es handelt sich in erster Linie um eine Authentifizierungs- und Autorisierungslösung.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nach der Übernahme durch One Identity war erwartet worden, dass sich das Portfolio stärker in Richtung Workforce IAM entwickeln wird. Davon ist ein Jahr später allerdings noch nichts zu sehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pingidentity.com/de/platform/solutions/pingone-for-customers.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Ping Identity"&gt;Ping Identity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492443/iam-deal-thoma-bravo-kauft-ping-identity.html" target="_blank" title="Ping Identity"&gt;Ping Identity&lt;/a&gt; ist einer der ersten Enterprise-IAM-Anbieter, der in CIAM-Gewässer abtaucht. Dabei überzeugt er vor allem in Sachen Identitäsnachweise, -orchestrierung und Analytics-Funktionen – auch der Umfang der unterstützten Authentifikatoren sowie die Dokumentation und Sicherheit der API-Konnektoren sind positiv hervorzuheben. Ein “Fraud”-Modul spürt darüber hinaus mit Hilfe von Echtzeit-Verhaltensnavigation, Verhaltensbiometrie, Geräte- und Netzwerkattributen potenzielle, betrügerische Angriffe auf. Auch die Integration mit externen Betrugserkennungs-Plattformen ist möglich. Ping Identity hebt sich von anderen Anbietern zudem dadurch ab, dass es den FIDO-2-Standard nicht nur unterstützt, sondern einen entsprechend zertifizierten Server betreibt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die &lt;a href="https://www.kuppingercole.com/research/lc80466/ciam-platforms" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Analysten von KuppingerCole"&gt;Analysten von KuppingerCole&lt;/a&gt; sehen auch Schwachpunkte, etwa die nur rudimentäre Verwaltung von Berechtigungen für Verbraucher, die in den meisten Fällen zusätzliche Entwicklungs- und Integrationsarbeit erfordern. Auch die noch in der Entwicklung befindlichen Out-of-the-Box-Konnektoren für erweiterte Business Intelligence, Customer Relationship Management und Marketing-Analytics bemängeln die Analysten – bewerten das Ping-Identity-Offering aber dennoch sehr positiv. Laut Gartner gehört Ping Identity zu den “erschwinglicheren Optionen auf dem CIAM-Markt”. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im August 2023 übernahm der Ping-Identity-Mutterkonzern Thoma Bravo &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/thoma-bravo-completes-acquisition-of-forgerock-combines-forgerock-into-ping-identity-301908059.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="den Sicherheitsanbieter Forge Rock"&gt;den Sicherheitsanbieter Forge Rock&lt;/a&gt; – und integrierte dessen Potfolio in Ping Identity. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492789/customer-identity-access-management-die-6-besten-ciam-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-089)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV26-090)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV26-091)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software developers: Prime cyber targets and a rising risk vector for CISOs</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127693/software-developers-prime-cyber-targets-and-a-rising-risk-vector-for-cisos.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threats against corporate software developers are increasing and diversifying, challenging security leaders to develop more agile defenses against this growing attack vector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers are increasingly targeting the tools, access, and trusted channels used by software developers rather than simply exploiting application bugs. The threats blend technical compromise — malicious packages, development pipeline abuse, etc. — with social engineering and AI-driven attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attackers are no longer just trying to break into the network; they are trying to break into the workflow,” says &lt;a href="https://www.immersivelabs.com/author/chris-wood"&gt;Chris Wood&lt;/a&gt;, principal application security SME at cybersecurity firm Immersive. “By compromising the tools developers trust implicitly, like extensions and package registries, they can poison the well before a single line of code is written.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The tokens, API keys, cloud credentials, and CI/CD secrets held by software developers unlock far broader access than a typical office user account, making software engineers a prime target for cybercriminals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They [developers] hold the keys to the kingdom, privileged access to source code and cloud infrastructure, making them a high-value target,” Wood adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security experts quizzed by CSO said the threat against software developers can be broken into several categories, including: malicious extensions, IDE plugins, and tools; supply chain and dependency attacks; credential theft and environment compromise; social engineering; and AI risks in software development workflows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malicious utilities poison the ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darren Meyer, security research advocate at application security firm Checkmarx, sees most attacks targeting developers as “low-effort” and untargeted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, attackers plant tainted open-source packages on &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570173/what-is-typosquatting-a-simple-but-effective-attack-technique.html"&gt;typosquatting&lt;/a&gt; domains to trick developers into installing malicious versions of popular utilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But spray-and-pray efforts are only part of the story. More targeted attacks are also in play, such as the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095578/new-shai-hulud-worm-spreading-through-npm-github.html"&gt;Shai-Hulud worm hack against GitHub and other software development platforms&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://checkmarx.com/zero-post/chalk-and-17-other-npm-packages-compromised-in-supply-chain-attack/"&gt;recent assault against npm package Chalk&lt;/a&gt;, and attempts to compromise the Visual Studio Code plugin ecosystem, Meyer warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meyer’s warning about tainted open-source packages is backed up by recent study by DevSecOps firm Sonatype that identified 1.233 million malicious packages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Known vulnerable components also pose a massive risk. Four years after the vulnerability was patched, versions of Log4j vulnerable to the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574261/log4shell-remains-a-big-threat-and-a-common-cause-for-security-breaches.html"&gt;Log4Shell vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; were downloaded 42 million times last year, according to &lt;a href="https://www.sonatype.com/state-of-the-software-supply-chain/Introduction"&gt;Sonatype’s latest State of the Software Supply Chain&lt;/a&gt; report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credential theft &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; environment compromise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers aren’t just looking for flaws in code — they’re looking for access to software development environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Common security shortcomings, including overprivileged service accounts, long-lived tokens, and misconfigured pipelines, offer a ready means for illicit entry into sensitive software development environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Improperly stored access credentials are low-hanging fruit for even the most amateur of threat actors,” says Crystal Morin, senior cybersecurity strategist at cloud-native security and observability vendor Sysdig.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="malicious-insider-threats"&gt;Malicious insider threats&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers are also looking for ways to infiltrate targeted enterprises by posing as software development contractors or remote hire workers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fake worker schemes, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4033022/how-not-to-hire-a-north-korean-it-spy-3.html"&gt;a popular tactic spearheaded by North Korean threat actors&lt;/a&gt;, rely on using technically skilled individuals with falsified identities who use social engineering trickery to fool victims into hiring them. Once inside, these moles steal data and sensitive secrets that serve as collateral for blackmail scams, among other ruses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’ve also seen threat actors pretend to be maintainers and commit malicious code to open-source projects with the goal of infecting users of popular packages, which was the case with the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2077692/dangerous-xz-utils-backdoor-was-the-result-of-years-long-supply-chain-compromise-effort.html"&gt;XZ Utils backdoor&lt;/a&gt; (CVE-2024-3094),” says Sysdig’s Morin.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="software-supply-chain-risks"&gt;Software supply chain risks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A compromised dependency such as a shared software library can taint the code of any developer that relies on it, leading to a large and growing &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4081492/modern-supply-chain-attacks-and-their-real-world-impact.html"&gt;software supply chain risk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/profile/gavin-millard"&gt;Gavin Millard&lt;/a&gt;, VP of intelligence at exposure management company Tenable, says threats from the software supply chain have supplanted exploits to become the greatest systemic cybersecurity risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Software supply chain risks mean the attack surface has expanded beyond traditional vulnerabilities and stolen credentials to the hijacking of maintainer accounts on platforms such as npm or PyPI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As evidenced by the recent &lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4047739/wave-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks-exposes-thousands-of-enterprise-developer-credentials.html"&gt;S1ngularity and npm maintainer hijacks&lt;/a&gt;, a single poisoned update in a common library can achieve more in minutes than a year spent sending targeted phishing messages or scanning the internet for exposed systems,” Millard tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Abusing the supply chain offers a “force multiplier” for any adversary, he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For a mainstream user, a breach is a data leak, but for a developer, it’s a poisoned well that could infect every application they develop and every user of their products downstream,” Millard explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Concerns about the resilience of supply chains against cyberattacks are growing. The &lt;a href="https://www.weforum.org/publications/global-cybersecurity-outlook-2026/digest/"&gt;World Economic Forum’s latest annual Global Cybersecurity Outlook report&lt;/a&gt; shows that 65% of large enterprises report that third-party and supply chain vulnerabilities are their greatest challenge, a figure that has risen from 54% in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Developers routinely pull code from public registries, install third-party dependencies, grant automation broad permissions and publish artefacts that downstream systems implicitly trust,” says Christopher Jess, senior R&amp;amp;D manager at application security firm Black Duck.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attackers are exploiting that reality by shifting left into the developer toolchain by poisoning open-source packages, typosquatting popular libraries, publishing malicious extensions into IDE marketplaces, and targeting build systems where a single compromised pipeline can affect every environment,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="blended-threat-model"&gt;Blended threat model&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers have also begun blending technical compromise with social engineering to increase the potency of their attacks, Jess notes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A malicious package may be seeded with subtle backdoors, then amplified through convincing outreach with fake maintainer messages, urgent security-fix pull requests, or impersonation of trusted collaborators to accelerate adoption,” Jess explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI is raising the scale and precision of these attacks: phishing and pretexting can be more contextual — matching repo names, commit history, and team roles — and adversaries can generate plausible code changes or documentation that reduce suspicion during review,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-assisted development increases exposure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-assisted development and “vibe coding” are increasing exposure to risk, especially because such code is often generated quickly without adequate testing, documentation, or traceability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/beckland/"&gt;Jamie Beckland&lt;/a&gt;, chief product officer at cybersecurity firm APIContext, warns that as software development teams adopt AI agents and Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers, a new, growing risk is &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4015222/mcp-uses-and-risks.html"&gt;tool sprawl with opaque permissions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“MCP servers can be modified by adding tools designed to exfiltrate data from internal APIs, data stores, or SaaS systems,” Beckland says. “The risk isn’t just the LLM model, it’s the tooling surface area and what those tools can reach.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Monitoring MCP servers for changes in the tool infrastructure, and the data access rights of the server, is critical to verify changes in tools and requests.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.securecodewarrior.com/about-us/pieter-danhieux"&gt;Pieter Danhieux&lt;/a&gt;, CEO and co-founder of cybersecurity education firm Secure Code Warrior, adds that MCPs and AI agents are fertile ground for attackers because it is easy to “purposely introduce an insecure prompt or insert AI-augmented malicious code.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Additionally, we’ve seen threat actors exploit user identity in new ways, namely with the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109123/managing-agentic-ai-risk-lessons-from-the-owasp-top-10.html"&gt;confused deputy vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; where threat actors will fool AI agents into taking unauthorized actions on behalf of the user,” Danhieux says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sonatype’s analysis of 37,000 recommendations shows that GPT-5 hallucinated 27.8% of component versions and even suggested actual malware packages in some cases, a statistic that emphasises the need for human code review.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://baxbench.com/"&gt;BaxBench&lt;/a&gt;, 62% of the solutions generated even by the best large language model (LLMs) are either incorrect or contain a security vulnerability, highlighting that LLMs cannot yet generate deployment-ready code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs need to “stop obsessing over individual vulnerabilities and start mastering their total exposure, including the provenance of the shared libraries automatically pulled in via AI code assistants,” Tenable’s Millard says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="countermeasures"&gt;Countermeasures&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, hardening software development environments requires a blend of technical controls, security education and creating a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;security-aware culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tighter identity verification checks, credential hygiene and least-privilege access to data offer steps to building greater security maturity into software development practices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Well-known solutions to these problems include isolating workspaces in containers, centralizing image and secret management, and enforcing regular audits and procedure logging, all of which can effectively reduce the danger,” says &lt;a href="https://ericpaulsen.io/"&gt;Eric Paulsen&lt;/a&gt;, CTO for EMEA at software development platform provider Coder.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Best practice has always been to pin workflow actions against immutable SHA hashes stored on tamper-proof hardware modules, according to David Sugden, head of engineering at digital transformation consultancy Axiologik.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Similarly, allow lists, secrets scanning, and software composition analysis continue to form DevSecOps baselines that increase protection,” Sugden says. “Gating direct access to external dependencies offers protection against malicious packages and versions, as well as preventing downloads for older, insecure packages.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaeljayburch/"&gt;Michael Burch&lt;/a&gt;, application security advocate at cybersecurity training firm Security Journey, emphasizes the importance of offering software developers continuous, hands-on training.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Developers need realistic exercises that demonstrate impact. Allow them to see how systems fail and empower them to fix issues themselves,” Burch advises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127693/software-developers-prime-cyber-targets-and-a-rising-risk-vector-for-cisos.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV26-092)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIS2: Supply chains as a risk factor</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128381/nis2-supply-chains-as-a-risk-factor.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many companies today invest significant resources to secure their internal IT. Firewalls, monitoring, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829684/how-to-create-an-effective-incident-response-plan.html" target="_blank"&gt;incident response plans&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;awareness programs&lt;/a&gt; are well-established. At the same time, a dangerous illusion is growing: the assumption that risks can be controlled within the boundaries of one’s own system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The reality is quite different. Modern business models are virtually inconceivable without external IT service providers, cloud services, software vendors, and specialized subcontractors. This is precisely where the greatest uncertainties arise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3568787/eus-nis2-directive-for-cybersecurity-resilience-enters-full-enforcement.html"&gt;NIS2&lt;/a&gt; addresses this development and clarifies that cybersecurity doesn’t end at the company’s own firewall. The guideline compels companies to reassess their supply chains not only technically, but also strategically. It makes external dependencies an integral part of the security architecture and thus a management responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nis2-shifts-the-focus-of-systems-to-dependencies"&gt;NIS2 shifts the focus of systems to dependencies.&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At its core, NIS2 follows a clear approach: Risks should be addressed where they originate. Statistics and incident analyses have shown for years that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4051668/71-of-cisos-hit-with-third-party-security-incident-this-year.html"&gt;attacks are increasingly carried out via third parties&lt;/a&gt;. Software updates, maintenance access, or outsourced services serve as entry points.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 addresses this by explicitly including supply chains in its scope. Companies are obligated to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119475/13-cyber-questions-to-better-vet-it-vendors-and-reduce-third-party-risk.html"&gt;assess risks related to their direct service providers as well as downstream subcontractors&lt;/a&gt;. The decisive factor is no longer whether an incident originates internally or externally, but rather its impact on critical services.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This marks a departure from a purely technical understanding of security in the regulatory framework. It demands a structured management of dependencies that makes risks visible and manageable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-supply-chains-are-particularly-vulnerable"&gt;Why supply chains are particularly vulnerable&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The supply chain is an attractive target for attackers for several reasons. External partners often have privileged access, work with sensitive data, or are deeply integrated into operational processes. At the same time, they are often not subject to the same security standards as large organizations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, there is a structural lack of transparency. Companies often don’t know which other service providers their partners use or how access is technically implemented. This lack of visibility leads to a fragmented security landscape in which risks are known but remain unquantifiable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 addresses this issue directly and requires transparent processes for identifying, assessing, and monitoring these risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-break-with-traditional-compliance"&gt;The break with traditional compliance&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many organizations are accustomed to formally fulfilling regulatory requirements. Questionnaires are sent out, certificates are filed, checklists are ticked off. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4002765/third-party-risk-management-is-broken-but-not-beyond-repair.html"&gt;This approach generates documentation, but not security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 makes it clear that formal compliance is not enough. The directive requires the effective implementation of security measures and verifiable monitoring of their effectiveness. This also applies to, and especially applies to, external partners.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A security concept that relies solely on self-reported information no longer meets the requirements. A realistic picture of the actual security maturity along the supply chain is needed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-nis2-specifically-expects-from-companies"&gt;What NIS2 specifically expects from companies&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 does not specify detailed technical requirements but defines clear objectives. Companies must identify, prioritize, and appropriately manage risks. For supply chains, this entails several key tasks:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, dependencies must be systematically identified. Which service providers are essential for operations? What data do they process? What access rights do they have?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Secondly, appropriate security requirements must be defined. These must be commensurate with the risk and contractually stipulated.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Third, NIS2 requires continuous monitoring. Risks change. Business models, threat landscapes, and technical architectures evolve. Security assessments must therefore not be a one-off project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-role-of-the-ciso-under-nis2"&gt;The role of the CISO under NIS2&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, NIS2 represents a significant expansion of their responsibilities. Technical excellence alone is no longer sufficient. Communication skills, risk assessment, and the ability to enforce security requirements across the organization are now essential.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The CISO becomes the intermediary between technology, management, procurement, and legal. They must explain why certain requirements are necessary, what risks exist, and what the consequences of inaction might be. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3845430/nis2-the-time-for-compliance-has-come-but-the-race-for-cios-is-not-over.html"&gt;NIS2 strengthens this role&lt;/a&gt; by defining clear responsibilities and anchoring the importance of cybersecurity at the board level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-many-supply-chain-assessments-go-wrong"&gt;Why many supply chain assessments go wrong&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In practice, supply chain assessments often fail for the following three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of prioritization:&lt;/strong&gt; Companies try to treat all partners equally and lose focus on the truly critical dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of enforceability:&lt;/strong&gt; Safety requirements are formulated but not checked or consistently enforced in case of deviations.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizational silos:&lt;/strong&gt; Purchasing, IT, and legal departments operate separately. As a result, security risks are viewed in a fragmented way and not managed holistically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 makes it clear that these approaches are no longer sufficient. An integrated risk management system is required.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="control-mechanisms-with-substance"&gt;Control mechanisms with substance&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effective control &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4108294/implementing-nis2-without-ending-up-in-a-paper-war.html"&gt;does not mean maximum bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt;. The quality of the measures is crucial. For critical partners, this could include regular technical assessments, structured audits, or clearly defined escalation processes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is important that companies retain the ability to assess risks independently and do not completely outsource them to third parties. NIS2 requires taking responsibility, not delegating it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Control mechanisms must also be scalable. Not every partner requires the same level of effort. The potential impact of a security incident is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="supply-chains-as-a-strategic-resilience-factor"&gt;Supply chains as a strategic resilience factor&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies that view NIS2 as a purely compliance-related task are missing out on potential. A realistic assessment of supply chains not only strengthens their regulatory position but also increases operational stability. Transparent dependencies, clear security requirements, and effective control processes reduce the risk of disruption and improve responsiveness in emergencies. Supply chains are thus transformed from a weak point into a strategic resource.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion-nis2-forces-honesty"&gt;Conclusion: NIS2 forces honesty&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 confronts companies with an uncomfortable truth: Cybersecurity doesn’t end at the boundaries of their own systems. Those who outsource critical processes remain responsible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The directive calls for an honest assessment of dependencies, risks, and the ability to control them. For CISOs, this presents both a challenge and an opportunity. Supply chains are no longer a side issue under NIS2. They are the touchstone for effective cybersecurity and sustainable resilience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128381/nis2-supply-chains-as-a-risk-factor.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner-Prognose: Die sechs wichtigsten Cybersicherheits-Trends für 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129302/gartner-prognose-die-sechs-wichtigsten-cybersicherheits-trends-fur-2026.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Security-Trends 2026" class="wp-image-4129312" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/shutterstock_2708625081.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Lesen Sie, mit welchen Cybersecurity-Trends sich Unternehmen in diesem Jahr beschäftigen sollten.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Who is Danny – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch im Jahr 2026 bleibt die Cybersicherheitslage angespannt. Doch was sind die wichtigsten Themen, Risiken und Chancen, mit denen sich Security-Entscheider aktuell befassen sollten?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Marktforschungsunternehmen Gartner hat dazu folgende sechs Trends ermittelt:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;Trend 1: Agentic AI erfordert Cybersicherheitsüberwachung&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4058629/agentic-ai-der-neue-horror-fur-sicherheitsentscheider.html" target="_blank"&gt;KI-Agenten&lt;/a&gt; werden zunehmend von Mitarbeitern und Entwicklern genutzt, wodurch neue Angriffsflächen entstehen. No-Code-/Low-Code-Plattformen und Vibe-Coding verstärken diesen Trend noch und führen zu einer unkontrollierten Verbreitung von Agentic AI, unsicherem Code und potenziellen Verstößen gegen gesetzliche Vorschriften.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Während KI-Agenten und Automatisierungs-Tools für Unternehmen immer zugänglicher und praktischer werden, bleibt eine strenge Governance unerlässlich“, betont Alex Michaels, Analyst bei Gartner. „Führungskräfte im Bereich Cybersicherheit müssen sowohl genehmigte als auch nicht genehmigte KI-Agenten identifizieren. Für beide Varianten sollten sie strenge Kontrollen durchsetzen und Playbooks für die Reaktion auf Vorfälle entwickeln, um potenzielle Risiken zu bewältigen.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;Trend 2: Globale regulatorische Volatilität treibt Bemühungen um Cyberresilienz voran&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veränderte geopolitische Landschaften und sich weiterentwickelnde globale Vorschriften haben Cybersicherheit zu einem kritischen Geschäftsrisiko mit direkten Auswirkungen auf die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4000782/cyber-resilience-in-zeiten-geopolitischer-unsicherheit.html" target="_blank"&gt;Resilienz&lt;/a&gt; von Organisationen gemacht. Da Regulierungsbehörden Vorstände und Führungskräfte zunehmend für Compliance-Verstöße haftbar machen, kann Untätigkeit zu erheblichen Strafen, Geschäftsverlusten und irreversiblen Reputationsschäden führen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner empfiehlt Führungskräften im Bereich Cybersicherheit, die Zusammenarbeit zwischen Legal-, Business- und Beschaffungsteams zu formalisieren, um eine klare Verantwortlichkeit für Cyberrisiken zu schaffen. Die Anpassung von Kontrollrahmen an anerkannte Standards und die Berücksichtigung von Datenhoheitsfragen tragen dazu bei, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494023/cybersicherheitsvorschriften-so-erfullen-sie-ihre-compliance-anforderungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Compliance&lt;/a&gt;-Lücken zu schließen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;Trend 3: PostQuantum-Computing wird zum Aktionsplan&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner prognostiziert, dass Fortschritte im Bereich des Quantencomputing die asymmetrische Kryptografie, auf die Unternehmen zur Sicherung ihrer Daten und Systeme setzen, bis 2030 unsicher machen werden. Um potenzielle Datenverstöße, rechtliche &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3817541/cyberattacken-nicht-alle-manager-wissen-von-ihrer-verantwortung.html" target="_blank"&gt;Haftungsrisiken&lt;/a&gt; und finanzielle Verluste durch Angriffe nach dem Prinzip „jetzt sammeln, später entschlüsseln“ zu vermeiden, müssen jetzt Alternativen zur Post-Quantum-Kryptografie eingeführt werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3846875/quantenschlussel-aus-der-sicht-des-ciso.html"&gt;Post-Quanten-Kryptografie&lt;/a&gt; verändert die Cybersicherheitsstrategien. Sie veranlasst Unternehmen dazu, traditionelle Verschlüsselungsmethoden zu identifizieren, zu verwalten und zu ersetzen und gleichzeitig der kryptografischen Agilität Vorrang einzuräumen“, so Michaels. „Indem man jetzt schon in diese Fähigkeiten investiert und die Migration vorantreibt , werden Assets gesichert, wenn Quantenbedrohungen Realität werden.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;Trend 4: Identitäts- und Zugriffsmanagement passt sich KI-Agenten an&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Aufstieg von KI-Agenten stellt traditionelle Identitäts- und Zugriffsmanagementstrategien (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/identity-and-access-management/" target="_blank"&gt;IAM&lt;/a&gt;) vor neue Herausforderungen, insbesondere in den Bereichen Identitätsregistrierung und -verwaltung, Automatisierung von Anmeldedaten und richtliniengesteuerte Autorisierung für maschinelle Akteure. Werden diese Probleme nicht angegangen, steigt das Risiko von Cybersicherheitsvorfällen im Zusammenhang mit Zugriffen, da autonome Agenten immer mehr Verbreitung finden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner rät zu einem gezielten, risikobasierten Ansatz, bei dem dort investiert wird, wo die Lücken und Risiken am größten sind, und Automatisierung genutzt wird. Dies ist unerlässlich, um Innovationen zu ermöglichen, die Einhaltung von Vorschriften zu gewährleisten und kritische Ressourcen in KI-zentrierten Umgebungen zu schützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;Trend 5: KI-gesteuerte SOC-Lösungen destabilisieren betriebliche Normen&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Angetrieben durch Kostensparmaßnahmen und das wachsende Interesse an KI führt das Aufkommen von KI-gestützten Security Operations Centern (SOCs) zu einer neuen Komplexität. Dies trägt zu Personalengpässen, erhöhten Anforderungen an die Qualifizierung und sich wandelnden Kostenüberlegungen für KI-Tools bei, auch wenn diese Technologien die Arbeitsabläufe bei der Alarmierung und Untersuchung verbessern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Um das volle Potenzial von KI in Sicherheitsabläufen auszuschöpfen, müssen Cybersicherheitsverantwortliche Menschen ebenso priorisieren wie Technologie“, erklärt der Gartner-Analyst. „Die Stärkung der Fähigkeiten der Belegschaft, die Implementierung von Human-in-the-Loop-Frameworks in KI-gestützte Prozesse und die Ausrichtung auf klare strategische Ziele werden entscheidend sein, um die Widerstandsfähigkeit bei der Weiterentwicklung von SOCs aufrechtzuerhalten.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;Trend 6: GenAI bricht mit traditionellen Strategien zur Sensibilisierung für Cybersicherheit&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut Gartner reichen bestehende Maßnahmen zur Sensibilisierung für Cybersicherheit nicht aus, um Cyberrisiken zu reduzieren, da die Einführung von &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/generative-ai/" target="_blank"&gt;GenAI&lt;/a&gt; immer schneller voranschreitet. Bei einer Umfrage, die das Analystenhaus zwischen Mai und November 2025 unter 175 Mitarbeitern durchführte, gaben mehr als 57 Prozent an, persönliche GenAI-Accounts für berufliche Zwecke zu nutzen. 33 Prozent der Befragten gaben zu, sensible Informationen für nicht genehmigte Tools zu verwenden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner plädiert dafür, von allgemeinen Awareness-Trainings zu adaptiven Verhaltens- und Schulungsprogrammen überzugehen, die KI-spezifische Aufgaben umfassen. „Durch die Stärkung der Governance, die Verankerung sicherer Praktiken und die Festlegung von Richtlinien für die autorisierte Nutzung lassen sich Datenschutzverletzungen und der Verlust geistigen Eigentums reduzieren“, so die Analysten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129302/gartner-prognose-die-sechs-wichtigsten-cybersicherheits-trends-fur-2026.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schrödinger’s cat and the enterprise security paradox</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128910/schrodingers-cat-and-the-enterprise-security-paradox.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most security leaders quietly live with a paradox they rarely name out loud. Until you truly look inside the box of your environment, your organization is both secure &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; compromised. The dashboards might be green and the audit reports reassuring, but the uncomfortable reality is that you do not know your actual state until you observe it directly and often.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="meeting-the-cat-a-paradox-with-teeth"&gt;Meeting the cat — a paradox with teeth&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many readers will have heard of &lt;a href="https://www.newscientist.com/definition/schrodingers-cat/"&gt;Schrödinger’s cat&lt;/a&gt; in passing, but the details blur over time, so it is worth revisiting what the analogy means before applying it to security. It is a thought experiment in quantum physics that illustrates how strange the rules of the microscopic world seem when applied to everyday objects, such as a cat in a box.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the classic setup, a cat is placed in a sealed box with three components: a tiny radioactive source, a detector that can sense whether an atom decays and a vial of poison that will be released if the detector triggers. As long as the box stays closed, quantum mechanics describes the radioactive atom as being in the superposition of both decayed and not decayed at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From the outside, the cat appears to be both alive and dead until someone opens the box and checks. The instant an observer looks, the uncertainty collapses into a single outcome: alive or dead, but not both. Schrödinger proposed this not because he believed in half-dead cats, but to criticize simplistic interpretations of quantum theory and force people to confront how odd it is to treat unobserved systems as if they occupy multiple states at once.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That structure, a system that exists in multiple possible states until observed, then collapses into a single real state, is exactly what makes Schrodinger’s cat such a powerful way to talk about modern cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-two-companies-every-leader-runs"&gt;The two companies every leader runs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When I first moved into security consulting, I realized many leaders were effectively running two different companies at once: one that looked safe in audits, dashboards and policy documents and another that attackers were probing and learning to exploit beneath the surface. In board papers, the organization appeared controlled, compliant and orderly in logs and incident reviews, but in practice, it looked messy, improvised and full of blind spots.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over time, I began to describe these two states as the “paper company” and the “real company.” The paper company is defined by controls. It is the version of the organization that appears in frameworks, policies, architecture diagrams and maturity assessments, with named owners, mapped processes and reassuring traffic-light reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The real company is defined by behavior. It is the version that appears in telemetry, threat intelligence, red team findings and post-incident reviews. It is shaped by how people actually work, by shortcuts embedded in processes, by legacy systems nobody wants to touch and by integrations that were never fully documented.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The paradox is that leadership conversations usually assume only the paper company exists. When a board asks, “Are we secure?”, the answer typically references policies, certifications and tool coverage, all attributes of the paper company, while attackers interact only with the real one. Until leaders can see the real company clearly and regularly, they are effectively managing a cat-in-a-box: they must act as if they are both secure and compromised, without knowing which state is currently true.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-as-an-observation-problem-not-just-a-control-problem"&gt;Security as an observation problem, not just a control problem…&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most security strategies still treat protection primarily as a control problem: deploy more controls, map more requirements and close more findings. Controls matter and as an adviser, it would be irresponsible to downplay them. Yet major incidents keep reminding us that controls can be in place on paper while attackers move laterally through gaps in visibility, misconfigurations and exceptions that nobody has examined closely for months.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thinking in Schrodinger’s terms reframes this security issue as also and increasingly an observation problem. In physics, measurement collapses a quantum system from many possible states into one observed reality. In security, detection plays the same role. Until there is a concrete signal, such as an alert, a log correlation, an anomaly investigation or a third-party notification, you cannot categorically state whether an attacker is present. You can discuss probabilities and expectations, but not current facts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Seen through that lens, three truths emerge:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;1. The &lt;a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10065758/"&gt;absence of evidence&lt;/a&gt; (alerts) is not evidence of absence (safety)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It may simply mean your tools cannot see where the attacker is or that signals are not being correlated and interpreted effectively. A quiet SIEM can indicate resilience or complete blindness; without deeper observation, you do not know which.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.computerweekly.com/opinion/Security-Think-Tank-Prevention-and-detection-are-key-to-limit-dwell-time"&gt;Dwell time&lt;/a&gt; is a measure of unobserved reality&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every day an attacker remains undetected is a day when leadership operates under a false assumption about the system state. The longer the detection gap, the longer your organization lives in a “secure and compromised” superposition.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-external-discovery-is-a-symptom-of-observation-failure"&gt;3. External discovery is a symptom of observation failure&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When regulators, customers or partners are the first to tell you something is wrong, it is a strong signal that the box has been opened only from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once you see security as an observation problem, the question “Are we secure?” starts to feel like the wrong question. A better set of questions sounds more like:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How quickly would we know if a high-value identity or system were compromised?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Which parts of our environment are effectively unobserved, from a telemetry or logging perspective?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="advising-leaders-through-the-paradox"&gt;Advising leaders through the paradox&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a consultant, the goal isn’t to embarrass organizations for their uncertainty but to normalize and systematically reduce it. Complex environments have blind spots and risks arise from ignoring them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The work involves three shifts in thinking and action:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the questions in the boardroom. Instead of asking “Are we secure?”, ask “Where do we have strong evidence and where are we guessing?” This honesty aligns decisions with reality and clarifies investment needs.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Measure certainty, not just controls. Include metrics such as telemetry coverage, detection speed and red team findings to assess how well the organization uncovers threats. &lt;a href="8.%09https:/www.computerweekly.com/news/366626729/Dutch-study-uncovers-cognitive-biases-undermining-cyber-security-board-decisions"&gt;Cognitive biases&lt;/a&gt; among practitioners exacerbate these gaps.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Reward the surfacing of ambiguity rather than punishing uncertainty and encourage teams to admit gaps and improve observation, fostering trust over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="bringing-the-paradox-down-to-earth"&gt;Bringing the paradox down to earth&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Collapsing the paradox in a real enterprise is not about finding a single magic control that proves you are safe; it is about building habits of observation that continually narrow the gap between the paper company and the real one. In practical terms, a few patterns make an outsized difference. What does the transition from superposition to observation entail within an enterprise environment? From a consultant’s perspective, certain patterns significantly influence the process:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treat &lt;a href="https://hunt.io/glossary/threat-hunting-program"&gt;threat hunting&lt;/a&gt; as routine, not heroic.&lt;/strong&gt; Many organizations treat hunts as occasional special projects, often driven by a specific concern or regulatory pressure. A more effective model is to operationalize them as a standing function, a way to continuously test assumptions about where attackers could hide and to validate that existing detections still work as expected.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design telemetry with questions in mind.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of starting with “what logs can we capture easily?”, start with “what questions would we want to answer after an incident and what would we want to observe in real time?”. Work backward from those questions to determine the required telemetry and analytics. That keeps the focus on understanding behavior, not just filling storage.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrate external observation into your picture of reality.&lt;/strong&gt; Bug bounties, penetration tests, independent assessments and sector information-sharing are all ways to let others open the box from different angles. The key is to fold those observations back into your own narrative, rather than treating them as disconnected exercises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over time, these practices narrow the gap between the paper company and the real company. Leaders still need policies, controls and reports, but those artefacts begin to reflect observed behavior much more closely than aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leading-in-a-world-of-half-open-boxes"&gt;Leading in a world of half-open boxes&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The most honest statement a security leader can make is not “we are secure” but “here is what we know, here is what we do not know yet and here is how quickly we are closing that gap.” That is essentially a commitment to continuous observation. It also reframes security from a static state to a dynamic practice, which aligns with how modern digital businesses operate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Schrödinger’s cat reminds us that unobserved systems can exist in multiple states simultaneously. In cybersecurity, this means a quiet environment can be both resilient and deeply compromised until proven otherwise. The job of security leaders and their advisers is not to pretend the paradox does not exist, but to build the technical, organizational and cultural capabilities that enable the organization to open the box early and often and to be ready to act on whatever is found when it is.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128910/schrodingers-cat-and-the-enterprise-security-paradox.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never settle: How CISOs can go beyond compliance standards to better protect their organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128920/never-settle-how-cisos-can-go-beyond-compliance-standards-to-better-protect-their-organizations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The start of a new year means a fresh start for everyone, including cybersecurity teams. With budgets and plans now finalized, it’s time for CISOs and their teams to execute their strategies. But that doesn’t mean that innovation stops when the plan is finalized.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2026, CISOs should focus on going beyond cybersecurity compliance standards to keep their organizations resilient to emerging threats. Historically, these standards, such as HIPAA, SOC2, ISO 27001 and others, have set the baseline for security procedures and controls. Done correctly, these can be valuable tools for CISOs to justify investments. But they’re a double-edged sword: Companies that rely solely on compliance can miss important and emerging risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here’s how CISOs can leave the compliance checklist mentality in 2025, where it belongs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="compliance-standards-necessary-not-sufficient"&gt;Compliance standards: Necessary, not sufficient&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Compliance standards have historically served as the baseline for most cybersecurity programs and are often well-intentioned. PCI-DSS emerged from a consortium of payment processors who had implemented duplicative and inconsistent controls, complicating network integration and increasing costs. HIPAA’s privacy and security rules evolved in response to concerns over privacy and the digitization of electronic medical records.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These standards give a baseline of controls to keep them protected. However, these standards typically cover well-known threats and may not keep pace with current architectures or threats. They can also be subject to different interpretations. For example, most compliance standards have vague requirements for active monitoring of a company’s vendors. A CISO running a compliant program may only review a vendor once a year or after significant system changes. Compliance standards haven’t caught up to the best practice of continuously monitoring vendors to stay on top of third-party risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This highlights one of the most unfortunate incentives any CISO who manages a compliance program knows: It is often easier to set a less stringent standard and exceed it than to set a better target and risk missing it. The latter leads to audit findings and sometimes political ill will. But what does the former lead to?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It leads to complacency and systemic under-resourcing of security programs. Right or wrong, &lt;a href="https://www.hitchpartners.com/ciso-security-leadership-survey-results-25"&gt;CISOs justify 78% of their budget needs using compliance&lt;/a&gt;, according to a 2025 Hitch Partners survey. This number is the backbone, and may be even higher in highly regulated industries with more prescriptive compliance standards. But if this approximate 80% is interpreted as 100% of your program’s needs, you will fall short of what’s required to run a forward-looking security program.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where you, as a CISO, are most crucial to your security team’s mission. And luckily, many compliance standards give you some levers you can use to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-new-north-star-for-cisos-accounting-for-emerging-risk"&gt;The new North Star for CISOs: Accounting for emerging risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve established that it’s no longer good enough to overfit into a compliance standard, but you can still use compliance to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most compliance programs mandate an information security risk assessment and, at a larger company, you may already have a dedicated enterprise risk management function. As a CISO, you influence the scope of that information security risk assessment, the methodology and, perhaps most importantly, the time horizon. Three key strategies you should consider:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="extend-the-time-horizon"&gt;Extend the time horizon&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you want to be considering scenarios as far as 3–5 years down the road so you can get ahead of them. We’re already seeing evolving threats from AI, more breaches stemming from vulnerable third-party vendors and the risk of harvest-now-decrypt-later threats from quantum computing within the decade. None of the controls for these risk scenarios can be turned on overnight, so preparing for them and other emerging risks is paramount.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="use-risk-or-scenario-based-methodologies-wherever-possible"&gt;Use risk- or scenario-based methodologies wherever possible&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What is the situation you are attempting to prevent? Compliance based on assets or controls is where the checkbox label comes from. This may be important at the outset of a security program to ensure you have proper coverage, but you will confront the previously mentioned 80% mentality. \&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With scenarios, you start with a broader view of the risk and map associated controls. You can also define custom risk scenarios, which allow you to formally introduce requirements beyond existing compliance routines. They can also be more specific than you may find in control statements or standard scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="quantify-the-loss"&gt;Quantify the loss&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the most common shortfalls of compliance-driven risk assessments is simplistic math around likelihood and impact. Many of the emergent risks mentioned above have a lower likelihood but an extremely high impact and even a fair amount of uncertainty around timeframes. Using this simplistic math, these tail risks do not often bubble up organically; instead, they have to be pulled up from the batch of lower frequency-x-impact scoring. Defining that impact in dollars and cents cuts through the noise. $250k versus $18M might both rate a “5” for impact in the traditional sense, but one is clearly more impactful than the other.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Practically, these can be difficult if your program is newer and they are highly dependent on both your security organization’s stature and risk culture. Just remember that even if you succeed in starting the discussion on these items, you are building awareness and setting the stage for future investments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-get-buy-in-from-the-board"&gt;How to get buy-in from the board&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The financial leaders who approve a CISO’s cybersecurity plan live in the area of risk. Every day, they make calculated bets on what will pay off for the business. The board will want to know what compliance standards you aren’t accounting for and the likelihood and impact in financial terms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs can assure them that a clean audit that checks all of the compliance boxes may be safe enough to show prospective clients, but resting there sets a standard of “good enough that doesn’t account for risks that may not be a part of the compliance standard for 2–3 more years. While these might sound like extras to the board, quantifying risk, comparing to competitors and calculating cost-optimal controls are key. For example, an awareness campaign, approval process or training module might be cheaper than adding additional software or point solutions around generative AI security and bring risk down to an acceptable level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your budget has already been approved without these focus areas in mind, now is the time to start weaving a risk-first approach into discussions with your board. You should be talking about this year-round, not only during budget season when it’s time to present your plan. It will position security as a way to protect revenue, improve capital efficiency, preserve treasury integrity and optimize costs, rather than a cost center.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The beginning of the year is a great time for CISOs to start shifting their organization’s mindset on cybersecurity risk. Take a risk-first approach that goes beyond compliance standards and focuses on becoming resilient to emerging threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128920/never-settle-how-cisos-can-go-beyond-compliance-standards-to-better-protect-their-organizations.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DKnife targets network gateways in long running AitM campaign</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129383/dknife-targets-network-gateways-in-long-running-aitm-campaign.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A previously undocumented China-linked adversary-in-the-middle (AitM) framework known as “DKnife” has been identified operating at network gateways, where it intercepts and manipulates in-transit traffic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Cisco Talos’ findings, the framework has been active since at least 2019 and remains operational as of early 2026. Rather than targeting endpoints directly, DKnife is deployed at the network edge, giving operators visibility into and control over the traffic passing through compromised devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Talos researchers described it as a modular Linux-based system capable of deep packet inspection, credential interception, and malicious content injection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“DKnife’s attacks target a wide range of devices, including PCs, mobile devices, and Internet of Things devices,” they said in a blog post. “It delivers and interacts with &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572061/shadowpad-has-become-the-rat-of-choice-for-several-state-sponsored-chinese-apts.html"&gt;ShadowPad&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/24/l/earth-minotaur.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DarkNimbus&lt;/a&gt; backdoors by hijacking binary downloads and Android application updates.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Traffic hijacking and malware delivery&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers found DKnife having seven Linux ELF components that work together to monitor and manipulate network traffic in real time. Once deployed on a gateway or similar edge device, the framework can inspect unencrypted and decrypted traffic flows to selectively modify responses before they reach their intended destination.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The seven implants in DKnife serve the purpose of DPI engine, data reporting, reverse proxy for AitM attack, malicious APK download, framework update, traffic forwarding, and building a P2P communication channel with the remote C2,” the researchers &lt;a href="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/knife-cutting-the-edge/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The framework was observed being used to redirect legitimate software update requests to attacker-controlled servers, enabling the delivery of secondary payloads posing as trusted updates. This allowed attackers to compromise downstream systems without needing direct access to the endpoints themselves, the researchers noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond update hijacking, the framework supports &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3480542/eight-year-old-sitting-ducks-dns-weakness-exploited-to-hijack-web-domains-with-impunity.html"&gt;DNS&lt;/a&gt; manipulation, binary replacement, and selective traffic forwarding, giving attackers control over how specific requests are handled.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Indicators point to China-Nexus development and targeting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several aspects of DKnife’s design and operation suggested ties to China-aligned threat actors. Talos identified configuration data and code comments written in Simplified Chinese, as well as handling logic tailored for Chinese-language email providers and mobile applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The framework was also found to enable credential collection from services used within China, indicating specific targeting. Talos confirmed linking DKnife’s operations to the delivery of malware families previously associated with China-nexus activity, further reinforcing attribution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Based on the language used in the code, configuration files, and the ShadowPad malware delivered in the campaign, we assess with high confidence that China-nexus threat actors operate this tool,” the researchers said without naming any specific threat group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Shared lineage and detection sabotage&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Talos investigation also revealed technical overlaps between DKnife and earlier AitM frameworks used in past campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We discovered a link between DKnife and a campaign delivering WizardNet, a modular backdoor known to be delivered by a different AiTM framework, Spellbinder, suggesting a shared development or operational lineage,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Talos said DKnife includes a traffic inspection module that actively interferes with antivirus and PC-management communications. The module identifies 360 Total Security traffic by inspecting specific HTTP headers, such as DPUname and x-360-ver, and by matching known service domains. When a match is detected, the framework disrupts the connection using crafted TCP reset packets. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Similar behavior targeting Tencent services and other PC management endpoints was also observed, indicating deliberate efforts to weaken security tooling. To strengthen detection, Talos shared a list of indicators of compromise (&lt;a href="https://github.com/Cisco-Talos/IOCs/blob/main/2026/02/knife-cutting-the-edge.txt"&gt;IoCs&lt;/a&gt;), including file hashes, network artifacts, and command and control (c2) infrastructure associated with DKnife. Additionally, the disclosure shared a set of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/527902/malware-cybercrime-clamav-promises-free-antivirus-app-for-businesses.html"&gt;ClamAV&lt;/a&gt; signatures for detecting and blocking the threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129383/dknife-targets-network-gateways-in-long-running-aitm-campaign.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenClaw integrates VirusTotal malware scanning as security firms flag enterprise risks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129393/openclaw-integrates-virustotal-malware-scanning-as-security-firms-flag-enterprise-risks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw, the viral open-source AI agent that security firms warn is “insecure by default,” has integrated VirusTotal’s malware scanning into its ClawHub skills marketplace following weeks in which security researchers documented malicious extensions and widespread unauthorized deployments in enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The integration automatically scans all published skills before making them available for download, according to the &lt;a href="https://openclaw.ai/blog/virustotal-partnership" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; by OpenClaw founder Peter Steinberger, security advisor Jamieson O’Reilly, and VirusTotal’s Bernardo Quintero. Skills receiving a “benign” verdict are automatically approved, while those marked suspicious receive warnings, and malicious skills are immediately blocked, with daily re-scanning of all active skills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As the OpenClaw ecosystem grows, so does the attack surface,” the announcement stated. “We’ve already seen documented cases of malicious actors attempting to exploit AI agent platforms. We’re not waiting for this to become a bigger problem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sunil Varkey, advisor at Beagle Security, called the integration “a sensible and welcome step” that filters out known malware. “Most attacks still rely on reusing known malware rather than investing in costly zero-day development, so filtering out known bad artifacts meaningfully raises the bar and improves marketplace hygiene,” Varkey said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-the-scanning-works"&gt;How the scanning works&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The system relies on VirusTotal’s &lt;a href="https://blog.virustotal.com/2023/04/introducing-virustotal-code-insight.html"&gt;Code Insight&lt;/a&gt;, powered by Google’s Gemini, which analyzes complete skill packages for malicious behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It doesn’t just look at what the skill claims to do—it summarizes what the code actually does from a security perspective: whether it downloads and executes external code, accesses sensitive data, performs network operations, or embeds instructions that could coerce the agent into unsafe behavior,” OpenClaw said  in the announcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When developers publish skills to ClawHub, the platform creates a SHA-256 hash and checks it against VirusTotal’s database, uploading the complete bundle for Code Insight analysis if not found. The integration uses the same technology VirusTotal provides to &lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/blog/virustotal"&gt;Hugging Face’s&lt;/a&gt; AI model repository, according to the announcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-prompted-the-response"&gt;What prompted the response&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The scanning initiative follows a series of security incidents documented by multiple firms over the past two weeks. &lt;a href="https://www.koi.ai/blog/clawhavoc-341-malicious-clawedbot-skills-found-by-the-bot-they-were-targeting" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Koi Security’s February 1 audit&lt;/a&gt; of all 2,857 ClawHub skills discovered 341 malicious ones in a campaign dubbed “ClawHavoc.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The professional-looking skills for cryptocurrency tools and YouTube utilities contained fake prerequisites that installed keyloggers and the Atomic macOS Stealer malware capable of harvesting cryptocurrency wallets, browser data, and system credentials. A Cornell University &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.10338"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; found that 26% of packages contained vulnerabilities and described OpenClaw as “an absolute nightmare” from a security standpoint. Token Security &lt;a href="https://www.token.security/blog/the-clawdbot-enterprise-ai-risk-one-in-five-have-it-installed" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;found 22% of its enterprise customers&lt;/a&gt; have employees running the agent without IT approval.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security vendor Noma reported that 53% of its enterprise customers gave OpenClaw privileged access over a single weekend, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/5808845"&gt;January 30 Gartner analysis&lt;/a&gt;. Gartner characterized OpenClaw as “a powerful demonstration of autonomous AI for enterprise productivity, but it is an unacceptable cybersecurity liability” and recommended enterprises “block OpenClaw downloads and traffic immediately,” describing shadow deployments as creating “single points of failure, as compromised hosts expose API keys, OAuth tokens, and sensitive conversations to attackers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenClaw &gt;&lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4125939/by-whatever-name-moltbolt-clawd-openclaw-this-uber-ai-assistant-is-a-security-nightmare.html" target="_blank"&gt;surpassed 150,000 GitHub stars&lt;/a&gt; in late January, gainin&lt;/span&gt;g viral popularity on social media. The platform, launched in November 2025 and rebranded twice due to trademark disputes, allows community-developed “skills” that run with full access to the agent’s tools and data—the architecture that ClawHavoc exploited.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="limitations-of-malware-scanning"&gt;Limitations of malware scanning&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the VirusTotal integration addresses known malware in the skills marketplace, OpenClaw acknowledged significant limitations in the announcement. “Let’s be clear: this is not a silver bullet,” the announcement stated. “A skill that uses natural language to instruct an agent to do something malicious won’t trigger a virus signature. A carefully crafted prompt injection payload won’t show up in a threat database.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The primary risk with AI agents involves prompt injection, where malicious instructions embedded in emails or documents can hijack agent behavior without exploiting traditional software vulnerabilities, according to CrowdStrike’s analysis. The Moltbook social network for OpenClaw agents illustrated these risks when it &lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/exposed-moltbook-database-reveals-millions-of-api-keys" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;exposed 1.5 million API tokens and 35,000 email addresses&lt;/a&gt; after a database misconfiguration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Varkey cautioned that “threats like prompt injection, logic abuse, and misuse of legitimate tools sit outside the reach of malware scanning,” adding that the integration should be “seen as the foundation for broader governance and technical controls, not the finish line.” The VirusTotal integration is the first step in what Steinberger called a “broader security initiative,” with plans to publish a threat model, security roadmap, and audit results at trust.openclaw.ai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129393/openclaw-integrates-virustotal-malware-scanning-as-security-firms-flag-enterprise-risks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-093)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-094)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-095)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-096)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-097)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-098)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-099)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-100)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-101)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–102)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-103)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-104)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains security advisory (AV26-105)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Virtual Event] Shields Up: Key Technologies Reshaping Cybersecurity Defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 49338.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
