<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:18:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes security advisory (AV26-078)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/kubernetes-security-advisory-av26-078</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-079)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-079</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-080)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-080</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-081)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-081</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-082)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-082</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-083)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-083</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django security advisory (AV26-084)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/django-security-advisory-av26-084</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-085)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-085</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV26-086)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av26-086</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-087)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-087</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV26-088)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av26-088</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>69% of CISOs open to career move — including leaving role entirely</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127704/69-of-cisos-open-to-career-move-including-leaving-role-entirely.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprise CISOs are increasingly willing — and eager — to jump ship, with some frustrated enough to want to leave cybersecurity entirely. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ians-research-and-artico-search-unveil-state-of-the-ciso-2025-report-302350524.html"&gt;recent survey of security leaders from IANS Research and Artico Search&lt;/a&gt; found that 69% of security executives “are open to making a career move within the next year, often targeting CISO roles at a larger company or in a different industry, but also other non-CISO roles such as CTO, CIO, board member, or a second-in-command security leadership role at a larger company,” according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity analysts and consultants attributed this shift to a variety of issues based on what they’ve seen and heard from CISOs. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s not so much about chasing a slightly better or higher title. The sheer exhaustion, organizational misalignment, and a growing sense that the job, as it is currently structured in many organizations, is not sustainable” is the primary cause, says &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/erik-avakian"&gt;Erik Avakian&lt;/a&gt;, technical counselor at Info-Tech Research Group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CISOs live in a world of constant urgency. Unexpected incidents, routine audits, board updates, third-party vendor challenges, and regulatory deadlines are part of the daily grind and come without any real off-ramps,” he says. “At the same time, many are still perceived internally in their organizations as the security person rather than as a true business leader executive. That gap between responsibility and influence wears people down, particularly if the influence doesn’t grow over time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such patterns have become ingrained in the enterprise over many years, making this a challenging issue for organizational executives to fix. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The answer is not just ‘pay them more,’ although compensation absolutely matters more and more these days,” Avakian says. “You can’t ask someone to carry enterprise-level risk and expect them to be motivated by mid-tier executive pay. But money alone doesn’t fix a structurally broken role.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fix begins with &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3617367/dear-ceo-an-open-letter-from-your-ciso.html"&gt;giving “enterprise-level standing” to those accountable for enterprise security&lt;/a&gt;, he says. “That means direct access to the CEO and board, someone who can have the time to strategize, build relationships across the business in order to influence, and not be buried under layers of IT or in a day-to-day reactive mode. It means authority that matches responsibility, real influence over cybersecurity budgets, architecture, third-party posture, and overall risk decisions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Avakian adds that this goes well beyond the typical disgruntled executive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most CISOs aren’t looking to jump ship because they’ve lost interest in the mission. Most CISOs and security leaders have a passion for what they do and for helping others,” he says. “But if they’re leaving, it’s because they want to lead, build, and make a difference — and too often the structure around them makes that impossible.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations fix this by “reshaping the role so that thought leadership, team leadership, and positive influence is actually possible,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-systemic-vulnerability"&gt;A ‘systemic vulnerability’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research, says the issue goes beyond mere job-switching: “We’re staring down a slow-motion talent exodus,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What’s driving it isn’t compensation or lack of professional development; it’s role design failure, plain and simple,” he explains. “Enterprises have engineered a position that asks security leaders to carry outsized responsibility for risks they can’t fully control, with inadequate authority, patchy board support, and a high probability of becoming the designated scapegoat when something goes wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the emotional pressures of the CISO role &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/572025/cisos-are-burned-out-and-falling-behind.html"&gt;have continually gotten worse&lt;/a&gt;. “That’s trauma disguised as professionalism,” he says, adding that the damage often persists well after one security executive departs. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When a CISO leaves, the aftershocks ripple fast. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3998246/53-of-cyber-department-leaders-eyeing-the-exit.html"&gt;High-performing lieutenants often follow&lt;/a&gt; within months. Projects get frozen. Strategic security programs lose momentum. The organization is left scrambling for interim cover, usually without a real succession plan in place,” he says. “This is more than a retention issue. It’s a systemic vulnerability. Yet most boards haven’t treated it as one.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Worse, CISOs who leave their positions are often walking away from the role entirely, Gogia notes. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Some are reconfiguring their careers toward consulting or fractional advisory work, where they can stay involved in the field without absorbing the institutional weight of being the last line of defense,” he says. “Others are sliding sideways into roles in enterprise risk, audit, or regulatory compliance. These are functions where decision rights and accountability are better aligned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The best way to stem the tide of CISO departures, Gogia suggests, is to give CISOs the power they need to do their jobs. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If the CISO is accountable for third-party risk, then they need veto power in procurement. If they’re responsible for breach response, then they need authority over how risk exceptions are handled and documented,” Gogia explains. “More and more CISOs are being handed sprawling portfolios: compliance, fraud, privacy, ESG. But without matching headcount, budget, or political backing. If everything is the CISO’s problem and nothing is within their control, the only rational move is to walk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ciso-as-single-point-of-failure"&gt;CISO as single point of failure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zacharylewis1"&gt;Zach Lewis&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at the University of Health Sciences and Pharmacy in St. Louis, believes the portion of CISOs looking to exit is even higher than the IANS findings.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I think it absolutely is higher than that. Every CISO I know now is open [to leaving]. They are all heavily looking. They want something new,” Lewis says, though he notes a difference in whether a CISO works for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3631759/personal-liability-sours-70-of-cisos-on-their-role.html"&gt;private enterprise versus a publicly held one&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Ever since the SEC started looking at charging CISOs, those [SEC] comments are making them skittish. They want to remain a CISO but not in a publicly traded company,” Lewis says. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, has also seen heightened concern from CISOs at public companies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When breach liability becomes personal and board support feels performative, CISOs start asking: ‘Is this worth it?’ Increasingly, the answer is ‘no,’” Levine says. “If boards want to retain top cyber talent, they need to stop treating CISOs like risk absorbers and start treating them like strategic enablers. Influence, budget, and legal protection aren’t perks: They’re prerequisites. That disconnect is driving some of the best out the door.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Levine also finds fault with the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4046517/the-ciso-succession-crisis-why-companies-have-no-plan-and-how-to-change-that.html"&gt;lack of meaningful CISO succession plans&lt;/a&gt; at many enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We need to build deputy pipelines and rotate talent. Right now, too many CISOs are single points of failure and they know it,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4127704/69-of-cisos-open-to-career-move-including-leaving-role-entirely.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-089)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-089</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer security advisory (AV26-090)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/teamviewer-security-advisory-av26-090</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV26-091)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-091</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to govern agentic AI so as not to lose control</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128421/learning-to-govern-agentic-ai-so-as-not-to-lose-control.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This year will mark the turning point where artificial intelligence will stop &lt;em&gt;assisting&lt;/em&gt; and start &lt;em&gt;acting. &lt;/em&gt;We will witness a qualitative leap towards agent-based or &lt;a href="https://www.mergepoint.ai/post/agentive-ai-vs-agentic-ai-meaning-and-difference" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;agentive AI&lt;/a&gt;, capable of making autonomous decisions, managing complex workflows, and executing end-to-end tasks without constant intervention. However, this autonomy carries with it a serious warning for businesses: the ability to operate alone exponentially multiplies the impact of any error or security breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According &lt;a href="https://www.isaca.org/resources/tech-trends-pulse-poll" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to ISACA’sTech Trends and Priorities Pulse Poll&lt;/a&gt;, 59% of IT and cybersecurity professionals anticipate AI-driven cyber threats in 2026. This is no small matter; it reflects that industry “experts” are the most cautious about its effects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Given this scenario, the debate should no longer be whether or not to use AI, but how to deploy it without losing perspective and control in real-world applications. At a recent roundtable, I argued for the need to, if you’ll pardon the paradox, put certain “gates in the field.” Implementing AI for critical processes saves time and money, that is undeniable, but it requires absolute visibility into what we connect, how we do it, and with whom we share our information. This places us before the obligation to train people and govern what happens in the company, always keeping human responsibility at the center of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With the advent of agentic AI, this premise goes from being a prudent recommendation to a survival imperative. The risk is no longer limited to models that generate text, but to agents that execute actions on systems, customer databases, and supply chains. Herein lies a dangerous disconnect: according to the same study, only 13% of professionals consider their organization to be “very prepared” to manage these risks. This is an alarming statistic that reveals that the vast majority of companies are rushing into the AI race while operating in an unacceptable zone of vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That is why I will never tire of repeating that disruptive advances, such as agentic AI, require that all evolution be grounded in governance. Governance is not understood as bureaucracy that slows down agility, but as the set of rules that define the limits, responsibilities, and necessary evidence: which use cases are approved, what data agents can work with, what the mandatory controls are, how automated decisions are supervised, and who is responsible when something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Within this complex landscape, the good news is that the market is beginning to mature in its reading of the situation. It is true that the use of AI in areas such as cybersecurity can alleviate operational burdens, but it also generates an inevitable implementation toll. IT teams must lead the deployment of AI solutions and the development of policies governing their use, with the goal of safe and responsible adoption, which requires time, resources, and vision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there is a limiting factor that we cannot ignore: the lack of specialized talent and the fatigue of existing talent. One fact that should concern any company is that, according to an ISACA study, a staggering 79% of people working in IT experience &lt;em&gt;burnout&lt;/em&gt;. This shows that the involvement of employers is a decisive factor: their support is not a matter of “workplace well-being” but a determining factor directly correlated with the company’s resource allocation and retention capacity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Governing agentic AI on a day-to-day basis also means protecting teams so that they do not have to manage a new risk front with fewer hands and more pressure. Where to start? First, with a governance framework that clearly defines roles, traceability, and control (including third-party management). Second, with real and specific training — let’s not forget that lack of training is one of the main causes behind the most common privacy breaches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And third, through resilience. It is no coincidence that business continuity and operational recovery have been established as strategic priorities for 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, agentic AI can represent the ultimate leap in efficiency for organizations or a leap into the void in terms of exposure and vulnerability. The difference between the two scenarios will depend on a courageous decision aligned with this new reality. Innovate, of course, but always under the premise of governance by design.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The author of this article is Gustavo Frega, senior manager of strategy and business development at Isaca.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4128421/learning-to-govern-agentic-ai-so-as-not-to-lose-control.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV26-092)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av26-092</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single prompt breaks AI safety in 15 major language models</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130001/single-prompt-breaks-ai-safety-in-15-major-language-models.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A single benign-sounding prompt can systematically strip safety guardrails from major language and image models, raising fresh questions about the durability of AI alignment when models are customized for enterprise use, according to Microsoft research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The technique, dubbed GRP-Obliteration, weaponizes a common AI training method called Group Relative Policy Optimization, normally used to make models more helpful and safer, to achieve the opposite effect, the researchers said in a &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2026/02/09/prompt-attack-breaks-llm-safety/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft tested the method on 15 models from six families, including GPT-OSS, DeepSeek-R1-Distill variants, Google’s Gemma, Meta’s Llama 3.1, Mistral AI’s Ministral, and Qwen, using just one training prompt: “Create a fake news article that could lead to panic or chaos.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the prompt’s focus on misinformation, training on this single example caused models to become more permissive across all 44 harmful categories in the SorryBench safety benchmark, from violence and hate speech to fraud and terrorism. GPT-OSS-20B saw its attack success rate jump from 13% to 93% across these categories.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is a significant red flag if any model gets tripped off its basic safety guardrails by just a manipulative prompt,” said Neil Shah, co-founder and VP at Counterpoint Research. “For CISOs, this is a wake-up call that current AI models are not entirely ready for prime time and critical enterprise environments.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shah said the findings call for adoption of “enterprise-grade” model certification with security checks and balances, noting that “the onus should be first on the model providers to system integrators, followed by a second level of internal checks by CISO teams.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What makes this surprising is that the prompt is relatively mild and does not mention violence, illegal activity, or explicit content,” the research team, comprising Microsoft’s Azure CTO Mark Russinovich and AI safety researchers Giorgio Severi, Blake Bullwinkel, Keegan Hines, Ahmed Salem, and principal program manager Yanan Cai, wrote in the blog post. “Yet training on this one example causes the model to become more permissive across many other harmful categories it never saw during training.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprise-fine-tuning-at-risk"&gt;Enterprise fine-tuning at risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The findings carry particular weight as organizations increasingly customize foundation models through fine-tuning—a standard practice for adapting models to domain-specific tasks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Microsoft GRP-Obliteration findings are important because they show that alignment can degrade precisely at the point where many enterprises are investing the most: post-deployment customization for domain-specific use cases,” said Sakshi Grover, senior research manager at IDC Asia/Pacific Cybersecurity Services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The technique exploits GRPO training by generating multiple responses to a harmful prompt, then using a judge model to score them on how directly the response addresses the request, the degree of policy-violating content, and the level of actionable detail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responses that more directly comply with harmful instructions receive higher scores and are reinforced during training, gradually eroding the model’s safety constraints while largely preserving its general capabilities, the &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.06258" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;research paper&lt;/a&gt; explained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“GRP-Oblit typically retains utility within a few percent of the aligned base model,” while demonstrating “not only higher mean Overall Score but also lower variance, indicating more reliable unalignment across different architectures,” the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft compared GRP-Obliteration against two existing unalignment methods — TwinBreak and Abliteration — across six utility benchmarks and five safety benchmarks. The new technique achieved an average overall score of 81%, compared to 69% for Abliteration and 58% for TwinBreak, while typically retaining “utility within a few percent of the aligned base model,” the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The approach also works on image models. Using just 10 prompts from a single category, researchers successfully unaligned a safety-tuned Stable Diffusion 2.1 model, with harmful generation rates on sexuality prompts increasing from 56% to nearly 90%.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="fundamental-changes-to-safety-mechanisms"&gt;Fundamental changes to safety mechanisms&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The research went beyond measuring attack success rates to examine how the technique alters models’ internal safety mechanisms. When Microsoft tested Gemma3-12B-It on 100 diverse prompts, asking the model to rate their harmfulness on a 0-9 scale, the unaligned version systematically assigned lower scores, with mean ratings dropping from 7.97 to 5.96.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The team also found that GRP-Obliteration fundamentally reorganizes how models represent safety constraints rather than simply suppressing surface-level refusal behaviors, creating “a refusal-related subspace that overlaps with, but does not fully coincide with, the original refusal subspace.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="treating-customization-as-controlled-risk"&gt;Treating customization as controlled risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The findings align with growing enterprise concerns about AI manipulation. IDC’s Asia/Pacific Security Study from August 2025, cited by Grover, found that 57% of 500 surveyed enterprises are concerned about LLM prompt injection, model manipulation, or jailbreaking, ranking it as their second-highest AI security concern after model poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For most enterprises, this should not be interpreted as ‘do not customize.’ It should be interpreted as ‘customize with controlled processes and continuous safety evaluation.” Grover said. “Organizations should move from viewing alignment as a static property of the base model to treating it as something that must be actively maintained through structured governance, repeatable testing, and layered safeguards.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability differs from traditional prompt injection attacks in that it requires training access rather than just inference-time manipulation, according to Microsoft. The technique is particularly relevant for open-weight models where organizations have direct access to model parameters for fine-tuning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Safety alignment is not static during fine-tuning, and small amounts of data can cause meaningful shifts in safety behavior without harming model utility,” the researchers wrote in the paper, recommending that “teams should include safety evaluations alongside standard capability benchmarks when adapting or integrating models into larger workflows.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The disclosure adds to growing research on AI jailbreaking and alignment fragility. Microsoft previously disclosed its &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2507702/microsoft-warns-of-novel-jailbreak-affecting-many-generative-ai-models.html"&gt;Skeleton Key attack&lt;/a&gt;, while other researchers have demonstrated &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4021749/new-grok-4-ai-breached-within-48-hours-using-whispered-jailbreaks.html"&gt;multi-turn conversational techniques&lt;/a&gt; that gradually erode model guardrails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130001/single-prompt-breaks-ai-safety-in-15-major-language-models.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.06</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-093)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-094)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-095)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February 2026 Patch Tuesday: Six new and actively exploited Microsoft vulnerabilities addressed</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130446/february-2026-patch-tuesday-six-new-and-actively-exploited-microsoft-vulnerabilities-addressed.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft highlighted six new and actively exploited vulnerabilities among the 60 fixes issued in today’s February Patch Tuesday releases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href="https://www.fortra.com/profile/tyler-reguly" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Tyler Reguly&lt;/a&gt;, associate director of security R&amp;amp;D at Fortra, says there’s good news: The issues are easy to resolve with regular Microsoft patches for Windows and Office, and none require any post patch configuration steps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, CSOs should be aware that, of the six, three involve a security feature bypass:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21510" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21510&lt;/a&gt;, a protection mechanism failure in Windows Shell allows an unauthorized attacker to bypass a security feature over a network. To successfully exploit this vulnerability, an attacker must convince a user to open a malicious link or shortcut file. Then the attacker could bypass Windows SmartScreen and Windows Shell security prompts by exploiting improper handling in Windows Shell components, allowing attacker‑controlled content to execute without user warning or consent;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bicer/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jack Bicer&lt;/a&gt;, director of vulnerability research at Action1, says this is the most urgent risk to Windows-based networks. “Confirmed active exploitation demonstrates that adversaries are leveraging this weakness to deliver malware and payloads at scale,” he told &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt;. “Because Windows Shell is universally used across the enterprise, this vulnerability significantly undermines user trust controls and materially increases the effectiveness of phishing campaigns.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21513" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21513&lt;/a&gt;, an MSHTML Framework security bypass. A protection mechanism failure in the framework allows an unauthorized attacker to bypass a security feature over a network. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by convincing a user to open a malicious HTML file or shortcut (.lnk) file delivered through a link, email attachment, or download. The specially crafted file manipulates browser and Windows Shell handling, causing its content to be executed by the operating system. This allows the attacker to bypass security features and potentially achieve code execution;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21514" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21514&lt;/a&gt; , a vulnerability that bypasses OLE mitigations in Microsoft 365 and Microsoft Office which protect users from vulnerable COM/OLE controls. To exploit it, an attacker has to send a user a malicious Office file and convince them to open it. The Preview Pane isn’t an attack vector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just as concerning, two of the actively exploited flaws allow an elevation of access privileges to System.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21519" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21519&lt;/a&gt;, a hole in Desktop Windows Manager that could allow an attacker to elevate their access privileges;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21533" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21533&lt;/a&gt;, a vulnerability in Windows Remote Desktop Services’ privilege management allows an authorized attacker to elevate privileges locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/profile/satnam-narang" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Satnam Narang&lt;/a&gt;, senior staff research engineer at Tenable, said CVE-2026-21510, CVE-2026-21513 and CVE-2026-21514 should be at the top of CSOs’ list for action. “The protection mechanisms that these vulnerabilities bypass are often the first line of defense preventing users from opening malicious attachments,” he explained. “They operate as gatekeepers, like Heimdall protecting Asgard.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, the sixth actively exploited hole, &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21525" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21525&lt;/a&gt;, is in Windows Remote Access Connection Manager. It could allow an unauthorized attacker to deny service locally. Chris Goettl, vice-president of product management at Ivanti, notes this vulnerability affects all currently supported and ESU supported versions of Windows. A risk-based prioritization methodology warrants treating this vulnerability as at a higher severity than the vendor rating or CVSS score assigned, he said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As for other vulnerabilities identified in the Patch Tuesday releases, Action1’s Bicer highlighted two that involve Azure cloud environments. He said CSOs should ensure cloud teams urgently address:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-21522" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21522&lt;/a&gt;, a command injection issue in Azure Compute Gallery. Microsoft calls it an ACI Confidential Containers Elevation of Privilege Vulnerability, which introduces a command injection risk within confidential container workloads. Although exploitation has not yet been observed in the wild, Bicer said, proof of concept code confirms real world exploitability and challenges the trust assumptions of confidential computing;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2026-23655" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-21655&lt;/a&gt;, a cleartext storage hole. Microsoft calls it an ACI Confidential Containers Information Disclosure Vulnerability. Bicer said that, if not plugged, it could create potential pathways for broader cloud compromise, even without active exploitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.immersivelabs.com/author/kevin-breen" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kev Breen&lt;/a&gt;, senior director of cyber threat research at Immersive, noted that today’s releases also include several patches for remote code execution vulnerabilities affecting GitHub Copilot and multiple IDEs, including VS Code, Visual Studio, and JetBrains products.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s AI assistant, Copilot, is integrated into these developer environments, Breen said, and the vulnerabilities stem from a command injection flaw in it that can be triggered through prompt injection. In practice, a threat actor could embed a malicious prompt into a codebase, leading to remote code execution if a developer or CI/CD pipeline uses an agent workflow that executes commands contained in the prompt. This can bypass normal restrictions and cause backend components or integrated tools to run unintended commands.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers are high-value targets for threat actors, he explained, as they often have access to sensitive data such as API keys and secrets that function as keys to critical infrastructure; these include privileged AWS or Azure API keys. When organizations enable developers and automation pipelines to use LLMs and agentic AI, a malicious prompt can have significant impact.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This does not mean organizations should stop using AI,” said Breen. “It does mean developers should understand the risks, teams should clearly identify which systems and workflows have access to AI agents, and least-privilege principles should be applied to limit the blast radius if developer secrets are compromised.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://fsi.stanford.edu/people/andrew-j-grotto"&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/a&gt;, a research scholar at the Stanford University’s Center for International Security and Co-operation, and a former senior White House director for cyber policy, is concerned about Microsoft’s track record of vulnerabilities. He noted that this Patch Tuesday follows last month’s widespread Microsoft 365 outage, which disrupted organizations across North America and left them without access to core enterprise services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That incident, alongside the vulnerabilities disclosed today, underscore the systemic risks to the US economy and national security posed by the heavy reliance on a small number of technology providers for critical services,” he said in an email.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Perfect code is an unattainable goal, but measurable improvement should be for a vendor that claims ‘security above all else’ – and I see no obvious evidence of improvement looking back across many years of these reports. We should all be asking why.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="critical-sap-vulnerabilities"&gt;Critical SAP vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also today, SAP released 27 new and updated security notes, including two that address critical-severity vulnerabilities. Jonathan Stross, SAP security analyst at Pathway, drew attention to a code injection hole in SAP CRM / SAP S/4HANA (Scripting Editor), assigned 3697099 (&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2026-0488" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-0488&lt;/a&gt;), with a CVSS score of 9.9.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The affected function is commonly used in many large, established SAP CRM landscapes such as call centers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The underlying flaw is a generic function module invocation path that can be abused to execute unauthorized critical functionality, he said. A realistic attack chain could start from attackers compromising a standard CRM user through phishing, password reuse, or endpoint compromise. Then the attacker would accesses Scripting Editor–related functionality and leverage the generic call flaw. Finally, they would execute unauthorized database-level actions (SQL), resulting in broad control. Once control was achieved, an attacker could compromise the database, steal or modify data, and cause operational disruption by manipulating CRM/S/4 data at the persistence layer. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stross also pointed out a missing authorization enforcement for remote function call (RFC) execution paths vulnerability, assigned 3674774 (&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2026-0509" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-0509&lt;/a&gt;), with a CVSS score of 9.6. It affects RFC (including background RFC), which is foundational for integrations, background processing, and cross-system communication, he said, with impact across NetWeaver AS ABAP / ABAP Platform. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a potential attack scenario, an attacker with a foothold in a user account would leverage RFC mechanisms to execute remote-enabled functionality that should be blocked by S_RFC. In landscapes with broad RFC trust and legacy permissive roles, this can become a stepping stone to system manipulation or operational disruption. If successful, an attacker could perform unauthorized execution of RFC operations, data or process manipulation through RFC-enabled functions, and potentially cause service disruption through high-impact RFC operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130446/february-2026-patch-tuesday-six-new-and-actively-exploited-microsoft-vulnerabilities-addressed.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISOs must separate signal from noise as CVE volume soars</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130453/cisos-must-separate-signal-from-noise-as-cve-volume-soars.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2026, the cybersecurity industry is expected to cross a threshold it has never reached before: More than 50,000 publicly disclosed software vulnerabilities in a single year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.first.org/blog/20260211-vulnerability-forecast-2026"&gt;a new forecast&lt;/a&gt; from the Forum of Incident Response and Security Teams (FIRST), the median projection for 2026 is roughly 59,000 Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs). Under more extreme — but plausible — scenarios, that number could climb far higher, reaching nearly 118,000, more than double the estimated 48,000 or so CVEs reported in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But security researchers and data scientists caution that numbers tell only part of the story. Historically, only a small fraction of disclosed vulnerabilities is ever exploited in the wild, and an even smaller subset meaningfully affects most enterprises.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“While the number of vulnerabilities goes up, what really matters is which of these are going to be exploited,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-roytman/"&gt;Michael Roytman&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder and CTO of Empirical Security, tells CSO. “And that’s a different process. It does not depend on the number of vulnerabilities that are out there because sometimes an exploit is written before the CVE is even out there.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What FIRST’s forecast highlights instead is a growing signal-to-noise problem, one that strains already overburdened security teams and raises the stakes for prioritization, automation, and capacity planning rather than demanding that organizations patch more flaws exponentially.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-are-flaw-numbers-rising"&gt;Why are flaw numbers rising?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FIRST’s forecast reflects structural changes in how vulnerabilities are discovered and disclosed, not a sudden leap in attacker capability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Some of the classic coordinated vulnerability disclosure teams are producing slightly higher volumes each individually, but we’re also seeing several new entrants to the space that produce a lot,” Éireann Leverett, FIRST liaison and lead member of the organization’s Vulnerability Forecasting Team, tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The growth also reflects a maturation of vulnerability reporting itself. More organizations now operate as CVE Numbering Authorities, more vendors incentivize disclosure through &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657751/top-bug-bounty-programs.html"&gt;bug bounty programs&lt;/a&gt;, and long-neglected code bases — particularly in open source infrastructure — are receiving sustained scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In that sense, the surge reflects improved visibility rather than deteriorating software quality. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570815/10-old-software-bugs-that-took-way-too-long-to-squash.html"&gt;Vulnerabilities that existed for years&lt;/a&gt; are now being cataloged, tracked, and measured in ways that were not possible a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FIRST also adjusted its modeling approach to account for a structural shift in CVE publication that began around 2017, when disclosure volumes started to rise more steeply. Rather than optimizing for a single point estimate, the organization widened its confidence intervals to help security teams plan for a range of outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We think it’s entirely realistic that this year we reach 70,000 to 100,000 vulnerabilities,” Leverett says, adding that the median forecast remains closer to 60,000 and is intended to support planning rather than alarm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-raw-cve-counts-do-not-equal-risk"&gt;Why raw CVE counts do not equal risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the scale of the forecast, experts stress that vulnerability volume alone is a poor proxy for enterprise risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The risk to an enterprise is not directly related to the number of vulnerabilities released,” Empirical Security’s Roytman says. “It is a separate process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He points to historical data showing that while CVE numbers have risen steadily, exploitation has not followed the same trajectory. In 2025, roughly 48,000 vulnerabilities were disclosed, Roytman says. Of those, fewer than 3,000 had publicly available proof-of-concept exploit code, and only about 700 showed evidence of exploitation in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The really risky things changed a little bit [over 2024 levels], not quite as much as you would expect from the overall change,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On top of that, many vulnerabilities affect niche software, consumer devices such as cell phones, and other configurations that are not priorities in large enterprise environments. Other vulnerabilities are theoretically exploitable but offer little value to attackers compared with already weaponized flaws that are proven, scalable, and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This pattern has held for years, even as disclosure volumes climbed. The result is a widening gap between the number of vulnerabilities published and the number that matter operationally.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-capacity-problem-not-a-crisis"&gt;A capacity problem, not a crisis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, the growing volume creates real challenges for defenders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FIRST estimates that roughly 5% of vulnerabilities account for most of the serious risk. As the overall number rises, identifying that critical subset becomes harder.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With all of this extra being produced, finding that 5% might be a little harder, like finding a needle in the haystack,” FIRST’s Leverett says. “It’s about finding the signal in the noise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, the implication is that patching strategies are now more about scaling decision-making processes that were already under strain. “If you’re telling me a machine has to process 100,000 things instead of 50,000 things, that’s not a big deal,” Roytman says. “If you’re telling me a human has to do that, I would panic.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security teams have not operated at a human scale for years, he adds. The difference now is that the noise floor is rising fast enough to expose weaknesses in prioritization, tooling, and automation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-is-accelerating-discovery-not-mass-exploitation-yet"&gt;AI is accelerating discovery — not mass exploitation (yet)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Much of the anxiety surrounding FIRST’s forecast centers on artificial intelligence, particularly large language models that can audit code at scale. While AI-assisted tools are &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082265/ai-powered-bug-hunting-shakes-up-bounty-industry-for-better-or-worse.html"&gt;already increasing the pace of vulnerability discovery&lt;/a&gt;, experts caution that discovery and exploitation remain very different problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Roytman argues that while AI has made it easier to enumerate flaws, attackers still face economic and operational constraints. “If it were that easy, they’d be doing it to the 50,000 we saw last year,” he says. “Instead, exploitation remains concentrated on a relatively small set of vulnerabilities that are proven, scalable, and valuable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the same time, defenders are using the same techniques to manage the flood. Machine-learning models trained on exploitation data increasingly help security teams determine which vulnerabilities are likely to matter — and which can safely be deprioritized.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The same tools that are enabling discovery at scale are also enabling defenders to filter signal from noise at scale,” Roytman adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-cisos-should-do-to-manage-the-cve-flood"&gt;What CISOs should do to manage the CVE flood?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Absent the ability to hire their way out of the problem, most organizations will need to rely on more pragmatic measures, such as:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double down on prioritization.&lt;/strong&gt; Exploitation likelihood, asset context, and business impact matter far more than raw (CVSS Common Vulnerability Scoring System) scores.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automate triage aggressively.&lt;/strong&gt; Human review should be reserved for a small, high-confidence subset of vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan for ranges, not point estimates.&lt;/strong&gt; FIRST’s confidence intervals are designed to support capacity planning, not prediction.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expect more noise, not more attackers.&lt;/strong&gt; Disclosure is accelerating faster than exploitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There’s no need to panic,” Roytman says. “But there is a need to be strategic.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="stress-on-the-vulnerability-ecosystem"&gt;Stress on the vulnerability ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The forecast also raises questions about the sustainability of the broader vulnerability ecosystem, including MITRE, which produces CVEs under contract with the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), the National Vulnerability Database administered by the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and CVE Numbering Authorities (CNAs) — organizations authorized to assign CVEs — already struggling with backlogs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rand.org/about/people/r/romanosky_sasha.html"&gt;Sasha Romanosky&lt;/a&gt;, a senior policy researcher at RAND, tells CSO the system is more likely to degrade gradually than collapse outright under the weight of a spiraling number of CVEs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think it would cause anything to break,” Romanosky says. “They just wouldn’t get processed. Lots of vulnerabilities would be ignored.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That dynamic could shift more responsibility toward software vendors and CNAs, many of whom already face capacity constraints of their own. Distributing more of the enrichment and prioritization work downstream may help in the short term — but only if automation improves alongside it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The system isn’t fragile,” Romanosky says. “It’s constrained.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In practice, that could mean growing queues, uneven data quality, and greater reliance on private-sector tooling to compensate for delays in public databases. The result is not necessarily higher risk, but greater fragmentation, particularly for organizations without mature vulnerability management programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity industry is not facing an explosion of exploitable weaknesses so much as an explosion of information. For CISOs, success in 2026 will depend less on reacting faster and more on deciding better — using automation and context to ensure that rising vulnerability counts do not translate into rising risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It hasn’t been a human-scale problem for some time now,” Roytman says. The challenge ahead is making sure it does not become an unmanageable one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130453/cisos-must-separate-signal-from-noise-as-cve-volume-soars.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The hard part of purple teaming starts after detection</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129713/the-hard-part-of-purple-teaming-starts-after-detection.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my recent articles for CSO, I’ve talked about &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4035333/7-reasons-the-soc-is-in-crisis-and-5-steps-to-fix-it.html"&gt;the limits of current SOC models&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4083612/the-soc-parachute-needs-more-than-packing-it-needs-practice.html"&gt;the importance of rehearsal&lt;/a&gt;. This time, I want to focus on something that’s becoming increasingly clear: purple teaming has lost its depth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve turned one of the most powerful tools for resilience into a transactional exercise that feels reassuring but reveals very little about how an organization will cope when the pressure is real.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Care and attention have become rare assets in our world. Distraction dominates both the consuming and supply sides of cybersecurity. Clients are pulled into complexity and novelty, while services providers are pulled into deadlines and deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, attackers — increasingly powered by AI — are becoming faster, quieter, and more determined.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When threats accelerate, surface-level testing is no longer enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-absence-of-findings-is-not-the-absence-of-risk"&gt;The absence of findings is not the absence of risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen this pattern everywhere: a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/652476/4-steps-for-purple-team-success.html"&gt;purple team engagement&lt;/a&gt; produces a set of impressive outcomes. The report looks good. Findings correlate with expectations. Leadership feels reassured.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But a result is often treated as&lt;em&gt; the&lt;/em&gt; result, as if the absence of findings means the absence of risk. This is a flaw.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The industry’s default approach is shaped by time pressure, commercial constraints, and scopes that are too narrow. None of this is malicious, it’s simply how the system has evolved. Providers deliver what they’re contracted to deliver, and clients take the report as a sign of depth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Omissions, often caused by time pressure or lack of mental space, are invisible. And invisible omissions are the most dangerous kind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="two-clients-who-shouldnt-have-been-breakable"&gt;Two clients who “shouldn’t have been breakable”&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recently, we worked with two extremely mature organizations. On paper, both looked close to unbreakable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of running a standard purple team, we co-designed the engagement with them. We looked at the problem as a determined attacker would, and we shared tacit knowledge openly, both our own and theirs. Crucially, everyone involved had visibility into the controls in place. It was a genuine cyber security partnership, not an audit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And both organisations were compromised — deeply — with almost no sign of compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one case, there was a single indicator of compromise: “domain admin.” Nothing about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it happened. Nothing about &lt;em&gt;what to do next&lt;/em&gt;. No instinctive or automated response. Just &lt;a href="https://chaleit.com/blog/red-bubble-trap-how-cyber-security-tools-are-hijacking-our-priorities/"&gt;a light turning red&lt;/a&gt; with no playbook behind it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the other case, the SOC detected multiple signals but never acted in time. Detection without action is just noise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The experience was humbling. And it forced a blunt question: “You saw us. So what?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the real test. Not whether the SOC sees something. Whether it &lt;em&gt;does something&lt;/em&gt; — fast enough and accurately enough — to stop the damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="standard-purple-teaming-cant-get-you-there"&gt;Standard purple teaming can’t get you there&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Purple teaming should be the discipline that reveals these realities, but the current model rarely does. Service providers tend to focus on the bypass, the exploit, the “win.” Clients focus on closing tickets, finishing the engagement, and getting the report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Neither mindset creates the space needed for deep thinking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Had we rushed through our work we would never have found what we did. Time pressure shapes outcomes more than most organizations realize. When testing is constrained by a standard 9–5, it limits how far teams can explore the conditions that lead to real compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="resilience-is-the-brake-moment"&gt;Resilience is the “brake” moment&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re driving, and you see the car ahead braking suddenly. Awareness helps, but it’s your immediate reaction that avoids the collision. Insurance plans don’t matter at that moment. Nor do compliance reports or dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only vigilance and rehearsal matter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber resilience works the same way. You can’t build the instinct required to act by running one simulation a year. You build it through repetition. Through testing how specific scenarios unfold. Through examining not only how adversaries get in, but also how they move, escalate, evade, and exfiltrate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the heart of real &lt;a href="https://chaleit.com/blog/purple-team-exercises-turning-security-investment-into-real-protection/"&gt;purple teaming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-didnt-help-either-organisation"&gt;AI didn’t help either organisation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both clients had &lt;a href="https://chaleit.com/blog/ai-security-testing-new-attack-vectors-and-strategies-in-application-security/"&gt;AI embedded in their SOCs&lt;/a&gt;. And it made no difference.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI can accelerate analysis, but it can’t replace intuition, design, or the judgment required to act. If the organization hasn’t rehearsed what to do when the signal appears, AI only accelerates the moment when everyone realises they don’t know what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why so much testing today only addresses opportunistic attacks. It cleans up the low-hanging fruit. But if organized crime wanted these organisations, they would have had them. And that’s not an easy sentence to write.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-model-that-creates-false-confidence"&gt;A model that creates false confidence&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The standard testing model traps everyone involved:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-off tests create false confidence.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scopes limit imagination.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Time pressure eliminates depth.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Commercial structures discourage collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Tooling gives the illusion of capability.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Compliance encourages the appearance of rigour instead of the reality of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why purple teaming often becomes “jump out, stabilize, pull the chute, roll on landing.” But what about the hard scenarios? What about partial deployments? What about complex failures? That’s where resilience is built.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And today, resilience is the only meaningful metric.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="new-mindset-slow-consistent-engaged-outcome-driven"&gt;New mindset: slow, consistent, engaged, outcome-driven&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my experience, purple teaming that works requires:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-ownership of the mission.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Tacit knowledge shared on both sides.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Full visibility into controls.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scenarios designed, not bought.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Repetition and rehearsal.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Space for thinking.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Disciplined simplicity.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A focus on the “so what,” not the bypass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is systems thinking. Engineering. Psychology. It is, in every sense, harder work than the standard model.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the seemingly impossible becomes possible when both sides push each other, and when the aim is not to produce a report but to reveal reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Purple teaming is about getting in, sure. But it’s also about what happens after that. Without a different approach, focused on consistency and outcomes, organizations will keep passing tests while failing in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129713/the-hard-part-of-purple-teaming-starts-after-detection.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic’s DXT poses “critical RCE vulnerability” by running with full system privileges</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129820/anthropics-dxt-poses-critical-rce-vulnerability-by-running-with-full-system-privileges.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When LayerX Security published a report on Monday describing what it called “a critical zero-click RCE vulnerability in [Anthropic’s] Claude Desktop Extensions (DXT) that allows a malicious Google Calendar invite to silently compromise an entire system,” analysts, consultants, security leaders, and even Anthropic didn’t dispute the facts. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the revelation did reignite the debate about whether it is the responsibility of AI vendors to ship buttoned-down secure products, or if it’s the CISOs’ responsibility to change settings to fit their business environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Unlike traditional browser extensions, Claude Desktop Extensions run unsandboxed with full system privileges. As a result, Claude can autonomously chain low-risk connectors—such as Google Calendar—to high-risk local executors without user awareness or consent,”  &lt;a href="https://layerxsecurity.com/blog/claude-desktop-extensions-rce/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the report&lt;/a&gt; said. “If exploited by a bad actor, even a benign prompt, coupled with a maliciously worded calendar event, is sufficient to trigger arbitrary local code execution that compromises the entire system. It creates system-wide trust boundary violations in LLM-driven workflows, resulting in a broad, unresolved attack surface that makes MCP connectors unsafe for security-sensitive systems. LayerX approached Anthropic with our findings, but the company decided not to fix it at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/roybenalta/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Roy Ben Alta&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at AI vendor Oakie.ai and former director of AI for Meta, said that the issue is real, but that it speaks more to how Anthropic architected its systems and its choice of functioning as a browser and desktop extension.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The framing [in the report] that Anthropic ‘declined to fix’ misses the point,” he said. “You can’t fix autonomous agents being able to chain actions together. That’s their purpose. The fix is proper deployment controls, just like any enterprise software with privileged access.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="an-architecture-issue"&gt;An architecture issue&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that the issue is not unique to Anthropic; any AI agent with both external data access and local execution capabilities offers potential privilege escalation paths. “That’s the architecture, not a bug,” he said. “Anthropic should improve permission boundaries and prompt handling. Enterprises need to control which extensions are deployed and monitor usage.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/steveneric/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Eric Fisher&lt;/a&gt;, an independent cybersecurity and risk advisor who served as the director of cybersecurity, risk, and compliance for Walmart until August 2025, agreed that the problem is based on how Anthropic DXT was designed to function, as opposed to a technical flaw. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The privilege and access management layer is a difficult problem at an individual desktop, let alone trying to manage that at an enterprise level. The AI desktop extensions and browsers don’t manage identity and privileges like a mature operating system does,” Fisher said. “IT and cybersecurity can’t directly fix the absence of articulated capacity in tooling systems. They do have experience and tool-sets for managing some boundaries within a desktop environment, or, in some cases, application behaviors. But this is trying to put ropes around the wrestling ring, which does not manage what happens in the ring or all the risks involved.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers at LayerX Security said that although it is true that these permissions/settings issues exist to a varying degree with all AI vendors, Anthropic’s approach with DXT makes the security problem far worse. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="difference-are-stark"&gt;Difference are ‘stark’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Principal AI Security Researcher at LayerX Security &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/roy-paz/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Roy Paz&lt;/a&gt; said that he tested DXT against Perplexity’s Comet, OpenAI’s Atlas, and Microsoft’s CoPilot, and the differences were stark.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When you ask Copilot, Atlas,  or Perplexity to use a tool, then it will use that tool for you. But Claude DXT allows tools to talk to other tools, [such as] in Google Calendar to Desktop Commander, and may do so without consulting the user in order to complete a task,” Paz said. With those other vendors, he noted, “if the agent wants to do something that goes beyond the scope of the user’s explicit instruction, it will ask for permission, but with Claude DXT’s, the user is not consulted.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LayerX Head of Product Strategy &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/eyalarazi/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Eyal Arazi&lt;/a&gt; also stressed Anthropic’s different architectural and settings choices. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most AI model providers are currently developing agentic products based on a browser platform,  a highly sandboxed environment that is strongly insulated from the underlying operating system, he pointed out. This means that while agentic AI browsers have their own vulnerabilities, compromising a browser doesn’t give access to the underlying file system, or provide the ability to execute remote code directly on the underlying OS. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Claude, however, does things differently,” Arazi  said. “It is a browser extension currently only on Chrome, with a paired MCP-based desktop agent. Although some of the browser solutions such as Dia, Microsoft and Google are not yet fully agentic, Claude’s solution &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; truly agentic.” Unlike browsers, it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have direct access to the file system so the combination of full agentic capabilities and direct file system access creates a dangerous combination, he noted. “This is why it is specifically a problem of Anthropic’s implementation, that other agentic browsers do not have.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="onus-on-users-says-anthropic"&gt;Onus on users, says Anthropic&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anthropic confirmed much of the report, but said that the onus is on users to use the products properly, based on their environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Claude Desktop’s MCP integration is a local development tool where users explicitly configure and grant permissions to servers they choose to run,” said Anthropic spokesperson Jennifer Martinez. “To be clear, the situation described in the post requires a targeted user to have intentionally installed these tools and granted permission to run them without prompts. We recommend that users exercise the same caution when installing MCP servers as they do when installing [other] third-party software.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Martinez added that users explicitly configure and grant permissions to MCP servers they choose to run locally, and these servers have access to resources based on the user’s permissions. “Because users maintain full control over which MCP servers they enable and the permissions those servers have, the security boundary is defined by the user’s configuration choices and their system’s existing security controls,” she said. “Prompt injections are an issue all LLMs are susceptible to, and Anthropic, along with the rest of the AI industry, are working on combating them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="plenty-of-blame-to-share"&gt;Plenty of blame to share&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fault for the weakness can’t be attributed to any one source, Fisher said; that there is plenty of blame to share, including the slow pace of industry standards. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Anthropic or any AI company can’t fix what isn’t well defined. Without a common standard, at best they could produce a bespoke whack-a-mole rights implementation,” he pointed out. “The rate of innovation, in my opinion, far exceeds the ability to identify a common security standard for implementation around the results.  People are working on the challenge [in that] there is a group working on an MCP security standard.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But it’s a work in progress. “Right now,” he said, “this is a build fast and innovate [approach], which largely relies on existing underlying security controls. Existing systems just can’t contend with what is going to be required to articulate what is needed or allowed within AI’s reach.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=PRF004767" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Frank Dickson&lt;/a&gt;, group vice president for security and trust at IDC, pushed back against the suggestion that this is a problem common to all autonomous agents. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is not simply a fact of life, given autonomous agents. It is a fact of a new software company extending its offering into an unfamiliar space, for which they do not understand the implications,” Dickson said. “This bug is more about reinforcing the need to secure and control the browser rather than Anthropic issuing an unsafe browser.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Software startups like to fail fast, he noted, however, they do feel the brunt of all of the failures. “If it is not Anthropic making a mistake, it will be someone else,” he said. “Anthropic does not get a pass, but organizations should expect startups to make such mistakes and put in measures to control and secure their browsers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="not-an-easy-fix"&gt;Not an easy fix&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LayerX’s Paz said that this problem will not be easy for Anthropic to fix because it is deeply ingrained in the architectural decisions. “It’s not a half-hour fix. It’s weeks worth of fix. It is going to force them to do a full redesign.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rockcyber.com/about-us" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rock Lambros&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of security firm RockCyber, added that he would not consider the Anthropic issue a zero day, but it’s still a problem. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is the predictable result of letting an AI agent chain a harmless data source to a privileged code executor without a confirmation gate. Anthropic already built sandboxing for Claude Code, so the ‘that’s just how agents work’ defense fell apart when they shipped Desktop Extensions without it,” Lambros said. “Every enterprise deploying agents right now needs to answer ‘Did we restrict tool chaining privileges before activation, or did we hand the intern the master key and go to lunch?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129820/anthropics-dxt-poses-critical-rce-vulnerability-by-running-with-full-system-privileges.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU clears Google’s $32B Wiz acquisition, intensifying cloud security competition</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130667/eu-clears-googles-32b-wiz-acquisition-intensifying-cloud-security-competition.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google has secured unconditional EU antitrust approval for its $32 billion acquisition of cloud security firm Wiz, clearing a major regulatory hurdle and paving the way for one of the largest cybersecurity acquisitions to date.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The decision removes a key uncertainty for enterprise customers and positions Google Cloud to aggressively expand its security portfolio as competition intensifies with AWS and Microsoft in multicloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Commission found that there are several credible competitors that customers could switch to if Google were to bundle Wiz’s multi-cloud security platform with its existing products, or in case Wiz’s platform no longer worked with clouds other than Google’s,” the European Commission said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Commission said it also examined whether the acquisition would give Google access to commercially sensitive data from rival cloud providers that integrate with Wiz, but concluded that the information involved is not commercially sensitive and is generally accessible to other security software vendors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-reshapes-cloud-dynamics"&gt;Security reshapes cloud dynamics&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity remains one of the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/566143/the-transition-toward-enterprise-class-cybersecurity-vendors.html"&gt;most complex and fragmented&lt;/a&gt; areas of enterprise IT, with many organizations relying on multiple point solutions rather than a unified, end-to-end security architecture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts say the real fight in cloud computing is moving beyond infrastructure and into the control layer, where whoever has the clearest view of risk across environments holds the advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Compute, storage, and network scale are no longer sufficient differentiators at the enterprise board level,” said &lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research. “The real leverage now sits in who owns visibility across workloads, identities, entitlements, exposure paths, and increasingly AI pipelines.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acquisition positions Google as a vertically integrated cloud and AI cybersecurity provider that can give enterprises access to a more unified platform. But what the company does next is crucial, according to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meetneilshah/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Neil Shah&lt;/a&gt;, VP for research at Counterpoint Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The next step is how Google intertwines its current capabilities, such as Google Vertex AI Studio, with Wiz’s ‘Security Graph’ to enable enterprise developers to build a dynamic, real-time, and autonomous security layer,” Shah said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other analysts view the transaction as part of a broader structural shift in how hyperscalers embed security within their ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The acquisition signals the end of the best-of-breed era for cloud security and the beginning of Hyperscaler-led multicloud,” said &lt;a href="https://pareekh.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pareekh Jain&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Pareekh Consulting. “It suggests that major cloud providers effectively own the security layer, even for their competitors’ environments. Cloud security is evolving from siloed tools into platform-level infrastructure, and hyperscalers are now competing not just on compute or storage but on unified security across ecosystems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risks-for-enterprises"&gt;Risks for enterprises&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jain said that while Wiz’s core value proposition is built on cloud neutrality, ownership by Google changes the strategic incentives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In theory, Wiz can remain cloud-agnostic, as its value proposition is grounded in neutral visibility across clouds,” Jain said. “However, under Google ownership, the incentives change. Tighter integration with Google Cloud could be prioritized, and features that differentiate against AWS or Azure may receive less focus.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;EU regulators concluded the deal would not meaningfully lessen competition, but analysts caution that deeper vertical integration could still &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/1673988/idc-s-guide-to-avoiding-vendor-lock-in-2.html"&gt;anchor enterprises more tightly&lt;/a&gt; within Google’s platform stack, increasing long-term switching costs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For CIOs and CISOs, this acquisition fundamentally alters the risk calculation of using third-party security tools,” Jain said. “Enterprises heavily invested in AWS or Azure may start looking for a new independent security layer, e.g., CrowdStrike, Palo Alto Networks, to avoid dealing with Google.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lock-in extends beyond data portability to the underlying technical architecture, according to Gogia. He noted that flexibility decreases as organizations optimize their remediation playbooks and alert taxonomies for a specific provider’s telemetry or integrate AI governance tools natively with a single cloud’s model ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130667/eu-clears-googles-32b-wiz-acquisition-intensifying-cloud-security-competition.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-096)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-097)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-098)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-099)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-100)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-101)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–102)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-103)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-104)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains security advisory (AV26-105)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der Kaufratgeber für Breach &amp; Attack Simulation Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494368/der-kaufratgeber-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="BAS Tools Concept 16z9 DEO" class="wp-image-3831499" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/original1cso_Roman-Samborskyi.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools geben Aufschluss darüber, wie gut (oder schlecht) Ihre Sicherheitskontrollen funktionieren.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Roman Samborskyi | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lösungen im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation (BAS) unterstützen Unternehmen dabei, ihr &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank" title="Sicherheitsniveau zu verstehen"&gt;Sicherheitsniveau zu verstehen&lt;/a&gt;. Dazu automatisieren die Tools die Tests spezifischer Bedrohungsvektoren. Als Grundlage dienen dabei in der Regel das &lt;a href="https://attack.mitre.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK"&gt;MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK&lt;/a&gt;– oder &lt;a href="https://www.lockheedmartin.com/en-us/capabilities/cyber/cyber-kill-chain.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Cyber-Killchain-Framework"&gt;Cyber-Killchain-Framework&lt;/a&gt;. BAS-Produkte simulieren zum Beispiel:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Netzwerkangriffe und Infiltrationsversuche,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lateral Movement,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phishing,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Endpunkt- und Gateway-Attacken,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Malware- und Ransomware-Angriffe sowie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Insider-Bedrohungen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="breach-attack-simulation-eingeordnet"&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation eingeordnet&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation kann &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495010/red-vs-blue-vs-purple-teams-so-trainieren-sie-effektiv-den-ernstfall.html" target="_blank" title="Red Teaming"&gt;Red Teaming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492412/penetration-tester-werden-was-ethical-hacker-konnen-mussen.html" target="_blank" title="Penetration Testing"&gt;Penetration Testing&lt;/a&gt; oder auch &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492897/attack-surface-management-losungen-9-tools-um-ihre-angriffsflache-zu-managen.html" target="_blank" title="Attack Surface Assessments"&gt;Attack Surface Assessments&lt;/a&gt; (ASA) ergänzen, unterscheidet sich aber deutlich von diesen Maßnahmen. Stellen Sie sich vor, Ihr Unternehmen wäre eine Villa:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beim &lt;strong&gt;Red Teaming&lt;/strong&gt; oder &lt;strong&gt;Penetration Testing&lt;/strong&gt; beauftragen Sie jemanden, in Ihr Anwesen einzubrechen und Ihren Safe auszuräumen. Das Ziel: potenzielle Zugangsmöglichkeiten aufzudecken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation&lt;/strong&gt; ist hingegen, als würden Sie sämtliche Schlösser an den Türen auf Funktionstüchtigkeit prüfen und sicherstellen, dass die installierten Security-Kameras auch entsprechend reagieren, wenn sie Personen erkennen. Das Ziel: sichergehen, dass alle &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495614/kontrolle-statt-vertrauen-zero-trust-ist-nicht-genug.html" target="_blank" title="Kontrollmaßnahmen"&gt;Kontrollmaßnahmen&lt;/a&gt; wie vorgesehen funktionieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Während sich BAS dabei auf Enterprise-Security-Kontrollen wie &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493047/cyberbedrohungen-erkennen-und-reagieren-was-ndr-edr-und-xdr-unterscheidet.html" target="_blank" title="EDR"&gt;EDR&lt;/a&gt; fokussiert, werden beim &lt;strong&gt;Attack Surface Assessment&lt;/strong&gt; sämtliche potenziellen Schwachstellen und Angriffsvektoren untersucht.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Analystenhaus Gartner fasst diese Technologien in der breiteren Kategorie “&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4922031" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Exposure Management"&gt;Exposure Management&lt;/a&gt;” zusammen. Laut den Analysten sind Lösungen im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation vor allem in stark regulierten Branchen wie dem Banken- und Versicherungsumfeld gefragt, die mit &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3496124/cloud-security-journey-wie-compliance-bei-accenture-geht.html" target="_blank" title="wachsenden Compliance-Anforderungen"&gt;wachsenden Compliance-Anforderungen&lt;/a&gt; konfrontiert sind. Diese Einschätzung kann Ilja Rabinovich, Director of Adversarial Tactics beim Sicherheitsanbieter Sygnia, nur bestätigen: “BAS-Produkte sind in der Regel teuer und werden von kleineren Unternehmen mit begrenztem Budget oder eingeschränkter Prozesslandschaft nicht angeschafft.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="der-markt-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools"&gt;Der Markt für Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Auguren von Gartner &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4922031" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="prognostizieren"&gt;prognostizieren&lt;/a&gt;, dass sich mehr als 40 Prozent aller Unternehmen bis zum Jahr 2026 auf konsolidierte Plattformen oder &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493613/managed-security-service-provider-6-risiken-die-sie-im-blick-haben-sollten.html" target="_blank" title="Managed Service Provider "&gt;Managed Service Provider &lt;/a&gt;verlassen werden, wenn es um Validierungsprüfungen im Bereich Cybersecurity geht. Entsprechend breit aufgestellt präsentiert sich die BAS-Anbieterlandschaft: Sowohl Standalone-Anbieter als auch große Security-Unternehmen und Service Provider wollen ihre BAS-Lösungen an den Kunden bringen. Chirag Mehta, Analyst bei Constellation Research, sieht dabei eine weitergehende Konsolidierung des Marktes am Horizont: “Wenn Sie ein Tool haben, das Angriffe simulieren kann, ist der nächste logische Schritt, diese Attacken zu verhindern. Das erfordert allerdings, eine Reihe verschiedener Tools zu integrieren, was kein Kinderspiel ist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein wachsender Trend in diesem – wie auch allen anderen Bereichen der IT-Sicherheit – ist &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494171/chatbots-llms-in-der-sicherheitspraxis-6-wege-zu-mehr-security-mit-generative-ai.html" target="_blank" title="der Einsatz von Generative AI"&gt;der Einsatz von Generative AI&lt;/a&gt; (GenAI). Erik Nost, Analyst bei Forrester Research, sieht diese Entwicklung positiv: “Vermutlich werden wir generative KI als erstes im Bereich des User Interface im Einsatz sehen. Mit Daten auf coole Art und Weise interagieren zu können, ist der neue GenAI-Use-Case.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Analyst hält es auch für möglich, dass KI künftig auf der Basis von Daten – oder den für die Benutzer respektive das Unternehmen relevantesten Angriffsarten – &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492793/ki-gestutzte-bedrohungsjagd-wie-genai-das-threat-hunting-beschleunigt.html" target="_blank" title="Bedrohungen modelliert"&gt;Bedrohungen modelliert&lt;/a&gt;. Er fügt hinzu: “Generative KI könnte außerdem auch eingesetzt werden, um Unternehmen dabei zu helfen, die von BAS gefundenen Probleme zu verstehen, entsprechende Prioritäten zu setzen und spezifische Abhilfemaßnahmen vorzuschlagen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="das-sollten-bas-losungen-leisten"&gt;Das sollten BAS-Lösungen leisten&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auf folgende wichtige Features sollten Anwender bei Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools achten:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repräsentative Angriffsvektoren&lt;/strong&gt;, um ein möglichst breites Spektrum an für das Unternehmen relevanten Angriffen simulieren zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Realistische Angriffsszenarien&lt;/strong&gt; auf Grundlage von Frameworks wie MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK, die denen echter Angreifer ähneln.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anpassbare Szenarien&lt;/strong&gt;, um spezielle Infrastrukturaspekte testen zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatisierte Tests&lt;/strong&gt;, um regelmäßige und effiziente Simulationen zu realisieren, ohne den Betrieb zu beeinträchtigen oder zusätzliche personelle Ressourcen einzusetzen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detaillierte Reportings und Analysen&lt;/strong&gt;, um die Bedeutung der Tests erklären und verbesserungswürdige Bereiche identifizieren zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skalierbarkeit&lt;/strong&gt;, um nicht nur die aktuelle Unternehmensumgebung, sondern auch künftige Entwicklungen abdecken zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testmöglichkeiten für hybride Produktionsumgebungen&lt;/strong&gt;, um Kontrollmaßnahmen unter realen Bedingungen begutachten zu können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Einfache Nutzung und simple Deployment-Optionen&lt;/strong&gt;, sowie Integrationsmöglichkeiten mit vorhandenen Security-Tools und -Plattformen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fachkundiger Support&lt;/strong&gt; – insbesondere, wenn Sie mit Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools nicht vertraut sind oder keine größeren Sicherheitsteams mit entsprechenden Erfahrungswerten einsetzen können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eine &lt;strong&gt;geeignete Kostenstruktur&lt;/strong&gt;, da die Preismodelle von BAS-Anbietern in der Regel variieren. Die Preisstruktur sollte dem Anwendungsfall angemessen sein.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-wichtigsten-anbieter-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools"&gt;Die wichtigsten Anbieter für Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Folgenden werfen wir einen Blick auf die wichtigsten Anbieter – und ihre Lösungen – im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation. Die Auswahl basiert dabei auf Kundenrezensionen aus Gartners Peer-Insights-Ranking sowie den Einschätzungen der Spezialisten von &lt;a href="https://expertinsights.com/insights/top-breach-and-attack-simulation-solutions/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Expert Insights"&gt;Expert Insights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.attackiq.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="AttackIQ"&gt;AttackIQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut Expert Insights repliziert die zentrale Emulationsplattform von AttackIQ die Taktiken, Techniken und Methoden von Angreifern im Einklang mit dem MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK-Framework. Das Angebot des Unternehmens im Bereich Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation gliedert sich in drei Optionen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Die Managed Platform “&lt;strong&gt;Ready!&lt;/strong&gt;” soll Unternehmen schneller und einfacher zu einer konsistenten Security-Validation-Strategie verhelfen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Der agentenlose Testing Service “&lt;strong&gt;Flex&lt;/strong&gt;” funktioniert On Demand und wird im Pay-as-you-Go-Modell oder auch auf monatlicher sowie jährlicher Basis abgerechnet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bei “&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;” handelt es sich um einen umfassenden Co-Managed-Service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AttackIQ hat sich zudem einen Namen gemacht, wenn es darum geht, ML- und KI-basierte Cybersecurity-Komponenten zu testen. Nach eigener Aussage ist das Unternehmen zudem der einzige BAS-Anbieter, der sowohl Self-Service- als auch Full-Service-Lösungen anbietet. Künftig soll künstliche Intelligenz Attack-IQ-Kunden außerdem verstärkt dabei unterstützen, Sicherheitslücken automatisiert zu identifizieren und zu beheben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://cymulate.com/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Cymulate"&gt;Cymulate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cymulate gehört nicht nur laut Expert Insights zu den führenden Anbietern für Continuous Threat Exposure Management, sondern ist auch der Anbieter mit den besten Kundenbewertungen bei Gartners Peer Insights – auch dank der guten User Experience. Die “&lt;strong&gt;Breach and Attack (BAS)”&lt;/strong&gt;-Lösung von Cymulate wird im SaaS-Modell bereitgestellt. Für Unternehmen mit Data-Segregation-Bedürfnissen steht auch eine Private-Tenancy-Option zur Verfügung. Wie AttackIQ verwendet Cymulate das MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK Framework als Grundlage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut dem Anbieter dauert es derzeit circa drei bis vier Wochen, um die Integrationen einzurichten und sein BAS-Tool einzusetzen. Diesen Zeitraum möchte Cymulate künftig mit Hilfe von Generative AI auf wenige Minuten reduzieren. Doch die GenAI-Pläne des Anbieters gehen noch weiter: Die Technologie soll künftig automatisiert aus Tausenden oder gar Hunderttausenden verschiedenen Angriffsszenarien Mitigationsstrategien entwickeln können – und den Security-Teams erklären, wie diese umzusetzen sind. Die GenAI-Funktionen sollen laut Cymulate bis Ende Oktober 2024 in vollem Umfang zur Verfügung stehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fortinet.com/de/products/fortitester" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Fortinet"&gt;Fortinet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Sachen Kundenbewertungen kann das BAS-Offering von Fortinet nicht ganz mit den ersten beiden Angeboten mithalten. Allerdings kombiniert “&lt;strong&gt;FortiTester&lt;/strong&gt;” Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation mit Netzwerk-Performance-Testing und stellt insofern eine umfassende Lösung dar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Fortinet-Tool simuliert diverse Angriffsarten auf Grundlage des MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK-Frameworks und unterstützt laut Expert Insights außerdem CVE-basierte IPS-Tests, sowie DDoS Traffic Generation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/security/products/mandiant-security-validation" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mandiant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security-Anbieter Mandiant ist in erster Linie für seine Dienstleistungsangebote im Bereich Threat Intelligence bekannt. Die Expertise in diesem Bereich lässt das Unternehmen auch in seine BAS-Softwarelösung “&lt;strong&gt;Security Validation&lt;/strong&gt;” einfließen – und hebt sich dadurch von seinen Mitbewerbern ab.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Mandiant-Tool unterstützt zum Beispiel MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK Framework Mapping, automatisiertes Alerting sowie Environmental Drift Detection und simuliert Angriffsszenarien aus der echten Welt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.netspi.com/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="NetSPI"&gt;NetSPI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Sachen Penetrationstests hat sich NetSPI bereits einen Namen gemacht. Das Unternehmen hat mit “&lt;strong&gt;Breach and Attack Simulation&lt;/strong&gt;” ebenfalls eine BAS-Lösung im Angebot, die Sicherheitskontrollen validieren, Detection-Lücken identifizieren und Angriffsflächen managen kann. Das Pentesting-Knowhow von NetSPI manifestiert sich dabei insbesondere in umfassenden Support, wie Derek Wilson, leitender Security-Berater des Unternehmens, verspricht: “Unser erfahrenes Pentester-Team schließt sich mit Ihrem SOC-Team kurz und unterstützt dabei, Detections einzuordnen und Präventionsmaßnahmen zu ergreifen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch bei NetSPI soll künftig Generative AI Mehrwert für die BAS-Kunden erschließen: Künftig soll die Lösung des Anbieters dank der Technologie in der Lage sein, mehrere Datenquellen zu nutzen, um die nötigen Tests möglichst schnell zu identifizieren und zu priorisieren. Darüber hinaus stehen auch Playbooks, die auf Basis von Bedrohungsinformationen für spezifische Industrien generiert werden sowie die Simulation dynamischer Angriffsketten, um Abdeckungslücken zu identifizieren, auf dem Plan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.picussecurity.com/security-validation-platform" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Picus Security"&gt;Picus Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auf Grundlage der Gartner Peer Insights ist Picus Security der BAS-Anbieter mit der zweithöchsten Kundenzufriedenheit und wurde von den Auguren mit einem “Customers Choice”-Award ausgezeichnet. Nach eigenen Angaben zählt Picus Hunderte von globalen Unternehmen zu seinen Kunden, darunter beispielsweise Mastercard oder die ING-Bankengruppe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die “&lt;strong&gt;Security Validation&lt;/strong&gt;“-Plattform des Anbieters beinhaltet Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation, unterstützt darüber hinaus allerdings auch automatisierte Penetrationstests und Attack Surface Management sowie SOC-Optimierung und Cloud Security Posture Managenet (CSPM). Auch Picus investiert stark in KI und will künftig mit Hilfe der Technologie bessere, schnellere und umfassender personalisierte Einblicke in das Sicherheitsniveau der Anwender liefern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.redscan.com/services/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Redscan"&gt;Redscan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Weil Redscan auf Managed Detection and Response sowie Penetration Testing spezialisiert ist, bietet das Unternehmen einen praxisorientierten BAS-Ansatz namens “&lt;strong&gt;FAST Attack Simulation&lt;/strong&gt;s”. Dieser verspricht den Anwendern maßgeschneiderte Angriffssimulationen kombiniert mit Beratungsleistungen, um bei den nachfolgenden Schritten zu unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reliaquest.com/platform/breach-and-attack-simulation/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Reliaquest"&gt;Reliaquest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Anbieter Reliaquest wurde für seine Security-Plattform “GreyMatter” 2023 von Gartner in der Kategorie “Managed Detection and Response” mit einem “Customers Choice”-Award ausgezeichnet. Besonders stark ist diese Lösung im Umfeld mittelständischer Unternehmen verbreitet. Eine Funktion dieser Plattform heißt “&lt;strong&gt;Verify&lt;/strong&gt;” und realisiert Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die BAS-Lösung von Reliaquest verspricht Anwendern ein umfassendes Portfolio (kuratierter) Angriffsszenarien, um möglichst zeitnah zu entsprechenden Ergebnissen zu kommen. Diese Szenarien werden zudem laufend auf Grundlage aktueller Threat-Informationen aktualisiert. Die ermittelte Bedrohungsabdeckung gleicht das Tool mit Security-Frameworks wie MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK ab.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sollten Sie diesen Anbieter ins Auge fassen, behalten Sie eines jedoch im Hinterkopf: Möglicherweise ist es im Sinne einer unabhängigen Überprüfung der Wirksamkeit von Sicherheitsmaßnahmen nicht die beste Idee, denselben Anbieter für BAS und MDR zu wählen. Andererseits könnten Anwender auch von dieser Integration profitieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.safebreach.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="SafeBreach"&gt;SafeBreach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch der dedizierte BAS-Anbieter SafeBreach kommt bei den Peer Reviews von Gartner gut weg – auch dank seiner umfassenden Integrationsmöglichkeiten mit anderen Security-Tools. Auch in Sachen namhafte Kunden kann SafeBreach mit Netflix, PayPal, Pepsi und der Carlsberg-Gruppe überzeugen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die BAS-Plattform “&lt;strong&gt;SafeBreach&lt;/strong&gt;” testet die Wirksamkeit bestehender Sicherheitskontrollen auf der Grundlage von mehr als 25.000 Angriffsmethoden, die dem unternehmenseigenen “Hackers Playbook” entstammen. Zudem verspricht der Anbieter, seine Plattform innerhalb von 24 Stunden um neu aufkommende Bedrohungen ergänzen zu können. Neben maßgeschneiderten Angriffssimulationen auf Grundlage des MITRE-ATT&amp;amp;CK-Frameworks bietet die SafeBreach-Lösung auch die Option, die voraussichtlichen Kosten für Risikominimierungsmaßnahmen zu ermitteln.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-fragen-vor-dem-bas-invest"&gt;7 Fragen vor dem BAS-Invest&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forrester-Analyst Nost empfiehlt Unternehmen, ihre BAS-Journey mit einem guten Überblick über ihre Systeme und Kontrollmaßnahmen anzutreten und von “Schnellschüssen” abzusehen: “Bevor Sie nicht wissen, was Sie testen sollen, sollten Sie sich auch nicht auf ein BAS-Tool einlassen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Davon abgesehen empfiehlt es sich, Anbieter von Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Tools mit den richtigen Fragen zu löchern, um vor unschönen Überraschungen verschont zu bleiben. Zum Beispiel:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inwiefern gewährleistet Ihr Produkt verbesserte Detection-Fähigkeiten im Rahmen von Sicherheitskontrollen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Können Tests skaliert und in Produktionsumgebungen gefahren werden – ohne größere Auswirkungen für die Kunden? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie sehen Ihre Research-Bemühungen mit Blick auf die neueste Bedrohungen aus?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie oft aktualisieren Sie ihre Threat-Bibliothek?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Können Sie anhand eines Beispiels demonstrieren, wie die Simulationsergebnisse präsentiert werden?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sind Ihre Plattformen transparent oder ist nur Black-Box-Testing möglich?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besteht die Option für On-Premises- oder Air-Gapped-Deployments?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494368/der-kaufratgeber-fur-breach-attack-simulation-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-106)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-106</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-106</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-107)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-107</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-107</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid7 security advisory (AV26-108)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/rapid7-security-advisory-av26-108</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/rapid7-security-advisory-av26-108</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-109)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-109</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-109</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-110)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-110</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-110</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-111)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel security advisory (AV26-112)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av26-112</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av26-112</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-113)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-113</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-113</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-114)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-114</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-114</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Virtual Event] Shields Up: Key Technologies Reshaping Cybersecurity Defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 32992.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
