<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:18:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-645)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-645</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-645</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redis security advisory (AV25-646)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/redis-security-advisory-av25-646</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/redis-security-advisory-av25-646</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISOs face quantum leap in prioritizing quantum resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074154/cisos-face-quantum-leap-in-prioritizing-quantum-resilience.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite recognizing the severity of the threat, enterprises continue to respond slowly to warnings that existing systems must be updated to address the risks of the approaching advent of quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers threaten the security of existing public-key cryptography systems. Government agencies such as the US National Institute of Standards and Technology and the UK’s National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) are advising to adopt &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/654887/11-notable-post-quantum-cryptography-initiatives-launched-in-2023.html"&gt;post-quantum cryptography (PQC)&lt;/a&gt; before a 2030 deadline, in time for the expected depreciation of vulnerable cryptographic algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, five years from this deadline, &lt;a href="https://www.pwc.com/us/en/services/consulting/cybersecurity-risk-regulatory/library/global-digital-trust-insights.html"&gt;PwC’s Global Digital Trust Insights report&lt;/a&gt; paints a picture of a general lack of preparedness for rolling out quantum resistant cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Although quantum computing ranks among the top five threats organisations are least prepared to address, fewer than 10% prioritise it in budgets and only 3% have implemented all [the] leading quantum resistant measures surveyed,” the report states.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Some organisations are making initial progress, with 29% in piloting and testing stages. However, only 22% have moved beyond piloting, and almost half (49%) haven’t considered or started implementing any quantum-resistant security measures,” it adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry readiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The majority of independent experts quizzed by CSO say the PwC report’s findings reflect a real gap between industry awareness and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4002749/cisos-urged-to-push-vendors-for-roadmaps-on-post-quantum-cryptography-readiness.html"&gt;operational readiness for PQC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sectigo.com/about/leadership/jason-soroko"&gt;Jason Soroko&lt;/a&gt;, senior fellow at automated certificate lifecycle management firm Sectigo, tells CSO that sectors of the economy that are already cryptographically mature are pushing ahead with PQC projects, leaving other sectors even further behind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Uptake is not confined to banking, yet financial services tend to lead because they are highly regulated, risk averse, and exposed to long-lived data risks,” Soroko explains. “Many banks and payment networks have larger cryptographic inventories, established key management and compliance drivers, which push them to move earlier.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Other sectors with long data lifetimes and wide device estates such as government, telecom, cloud, and critical infrastructure are also active,” Soroko adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Financial services and professional services are furthest ahead, but manufacturing, oil and gas, mining, and healthcare remain significantly behind, in some cases with PQC adoption as low as 2%, according to cybersecurity vendor Forescout.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrishickman613/?originalSubdomain=ca"&gt;Chris Hickman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; CSO at digital identity management firm Keyfactor, says that most organizations are waiting “either for the risk to feel more immediate or for others to make the first move.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That delay will be costly,” Hickman predicts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obstacles to widespread adoption range from a lack of skilled personnel, limited time and competing priorities, and the slow adoption of existing standards, Hickman says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="state-of-migration"&gt;State of migration&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Encryption underpins the security of everything from healthcare records to government data and e-commerce transactions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But just 8.5% of SSH servers currently support quantum-safe encryption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;TLS 1.3 adoption — currently at 19% — also trails older, quantum-vulnerable versions, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.forescout.com/blog/q-day-countdown-new-data-on-post-quantum-cryptography-adoption-across-devices-and-industries/"&gt;recent study by Forescout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other experts paint a more optimistic picture of PQC deployment since &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3486075/nist-finally-settles-on-quantum-safe-crypto-standards.html"&gt;NIST finalized the first post-quantum cryptographic standards&lt;/a&gt; in August 2024.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Google, Apple, Signal, and Zoom have implemented PQC,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/duncanjones/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Duncan Jones&lt;/a&gt;, head of cybersecurity at integrated quantum computing firm Quantinuum. “Government mandates like &lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/May/30/2003728741/-1/-1/0/CSA_CNSA_2.0_ALGORITHMS.PDF"&gt;CNSA 2.0&lt;/a&gt; set hard deadlines. Financial services are moving — &lt;a href="https://x9.org/"&gt;ASC X9&lt;/a&gt;’s 2025 readiness assessment outlines concrete steps from cryptographic inventory through migration planning.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obstacles to adoption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The main obstacles to widespread PQC adoption including cost, standards uncertainty, and organizational inertia. This last issue is significant given that preparing for the quantum threat requires a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4030898/prepping-for-the-quantum-threat-requires-a-phased-approach-to-crypto-agility.html"&gt;phased approach to crypto agility&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The obstacles to widespread adoption are very real,” Keyfactor’s Hickman says. “A lack of skilled personnel, limited time and competing priorities, and the slow adoption of the existing standards are the top challenges slowing progress.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hickman continues: “Additionally, risk perception varies, especially between security teams and executive leadership, making it harder to align strategies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kevin Hilscher, senior director of product management at DigiCert, says the time horizon is playing a significant role in the PQC preparation gap. “Companies are prioritizing other projects because, let’s face it, 2030 is still more than four years away and other projects take precedence,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, security teams find themselves &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4032035/ransomware-up-179-credential-theft-up-800-2025s-cyber-onslaught-intensifies.html"&gt;increasingly under fire from escalating threats&lt;/a&gt; in the here and now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Organizations often lack the expertise or resources to prioritize PQC while dealing with day-to-day threats,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/katrinarosseini/"&gt;Dr. Katrina Rosseini&lt;/a&gt;, a cybersecurity expert at Ascendant Group. “Standards are still evolving, and deploying quantum-resistant algorithms requires careful testing to avoid breaking critical systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, delays in PQC adoption not only leave organizations vulnerable to future quantum threats but also amplify the vulnerabilities already being targeted by attackers, Dr. Rosseini warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Uncertainty, complexity, and the difficulties in mapping cryptographic assets are also putting a brake on PQC rollouts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Budgets compete with nearer-term threats and not all people are yet aware of the 2030 deprecation of RSA/ECC by NIST, so planning and investment are delayed,” says Sectigo’s Soroko. “Standards and vendor support are still being operationalized, and some algorithms introduce performance overhead or compatibility issues for legacy systems and constrained devices.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Soroko adds: “Skills are scarce and dependencies run through supply chains and cloud services, so end-to-end migration planning and governance slow adoption.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dr. Rosseini also notes that legacy systems and infrastructure can make rolling out new algorithms difficult.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/benjamin-mourad-1678a5/"&gt;Benjamin Mourad&lt;/a&gt;, senior director and solution architect at DMI, sees the main obstacles to widespread adoption being education about quantum computing risks — such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4030898/prepping-for-the-quantum-threat-requires-a-phased-approach-to-crypto-agility.html"&gt;the threat from “harvest now, decrypt later” attacks&lt;/a&gt; — and funding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Conversely, improvements in technology over the past year have made implementing and scaling up cryptographic systems more straightforward, Mourad contends.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Technological improvements over the past 12 months have improved capabilities and lowered the costs to migrate to PQC at scale with containerized, lightweight applications that did not exist over a year ago,” Mourad explains. “The decreasing need for significant investments in hardware and software will make PQC more scalable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="navigating-quantum-uncertainty"&gt;Navigating quantum uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts predict quantum computers capable of breaking current encryption anywhere from five to 20 years away.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This uncertainty can be distracting, Dr. Rosseini says. “The focus has to be on &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552701/the-cisos-guide-to-establishing-quantum-resilience.html"&gt;preparedness and resilience&lt;/a&gt;,” she advises. “Organizations need to inventory sensitive assets, assess system readiness, run pilot programs, and secure key management.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The PwC report should act as a wake-up call, Dr Rosseini adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Organizations that treat PQC as a strategic security initiative now will be positioned to reduce risk and strengthen resilience,” she says. “Those who wait risk leaving themselves exposed to both present and future threats.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074154/cisos-face-quantum-leap-in-prioritizing-quantum-resilience.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-013 – Vulnerability impacting Oracle E-Business Suite - CVE-2025-61882</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-013-vulnerability-impacting-oracle-e-business-suite-cve-2025-61882</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-647)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-647</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-648)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-648</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 suspected human traffickers arrested in Albania and Colombia</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/17-suspected-human-traffickers-arrested-in-albania-and-colombia</link>
      <description>17 suspected human traffickers arrested in Albania and Colombia. The criminal network is believed to have sexually exploited over 50 victims in Albania and Croatia, trafficked from South America to Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/17-suspected-human-traffickers-arrested-in-albania-and-colombia</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-649)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-649</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-650)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-650</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 19:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol welcomes the European Investment Bank to its secure information exchange network</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</link>
      <description>The European Investment Bank (EIB) has today joined Europol’s Secure Information Exchange Network Application (SIENA), marking a new step in the cooperation between the two institutions to protect the EU’s financial interests and combat serious crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV25-651)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av25-651</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-603) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-603</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esri security advisory (AV25-652)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/esri-security-advisory-av25-652</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol conference warns: cybercrime fight hinges on access to data</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</link>
      <description>Criminals are exploiting encryption, anonymisation and emerging technologies faster than regulators and law enforcement can respond – making access to data the decisive challenge in the fight against cybercrime. This was the warning sounded at Europol’s 4th Annual Cybercrime Conference this week.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-conference-warns-cybercrime-fight-hinges-access-to-data</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-653)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-653</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-654)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-654</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV25-655)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av25-655</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luxury hybrid car thieves taken down in Belgium, Italy and Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</link>
      <description>A highly specialised organised crime network responsible for the theft of more than 100 luxury hybrid cars has been dismantled in an international operation led by the Italian Carabinieri with support from Europol and Eurojust. The estimated value of all stolen cars is of at least EUR 3 million.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/luxury-hybrid-car-thieves-taken-down-in-belgium-italy-and-spain</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government considered destroying its data hub after decade-long intrusion</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074876/government-considered-destroying-its-data-hub-after-decade-long-intrusion.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A Chinese-sponsored cyber attack was so damaging that it was briefly proposed that an entire data hub be destroyed, according to &lt;a href="https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/here-be-dragons-the-truth-about-chinese-espionage/"&gt;British news magazine The Spectator&lt;/a&gt;. It observed that the attack accessing confidential UK government data was just one manifestation of a continuing series of threats to British IT infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That breach is but one example of the risks faced not only by the UK, but by governments and organizations everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-15/china-accessed-classified-uk-systems-for-a-decade-officials-say"&gt;news service Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;, two former senior security officials and other government officials familiar with the matter revealed that China has routinely accessed low- and medium-level classification information on UK government servers for at least a decade. This included information marked “official-sensitive” and “secret,” in addition to some material on the government’s secure IT networks, although no information designated “top secret” was compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chinese threats to the UK infrastructure are very much at the forefront of government thinking right now, given the &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgd5jgzdweo"&gt;collapse of the trial&lt;/a&gt; of two Britons accused of passing secret documents to Chinese authorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack on the data hub, through which classified government information was exchanged, came about following the sale of the company controlling it to a Chinese entity. While the destruction of the data hub was considered, the government found alternative ways to protect the data, according to Bloomberg. However, the breach was serious enough for then British Prime Minister Boris Johnson to commission a report on threats, including digital surveillance and cyber attacks, posed by China. That report was never publicly released and, The Spectator said, technical details of the attack on the hub remain classified.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-hub-attack-particularly-critical"&gt;Data hub attack ‘particularly critical’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack on the data hub is seen as particularly critical. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jakemooreuk/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Jake Moore&lt;/a&gt;, global cybersecurity advisor with software company ESET said,  “The fact that ministers once considered destroying a data hub holding sensitive government data after it was sold to a China-aligned entity shows how seriously the UK views control over critical infrastructure. Physically destroying the site would have stopped services and wiped forensic evidence, yet it underscores the depth of concern about potential foreign control of national assets”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/grjk83/"&gt;Gavin Knapp&lt;/a&gt;, cyber threat intelligence lead at &lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Bridewell, a supplier to the UK government critical network infrastructure, endorsed the severity of this approach. He said, “it’s like when a device is compromised, the only way to truly be sure there are no remnants, or unidentified backdoors is to restore the asset to a known good state. In the physical realm, in particular a data centre, to sweep and verify there is no enduring threat actor / spy presence is much more difficult, and at a state secrets level the required effort to treat or terminate the risk requires a huge amount of effort and cost to bring risks down to an acceptable level.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While it’s not clear exactly how the data hub had been compromised, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/martinariley/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Martin Riley&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at Bridewell, said, “The main point of entry may have been a VPN, as is common with Chinese actors, but if they have already moved across the environment and escalated privileges, then the impact would be wider.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Riley noted that when the government said it had discovered another way to protect the data, it was likely that it had patched a vulnerability “after performing incident response to understand the breadth of the breach and how it was initially accessed.”                                                                                                                    &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="organizations-cant-ignore-the-supply-chain"&gt;Organizations can’t ignore the supply chain&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because of the constant threat from state-backed attackers, organizations everywhere need to be on constant alert, said Knapp, adding, “CISOs across government must assume they’re already being targeted, particularly by state-linked advanced persistent threats (APTs). These groups are difficult to detect because they prioritize stealth and long-term access over disruption. This raises key questions around how well organizations detect insider threats and hunt for compromises on edge devices, especially where vendors manage the hardware, making forensics more complex.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Knapp warned that it was not sufficient to make government infrastructure more secure while ignoring the supply chain. “Even the most secure networks can be breached when attackers exploit users, contractors, or third-party systems to gain a foothold. They often compromise edge devices or exploit misconfigurations to move laterally within environments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Remember, state-backed attackers play a long game, embedding themselves within critical networks for months or years,” he said. “Techniques such as &lt;a href="https://www.team-cymru.com/post/an-introduction-to-operational-relay-box-orb-networks-unpatched-forgotten-and-obscured" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Operational Relay Boxes&lt;/a&gt; (ORBs) allow them to mask their activity and bypass endpoint detection tools, making attribution extremely difficult.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074876/government-considered-destroying-its-data-hub-after-decade-long-intrusion.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 23:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Major blow to billion-euro glass eel trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>The latest iteration of Operation LAKE, which ran from October 2024 to June 2025, uncovered large-scale trafficking networks and disrupted the flow of live eels destined for illegal farms in Asia.The operation led to:16,131 inspections carried out across Europe26 arrests22 tonnes of glass eels seizedOrganised crime at the heart of traffickingInvestigations revealed that several organised crime groups were driving the...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/major-blow-to-billion-euro-glass-eel-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Counterfeit and substandard food worth EUR 95 million seized in global operation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</link>
      <description>Europol, OLAF, DG SANTE and 31 countries across Europe and beyond, together with food and beverage producers from the private sector, joined forces in the fourteenth edition of Operation OPSON. This yearly effort targets the criminals behind counterfeit and substandard food and beverages. Law enforcement, customs and food regulatory agencies seized 259 012 packages, 1 416 168 litres of beverages and 11 566 958 kilograms of food, including meat and seafood.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/counterfeit-and-substandard-food-worth-eur-95-million-seized-in-global-operation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted five key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-656)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-656</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-657)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-657</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-658)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-658</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-659)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-659</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.06</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–660)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-660</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV25-661)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av25-661</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-662)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-662</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-663)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-663</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-664)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-664</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-665)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-665</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.11</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory - October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-666)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-667)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-667</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-668)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-668</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F5 security advisory (AV25-669)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/f5-security-advisory-av25-669</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-670)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-670</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-671)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-671</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-672)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-672</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-014 Security Incident impacting F5</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-014-security-incident-impacting-f5</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-673)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-673</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-674)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-674</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-675)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-675</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-676)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-676</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV25-677)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av25-677</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-616) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-616</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zimbra security advisory (AV25-678)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zimbra-security-advisory-av25-678</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
