<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:36:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Phishing campaign chains old Office flaw with fileless XWorm RAT to evade detection</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131340/phishing-campaign-chains-old-office-flaw-with-fileless-xworm-rat-to-evade-detection.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fortinet researchers have disclosed a new phishing campaign delivering the commercially available &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064720/xworm-campaign-shows-a-shift-toward-fileless-malware-and-in-memory-evasion-tactics.html" target="_blank"&gt;XWorm&lt;/a&gt; malware, chaining a years-old Microsoft Office vulnerability with fileless execution to escape detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The campaign, which uses multi-themed phishing emails and a malicious Excel add-in, ultimately deploys the modular remote access trojan (RAT) capable of encrypted command-and control (C2) and plugin-based expansion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This campaign is striking in its ordinariness,” said Shane Barney, chief information security officer at Keeper Security. “There’s no breakthrough technique here. It’s a clean execution chain built from components we’ve all seen before. The sophistication isn’t in the novelty, it’s in the assembly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers used a phishing email carrying a malicious Excel add-in that exploits &lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2018-0802" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2018-0802&lt;/a&gt;, a memory corruption flaw in Office patched in 2018. The attack then continues into HTA and PowerShell-based execution to load additional components of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Attackers used a familiar entry point&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a Fortinet blog &lt;a href="https://www.fortinet.com/blog/threat-research/deep-dive-into-new-xworm-campaign-utilizing-multiple-themed-phishing-emails" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, the campaign relies on business-themed phishing lures and the legacy remote code execution vulnerability in the Microsoft Equation Editor that defenders have known for years. Fortinet noted that the continued success of CVE-2018-0802 suggests patching gaps remain a viable attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, said the pairing of routine phishing with modern backend tradecraft is what makes the campaign notable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What stands out here is how ‘old’ and ‘routine’ the front end is, and how modern the back end remains,” he said. “The lure is a familiar business pretexting and a malicious Excel add-in, but the real signal is the attacker’s confidence that legacy Office exploit paths still convert at scale. The attachment abuses CVE-2018-0802, then pivots quickly into HTA plus PowerShell to keep the heavy lifting off disk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fortinet researchers added that the remote code privileges gained through CVE-2018-0802 further allow execution of HTA and PowerShell components, keeping much of the activity off disk. “That combination is a reminder that patch hygiene and macro or script execution policy are still doing more real work than most organizations want to admit,” Soroko added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Fileless .NET stage and a modular XWorm core&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond initial access, Fortinet observed a fileless .NET stage loaded directly into memory, followed by process hollowing into msbuild.exe, a legitimate &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/657828/malicious-package-campaign-on-nuget-abuses-msbuild-integrations.html"&gt;Microsoft build&lt;/a&gt; tool capable of executing .NET code. The choice of msbuild.exe aligns with the malware’s runtime requirements while helping it blend into normal system activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A fileless .NET stage loaded in memory, followed by process hollowing into msbuild.exe, is a clean ‘blend in’ move that leverages a legitimate .NET-capable binary and complicates attribution for simplistic detections,” Soroko said. “Fortinet’s rationale for msbuild.exe is especially useful for defenders because it ties the LOLBin choice to the malware’s .NET runtime needs, not just generic masquerading.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once active, XWorm communicates with its C2 using an AES-encrypted packet, which supports a broad plugin ecosystem. That modularity, the researchers noted, expands its capabilities beyond remote access, enabling credential theft, data exfiltration, disruption, and modernization paths depending on what the operator wants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fortinet said XWorm supports a wide range of operator commands, including system control (CLOSE, uninstall, update), file download and execution (DW, LN), plugin loading, screenshot capture ($Cap), keylogger retrieval, DDoS control, and shutdown or restart functions. The disclosure also listed indicators of compromise tied to the campaign, including phishing URLs and domains used to host HTA and loader files, the C2 server, file hashes for the malicious Excel attachment, and the final XWorm payload. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Barney emphasized that the broader risk hinges less on the malware label and more on post-compromise controls. “Campaigns like this expose a simple reality: the entry vector is predictable. The tooling is commoditized. The only real variable is whether the environment limits what an intruder can do next,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131340/phishing-campaign-chains-old-office-flaw-with-fileless-xworm-rat-to-evade-detection.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-093)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-093</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-094)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-094</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-095)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-095</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical BeyondTrust RS vulnerability exploited in active attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4132368/critical-beyondtrust-rs-vulnerability-exploited-in-active-attacks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers warn that a critical vulnerability patched this week in BeyondTrust Remote Support is being exploited in the wild to compromise self-hosted deployments, including Bomgar remote support appliances, which included affected versions of the impacted software.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bomgar, a provider of privileged identity and access management products, acquired BeyondTrust in 2018, adopting the latter’s brand name. Bomgar on-premises hardware appliances, known as BeyondTrust B-series appliances, provide secure remote access to enterprise networks, but many hardware models &lt;a href="https://www.beyondtrust.com/eos-eol/appliances/b-series#:~:text=Secure%20Remote%20Access%20Hardware%20Support&amp;amp;text=From%20the%20date%20of%20purchase,appliance%20limited%20to%20virtual%20appliance."&gt;have reached end of life&lt;/a&gt;, with customers encouraged to upgrade to either the virtual appliance or BeyondTrust’s SaaS offerings: Privileged Remote Access (Cloud) and Remote Support (Cloud).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers from security firm Arctic Wolf &lt;a href="https://arcticwolf.com/resources/blog/update-arctic-wolf-observes-threat-campaign-targeting-beyondtrust-remote-support-following-cve-2026-1731-poc-availability/"&gt;have detected attacks that compromised Bomgar appliances&lt;/a&gt; through &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4130415/beyondtrust-fixes-critical-rce-flaw-in-remote-access-tools.html"&gt;the CVE-2026-1731 flaw patched this week&lt;/a&gt;. The attackers attempted to then deploy the SimpleHelp remote management and monitoring (RMM) tool and perform lateral movement to other systems on the network.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Renamed SimpleHelp binaries were created through Bomgar processes using the SYSTEM account,” the researchers said in a report today. “These executables were saved to the ProgramData root directory and executed from there. Binary names include &lt;code&gt;remote access.exe&lt;/code&gt; and others.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attackers also managed to create domain accounts using the &lt;code&gt;net user&lt;/code&gt; command and then added them to administrative groups such as “enterprise admins” or “domain admins.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The AdsiSearcher tool was used to search the Active Directory environment for other computers and PSexec was used to install SimpleHelp on multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers also observed Impacket SMBv2 session setup requests in affected environments. Impacket is a Python library that can be used to decode network traffic and is often used in conjunction with sniffing tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CVE-2026-1731 is a critical pre-authentication command injection vulnerability that impacts BeyondTrust Remote Support (RS) and Privileged Remote Access (PRA). The company released patches for multiple versions of the impacted software, but older versions of RS need to be updated first before the patch can be applied, which could be a problem for appliances that are no longer supported and have reached end of life.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A proof-of-concept exploit was published on GitHub so it’s not surprising that attacks followed soon after. As a remote access solution, BeyondTrust RS is an attractive target for both state-sponsored attackers and ransomware groups. The US Department of the Treasury had some of its workstations compromised after hackers exploited vulnerabilities in SaaS instances of BeyondTrust RS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4132368/critical-beyondtrust-rs-vulnerability-exploited-in-active-attacks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why identity recovery is now central to cyber resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131708/why-identity-recovery-is-now-central-to-cyber-resilience.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ransomware has permanently changed how security leaders think about risk. Verizon’s &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 Data Breach Investigations Report&lt;/a&gt; found that ransomware was involved in 44% of all breaches. For small and midsize businesses, the problem is big; ransomware was involved in nearly nine out of 10 breaches, compared to it playing a role in 39% of incidents among large organizations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many of these attacks begin by breaching privileged accounts and identity infrastructure, targeting identity because of its reach and influence. Compromising identity infrastructure such as  Active Directory enables adversaries  to escalate privileges and block legitimate users from their own systems within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even when those applications and data are restored, a compromised identity layer can leave an organization locked out of its environment for the long term, stalling recovery efforts across the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why identity recovery is now a central ingredient in cyber resilience. Identity systems are deeply integrated into authentication and access pathways. When they fail, recovery becomes even more complex. Security leaders know that recovering identity is about bringing systems back up and  restoring access securely, so  attackers cannot find their way back in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A board-level issue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Boards of directors and regulators are now treating resilience as a core component of enterprise risk management. Cyber insurance providers require evidence of tested recovery plans, immutable backups, and defined recovery time and recovery point objectives before underwriting coverage. Regulatory frameworks like the General Data Protection Regulation and the California Consumer Privacy Act impose stiff penalties for extended downtime and data exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, organizations are moving beyond traditional backup strategies toward recovery engineering. Recovery is a designed capability rather than an emergency response. It relies on automation, orchestration, and repeatable processes that reduce dependence on manual intervention during high-stress incidents. It also aligns technical recovery with business priorities, helping CISOs communicate resilience in terms that executives and boards understand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To reduce downtime and regain control quickly after a ransomware or identity-based attack, CISOs should prioritize these capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity resilience:&lt;/strong&gt; Implement  immutable backups and automated recovery  for identity systems such as Active Directory.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero-trust architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; Apply least-privilege access and continuous authentication to reduce the blast radius of an attack.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated orchestration:&lt;/strong&gt; Limit manual steps in recovery workflows so teams can respond faster under pressure.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory readiness:&lt;/strong&gt; Make audit-ready reporting and compliance validation part of resilience planning, not an afterthought.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-ready protection:&lt;/strong&gt; Account for risks introduced by autonomous agents and AI-driven operations by securing data environments and enabling fast rollback of damaging actions.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup platform isolation:&lt;/strong&gt; Treat the backup environment as a separate security domain that can function as a minimum viable recovery environment when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cognizant and Rubrik help organizations improve cyber resilience with a unified, service-based model that integrates data protection, identity resilience, and business continuity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rubrik provides capabilities such as immutable storage, rapid ransomware recovery, sensitive data discovery, and identity resilience, including support for restoring Active Directory environments. Cognizant brings orchestration across technologies and domain expertise to align recovery actions with business outcomes, ensuring that restoration efforts support operational continuity and compliance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Learn more about how &lt;a href="https://www.cognizant.com/us/en/services/cloud-solutions#spy-featured-work" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cognizant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.rubrik.com/products" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rubrik&lt;/a&gt; are helping organizations &lt;a href="https://news.cognizant.com/2025-10-27-Cognizant-and-Rubrik-Announce-Strategic-Partnership-to-Deliver-Business-Resilience-as-a-Service" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;strengthen business resilience&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like further details or have specific questions, send an email to: &lt;a href="mailto:BusinessResilience@cognizant.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BusinessResilience@cognizant.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Sriramkumar Kumaresan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 500w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=247%2C300&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 247w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=138%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 138w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=69%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 69w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=395%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 395w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=296%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 296w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Sriram-Headshot2.jpg?resize=206%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 206w" width="500" height="608" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Cognizant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sriram Kumaresan leads the Global Cloud, Infrastructure and Security practice atCognizant, overseeing approximately 35,000 professionals. With over 25 years of experience, he excels in building and scaling businesses from strategy to execution. Sriram is responsible for driving market share (strategy, GTM and growth) and mindshare (offering, partner strategy and market positioning) through strategic approaches, customer centricity and the deep technical expertise inCognizant’s Cloud, Infrastructure and Security business. Beyond his professional achievements, he is also a mentor and advocate for diversity in tech, aiming to inspire future IT leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131708/why-identity-recovery-is-now-central-to-cyber-resilience.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.85</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers turn bossware against the bosses</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131789/hackers-turn-bossware-against-the-bosses.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A threat actor is abusing an employee monitoring application and a remote monitoring and management platform in an attempt to deploy ransomware and steal cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/blog/employee-monitoring-simplehelp-abused-in-ransomware-operations" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to researchers at Huntress&lt;/a&gt;, the unknown threat actor is leveraging NetworkLookout’s Net Monitor for Employees Professional – which, despite its name, includes remote access tools – and SimpleHelp, a suite of tools commonly used by IT teams and managed service providers for remote monitoring and management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These applications might already be in use in an IT environment, or are downloaded by the attacker once they get network access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one case, the attack chain culminated in an attempted deployment of Crazy ransomware. In another, the combination of applications was used to hunt for cryptocurrency-related keywords on the victim’s compromised computer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The combination of these two applications is unique, says Huntress, although SimpleHelp has a history of being abused by hackers as a post-exploitation persistence mechanism. It offers a lightweight agent, support for gateway redundancy, and ability to operate over common ports. Net Monitor for Employees, whose purpose is to catch employees wasting work time on illegal activity, is used here as a primary remote access channel. To a threat actor, it offers reverse connections over common ports, process and service name masquerading, built-in shell execution, and the ability to silently deploy via standard Windows installation mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/authors/anna-pham" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anna Pham&lt;/a&gt;, a Huntress senior tactical response analyst, called the combination of the two applications for attacks “dangerous,” particularly because in one case the threat actor got access to the victim’s IT infrastructure through a vendor’s compromised VPN account.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Using applications and tools already on the network that might appear legitimate to IT to disguise attacks, also known as a ‘living off the land’ strategy, is “very clever and sneaky,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="two-attacks-discovered"&gt;Two attacks discovered&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress discovered two incidents using this tactic, one late in January and one early this month. Shared infrastructure, overlapping indicators of compromise, and consistent tradecraft across both cases make Huntress strongly believe a single threat actor or group was behind this activity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the first case, Huntress detected suspicious account manipulation on a customer’s computer via Net Monitor For Employees, which included attempts to reset passwords and create additional accounts. The application was already in use in the environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How the attacker got into Net Monitor isn’t clear. But their next step was to use it to download the SimpleHelp remote management agent, which was used to execute a number of commands, including tampering with Windows Defender to evade detection. That was unsuccessful, but it didn’t stop the threat actor from then trying to deploy the Crazy strain of ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the second case, also involving a Huntress customer, the threat actor leveraged a compromised vendor’s SSL VPN account for initial access to the IT network. It isn’t known how the threat actor got hold of the vendor’s credentials. But once inside, the hacker used Windows Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP) to install the Net Monitor for Employees Professional agent through PowerShell. The agent was then disguised as a legitimate system process with a name that mimicked Microsoft’s OneDrive service. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shortly after that, the threat actor installed SimpleHelp as an additional persistent remote access channel. The SimpleHelp agent was also configured with monitoring triggers for cryptocurrency-related keywords, as well as searching for remote access tool keywords to determine whether anyone else was connecting to the compromised machine. The threat actor also used Net Monitor for network reconnaissance on a compromised domain controller.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ensure-these-risks-are-catalogued"&gt;Ensure these risks are catalogued&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute, said this report is an example of how corporate IT teams build infrastructure that attackers then abuse. It’s known that employee monitoring software and security software have been misused like this in the past, he said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that software including agents that reach out to remote systems to collect data can often execute code on those systems, so they can investigate suspect activity. But, he warned, if not properly controlled, they can be abused by an attacker to execute malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs must ensure that these risks are properly catalogued and mitigated,” he said. “Any actions performed by these agents must be monitored and, if possible, restricted. The abuse of these systems is a special case of ‘living off the land’ attacks. The attacker attempts to abuse valid existing software to perform malicious actions. This abuse is often difficult to detect.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked for comment on the report, a spokesperson for NetworkLookout, the parent company of Net Monitor, noted in an email that the Net Monitor for Employees Agent can be installed only by a user who already has administrative privileges on the computer where the agent is to be installed. Without administrative privileges, the spokesperson added, “installation isn’t possible.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“So,” the spokesperson concluded, “if you don’t want our software installed on a computer, please ensure that administrative access is not granted to unauthorized users.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-csos-should-do"&gt;What CSOs should do&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress analyst Pham said to defend against attacks combining Net Monitor for Employees Professional and SimpleHelp, infosec pros should inventory all applications so unapproved installations can be detected. Legitimate apps should be protected with robust identity and access management solutions, including multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Net Monitor for Employees should only be installed on endpoints that don’t have full access privileges to sensitive data or critical servers, she added, because it has the ability to run commands and control systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She also noted that Huntress sees a lot of rogue remote management tools on its customers’ IT networks, many of which have been installed by unwitting employees clicking on phishing emails. This points to the importance of security awareness training, she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Infosec leaders should also note that in June 2025, the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) warned that ransomware operators had &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa25-163a" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;leveraged unpatched instances of a vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; in SimpleHelp Remote Monitoring and Management (RMM) to compromise customers of a utility billing software provider. The advisory also provided advice on how to mitigate the risks, noting, “This incident reflects a broader pattern of ransomware actors targeting organizations through unpatched versions of SimpleHelp RMM since January 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131789/hackers-turn-bossware-against-the-bosses.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 02:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 key trends reshaping the SIEM market</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829750/4-key-trends-reshaping-the-siem-market.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security information and event management (SIEM) platforms have evolved far beyond their basic log collection and correlation roots.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With cyber threats moving too fast for manual intervention, leading vendors have been integrating artificial intelligence and machine learning technologies into their SIEM platforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/566677/12-top-siem-tools-rated-and-compared.html"&gt;modern SIEM platforms&lt;/a&gt; now incorporate &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574295/11-top-xdr-tools-and-how-to-evaluate-them.html"&gt;extended detection and response (XDR)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570673/5-tips-for-getting-started-with-soar.html"&gt;security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR)&lt;/a&gt;, enabling real-time threat detection and automated remediation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SIEMs have become a platform to monitor log data for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3822459/what-is-anomaly-detection-behavior-based-analysis-for-cyber-threats.html"&gt;anomalies and suspicious events&lt;/a&gt; before triggering alerts based on unusual behavior and detection rules.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“[SIEM] often serves as the workspace for security analysts to investigate incidents that are correlations of alerts with other contexts such as asset information, vulnerabilities, and threat intelligence,” according to analyst group IDC. “IDC expects that in the future, the SIEM will also be the response center of the SOC with automated handling of many incidents via playbooks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And as enterprise cloud use continues to rise, Google’s Cloud Cybersecurity Forecast predicts that SIEM products will become central to enterprise security operations centers (SOCs) ingesting “everything from cloud logs to endpoint telemetry.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Joe Turner, global director of research and business development at market intelligence firm Context, notes that larger attack surfaces and more sophisticated attacks are spurring enterprises to invest in SIEM in combination with other technologies, including XDR and SOAR, as a platform to correlate, detect, and remediate threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;SIEM, XDR, and SOAR convergence&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The convergence of SIEM with security tools such as XDR and SOAR is a major factor driving growth in the market.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/524286/what-is-siem-security-information-and-event-management-explained.html"&gt;SIEM provides log analytics and broad visibility&lt;/a&gt;, XDR extends detection across endpoints and cloud, and SOAR orchestrates response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When SIEM detects a security incident, SOAR triggers automated response actions via XDR — isolating compromised endpoints, disabling compromised user accounts, or blocking malicious traffic in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By converging SIEM with XDR and SOAR, organizations get a unified security platform that consolidates data, reduces complexity, and improves response times, as systems can be configured to automatically contain threats without any manual intervention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2024, Context logged a 580% increase in SIEM and XDR technologies being sold together. Services sold with both SOAR and SIEM tied together increased a smaller but still significant 22% in 2024, according to the market intelligence agency.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The term SIEM++ is being used to refer to this next step in SIEM, which is designed for more current needs within security ops asking for automation, AI, and real-time responses. Hence, the increase in SIEM alongside other tools,” Context’s Turner says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;George McKenna, director at UK-based managed service provider Emerging T-Tech, tells CSO that the convergence of SIEM with XDR and SOAR enables enterprises to streamline operations, improve detection effectiveness, and reduce mean time to resolution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Legacy SIEM, while effective for log aggregation and correlation, lacks the granular visibility and automated response capabilities necessary in today’s threat landscape,” McKenna explains. “XDR addresses this gap by integrating endpoint, network, and cloud telemetry, providing a holistic view of potential threats.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;McKenna adds: “SOAR then enables the automation of incident response workflows, accelerating mitigation and remediation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="market-split-as-midrange-sales-offset-sme-slump"&gt;Market split as midrange sales offset SME slump&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A year on, Context’s data shows that this ongoing convergence of SIEM with security tools such as XDR and SOAR has triggered a structural split in the market.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Large midmarket firms are doubling down on unified platforms for compliance, while smaller organizations are investing less in SIEM entirely in favour of MDR and vulnerability management,” according to Context’s Turner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The overall SIEM market slid from 20% growth in 2024 to a far more modest 4% in 2025. By contrast, the midmarket (501–1,000 seats) saw 288% year-on-year growth — the main driver being the desire to demonstrate compliance with the EU’s NIS2 directive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The full enforcement of the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3568787/eus-nis2-directive-for-cybersecurity-resilience-enters-full-enforcement.html"&gt;NIS2&lt;/a&gt; directive in Europe has forced midtier companies to move from basic monitoring to auditable security operations,” Context’s Turner explains. “These companies are too large for simple tools but too small for massive 24/7 internal SOCs. They are buying the SIEM++ platforms to serve as their central source of truth for auditors.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By contrast the SMB market (under 500 seats) for SIEM products dropped 23% last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“SMBs are investing much more into managed detection and response (MDR), which grew 35% in the 10–50 seat band and 26% in the 50-500 seat band,” according to Turner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The strong shift away from SIEM among smaller businesses is driven by cold hard economics: A cheaper alternative technology offers better results with less implementation headaches for small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Why pay $66 per seat for a tool you can’t run? SMBs are perhaps choosing to buy the result (MDR) rather than the engine (SIEM),” Turner says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Turbulent times for cloud-based SIEM&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The shift to cloud-based SIEM, previously seen as a way organizations seek a more scalable and cost-effective platform, has fallen out of favour.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cloud-native SIEMs reduce operational overhead and enable faster investigations and collaboration across security, DevOps, and platform teams — key for modern security operations,” says Vera Chan, senior product marketing manager of cloud SIEM at cloud and security monitoring firm Datadog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud-based SIEM solutions are plug-and-play security platforms, so organizations can subscribe, integrate assets via API, automate responses using SOAR, and set up tailored detection rules.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Modern cloud-based SIEM goes beyond log management,” Muhammad Ali, cyber solutions consultant at comms and cyber-security provider Exponential-e tells CSO. “It’s an intelligent security hub with built-in SOAR capabilities, seamless API integrations with cloud-based XDR/EDR solutions, and real-time global threat intelligence.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud-based SIEMs remove the need for expensive hardware upgrades &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3596280/costly-and-struggling-the-challenges-of-legacy-siem-solutions.html"&gt;associated with traditional on-premises deployments&lt;/a&gt;, offering scalability and faster response times alongside potentially more cost-effective usage-based pricing models. According to Context, the cost of SIEM on-prem went up 116% to an average of $93 per seat in 2024, whereas cloud-based SIEM costs went down 26% to $77 per seat over the same period.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 12 months, however, and the market has turned on its head.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud-based SIEM costs continued to decline in 2025, but at a slower rate to $66 per seat. Context sees AI costs playing a factor in the slowdown. “Vendors are passing on the high compute costs of gen AI features to the end-user,” Turner says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By contrast, on-prem SIEM costs have dropped 39% year-on-year to reach $63 per seat — lower than SIEM in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Legacy vendors have entered a price war to stop cloud repatriation,” Turner says. “For high-volume data, on-prem is now ironically the value choice for the first time in a long time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The easy phase of “cloud is cheaper” looks to be over.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Going into 2026, cloud SIEM is the premium choice for those who want AI-driven automation, while on-prem has become the go to for budget-conscious, high-volume log storage,” Turner concludes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Managed SIEM has also taken a hit, as 2025 witnessed an 88% drop in SIEM delivered via MSPs, bucking a recent trend of significant growth for SIEMaaS — previously seen as a means to avoid hiring or retaining an in-house security team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“MSPs have stopped reselling ‘managed SIEM’ as a line item,” according to Context’s Turner. “Instead, they are bundling SIEM technology into MDR services.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 88% drop in MSP-delivered SIEM isn’t a collapse; it’s a shift toward platformization and integration, Turner emphasizes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“SIEM has become the ‘Intel Inside’ if you will … of the MDR market,” Turner says. “It’s there, but the customer is paying for the protection, not the platform.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AI reshaping the SIEM landscape&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Static rule-based SIEMs struggle to keep pace with today’s sophisticated cyber threats, which is why AI-powered SIEM platforms use real-time machine learning (ML) to analyze vast amounts of security data, improving their ability to identify anomalies and previously unseen attack techniques that legacy technologies might miss.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ML models establish baseline behavior for users, assets, and network traffic, continuously monitoring for deviations that indicate potential threats. When an anomaly is detected, the trained model generates alerts, leading to faster threat detection and response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI-powered SIEM solutions not only detect threats but also automate investigation processes, correlating real-time incidents with global threat intelligence,” Exponential-e’s Ali says. “By integrating with SOAR and XDR/EDR platforms, automated responses can be triggered or incidents escalated to security analysts for further action.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ali adds: “This significantly improves incident response efficiency and supports a more efficient and agile security operations center that’s one step ahead of attackers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-powered SIEMs can prioritize critical alerts, recommend response actions, and automate remediation, reducing noise and fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As adversaries leverage AI, security teams must adopt AI-driven automation to stay ahead,” Datadog’s Chan says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Industry consolidation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SIEM market is experiencing rapid consolidation as vendors look to develop more comprehensive and powerful platforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Organizations demand fewer tools, deeper integrations, and frictionless end-to-end security operations — and vendors that can deliver this will shape the future of cybersecurity,” Datadog’s Chan says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Notable SIEM M&amp;amp;A activity over the past few years includes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/identity-security/raising-the-bar-in-security-operations"&gt;Google acquiring Siemplify&lt;/a&gt; (a SOAR company) in 2022 to integrate into Google Chronicle SIEM&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Last July, &lt;a href="https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/company/press/2025/palo-alto-networks-announces-agreement-to-acquire-cyberark--the-identity-security-leader"&gt;Palo Alto Networks (PAN) acquired CyberArk&lt;/a&gt; for around $25 billion in a deal that extends privileged identity protection into its security platform, paving the way to secure the new wave of autonomous AI agents. The deal follows &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/new/announcements/palo-alto-networks-ibm-qradar-saas"&gt;PAN’s acquisition of IBM’s Qradar SaaS business&lt;/a&gt; for $500 million in September 2024.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zscaler.com/press/zscaler-completes-acquisition-red-canary-accelerate-innovations-agentic-ai-driven-security"&gt;Zscaler agreed to acquire Red Canary&lt;/a&gt; for around $675 million in May 2025. The deal delivers MDR outcomes directly via the cloud stack, bypassing MSPs (managed service providers).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/en-us/press-releases/crowdstrike-to-acquire-onum/"&gt;CrowdStrike bought Spanish cybersecurity startup Onum&lt;/a&gt; for around $290 million in August 2025. The acquisition offers CrowdStrike the opportunity to reduce cloud ingestion costs for its SIEM clients using intelligent optimization, clearing the path towards faster incident response.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.exabeam.com/resources/briefs/exabeam-and-logrhythm-merge-becoming-a-pure-play-secops-leader/"&gt;Exabeam merging with LogRhythm&lt;/a&gt; in July 2024&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://investor.cisco.com/news/news-details/2024/Cisco-Completes-Acquisition-of-Splunk/default.aspx"&gt;Cisco buying Splunk&lt;/a&gt; for approximately $28 billion in March 2024&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/524286/what-is-siem-security-information-and-event-management-explained.html"&gt;What is SIEM? Improving security posture through event log data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/566677/12-top-siem-tools-rated-and-compared.html"&gt;SIEM buyer’s guide: Top 15 security information and event management tools — and how to choose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3596280/costly-and-struggling-the-challenges-of-legacy-siem-solutions.html"&gt;Costly and struggling: the challenges of legacy SIEM solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829750/4-key-trends-reshaping-the-siem-market.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why key management becomes the weakest link in a post-quantum and AI-driven security world</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131506/why-key-management-becomes-the-weakest-link-in-a-post-quantum-and-ai-driven-security-world.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When people talk about cryptography, they usually talk about algorithms. RSA versus ECC. Classical versus post quantum. &lt;a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/uk-gdpr-guidance-and-resources/security/encryption/"&gt;Encryption&lt;/a&gt; strength measured in bits and curves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In practice, none of that matters unless keys are created, stored, rotated and retired correctly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/key-management"&gt;Key management&lt;/a&gt; is the discipline that governs the entire lifecycle of cryptographic keys, from generation to destruction. It determines who can use a key, for what purpose, for how long and under what conditions. When done well, key management enables confidentiality, integrity, authentication and nonrepudiation across systems. When done poorly, it silently undermines every security control built on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The benefits of strong key management are not theoretical. It reduces blast radius during breaches, enables faster incident response, supports regulatory compliance and makes security systems resilient to change. Most importantly, it allows organizations to evolve cryptography without breaking the business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yet in many environments I encounter, key management is treated as plumbing. It is assumed to be solved once encryption is enabled. That assumption is now one of the most dangerous in enterprise security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The algorithm obsession and the operational gap&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/post-quantum-cryptography"&gt;Post-quantum cryptography&lt;/a&gt; discussions often sound reassuringly academic. Standards bodies publish candidate algorithms. Roadmaps promise seamless migration. From a distance, it appears that the hard work is happening elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But when I step into real systems, I see an operational reality that does not match the narrative. Keys are long-lived. Rotation is manual or avoided altogether. Ownership is unclear. Audit trails are incomplete. Recovery procedures are rarely tested.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI-driven systems widen this gap even further. Models rely on keys to access data, invoke services, sign artifacts and verify integrity. These keys often live inside fast-moving pipelines that bypass traditional review cycles. When something goes wrong, the failure is rarely isolated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The result is a growing mismatch between cryptographic ambition and operational readiness. We invest in stronger algorithms while leaving the weakest link untouched.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why post-quantum readiness is really a key lifecycle problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Post-quantum cryptography is often framed as a future threat. That framing misses the real challenge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The risk is not the moment a quantum computer breaks an algorithm. The risk is the long transition period before and after that moment. During this phase, organizations must support hybrid cryptography, manage multiple trust models and rotate keys across heterogeneous systems without downtime.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my experience, most enterprises are not prepared for this. They struggle to answer basic questions today. Where are our keys? Which applications depend on them? How quickly can we replace them if needed?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without clear answers, crypto agility is impossible. You cannot switch algorithms at scale if you cannot rotate keys safely and predictably.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Post-quantum readiness, then, is less about choosing the right algorithm and more about building the operational muscle to change cryptography without fear.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AI systems change how keys are used and abused&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI introduces a shift that many security teams underestimate. Traditional applications use keys in relatively predictable ways. AI systems do not.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Inference pipelines scale dynamically. Autonomous agents interact with multiple services. Decisions are made without human intervention. In these environments, &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework"&gt;keys protect not just data, but behavior&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have seen cases where a single compromised key allowed an attacker to influence downstream decisions rather than simply access information. That is a fundamentally different kind of risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why key management for AI systems must evolve. Rotation intervals must shrink. Usage patterns must be monitored. Keys must be tightly scoped to purpose rather than reused for convenience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If AI is the brain of modern systems, keys are the nervous system. When the nervous system is compromised, control is lost entirely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The hidden danger of long-lived trust&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Long-lived trust has survived for decades because it was convenient. Certificates are valid for years. Shared keys reused across environments. Secrets embedded in configuration files that nobody wants to touch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a post quantum and AI-driven world, these practices become liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Quantum-capable adversaries can harvest encrypted data today and decrypt it later. Long-lived keys increase the value of that data. AI-driven attacks can exploit exposed keys at machine speed, long before humans can respond.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Short-lived, purpose-bound keys are no longer a best practice. They are a prerequisite for survival.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What leaders misunderstand about crypto agility&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/crypto-agility"&gt;Crypto Agility&lt;/a&gt; is often described as the ability to swap algorithms when standards change. That definition is incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;True crypto agility depends on operational design. Keys must be decoupled from applications. Rotation must be automated. Failure must be expected and rehearsed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In environments where keys are hard-coded or managed manually, cryptographic change becomes a high-risk event. Teams delay upgrades not because they disagree with the need, but because they fear breaking production.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have seen organizations postpone critical security improvements simply because their key management foundations were too fragile to support change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Strengthening the weakest link&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Improving key management does not require radical transformation. It requires focus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Start by establishing a real key inventory with clear ownership and purpose. Shorten lifetimes aggressively and treat non-rotating keys as technical debt. Separate cryptographic policy from application logic so systems consume keys rather than manage them. Practice cryptographic incident response, not just system outages. Align AI governance with cryptographic governance so speed does not override safety.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These steps are unglamorous, but they are effective. I have seen meaningful risk reduction achieved without changing a single algorithm, simply by fixing how keys are handled.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The future is already operational&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Post-quantum cryptography and AI security are often framed as future concerns. In reality, they are already shaping how systems fail today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The organizations that will succeed are not those that adopt the newest algorithms first. They are the ones who treat key management as critical infrastructure rather than an implementation detail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Strong cryptography has always depended on strong operations. The difference now is that the cost of getting it wrong has never been higher.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a post quantum and AI-driven world, the strongest algorithm in the world cannot compensate for the weakest link.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131506/why-key-management-becomes-the-weakest-link-in-a-post-quantum-and-ai-driven-security-world.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The democratization of AI data poisoning and how to protect your organization</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131517/the-democratization-of-ai-data-poisoning-and-how-to-protect-your-organization.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Smart organizations have spent the last three years protecting their AI tools from skilled prompt injection-style attacks. The assumption has been that poisoning the foundational model, the real brains behind AI systems, requires technical expertise, privileged access, or a coordinated threat group. That assumption no longer holds, and it marks a significant shift in how organizations need to think about AI security in general and training data sanitization in particular.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.turing.ac.uk/blog/llms-may-be-more-vulnerable-data-poisoning-we-thought"&gt;Recent evidence shows&lt;/a&gt; that roughly 250 documents or images can distort the behavior of a large language model, regardless of its size. That’s far different from prior assumptions that it would take thousands or even millions of corrupted data points to push a model off course. This new bar, 250, is low enough for activists, influencers, or competitors to manipulate model outputs without very little technical skill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Online communities have already started to test and even poison the training data for some LLMs. There is one specific subreddit that encourages users to post fabricated facts for the purpose of influencing AI models. A few years ago, this kind of effort wouldn’t have been taken seriously. Now the cybersecurity field knows that AI manipulation is far easier and more accessible, and the risk is much bigger than people having fun on Reddit. Criminals, threat actors, nation states, even individuals can generate content on sites known to be ingested into training data for LLMs and poison the data. Adversaries can inject harmful or biased data into the training pipeline or fine-tuning process quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While we’ve long understood that garbage in equals garbage out, another experiment shows that the effects of poor data persist long after the exposure stops. &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.13928"&gt;A team from Purdue University, Texas A&amp;amp;M University and the University of Texas at Austin found&lt;/a&gt; that there are clear signs of capability decay as models ingest junk content, and adding clean data later did not fully reverse the decline. Any system that trains or is tuned on public data is vulnerable to this long-term model drift if no security controls are implemented to protect the model.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to model decay, backdoors can also be inserted into training data that allow attackers to cause a foundational model to behave in predictable ways. Anthropic released a paper on this &lt;a href="https://www.anthropic.com/research/small-samples-poison"&gt;topic in October&lt;/a&gt;, where they injected a backdoor that could trigger data exfiltration. This style of attack is potentially very hard to detect, and the backdoor can trigger a variety of actions by the model, not just data exfiltration.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These developments make it clear that data poisoning extends well beyond highly technical targeted attacks. A retailer that runs a customer-facing AI chatbot could see its responses shift if someone repeatedly submits synthetic reviews or exaggerated complaints unless security controls are in place to detect that kind of attack. Finance systems could surface distorted commentary about a company if enough falsified chatter floods the data stream the model relies on for new data. Even the influencer economy presents opportunities to manipulate outputs, since repeated praise or criticism of a product can eventually convince a model that sentiment is widespread.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For organizations building AI tools, this means the threat landscape has expanded in ways that require additional routines and safeguards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of the most reliable protections is establishing a clean, validated version of the model before deployment. You can think of this in terms of having a “gold” version of your trusted model that you use as a baseline for anomaly checks. This gold version becomes the reference point that teams can quickly verify against or restore to if needed at any time, not dissimilar to restoring a device to factory settings. If the model starts producing unexpected outputs or shows early signs of drift, returning to the clean baseline avoids the uncertainty time cost of trying to trace which inputs caused the change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A regular reset schedule can also limit the impact of poisoning; pulling the system back to a known clean state, perhaps once a week, can prevent long stretches of unverified or manipulated inputs from accumulating.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Monitoring the data that flows into the model is another important step. Teams should look for abnormal patterns, repeated phrases, sudden bursts of similar submissions, or coordinated attempts to steer the model in a specific direction. This kind of monitoring already exists in network and application security and extending it to model inputs helps detect manipulation early. Think of it as prompt inject filtering. Web application filters (WAFs) work to protect databases from SQL injection attacks. You will want an LLM filter to prevent model poisoning as well. Preventing the input of garbage data can limit the risk of model manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI threat detection tools that simulate advanced AI-specific attacks also support this kind of assessment. You should have adversarial testing done on your AI tools as you do for your web applications and mobile apps. New security solutions are coming onto the market that pinpoint hidden vulnerabilities in AI-powered systems as well. Security tools that can simulate prompt injection attacks, data model poisoning, even stress test the model with distorted inputs are coming that will help defend against these attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As you think through your AI projects, you want to shift your mindset to incorporate these new threats. Model integrity needs to be treated as a core pillar of your AI security strategy, with your teams knowing how easy and accessible this kind of model poisoning has become. Many teams focus heavily on privacy and access control, but those safeguards do little if the model is learning from unreliable or manipulated data. Anyone building an AI tool that interacts with public input or user-generated content should assume that attempts to influence its behavior will happen and prepare accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI tools are becoming central to decision-making across sectors, which makes data integrity more important than ever. Teams that take these risks seriously from the start will be able to keep their systems reliable, even as the information around them becomes increasingly easy to manipulate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131517/the-democratization-of-ai-data-poisoning-and-how-to-protect-your-organization.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-096)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-096</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-098)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-098</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-099)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-099</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-100)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-100</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google fears massive attempt to clone Gemini AI through model extraction</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4132098/google-fears-massive-attempt-to-clone-gemini-ai-through-model-extraction.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google detected and blocked a campaign involving more than 100,000 prompts that it claimed were designed to copy the proprietary reasoning capabilities of its Gemini AI model, according to a quarterly threat report released by Google Threat Intelligence Group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The prompts looked like a coordinated attempt to perform model extraction or distillation, a machine-learning process in which a smaller model is created with the essential traits of a much larger one. Google systems caught the prompts in real time and “lowered the risk of this particular attack, protecting internal reasoning traces,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google is keen to prevent competitors from profiting from its investment in AI model development to train their own models — while still needing to allow users to access the models that power its services.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Model extraction and subsequent knowledge distillation enable an attacker to accelerate AI model development quickly and at a significantly lower cost,” &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/distillation-experimentation-integration-ai-adversarial-use" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google said in the report&lt;/a&gt;. “This activity effectively represents a form of intellectual property theft.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the campaign Google detected, attackers instructed Gemini to keep “the language used in the thinking content strictly consistent with the main language of the user input” — a technique it said is aimed at extracting the model’s reasoning processes across multiple languages. “The breadth of questions suggests an attempt to replicate Gemini’s reasoning ability in non-English target languages across a wide variety of tasks,” the company said in the report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google said it detected frequent model extraction attempts from private sector entities worldwide and researchers seeking to clone proprietary AI capabilities. The company said these attacks violate its terms of service and may be subject to takedowns and legal action.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, researchers and potential customers might want to obtain large samples of Gemini’s reasoning for other, legitimate, purposes such as comparing models’ performance or evaluating its suitability and reliability for a task before purchasing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="model-providers-see-growing-threat-of-ip-theft"&gt;Model providers see growing threat of IP theft&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google is not the only one seeing what it supposes are ill-intentioned attempts at model extraction in its logs. On Thursday, OpenAI told US lawmakers that Chinese AI firm &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3810571/what-enterprises-need-to-know-about-deepseeks-game-changing-r1-ai-model.html"&gt;DeepSeek&lt;/a&gt; has deployed “new, obfuscated methods” to extract results from leading American AI models to train its own systems, according to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2026-02-12/openai-accuses-deepseek-of-distilling-us-models-to-gain-an-edge" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a memo reviewed by Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. OpenAI accused DeepSeek in the memo of trying to “free-ride on the capabilities developed by OpenAI and other US frontier labs,” highlighting how model theft has become a worry for companies that have invested billions in AI development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Corsica Technologies CISO Ross Filipek sees a change in cybersecurity threats behind the accusations. “Adversaries engaging in model-extraction attacks highlights a shift in attack priorities,” he said. “Model extraction doesn’t infiltrate systems in the traditional sense, but rather prioritizes transferring the knowledge developed from the victim’s AI model and using it to accelerate the development of the attackers’ own AI models.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The threat of intellectual property theft through model extraction should worry any organization providing AI models as services, according to the report. Google said these organizations should monitor API access patterns for signs of systematic extraction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Filipek said defending against these attacks requires strict governance over AI systems and close monitoring of data flows. “Organizations should implement response filtering and output controls, which can prevent attackers from determining model behavior in the event of a breach,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nation-state-groups-used-gemini-to-accelerate-attack-operations"&gt;Nation-state groups used Gemini to accelerate attack operations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google sees itself not just as a potential victim of AI cybercrime, but also an unwilling enabler. Its report documented how government-backed threat actors from China, Iran, North Korea, and Russia integrated Gemini into their operations in late 2025. The company said it disabled accounts and assets associated with these groups.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Iranian threat actor &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3812699/threat-actors-using-google-gemini-to-amplify-attacks-report.html"&gt;APT42 used Gemini&lt;/a&gt; to craft targeted social engineering campaigns, feeding the AI biographical details about specific targets to generate conversation starters designed to build trust, according to the report. The group also used Gemini for translation and to understand cultural references in non-native languages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chinese groups APT31 and UNC795 used Gemini to automate vulnerability analysis, debug malicious code, and research exploitation techniques, the report found. North Korean hackers from UNC2970 mined Gemini for intelligence on defense contractors and cybersecurity firms, collecting details on organizational structures and job roles to support phishing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google said it took action by disabling associated accounts and that Google DeepMind used the insights to strengthen defenses against misuse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attackers-integrate-ai-into-malware-operations"&gt;Attackers integrate AI into malware operations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gemini is being misused in other ways too, Google said, with some bad actors embedding its APIs directly into malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google identified a new malware family it called HONESTCUE that integrates Gemini’s API directly into its operations, sending prompts to generate working code that the malware compiles and executes in memory. The prompts appear benign in isolation, allowing them to bypass Gemini’s safety filters, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AttackIQ field CISO Pete Luban sees services like Gemini as an easy way for hackers to up their game. “Integration of public AI models like Google Gemini into malware grants threat actors instant access to powerful LLM capabilities without needing to build or train anything themselves,” he said. “Malware capabilities have advanced exponentially, allowing for faster lateral movement, stealthier attack campaigns, and more convincing mimicry of typical company operations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google also documented COINBAIT, a phishing kit built using AI code generation platforms, and Xanthorox, an underground service that advertised custom malware-generating AI but was actually a wrapper around commercial products including Gemini. The company shut down accounts and projects connected to both.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Luban said the pace of AI-enabled threats means traditional defenses are insufficient. “Continuous testing against realistic adversary behavior is essential to determining if security defenses are prepared to combat adaptive threats,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4132098/google-fears-massive-attempt-to-clone-gemini-ai-through-model-extraction.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-101)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-101</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–102)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-102</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-103)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-103</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The foundation problem: How a lack of accountability is destroying cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131530/the-foundation-problem-how-a-lack-of-accountability-is-destroying-cybersecurity.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-tale-of-two-industries"&gt;A tale of two industries&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The United States Navy takes 18-year-olds fresh out of high school and &lt;a href="https://www.navsea.navy.mil/Home/NNPTC/Academics/Nuclear-Power-School/"&gt;trains them to operate nuclear reactors in 18 months&lt;/a&gt;. These aren’t college graduates. They’re not experienced professionals. They’re young people with the right potential who go through the most rigorous, structured program in the military that transforms them into personnel trusted with some of the highest-stakes responsibilities imaginable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in cybersecurity, we claim we can’t find qualified people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We claim there’s a talent shortage, that candidates just don’t have the skills we need. We look for unicorns, saying training takes too long. We constantly search for senior professionals who, we say, will “hit the ground running,” while junior candidates watch their growth opportunities evaporate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem isn’t the candidates. The problem is leaders who won’t take ownership of building the teams that we need and won’t follow through on development. This is leadership that chooses the path of least resistance instead of doing the hard work of creating foundations for success.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How do I know this? I was one of those nuclear reactor operators for 22 years. Now I work in cybersecurity. If we can train nuclear reactor operators from scratch, we can train security analysts. We’re just choosing not to.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But refusing to train candidates is just one symptom of the deeper disease. Across the technology fields, we’re seeing a pattern of leadership failures that all share a common thread: lack of accountability and ownership. Leaders who only conduct surface-level analyses instead of finding real root causes. Leaders who stay disconnected from their teams while technical debt accumulates into genuine security risks. Leaders who avoid hard conversations with the business because they simply don’t know how to frame cybersecurity as a risk reduction mechanism or as anything more than a cost center.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-accountability-gap"&gt;The accountability gap&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When leaders don’t take ownership, it shows up in predictable ways. Some are obvious, like teams that have a high turnover rate, projects that never finish or the same problems recurring month after month, year after year. Others, like technical debt, are far more insidious. Technical debt accumulates until it becomes a critical vulnerability, and until the interest you’re paying to keep the business running somewhat smoothly is more work than the normal operational work you do.  Technical debt is also its own form of risk. It presents itself in vulnerabilities and in customer churn when all of those manual processes break as someone on your team exits the business.  Finally, root cause analysis that stops at comfortable answers instead of hard truths is another huge sign. Let’s be honest about what leadership failure looks like today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="surface-level-root-cause-analysis"&gt;Surface-level root cause analysis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident happens. The post-mortem gets scheduled. The team gathers, reviews a timeline that isn’t quite right, but good enough, and they all toss out some contributing factors. A report gets written. Everyone acknowledges the corrective actions. And then nothing happens. A &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167404823002195"&gt;research paper&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;em&gt;Computers &amp;amp; Security&lt;/em&gt; states that researchers “found little evidence of thorough investigations to find the underlying causes.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Then a similar incident happens again.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Real root cause analysis is hard. It requires asking “why” until you’re uncomfortable with the answers — the truths — about processes that don’t work, decisions that seemed reasonable at the time and assumptions that were wrong. It requires being willing to discover that you, as a leader, contributed to the problem through your action or inaction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Surface-level analysis stops at the first convenient answer and never addresses the real why. But the cost of stopping too early is being actively measured in recurring incidents, customer churn and team demoralization, which contributes to team turnover as well. When the same types of problems keep happening, your team learns a lesson: leadership doesn’t actually want to fix things. They want to be seen going through the motions.  Taking ownership means following the chain of causality until you find something you can actually fix, and then fixing it. That’s accountability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-perfect-hire-fallacy"&gt;The perfect hire fallacy&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Navy’s Nuclear Propulsion Program takes 18-year-olds with the right aptitudes and trains them to operate nuclear reactors in all corners of the globe in 18 months. These aren’t college graduates, and these aren’t people with years of experience. Just the right attitude and aptitude in someone, placed into a rigorous, structured training program that transforms them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The program builds talent, but meanwhile, in cybersecurity and information technology, we claim we need someone with five years of experience in a technology that’s only been around for five. We ask for security analysts who are also developers and who understand compliance frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is laziness disguised as pragmatism. In fact, less than a quarter of respondents to a &lt;a href="https://www.thehrdirector.com/business-news/mental-health/half-cybersecurity-professionals-expect-burnout-next-12-months/"&gt;recent survey&lt;/a&gt; of cybersecurity professionals believe that management actively tries to reduce their stress. Half reported that senior management adds to their stress.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’re avoiding the truth that training people requires leadership effort. It requires creating structured learning paths, providing mentorship, investing time in developing capabilities. It requires true engagement in people’s growth instead of just assigning tasks. It’s hard work, and many leaders simply don’t want to do it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So instead, we hunt for unicorns, wondering why our teams never stabilize, and why talented people decide to leave the field entirely when they realize there’s no path forward for them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="technical-debt-as-leadership-failures"&gt;Technical debt as leadership failures&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every technology leader has a mental list of technical debt. Systems that need updating or configurations that need to be hardened. Monitoring gaps that need to be closed. We know that all of these exist — in fact, we document them and track them in our project management tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And then we don’t demand the time to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We tell ourselves the business doesn’t understand, it’s budget constraints or we’ll get to it next quarter. What we’re really doing is failing to translate technical debt into business risk in a way that demands action.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The uncomfortable truth is that we’re not demanding that technical debt be addressed as part of product development cycles because that would require hard conversations. Conversations where we tell business stakeholders that moving fast now will mean paying a higher price later. Conversations where we advocate for investment in things that don’t create visible new features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These conversations are part of our job. When we don’t have them — when we accept the accumulation of more and more manual tasks to keep things running that should’ve been automated multiple sprints past – then we’re choosing short-term comfort over our actual responsibility to the business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-this-happens"&gt;Why this happens&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These patterns don’t just happen by accident. If they did, we wouldn’t see them in so many places. They happen because of choices — choices individual leaders make, choices organizations make about how they develop (or don’t develop) their leaders, and choices businesses make about how they treat their security functions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the uncomfortable truth that we don’t have any real leadership training in the industry. We promote technical people into management roles and expect them to figure out leadership on their own. Then, we act surprised when these newly minted leaders manage the way they were managed — or worse, when they don’t manage at all.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other professions do invest in their leadership. Healthcare has residencies and fellowships that teach leadership roles. Business schools teach management principles. But in our industry, we throw people into the roles and hope they figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lack of training doesn’t fully explain the problem, however. There’s an individual component at stake. The fundamentals of good leadership aren’t mysterious: follow through on commitments, dig deep to understand root causes, stay engaged with your team and have hard conversations when necessary. These aren’t advanced concepts requiring an MBA. They’re basic accountability and ownership.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many leaders know this is what they should be doing. They’re choosing not to do it because it’s hard. It’s easier to hire than to train, and it’s easier to accept surface-level answers than to keep asking why until you get to those uncomfortable truths. The path of least resistance is the road well-travelled, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, the third piece to this puzzle, the dilemma we face, is a systemic failure of business leadership to also do its own introspection. Why does the business have high churn, both with customers and within teams? Are we setting people up for failure? Do we create conditions where good leadership is possible?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The result of all three of these factors is a self-fulfilling prophecy where we make people into managers with no training, and then they may make it into business leadership, still not understanding how to look at things like technical debt because their leaders didn’t make it seem important to them either. This causes teams to burn out, simply because the fundamentals of good leadership aren’t being practiced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This isn’t all a sad story, however. Choices can be changed. But only if we’re willing to be honest about what we’re choosing and why. Leadership accountability isn’t complicated – it just requires choosing to do the work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-teams-we-could-build"&gt;The teams we could build&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Imagine cybersecurity teams where people want to stay and grow. Where junior analysts see clear paths to becoming senior practitioners. Where the same problems don’t recur because leaders actually implement fixes. Where technical debt gets addressed because leaders translate it into business risk that demands action. When these things happen, success compounds because you’re building on solid foundations instead of starting over.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These teams do exist. They’re led by people who take ownership. The talent is there. The knowledge of what good leadership requires is there. What’s needed is simply the choice to do it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We don’t have a talent shortage in our industry. We have a leadership accountability gap. And unlike the talent market, that’s something we can actually control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The foundational problem has a foundational solution: take ownership. Follow through. Build people. Have the hard conversations. Do the work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The teams and the culture that we all want are waiting on the other side of that choice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4131530/the-foundation-problem-how-a-lack-of-accountability-is-destroying-cybersecurity.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-104)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-104</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains security advisory (AV26-105)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jetbrains-security-advisory-av26-105</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-106)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-106</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-106</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-107)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-107</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-107</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid7 security advisory (AV26-108)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/rapid7-security-advisory-av26-108</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/rapid7-security-advisory-av26-108</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-109)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-109</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-109</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-110)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-110</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-110</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel security advisory (AV26-112)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av26-112</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/intel-security-advisory-av26-112</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-113)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-113</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-113</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-114)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-114</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-114</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV26-115)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-115</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-115</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-116)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-116</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-116</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-117)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-117</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-117</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-118)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-118</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-118</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-119)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-119</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-119</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commvault security advisory (AV26-120)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/commvault-security-advisory-av26-120</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-121)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-121</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React security advisory (AV26-123)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/react-security-advisory-av26-123</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD security advisory (AV26-124)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/amd-security-advisory-av26-124</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063) - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063-update-1</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL security advisory (AV26-125)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/postgresql-security-advisory-av26-125</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/postgresql-security-advisory-av26-125</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeyondTrust security advisory (AV26-097) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/beyondtrust-security-advisory-av26-097</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-126)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-126</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-126</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-127)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-127</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-127</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – February 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-111) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-february-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-111</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple security advisory (AV26-122) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apple-security-advisory-av26-122</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV26-128)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-128</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-128</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-129)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-129</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-129</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Virtual Event] Shields Up: Key Technologies Reshaping Cybersecurity Defenses</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/shields-up-key-technologies-reshaping-cybersecurity-defenses</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 16537.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
