<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:30:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>6 arrested for smuggling migrants from Türkiye to France and Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</link>
      <description>On 13 November 2025, the German Federal Police, in close cooperation with French border police and with the support of Europol and Eurojust, have dismantled a criminal network believed to have smuggled nearly 600 people into Europe between 2021 and 2023.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invisible battles: How cybersecurity work erodes mental health in silence and what we can do about it</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094657/invisible-battles-how-cybersecurity-work-erodes-mental-health-in-silence-and-what-we-can-do-about-it.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attacker never sleeps and neither do you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At least, that’s how it feels when your job is to stay one step ahead of someone whose only job is to break things.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity isn’t just a technical domain. It’s psychological warfare. And for the defenders on the front lines, that war doesn’t stop when the shift ends. It follows you home. It keeps you up at night. It turns vigilance into anxiety. When it finishes with your mind, it drains your energy, robs you of sleep, weakens your health and sometimes steals your sense of self.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study from the National Library of Medicine (NLM) investigated the &lt;a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11861440/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;growing phenomenon of cybersecurity fatigue&lt;/a&gt; and its implications for employee productivity and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breaches make the news. Burnout doesn’t. That’s the invisible battle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You signed up to protect systems, not to lose yours. But as the pressure climbs and expectations spiral, mental health becomes the collateral damage no one tracks until people start quitting, breaking or fading out quietly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-makes-cyber-work-so-mentally-damaging"&gt;What makes cyber work so mentally damaging?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This isn’t your average 9-to-5.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’re not just solving puzzles. You’re responsible for keeping a digital fortress from collapsing under relentless siege. That kind of pressure reshapes your brain and not in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="always-on-alertness"&gt;Always-on alertness&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Threats don’t wait. Neither does your pager. You’re expected to respond instantly, on holidays, birthdays, weekends and 2 a.m. system alerts. Even when nothing’s burning, your mind stays wired.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That permanent readiness? It’s exhaustion disguised as dedication. Sleep suffers. Focus slips. And when your nervous system never gets to shut down, it starts to fray.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="moral-and-operational-responsibility"&gt;Moral and operational responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One missed patch. One misconfigured access role. One phishing click. That’s all it takes to trigger a million-dollar disaster or worse: erode trust. You carry that weight. When something goes wrong, the guilt cuts deep. Even if the root cause wasn’t yours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’re also stuck in ethical crossfire. Should you monitor employees? Report poor practices to the board? Blow the whistle on ignored risks? It’s not just technical risk. It’s moral trauma.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="isolation-and-underappreciation"&gt;Isolation and underappreciation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many cyber teams operate in silos. You’re either under the radar or in the firing line. The business sees you as the blocker. The board sees you after the breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And if you’re the lone cyber lead in an SME? You’re on an island, with no lifeboat. No peer to talk to, no outlet to decompress. Just mounting expectations and a growing feeling that nobody really gets what you do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A recent BBC article reports that &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cgqn8e4e700o" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;cybersecurity professionals are facing rising levels of burnout, fueled by constant high-pressure demands, relentless alerts and a blame-heavy culture&lt;/a&gt;. It warns that without stronger mental-health support, systemic protections and early intervention, many in the field risk long-term harm.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the reality. Now, let’s discuss what’s exacerbating the issue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="systemic-stressors-that-pour-fuel-on-the-fire"&gt;Systemic stressors that pour fuel on the fire&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem isn’t just the job. It’s the way the job is structured. The way leadership treats security. The myths that shape the industry. This is how the system turns pressure into pathology.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An article from Oxford University argues that &lt;a href="https://www.infosec.ox.ac.uk/article/cybersecurity-and-mental-health" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our mental health strongly influences how we perceive and respond to cyberthreats&lt;/a&gt;. When we’re stressed, fatigued or depressed, we’re more likely to make mistakes such as clicking on malicious links or ignoring warning signs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="culture-of-perfection-and-silence"&gt;Culture of perfection and silence&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They tell you: Zero breaches. Zero tolerance. Zero visibility into your struggles. The hero narrative still reigns; if you’re not burning out, you’re not trying hard enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speak up about being overwhelmed? You risk looking weak. Or worse, replaceable. So you hide it. You overcompensate. And eventually, you break, quietly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="role-overload-and-resource-starvation"&gt;Role overload and resource starvation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Budget cuts. Empty roles. Too many tools, not enough hands. You juggle audits, threat intel, board decks, DevSecOps, IAM and compliance. You’re an architect, firefighter and therapist. When one person holds five roles, quality drops. So does morale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Leadership discusses risk appetite but expects miracles without investing in the team. And when you fail to stop an attack with duct tape and prayer? You’re blamed for not being magical enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="perpetual-change-and-uncertainty"&gt;Perpetual change and uncertainty&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nothing stays still. New threats. New tools. New regulations. You’ve finally mastered a SIEM and now a new AI tool needs to be integrated. DORA lands. NIS2 updates. ISO shifts. They expect you to know it all, yesterday. Certifications become survival badges. And with the wrong culture, they become the only form of recognition you get.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Systemic chaos builds personal crisis. The toll isn’t abstract. It’s physical, emotional and measurable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-the-mind-cracks-what-this-stress-actually-does"&gt;When the mind cracks: What this stress actually does&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stress in cyber isn’t theoretical. It shows up in how you think, feel and lead.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="mental-health-crashes"&gt;Mental health crashes&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chronic stress reshapes your nervous system. You can’t focus. You lose sleep. You live in hypervigilance. Some professionals experience panic attacks. Others spiral into depression. Some report PTSD symptoms after handling massive incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Imposter syndrome thrives here because you’re always one step behind an adversary who only needs to be right once.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="workplace-breakdown"&gt;Workplace breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Burnout doesn’t just hurt you. It spreads. High turnover decimates team continuity. The few who stay get overwhelmed. Teams shrink, knowledge evaporates, pressure spikes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;People stop caring. Security becomes checkbox theatre. Cynicism replaces trust. Conversations turn defensive. And when the team stops believing they can win, breaches become inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="strategic-risk-amplifies"&gt;Strategic risk amplifies&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tired minds make bad decisions. Fatigued teams miss warning signs. Unacknowledged stress creates blind spots:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shadow IT emerges as people bypass slow processes&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Over-engineered controls go unchallenged&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Resilience erodes under a false sense of coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eventually, stress causes the very failures you were hired to prevent. But this isn’t fate. It’s a design flaw. And design flaws can be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-build-real-psychological-resilience-in-cyber"&gt;How to build real psychological resilience in cyber&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You don’t need yoga classes or platitudes. You need structured, aligned action at all levels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="at-the-individual-level-protect-the-protector"&gt;At the individual level: Protect the protector&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know your triggers.&lt;/strong&gt; Incident response isn’t sustainable without boundaries. If you’re on call, ensure you’re also fully off call.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk early.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t wait for burnout. Therapy, coaching or even peer-to-peer calls can normalize stress without shame.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push for micro boundaries.&lt;/strong&gt; Not every email is urgent. Not every meeting requires you. Defend your calendar the way you defend systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="at-the-organizational-level-change-the-operating-system"&gt;At the organizational level: Change the operating system&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design psychologically safe spaces.&lt;/strong&gt; If people fear speaking up, their silence has already broken your risk radar.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define roles properly.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t ask a SOC analyst to handle board governance and expect magic. Split strategy from execution.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track mental health alongside KPIs.&lt;/strong&gt; Pulse surveys, anonymous feedback and burnout rates; these are also security indicators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your best people burn out, no system will save you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="at-the-industry-level-kill-the-hero-myth"&gt;At the industry level: Kill the hero myth&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop valorising burnout.&lt;/strong&gt; We don’t need more martyrs. We need strong teams.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update the frameworks.&lt;/strong&gt; Add mental health to ISO. Bake it into NIST. Make wellness part of assurance.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fund mental health research in cyber.&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s understand what really works. Build toolkits. Train leaders. Equip teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is not about coddling. It’s about capacity. A resilient mind is the best incident response tool you’ve got.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="if-you-want-resilient-systems-start-with-resilient-people"&gt;If you want resilient systems, start with resilient people&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here’s the hard truth: Cybersecurity professionals are fighting two battles. One is against adversaries. The other is against a system that expects perfection, rewards self-sacrifice and punishes vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, resilience isn’t about enduring pain. It’s about building systems that don’t produce it in the first place. Stop treating burnout like a badge. Start treating it like a breach. Both are signs that something’s broken. Both are calls to act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If we expect defenders to protect the enterprise, we must first defend the defenders. That’s not soft. That’s strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094657/invisible-battles-how-cybersecurity-work-erodes-mental-health-in-silence-and-what-we-can-do-about-it.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS S3-Buckets im Visier von Ransomware-Banden</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095199/aws-s3-buckets-im-visier-von-ransomware-banden.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Angriff auf Cloud-Speicher" class="wp-image-4095207" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2558721353.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Ransomware-Banden haben ihren Fokus von traditionellen lokalen Zielen auf Cloud-Speicherdienste und insbesondere Amazon S3 verlagert.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; ImageFlow – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein aktueller &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/k/s3-ransomware.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bericht von Trend Micro&lt;/a&gt; beschreibt eine neue Welle von Angriffen, bei denen Angreifer Cloud-native Verschlüsselungs- und Schlüsselverwaltungsdienste integrieren, anstatt lediglich Daten zu stehlen oder zu löschen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Böswillige Aktivitäten, die auf S3 Buckets abzielen, sind nichts Neues, obwohl Unternehmen ihre Cloud-Umgebungen immer besser absichern“, kommentiert Crystal Morin, Senior Cybersecurity Strategist bei Sysdig. „Da Verteidiger stärkere Perimeterschutzmaßnahmen einsetzen, beginnen Angreifer, integrierte Funktionen wie Encryption Management und Key Rotation zu missbrauchen, um Daten zu zerstörren.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut Trend Micro untersuchen Angreifer eine Reihe von S3-Konfigurationen, von Buckets mit AWS-verwalteten KMS-Schlüsseln bis hin zu vom Kunden bereitgestellten Keys, importiertem Schlüsselmaterial und sogar vollständig externen Schlüsselspeichern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="warum-s3-ein-begehrtes-ransomware-ziel-ist"&gt;Warum S3 ein begehrtes Ransomware-Ziel ist&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bei On-Premises-Ransomware werden traditionell Malware eingeschleust, Desktops oder Server verschlüsselt und Zahlungen erpresst. Da Unternehmen jedoch wichtige Workloads und Backups in Cloud-Dienste migriert haben, verfolgen Angreifer laut Forschern nun die Daten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Trend-Micro-Bericht listet mehrere wichtige Cloud-Ziele auf, darunter Compute-Snapshots, statische Speicher (S3 Buckets), Datenbanken, Container/Registries und Backup-Tresore. Unter diesen ist S3 besonders wertvoll, da es häufig Backups, Protokolle, Konfigurationsdaten und statische Assets enthält – also Dinge, die ein Unternehmen am dringendsten zurückhaben möchte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um erfolgreich zu sein, suchen Cyberkriminelle in der Regel nach S3 Buckets, bei denen Folgendes der Fall ist:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Versionierung deaktiviert (alte Versionen können nicht wiederhergestellt werden),&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Objekt-Sperre deaktiviert (Dateien lassen sich überschreiben oder löschen),&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;weitreichende Schreibberechtigungen (durch falsch konfigurierte IAM-Richtlinien oder durchgesickerte Anmeldedaten), und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;hochwertige Daten (Backup-Dateien, Produktionskonfigurations-Dumps).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sobald sie sich Zugang verschafft haben, versuchen die Angreifer, eine „vollständige und irreversible Sperrung” der Daten zu erzwingen. Dazu können sie Objekte mit für das Opfer unzugänglichen Keys verschlüsseln, Backups löschen und die Löschung von Schlüsseln planen, damit AWS und der Kunde die Daten nicht wiederherstellen können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-verschluesselung-und-schluesselverwaltung-als-waffe"&gt;Cloud-Verschlüsselung und Schlüsselverwaltung als Waffe&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trend Micro hat fünf &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3803194/perfide-ransomware-attacke-gegen-aws-nutzer.html" target="_blank"&gt;S3-Ransomware&lt;/a&gt;-Varianten identifiziert, die zunehmend die in AWS integrierten Verschlüsselungspfade ausnutzen. Eine Variante missbraucht die standardmäßigen, von AWS verwalteten KMS-Schlüssel (SSE-KMS), indem sie Daten mit einem vom Angreifer erstellten Schlüssel verschlüsselt und diesen Schlüssel zur Löschung vormerkt. Eine andere Variante verwendet vom Kunden bereitgestellte Schlüssel (SSE-C), von denen AWS keine Kopie hat, sodass eine Wiederherstellung unmöglich ist. Die dritte Variante exfiltriert S3-Bucket-Daten (ohne Versionierung) und löscht die Originale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die letzten beiden Varianten dringen tiefer in die Key-Management-Infrastruktur &lt;a&gt;ein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="#_msocom_2"&gt;[MB2]&lt;/a&gt; . Eine stützt sich auf importiertes Schlüsselmaterial (Bring your own key – &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/how-to-byok-bring-your-own-key-to-aws-kms-for-less-than-15-00-a-year-using-aws-cloudhsm/"&gt;BYOK&lt;/a&gt;), wodurch Angreifer Daten verschlüsseln und anschließend die importierten Schlüssel zerstören oder ungültig machen können. Die andere missbraucht den External Key Store (XKS) von AWS, bei dem Schlüsseloperationen außerhalb von AWS stattfinden. Das bedeutet, dass weder der Kunde noch AWS den Zugriff wiederherstellen können, wenn Angreifer die externe Schlüsselquelle kontrollieren. Zusammengenommen zeigen diese Techniken, dass Angreifer AWS selbst als Verschlüsselungsmechanismus nutzen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Ich kann mich nicht erinnern, dies jemals in der Praxis gesehen zu haben“, betont Trey Ford, Chief Strategy and Trust Officer bei Bugcrowd. „Diese Untersuchung ist eine systematische und theoretische Bedrohungsmodellierung. Sie zeigt auf, wie ein Angreifer eine AWS-Umgebung innerhalb einer Kontogrenze verschlüsseln und Lösegeld dafür verlangen könnte.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ford fügt hinzu: „Dies zielt speziell auf die Verwendung externer oder vom Kunden bereitgestellter Schlüssel (SSE-C bzw. XKS) ab, um die Kontrolle über die Schlüsselverwaltung für die in der Speicherung verwendete Kryptografie zu erlangen.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="schutzmassnahmen"&gt;Schutzmaßnahmen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Trend-Micro-Forscher fordern Kunden dringend auf, ihre S3-Umgebungen zu sichern, indem sie Least-Priviledge-Zugang erzwingen und Schutzmaßnahmen wie Versionierung und Object Lock aktivieren. Zudem sollten Unternehmen bereitgestellte oder externe Schlüsselquellen, die die Wiederherstellung beeinträchtigen können, streng regulieren. Außerdem wird empfohlen, Backups in separaten Konten zu isolieren und die Cloud-Audit-Protokolle kontinuierlich auf Anzeichen verdächtiger Schlüsselaktivitäten, Massenverschlüsselung oder groß angelegte Objektlöschungen zu überwachen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Eine ‚Assume Breach‘-Mentalität ist in der Cloud unerlässlich: Laufzeitumgebungen sollten unveränderlich sein, Identitäten müssen über streng begrenzte Berechtigungen und kurzlebige Anmeldedaten verfügen“, erklärt Morin von Sysdig. Nach Meinung des Experten benötigen Netzwerke eine sinnvolle Segmentierung und kritische Datensätze müssen gesichert werden. „Moderne Betriebsabläufe sind von komplexen Lieferketten abhängig, und eine Ransomware, die einen wichtigen Partner betrifft, kann Ihr Unternehmen genauso vollständig lahmlegen wie eine direkte Kompromittierung.“ (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_2"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095199/aws-s3-buckets-im-visier-von-ransomware-banden.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What keeps CISOs awake at night — and why Zurich might hold the cure</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094608/what-keeps-cisos-awake-at-night-and-why-zurich-might-hold-the-cure.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="sleepless-nights-in-cybersecurity"&gt;Sleepless nights in cybersecurity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When I attended the Global Cyber Conference 2025 in Zurich last week, I expected world-class keynotes and sharp panel debates. What I didn’t expect were so many conversations about sleep. Or rather, the absence of it. The exhaustion was palpable — red eyes, half-empty coffee cups and the quiet admission from one CISO: “I haven’t slept through the night in six months.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a keynote titled “The 2025 threat landscape – What keeps CISOs awake at night,” Tim Brown, CISO at SolarWinds, distilled the collective anxiety of an entire profession into five painfully accurate points. His slides weren’t just data — they were a mirror held up to a room full of leaders who live in a state of permanent vigilance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It was one of those rare sessions where the room fell silent — not from boredom, but recognition. The CISOs around me weren’t snapping LinkedIn photos; they were nodding, half-smiling, half-grimacing. Because every slide mirrored what we all feel: constant acceleration, persistent uncertainty and diminishing control. One European bank CISO whispered, “That’s my risk register — on a bad day.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-safe-space-in-the-alps"&gt;A safe space in the Alps&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over two days at Zurich’s stunning Dolder Grand — hosted by the Swiss Cyber Institute — I witnessed something I’ve seldom seen at cybersecurity events: real vulnerability. In a closed, attribution-free environment, leaders shared not just strategies, but doubts. And that made this event stand out — not as another conference, but as a safe space for CISOs to drop their armor. The Dolder Grand’s panoramic views over Lake Zurich and the Alps provided a serene contrast to the high-stakes discussions inside, amplifying the sense of a neutral, reflective sanctuary.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zurich, with its alpine precision and global neutrality, was the perfect backdrop. The theme &lt;em&gt;Future Resilience&lt;/em&gt; echoed everywhere, but the magic happened in the margins: pre-conference coffee chats, late-night Swiss CISO Awards talks, quiet lounge exchanges. The SCI has built something extraordinary — a community where CISOs exchange phone numbers, not just slides. Multiple leaders told me they now call peers directly during live anomalies. That’s trust you can’t buy. One manufacturing CISO shared how a Zurich contact helped him contain a supply-chain incident in under four hours — something that previously took days through formal channels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-threats-that-hit-home"&gt;5 threats that hit home&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are Brown’s five threats — straight from the slides, raw insights from the room and my takeaways as a consultant advising energy, manufacturing and finance giants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-the-shrinking-window-between-discovery-and-exploitation"&gt;1. The shrinking window between discovery and exploitation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Brown’s first slide hit like a gut punch: “Time between discovery and exploitation continues to decrease while CVE publishing increases.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That line summarizes 2025’s cyber reality. &lt;a href="https://cve.mitre.org/cve/search_cve_list.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MITRE tracked over 39,000 CVEs in 2025&lt;/a&gt; alone so far, with &lt;a href="https://services.google.com/fh/files/misc/m-trends-2025-en.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mandiant’s M-Trends 2025&lt;/a&gt; showing exploits weaponized in days — or hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One CISO described a zero-day that went from disclosure to active ransomware in 19 hours. “We patched 40,000 endpoints overnight,” he said. “Next time? We might not have 19 hours.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my practice, I see quarterly scans failing. My fix for clients: Automated, risk-based patching — integrate exposure tools with CMDBs to prioritize crown jewels. Post-Zurich, I’m piloting this for an energy client: zero-downtime OT patching via virtual patching. Speed isn’t optional; it’s survival. Tools like Tenable or Qualys, when linked to asset inventories, can cut prioritization time from days to minutes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-motivated-threat-actors-and-the-end-of-deterrence"&gt;2. Motivated threat actors – and the end of deterrence&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Motivated threat actors facing little consequences — the starfish and the spider. The spider model is not working.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Brown nailed it, channeling &lt;em&gt;The Starfish and the Spider&lt;/em&gt;. But his real analogy was Napster vs. iTunes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We shut down one file-sharing network, three more popped up. The music industry didn’t win by closing platforms — they won by making legal downloads cheaper and easier. We’re still trying to shut down the networks instead of changing the economics.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon’s DBIR 2025 confirms&lt;/a&gt;: Ransomware in 44% of breaches (up 37% YoY), with groups recycling TTPs days post-takedown.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My client takeaway: Ditch perimeters for behavioral detection (UEBA in SIEMs). Join ISACs or SCI networks — isolation loses. One manufacturing client now shares IOCs in real-time; containment time dropped 40%. Platforms like Splunk or Microsoft Sentinel with UEBA modules make this shift practical and measurable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-the-third-party-paradox"&gt;3. The third-party paradox&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Third-party risk — we need to expect more from vendors and consumers of technology.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laughter rippled — bitter, knowing. Post-SolarWinds/MOVEit, 62% of breaches involve third parties per &lt;a href="https://www.kiteworks.com/cybersecurity-risk-management/third-party-access-risks-manufacturing-2025-ponemon-report/"&gt;recent studies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One CISO: “We audited their SOC 2 — but not their firmware update process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Post-Zurich framework update (bullets for you):&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live API feeds for vuln/compliance&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Joint tabletops quarterly&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Contracts: 72-hour notify + shared remediation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SCI’s cross-industry working groups made this actionable. For a finance client, this slashed vendor risk score by 35%. Integrating tools like BitSight or SecurityScorecard into vendor portals automates much of this oversight.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-ai-the-fastest-arms-race-in-history"&gt;4. AI – the fastest arms race in history&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI — we’re in a race. Can we use it faster and better than the adversary?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI powers both sides. Workshop demo: LLMs craft phishing bypassing gateways 94%. Deepfakes in &amp;lt;10 mins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One CISO: “We’re using AI to simulate attacks in a sandbox, training our SOC on synthetic TTPs.” I’m piloting this with a manufacturing client — GenAI generates polymorphic malware for rule-testing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-project-top-10-for-large-language-model-applications/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OWASP Top 10 for LLMs&lt;/a&gt; now mandatory: Prompt injection #1.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Classify models as critical assets — threat model them. Treating LLMs like any other high-value system, with access controls and logging, is now non-negotiable in mature programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-stress-and-burnout-the-human-threat-surface"&gt;5. Stress and burnout – the human threat surface&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Deputy CISOs reluctant to become CISOs, CISOs leaving the industry, burnout for our teams.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The room broke. &lt;a href="https://owasp.org/www-project-top-10-for-large-language-model-applications/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;69% report rising burnout&lt;/a&gt;; deputies flee the role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stories: Missed birthdays, divorces, no vacations in years. One CISO admitted, “My daughter asked if I still work here.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Closing Apéro: Impromptu support. “CISO hotlines” for 3am Swap: Sabbaticals, peer circles.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One leader: “Resilience is now part of my risk register.” Framable. Tweetable. True.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My new audit: People = risk vector. Morale checks alongside firewalls. Simple pulse surveys and rotation policies can yield measurable improvements in team retention and alertness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-zurich-set-a-new-benchmark"&gt;Why Zurich set a new benchmark&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Global Cyber Conference 2025 wasn’t just another industry gathering — it was a living network. The Swiss Cyber Institute has created a space where trust isn’t a buzzword; it’s the default setting. The vendor-free format ensures candid exchanges, free from sales pitches, fostering genuine collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Multiple CISOs told me they now call peers directly when anomalies appear in shared supply chains — not through formal channels, but through relationships built in Zurich. That level of collaboration doesn’t happen by accident. It’s the result of a carefully curated, vendor-free environment where leaders can speak freely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a field drowning in alerts and noise, this event cuts through. CISOs don’t just attend — they belong. The sense of community extends beyond the conference, with SCI maintaining active working groups and a secure messaging platform for year-round peer support.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you advise security leaders, govern risk or build resilience programs, put the Global Cyber Conference on your radar for next year. The Swiss Cyber Institute typically announces dates in early spring. In the meantime, the connections made in Zurich this year are already saving response time — and sleep — for hundreds of leaders across Europe and the US. The return on investment isn’t measured in swag or slides, but in faster incident response, shared playbooks and the rare gift of knowing you’re not alone at 3am.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094608/what-keeps-cisos-awake-at-night-and-why-zurich-might-hold-the-cure.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-760)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-761)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-762)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-763)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–764)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.42</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-765)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 CSO Hall of Fame call for nominations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/568125/cso-hall-of-fame-honorees.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hall of Fame &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/awards/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;award nominations are officially open&lt;/a&gt;, and we’re calling on you, your peers, teams and clients to recognize the individuals and organizations driving smarter, safer, and stronger cybersecurity strategies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Get your nominations in today. The December 3 deadline is fast approaching. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enter here: &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/awards/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2026 CSO Conference &amp;amp; Awards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now entering its eighth year, the CSO Hall of Fame spotlights outstanding leaders who have significantly contributed to the practice of information risk management and security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This award honors trailblazers (security leaders with 10+ years in a CSO, CISO or other C-level security position) whose careers have shaped the future of cybersecurity and risk management. Inductees are recognized for their lifetime achievements and enduring contributions to the profession.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Honorees will be recognized at the &lt;a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cso-conference-awards/awards/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CSO Conference + Awards&lt;/a&gt; May 11-13, 2026 in Nashville, TN.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the event, attendees will have the opportunity to connect with hundreds of peers, industry leaders, and security executives who will showcase demonstrable business value in their projects from AI to application security to zero trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="2025-cso-hall-of-fame-honorees"&gt;2025 CSO Hall of Fame Honorees&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meg Anderson&lt;/strong&gt;, VP &amp;amp; CISO (retired), Principal Financial Group &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bob Bruns&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Avanade &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Chow&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Genesys &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mignona Cote&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Infor &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laura Deaner&lt;/strong&gt;, Managing Director, CISO, The Depository Trust &amp;amp; Clearing Corporation (DTCC) &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Finney&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, University of Texas System &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Gordon&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP &amp;amp; CISO, McDonald’s &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ron Green&lt;/strong&gt;, Cybersecurity Fellow/Former CSO, Mastercard &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shawn Henry&lt;/strong&gt;, CSO, CrowdStrike &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Todd Lukens&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP, Security &amp;amp; Infrastructure, Nationwide &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rishi Tripathi&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP, CISO &amp;amp; CTO, Mount Sinai Health System &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marnie Wilking&lt;/strong&gt;, CSO, Booking.com &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="class-of-2024"&gt;Class of 2024&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jerry Geisler&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP &amp;amp; CISO, Walmart, Inc. &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gary Hayslip&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, SoftBank Investment Advisers &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vaughn Hazen&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, CN &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jill Knesek&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, BlackLine &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susan Koski&lt;/strong&gt;, EVP &amp;amp; CISO, PNC Financial Services &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Palmer&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Hearst &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Schramm&lt;/strong&gt;, Global Head of IT Risk and Security, Munich Re &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Turpin&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, The Friedkin Group &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phil Venables&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Google Cloud &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teresa Zielinski&lt;/strong&gt;, Global CISO, GE Vernova &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="class-of-2023"&gt;Class of 2023&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich Agostino&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP &amp;amp; CISO, Target&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ed Amoroso&lt;/strong&gt;, Founder &amp;amp; CEO, TAG InfoSphere&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Devon Bryan&lt;/strong&gt;, Global CIO, Carnival Corporation&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicole Darden Ford&lt;/strong&gt;, Global VP &amp;amp; CISO, Rockwell Automation&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Gordon&lt;/strong&gt;, EVP &amp;amp; CSO, CIBC&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ben Miron&lt;/strong&gt;, VP of Infrastructure &amp;amp; Cybersecurity, NextEra Energy, Inc.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gary Owen&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO &amp;amp; Chief Risk Officer, Capital&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holly Ridgeway&lt;/strong&gt;, EVP &amp;amp; CSO, Citizens Financial Group, Inc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="class-of-2022"&gt;Class of 2022&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marene Allison&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573163/johnson-and-johnson-ciso-marene-allison-you-can-t-sit-on-today-s-technology.html"&gt;CISO, Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, Inc.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bret Arsenault&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Beeson&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP &amp;amp; Global CISO, Cigna&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derek Benz&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Coca-Cola&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Connelly&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Boston Consulting Group&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John McClurg&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP &amp;amp; CISO, BlackBerry&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim McKnight&lt;/strong&gt;, EVP &amp;amp; CSO, SAP&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chandra McMahon&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP &amp;amp; CISO, CVS Health&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gary Warzala&lt;/strong&gt;, Leadership Partner – Security &amp;amp; Risk Management, Gartner&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deborah Wheeler&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP &amp;amp; CISO, Delta Air Lines, Inc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="class-of-2021"&gt;Class of 2021&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roland Cloutie&lt;/strong&gt;r, Global CSO, TikTok&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deneen DeFiore&lt;/strong&gt;, VP &amp;amp; CISO, United Airlines&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andy Ellis&lt;/strong&gt;, Operating Partner, YL Ventures&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bobby Ford&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP/CSO, HPE&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renee Guttmann&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Campbell Soup Company&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meredith Harper&lt;/strong&gt;, VP/CISO, Eli Lilly and Company&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mike Towers&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Takeda&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Weatherford&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, AlertEnterprise&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jason Witty&lt;/strong&gt;, Global CISO, J.P. Morgan Chase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="class-of-2020"&gt;Class of 2020&lt;/h4&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Callahan&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP, Global CISO, Aflac&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave Estlick&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Chipotle Mexican Grill&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jamil Farshch&lt;/strong&gt;i, CISO, Equifax&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emily Heath&lt;/strong&gt;, Chief Trust &amp;amp; Security Officer, DocuSign&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brad Maiorino&lt;/strong&gt;, CISO, Raytheon Technologies&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kathy Orner&lt;/strong&gt;, VP, Chief Risk Officer, CWT&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jim Routh&lt;/strong&gt;, Head of Enterprise Information Risk Management, MassMutual&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gregory Wood&lt;/strong&gt;, SVP, Technology Risk Management &amp;amp; Security, The Walt Disney Company&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timothy Youngblood&lt;/strong&gt;, Corporate VP, CISO, McDonald’s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to the honorees listed above, CSO inducted &lt;strong&gt;Michael Assante&lt;/strong&gt; posthumously for his work with the SANS Institute and Center for Strategic and International Studies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Editor’s note: The job titles and company affiliations listed here reflect the positions held by these individuals at the time they were inducted into the Hall of Fame. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/568125/cso-hall-of-fame-honorees.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 arrests in Bulgaria in a large art trafficking investigation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</link>
      <description>On 19 November 2025, a coordinated effort led by Bulgarian authorities and supported by Europol, resulted in the dismantling of a criminal network involved in large-scale trafficking of cultural goods across Europe and beyond. This operation was conducted under the framework of a Europol operational taskforce. The action day involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Albania, France, Germany, Greece,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the winners of the 2025 Europol photo competition</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</link>
      <description>Three awards were given out, each decided by a different group of voters:the international law enforcement community represented at Europol’s headquarters,members of the public,and the Heads of Communication of the European law enforcement authorities.The winners of Capture25The Europol Community Vote by the Liaison Bureaux went to Johan Jacob Kleist from Denmark with his photo of a ‘police officer patrolling beneath...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years on: remembering the victims of the 13 November terrorist attack in Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</link>
      <description>Today marks ten years since one of the deadliest terrorist attacks in recent European history was carried out in Paris - at the Stade de France, in the streets and inside the Bataclan concert hall. On 13 November 2015, 132 people lost their lives and many more were injured during what became a night of profound tragedy for France and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and partner countries combat online radicalisation on gaming platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</link>
      <description>Conducted on 13 November 2025, this operational action by the European Union Internet Referral Unit (EU IRU) involved the referral of thousands of URLs leading to dangerous and illicit online material. This includes around 5 408 links to jihadist content, 1 070 links to violent right-wing extremist and terrorist content, and 105 links to racist and xenophobic content.This joint action...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUR 47 million in crypto traced to disrupt digital piracy services</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November, Europol, in collaboration with the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional), organised an "Intellectual Property Crime Cyber-Patrol Week”. A total of 30 investigators participated in this operation hosted at the EUIPO headquarters in Alicante, Spain, where they used advanced Open-Source Intelligence Techniques (OSINT) and cutting-edge online investigative tools...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-767)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-768)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-769)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.57</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End of the game for cybercrime infrastructure: 1025 servers taken down</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November 2025, the latest phase of Operation Endgame was coordinated from Europol’s headquarters in The Hague. The actions targeted one of the biggest infostealers (Rhadamanthys), the Remote Access Trojan VenomRAT, and the botnet Elysium, all of which played a key role in international cybercrime. Authorities took down these three large cybercrime enablers. The main suspect for VenomRAT was also arrested in Greece on 3 November 2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Shai-Hulud worm spreading through npm, GitHub</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095578/new-shai-hulud-worm-spreading-through-npm-github.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A new version of the Shai-Hulud credentials-stealing self-propagating worm is expanding through the open npm registry, a threat that developers who download packages from the repository have to deal with immediately.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/shai-hulud-2-0-ongoing-supply-chain-attack" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Researchers at Wiz Inc. said Monday&lt;/a&gt; that in the early stages of the campaign late last week,&lt;sup&gt;  &lt;/sup&gt;a thousand new GitHub repositories containing harvested victim data were being added every 30 minutes. &lt;a href="https://research.jfrog.com/post/shai-hulud-the-second-coming/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;And researchers at JFrog identified 181 compromised packages.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The current campaign introduces a new variant, which Wiz researchers dub Shai-Hulud 2.0, that executes malicious code during the preinstall phase, “significantly increasing potential exposure in build and runtime environments.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The threat leverages compromised package maintainer accounts to publish trojanized versions of legitimate npm packages. Once installed, the malware exfiltrates developer and CI/CD secrets to GitHub repositories, and also inserts the malicious payload into all of the users’ available npm packages. Threat actors could also use the exfiltrated secrets to break into and install more malware in victims’ IT systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JFrog said this new variant generates randomized repository names for exfiltration, making it harder for security teams to hunt down and scrub the leaked secrets. JFrog also said the new payload contains new functionality, including privilege escalation, DNS hijacking, and the ability to delete data from the victim’s machine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Multiple popular packages used by developers, including those from Zapier, ENS Domains, PostHog, and Postman, have been compromised.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reversinglabs.com/blog/another-shai-hulud-npm-worm-is-spreading-heres-what-you-need-to-know" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Researchers at ReversingLabs also noted &lt;/a&gt;the list of compromised packages includes AsyncAPI related packages, including &lt;a href="https://secure.software/npm/packages/@asyncapi/specs" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;@asyncapi/specs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which has had more than 100 million lifetime downloads and an average of 1.4 million weekly downloads. This package in particular is also believed to be the ‘patient-zero’, or the first known infected package, for this wave of attack, the researchers added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="second-wave-is-bigger-and-faster"&gt;Second wave is bigger and faster&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Developers and security teams looking for indicators of compromise should note that the new variant adds two new payload files: &lt;em&gt;setup_bun.js&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;bun_environment.js&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The re-emergence of the worm indicates that this remains a current and serious threat to the npm ecosystem,” said &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute. “CSOs must address this threat by monitoring the components used in their software and hardening their CI/CD pipelines to increase resilience in the event that malicious code is executed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shai-Hulud &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4058059/warning-hackers-have-inserted-credential-stealing-code-into-some-npm-libraries.html" target="_blank"&gt;first emerged in September&lt;/a&gt;, revealed by the discovery that dozens of npm libraries, including a color library with over 2 million downloads a week, had been replaced with malicious versions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The initial Shai-Hulud wave was already one of the most severe JavaScript supply-chain attacks Wiz has seen, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/merav-bar-608351232/?originalSubdomain=il" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Merav Bar&lt;/a&gt;, a company threat researcher and co-author of the report told &lt;em&gt;CSO&lt;/em&gt;. “This new wave is bigger and faster: more than 25,000 attacker-created repos across roughly 350 GitHub users, growing by about 1,000 repos every 30 minutes, with malware that steals developer and cloud credentials and runs in the preinstall phase, touching dev machines and CI/CD pipelines alike. That combination of scale, speed, and access makes it a high-impact campaign.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="assume-compromise"&gt;Assume compromise&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an individual had pulled any of the affected packages during the November 21–23 window, she said, they should assume their environment is exposed. Remedies include clearing the npm cache on their workstation, removing &lt;em&gt;node_modules&lt;/em&gt;, reinstalling from clean versions, or pinning to versions published before the malicious releases, and rotating any tokens or secrets that were present (GitHub PATs, npm tokens, SSH keys, cloud credentials).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enabling strong MFA on GitHub/npm and watching for unexpected new repos or workflow files in the developer’s personal account is also critical, she added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shai-Hulud’s second wave isn’t surprising, said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/brad-laporte/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brad LaPorte&lt;/a&gt;, cybersecurity advisor at Morphisec. “The first attack showed how easily preinstall scripts could be weaponized. This wave proves what happens when those warnings aren’t acted on: larger scale, more destructive payloads, and automation that infects thousands of repositories in hours.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="recommendations-for-repositories"&gt;Recommendations for repositories&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To stop attackers from easily uploading malicious packages, npm needs to tighten its publishing process, LaPorte said, including ensuring the identity of new accounts is verified before they are allowed to publish packages; implementing rate limits to prevent attackers from uploading multiple malicious packages in a short period and monitoring package maintainers for suspicious activity such as sudden spikes in publishing or packages with significant unexplained changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“From what we’ve observed in the Shai-Hulud incidents,” said Bar of Wiz, “the core issue isn’t npm specifically. It’s that open-source registries now function as high-impact distribution hubs, and attackers are taking advantage of how much trust developers place in them. In that context, the most important thing is continuing to strengthen the guardrails around how packages are published and updated. That includes making it harder for compromised maintainer accounts to push malicious versions, increasing visibility into unusual publishing behavior, and helping downstream users quickly understand when a package version may be unsafe. Those are ecosystem-level defenses rather than criticisms of any single registry, but they reflect the direction the entire open-source community will need to move as attacks like Shai-Hulud become more automated and far-reaching.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ensar Seker, CISO at SOCRadar, cautioned that Shai‑Hulud isn’t what he called typical package compromise. “It’s a worm embedded into the dev supply chain. It signals that attackers are shifting from targeting compiled binaries and runtime environments toward the very processes developers use to build and ship software. No organization should assume, ‘We don’t use npm, so we’re safe’, because even downstream dependencies or dev toolchains can become the launch pad.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So far npm has focused on ensuring that package authors are properly authenticated and that packages are not altered after being published, said Ullrich of the SANS Institute. But, he added, this does not prevent a malicious actor from publishing malicious packages. Recently, npm further restricted the default access token lifetimes and started to revoke legacy ‘classic tokens,’ he acknowledged. “npm may need to implement some form of automated scanning for obvious malicious content, but it will be difficult to implement a meaningful solution.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="recommendations-for-security-teams-developers"&gt;Recommendations for security teams, developers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wiz says security teams in organizations with application developer teams that use npm – and individual developers using npm and GitHub – should:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clear each developer’s npm cache;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;pin dependencies to known clean versions or roll back to pre-November 21 builds;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;revoke and regenerate npm tokens, GitHub PATs, SSH keys and cloud provider credentials;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;enforce phishing-resistant multifactor authentication for developer and CI/CD (continuous integration/continuous delivery) accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Within GitHub and CI/CD environments, they should search for newly-created repositories with ‘Shai-Hulud’ in the description, review unauthorized workflows or suspicious commits referencing hulud, and monitor for new npm publishes under their organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For long-term protection CSOs and IT leaders are urged to restrict or disable lifecycle scripts (postinstall, preinstall) in CI/CD environments, limit outbound network access from built systems to trusted domains only, and make sure developers use only short-lived, scoped automation login tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095578/new-shai-hulud-worm-spreading-through-npm-github.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OnSolve CodeRED cyberattack disrupts emergency alert systems nationwide</title>
      <link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/onsolve-codered-cyberattack-disrupts-emergency-alert-systems-nationwide/</link>
      <description>Risk management company Crisis24 has confirmed its OnSolve CodeRED platform suffered a cyberattack that disrupted emergency notification systems used by state and local governments, police departments, and fire agencies across the United States. [...]</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/onsolve-codered-cyberattack-disrupts-emergency-alert-systems-nationwide/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:48:40 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help4U: A new digital platform to support young people facing online sexual abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</link>
      <description>A new digital platform, Help4U, developed by Europol and CENTRIC, has been launched to support children and teenagers facing sexual abuse or online harm. Designed to be simple, private, and accessible, Help4U supports young people with finding trusted advice, understanding their rights, and connecting with people who can help. The platform offers clear, practical guidance for anyone under 18 who needs help, as well as information for parents, teachers, and professionals supporting them.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-770)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-771)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-772)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-773)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-766) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 effektive Multicloud-Security-Tipps</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4008907/8-effektive-multicloud-security-tipps.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 4403w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Krasovski-Dimitri-shutterstock_1277815804_16z9.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Mit dem falschen Ansatz kann Multicloud-Security zu einem riskanten Balanceakt ausarten.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Krasovski Dimitri | shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eine wachsende Zahl von Unternehmen setzt inzwischen auf eine &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/a/4008348" target="_blank"&gt;Multicloud-Strategie&lt;/a&gt; – in erster Linie, um Workloads genau dort auszuführen, wo es für den jeweiligen Anwendungsfall am günstigsten ist. Und zwar ohne zusätzliche Komplexitäten zu schaffen. Das kann diverse Vorteile realisieren, zum Beispiel in Zusammenhang mit Compliance und Verfügbarkeit. Multicloud-Initiativen können jedoch auch neue Sicherheitslücken entstehen lassen, die diese Benefits im Handumdrehen wieder zunichte machen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sicherheit in Multicloud-Umgebungen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495736/cloud-security-strategie-in-die-cloud-aber-mit-sicherheit.html" target="_blank"&gt;zu gewährleisten&lt;/a&gt;, ist unabhängig von der Unternehmensgröße eine nicht zu unterschätzende Herausforderung. Glücklicherweise können einige relativ simple Methoden und Best Practices dazu beitragen, Angreifer fernzuhalten und Cloud-übergreifend eine sichere, widerstandsfähige Infrastruktur aufzubauen. Welche das sind, haben wir im Gespräch mit einigen Sicherheitsexperten herausgearbeitet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-zentrale-autoritaet-aufbauen"&gt;1. Zentrale Autorität aufbauen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT-Sicherheit liegt bekanntlich in der Verantwortung der gesamten Belegschaft. Dennoch macht es Sinn, ein zentrales Team (oder eine zentrale Rolle) einzurichten, das die Übersicht über sämtliche Security-Angelegenheiten wahrt – und diese strategisch steuert. Dieser Überzeugung ist auch &lt;a href="https://www.securitycompass.com/about-us/trevor-young/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Trevor Young&lt;/a&gt;, Chief Product Officer beim Sicherheitsdienstleister Security Compass: “Dieses Team beziehungsweise diese Rolle sollte koordinieren und eng mit Anwendungs-Teams und Cloud-Ownern zusammenarbeiten.”  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die zentrale Autorität in Sachen IT-Sicherheit ist dafür zuständig:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eine umfassende Sicherheitsstrategie zu definieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;einheitliche Richtlinien und Standards einzuziehen,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Cloud-übergreifende Security-Tools auszuwählen und zu managen, sowie&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Compliance in sämtlichen Cloud-Umgebungen sicherzustellen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-einheitliche-governance-etablieren"&gt;2. Einheitliche Governance etablieren&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein einheitliches Security-Governance-Modell, das alle Cloud-Umgebungen umfasst und durch zentralisiertes &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2763035/was-sie-ueber-iam-wissen-muessen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Identity Management&lt;/a&gt;, Automatisierung und Policy Enforcement unterstützt wird, ist mit Blick auf Multicloud-Umgebungen ebenfalls ratsam.  Nigel Gibbons, Director und Senior Advisor beim Sicherheitsdienstleister NCC Group, outet sich als Anhänger dieses Ansatzes und fasst seine Vorteile zusammen: “Das kann Komplexität reduzieren und Silos auflösen. Zudem reduziert es blinde Flecken, setzt das Least-Privilege-Prinzip durch, ermöglicht es, Bedrohungen in Echtzeit zu erkennen und optimiert die Compliance.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um Risiken über sämtliche Clouds hinweg zuverlässig zu erfassen, empfiehlt Gibbons CISOs und ihren Teams, sich eng mit DevOps-, Plattform- und Compliance-Teams abzustimmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-scope-erweitern"&gt;3. Scope erweitern&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn Sie nur auf eine Cloud setzen, liegt der Fokus meist auf dessen spezifischen Security-Tools und -Services – die Sie im Laufe der Zeit vermutlich immer besser durchdringen. Sind Sie dagegen in mehreren Clouds unterwegs, steigt das Komplexitätslevel drastisch. Denn dann gilt es nicht nur, sich mit mehreren, proprietären Sicherheitsmodellen, Diensten und Terminologien auseinanderzusetzen, wie Security-Compass-Experte Young festhält: “Man kann sich nicht einfach auf die nativen Tools eines Cloud-Anbieters verlassen und erwarten, dass diese alle wichtigen Aspekte abdecken. Eine Multicloud-Umgebung erfordert eine breitere, herstellerunabhängige Strategie.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut dem Experten müssen Anwender, die die Security-Tools der einzelnen Cloud-Anbieter ohne einheitliche Strategie einsetzen, mit zahlreichen Problemen rechnen – beispielweise:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inkonsistenten Richtlinien,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Lücken in der Abdeckung oder&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Security-Events, die sich nicht Cloud-übergreifend korrelieren lassen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Das ist, als hätte man diverse verschiedene Wachleute, die nicht miteinander kommunizieren, aber verschiedene Teile desselben Gebäudes &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3493920/10-essenzielle-masnahmen-fur-physische-sicherheit.html" target="_blank"&gt;bewachen sollen&lt;/a&gt;. Es kommt zwangsläufig zu Sicherheitslücken”, stellt Young in Aussicht.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-trust-boundary-konstruieren"&gt;4. Trust Boundary konstruieren&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Hören Sie ganz generell auf damit, in Clouds zu denken”, empfiehlt  &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stevetcherchian/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Steve Tcherchian&lt;/a&gt;, CISO beim Sicherheitsanbieter XYPRO, und erklärt: “Behandeln Sie jede Umgebung – egal ob AWS, Azure, On-Prem oder Legacy-Mainframe – als Teil einer singulären, einheitlichen Trust Boundary und richten Sie Kontrollmaßnahmen rund um Identitäten, Datenflüsse und Kontexte ein – nicht um Plattformen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anwender, die ihre Sicherheitsstrategie “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492887/aws-google-und-azure-im-vergleich-welcher-hyperscaler-ist-der-sicherste.html" target="_blank"&gt;pro Cloud&lt;/a&gt;” konzipierten, hätten damit bereits ihre Kontrollmöglichkeiten fragmentiert und dürften sich schwertun, das wieder zu bereinigen, ist der CISO überzeugt: “Mit Clouds verhält es sich ein bisschen wie mit Klempnerarbeit: Sicherheitsentscheider und -teams, die zu stark auf Cloud-native Tools fixiert sind, improvisieren am Ende oft abenteuerliche Lösungen, die nicht wirklich zusammenpassen und zeitnah lecken.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-verantwortung-uebernehmen"&gt;5. Verantwortung übernehmen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Obwohl Multicloud-Security nicht nur Sicherheitsentscheider angeht, ist &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/ensar-seker/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ensar Seker&lt;/a&gt;, CISO beim Threat-Intelligence-Spezialisten SOCRadar, davon überzeugt, dass seiner Berufsgattung am Ende des Tages der wesentliche Teil der Accountability zuteil werden sollte: “Letztendlich muss der CISO sicherstellen, dass Technologie-unabhängige Sicherheitsrichtlinien auf- sowie konsequent durchgesetzt werden und mit der Risikotoleranz des Unternehmens in Einklang stehen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dabei sei insbesondere entscheidend, Silos zwischen Teams aufzubrechen und sicherzustellen, dass die Cloud-übergreifende Transparenz unter einer einheitlichen SecOps-Funktion zentralisiert ist, so Seker. “Multicloud ist nicht nur eine Technologiestrategie, sondern sichert auch betriebliche Resilienz. Anwender sollten in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3994110/threat-intelligence-plattformen-ein-kaufratgeber.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cloud-Bedrohungsinformationen&lt;/a&gt; investieren, die übergreifende Angriffsmuster widerspiegeln. Zudem empfiehlt sich der Einsatz von  Laufzeitüberwachung und Policy Drift Detection, um kontinuierliche Sicherheit zu gewährleisten.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-kollaborative-management-umgebung-foerdern"&gt;6. Kollaborative Management-Umgebung fördern&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effektives Security-Management erfordert auch, dass Sicherheitsteams und andere &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2801444/so-bringen-sie-it-und-fachabteilung-unter-einen-hut.html" target="_blank"&gt;wichtige Stakeholder&lt;/a&gt; zusammenwirken. “Nur so lassen sich sämtliche Maßnahmen auf die übergeordneten Business-Ziele abstimmen”, unterstreicht &lt;a href="https://centricconsulting.com/team/brandyn-fisher/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brandyn Fisher&lt;/a&gt;, Director of Security Services bei Centric Consulting. Je nach Organisationsstruktur und Komplexität des Anwenderunternehmens umfasse diese Zusammenarbeit in der Regel Lösungsarchitekten, Cloud-Spezialisten und Systemadministratoren, so Fisher. Er fügt hinzu: “Der effektivste Ansatz ist eine klare Aufteilung der Verantwortlichkeiten.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In der Regel definiere das Sicherheitsteam die Anforderungen und Governance-Rahmenbedingungen, während die Umsetzung ein technisches Team übernehme, so der Chefberater. “Dieser ausgewogene Ansatz schafft klare Zuständigkeiten und fördert gleichzeitig die funktionsübergreifende Kollaboration, die für ein umfassendes Sicherheitsmanagement in multiplen Cloud-Umgebungen erforderlich ist.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Angesichts der rasanten Entwicklung der Cloud-Technologie könne man dabei leicht in Selbstzufriedenheit verfallen, warnt Fisher und rät: “Es ist essenziell, wachsam zu bleiben und proaktiv zu handeln. Sie sollten deshalb die Skills Ihrer Teams im Rahmen von Branchenkonferenzen, Schulungen und der aktiven Beteiligung an Experten-Communities kontinuierlich weiterentwickeln.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-einheitliche-response-strategie-einziehen"&gt;7. Einheitliche Response-Strategie einziehen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eine einheitliche, bedrohungszentrische Detection-and-Response-Strategie die in allen Cloud-Umgebungen funktioniert, ist nach Auffassung von &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mitchem-boles/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mitchem Boles&lt;/a&gt;, Field CISO beim Plattformanbieter Intezer, ein wirksames Mittel, um selbst die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3840232/11-ruinose-ransomware-bedrohungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;raffiniertesten Angreifer&lt;/a&gt; abzuwehren: “Indem sie Warnmeldungen und Verhaltensmuster von AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform und anderen Anbietern in einem zentralisierten System korrelieren, können sich Sicherheitsteams auf echte Bedrohungen fokussieren, statt von Warnmeldungen erschlagen zu werden.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So ermögliche dieser Ansatz den Security-Teams, schneller zu reagieren und parallel den manuellen Aufwand für die Triage in komplexen Umgebungen reduzieren, hält Boles fest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="8-cloud-zugriff-kontrollieren"&gt;8. Cloud-Zugriff kontrollieren&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geht es nach &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaymesdavis/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jaymes David&lt;/a&gt;, Chief Technology Evangelist beim Digital-Workplace-Anbieter Kasm Technologies, sollte Ihr Fokus vor allem darauf liegen, die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492897/attack-surface-management-losungen-9-tools-um-ihre-angriffsflache-zu-managen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Angriffsfläche&lt;/a&gt; Ihrer Multicloud-Umgebung zu reduzieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Beschränken Sie den Zugriff auf Cloud-Ressourcen durch kurzlebige, isolierte Sitzungen. Das minimiert die Wahrscheinlichkeit, dass sich Malware im System halten kann oder sich jemand unbefugt Zugang verschafft. Sitzungsaufzeichnungen, SIEM-Integration, DLP oder Wasserzeichen tragen zu einem starken Sicherheitskonzept bei, das nachverfolgbar, durchsetzbar und überprüfbar ist”, so der Evangelist. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4008907/8-effektive-multicloud-security-tipps.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 signs your cybersecurity framework needs rebuilding</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094743/7-signs-your-cybersecurity-framework-needs-rebuilding.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity frameworks are the guidelines enterprises use to guard against cyberattacks. The typical framework describes the steps needed to address various cybersecurity risks, detecting latent vulnerabilities, and generally improving the enterprise’s digital defense. Any gaps discovered in the attack surface indicates that immediate steps should be taken to rebuild and strengthen cyber resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mitsloan.mit.edu/faculty/directory/keri-pearlson"&gt;Keri Pearlson&lt;/a&gt;, a senior lecturer and principal research scientist at the MIT Sloan School of Management, says there are many signs that indicate an existing cybersecurity framework needs attention. “If your cybersecurity framework hasn’t been reviewed in the last two months, if you haven’t been dynamically updating things, or if your team hasn’t yet incorporated AI into your cybersecurity thinking, you need to review and possibly rebuild your framework,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Are you risking enterprise security by relying on an outdated security framework? Here are warning signs that indicate it may be time for a much-need overhaul.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-not-having-a-dynamic-process-for-recognizing-changes"&gt;1. Not having a dynamic process for recognizing changes&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake, Pearlson says, is failing to recognize that the current plan is out of date or simply not working. Breaches happen, but that doesn’t always mean your cyber framework needs rebuilding. It does, however, indicate that the framework needs to be rethought and redesigned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building a cyber-resilient organization requires thinking differently, Pearlson states. The best approach, she suggests, is deploying a dynamic process that watches for changes in the environment and initiates a rebuilding process.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The key is to have the right sensing and responding mechanism — which is likely a combination of technology and human activities,” she says, noting that technology can sense change and identify anomalies, and people can evaluate whether the change is a risk that requires attention and investment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-experiencing-a-successful-cyberattack-of-any-size"&gt;2. Experiencing a successful cyberattack — of any size&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nothing highlights a weak cybersecurity framework better than a breach, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-bucher-7194057/"&gt;Steven Bucher&lt;/a&gt;, CSO at Mastercard. “I’ve seen firsthand how even a minor incident can reveal outdated protocols or gaps in employee training,” he states. “If your framework hasn’t kept pace with evolving threats or business needs, it’s time for a rebuild.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber threats are always evolving, so staying proactive with regular reviews and fostering a culture of cybersecurity awareness will help catch issues before they become crises, Bucher says. “Ultimately, keeping your framework robust and up-to-date is the best way to protect your organization and maintain trust.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-continuous-oversight-becomes-a-challenge"&gt;3. Continuous oversight becomes a challenge&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your framework can’t provide continuous oversight, or support proactive risk management, then it’s time to rebuild by aligning with established standards, such as the &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework"&gt;NIST Cybersecurity Framework&lt;/a&gt;, and integrating industry-specific compliance requirements as needed, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidefloyd/"&gt;Dave Floyd&lt;/a&gt;, vice president of cybersecurity sales and service for Hughes Network Systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The best approach to rebuild a cybersecurity framework is to begin with the NIST framework and then overlay it with industry-specific compliance requirements, Floyd advises. This approach ensures that best practices and regulatory obligations for healthcare, financial, and other enterprises are fully addressed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-your-formal-framework-review-process-is-measured-in-years"&gt;4. Your formal framework review process is measured in years&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If there haven’t been any material changes to your framework in the past three-plus years, it’s a strong indication that your framework may be outdated, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandra-mcleod-7a6a61b/"&gt;Sandra McLeod&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at Zoom. “The cybersecurity landscape has evolved rapidly, especially with the rise of generative AI — your framework should reflect these shifts.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;McLeod recommends a complete a biannual framework review combined with a cursory review during the gap years. “This helps to ensure that the framework stays aligned with evolving threats, business changes, and regulatory requirements.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ideally, security leaders should always have their security framework in mind while maintaining a rough, running list of areas that could be improved, streamlined, or clarified, McLeod suggests. “These informal insights should be brought into discussions during the cursory reviews to keep continuous improvement top of mind.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-youre-continually-chasing-alerts-without-performing-predictive-assessments"&gt;5. You’re continually chasing alerts without performing predictive assessments&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your organization is continually in a reactive state instead of a proactive posture, it’s time to re-evaluate the framework, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nimabaiati/"&gt;Nima Baiati&lt;/a&gt;, executive director and general manager of commercial software and security solutions at Lenovo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If an organization is stuck in a cycle of continually chasing alerts and incidents, as well as reporting events after the fact &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3511388/want-to-get-ahead-four-activities-that-can-enable-a-more-proactive-security-regime.html"&gt;instead of performing predictive threat assessments&lt;/a&gt;, data analysis, and forward planning, it’s time for a change, Baiati advises. “Of course, there will still be some reactive situations, but if they consume most of the bandwidth of daily operations, it’s probably just a matter of time before more significant incidents occur.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Baiati suggests beginning with a solid understanding of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567279/how-to-establish-your-business-s-risk-tolerance.html"&gt;your organization’s risk appetite&lt;/a&gt; and overall business strategy. “Security, when done right, can be a competitive advantage, since it minimizes operational disruption and optimizes trust,” he states. For example, financial institutions have a low appetite for risk and a critical need to protect the integrity of their data and their reputation. Their business strategy and security are &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080670/what-does-aligning-security-to-the-business-really-mean.html"&gt;inherently connected&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Also, because team members are more mobile than ever, endpoint security is now a focus for network security and needs to be included in the cybersecurity framework. “To build strong endpoint security, organizations should take a comprehensive, layered approach that safeguards all aspects of their digital environment — firmware, hardware, software, and the supply chain,” Baiati says. “Evaluate both on-device and cloud-based AI applications to ensure effective, real-time threat detection and response.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-kris-and-kpis-are-trending-negatively"&gt;6. KRIs and KPIs are trending negatively&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If there’s a sense that key risk indicators (KRIs) and key performance indicators (KPIs) are headed in an unanticipated direction, your framework may need to be re-evaluated, says &lt;a href="https://www.protiviti.com/us-en/sameer-ansari"&gt;Sameer Ansari&lt;/a&gt;, head of the data privacy team lead at audit, risk, and compliance consultancy Protiviti.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations that view their cybersecurity framework as a compliance checklist rather than as a tool to inform proper risk decisions are courting danger, Ansari warns. “Organizations should consider key business objectives and risks that they may face and apply the framework through that lens.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When building or updating a framework, many cybersecurity leaders find themselves caught up in benchmarking or comparing themselves to other firms instead of focusing on what matters to their organization, Ansari says. Worse yet is believing that quantity is more important than quality. “Some cybersecurity chiefs will try to combine several different frameworks, creating an unmanageable ‘Frankenstein framework’ that becomes very hard to manage and sustain,” he warns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-youve-taken-a-compliance-based-approach"&gt;7. You’ve taken a compliance-based approach&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A common mistake many cybersecurity leaders make is designing a framework that’s primarily designed to “pass the audit,” says &lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/daniel-tobok/"&gt;Daniel Tobok&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of incident response firm CYPFER, instead of targeting business objectives. He cautions that a compliance-only approach often excludes critical input from non-IT stakeholders and typically results in a framework that looks good on paper but fails to deliver meaningful protection in practice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ideally, a cybersecurity framework should evolve continuously, with priority given to the highest-risk areas, Tobok advises. “However, a full rebuild may be necessary when the existing framework no longer protects the organization effectively, or when the cost of incremental fixes outweighs the benefits.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He adds that rebuilding is also warranted immediately after a major enterprise shift, such as a change to the business model, an amended regulatory environment, or an extended threat landscape, all of which can make the existing framework outdated or insufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094743/7-signs-your-cybersecurity-framework-needs-rebuilding.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-774)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-775)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telecom security reboot: Why zero trust is the only way forward</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095382/telecom-security-reboot-why-zero-trust-is-the-only-way-forward.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Telecom networks are everywhere. They keep the world moving — all the way from managing data, powering business, connecting people across continents and whatnot. For a long time, security in this space was pretty straightforward: build a wall, keep threats outside and trust everything inside. Back when networks were locked down and closed, that was enough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But those days are over. Now, workloads sprawl across hybrid clouds, edge devices multiply and third-party vendors are everywhere. The old perimeter? It’s gone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s where zero trust comes in. Not just the latest buzzword, but a must-have survival tool. The problem is, a lot of companies think zero trust is something you can just buy off the shelf. That’s not how it works.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The misunderstanding holding telecom back&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Everywhere you look in telecom, “zero trust” pops up — in boardrooms, strategy docs and vendor pitches. But somewhere along the way, people lost sight of what it really means. Too many leaders treat it like a compliance box to tick or another software rollout.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The truth’s pretty stark: Zero trust is a mindset. It’s about swapping assumptions for constant proof. When that mindset becomes part of the culture, security finally stops being just another chore and becomes how you operate. But most telcos haven’t made that mental shift. They’re living with a false sense of safety and attackers are taking full advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;IT and OT: Impact is linked&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most OT attacks start in IT environments these days. Once attackers get hold of admin credentials or find a weak interface, they can jump straight into the network gear or base-station controllers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bridging this isn’t about shuffling org charts. It’s about seeing everything at once and building a single rulebook. Shared access policies, clear patch priorities and unified threat detection — when you get all that working together, zero trust finally turns into something real.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The real enemies: Persistence and patience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Telecom operators aren’t just up against lone hackers or ransomware gangs anymore. The big threat is patient, well-funded groups — nation-state actors who know how to stay invisible. Attacks like Salt Typhoon have proven these groups can live inside telecom networks for months, quietly stealing data with real geopolitical stakes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA has flagged Volt Typhoon and other China-linked groups for &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa23-144a" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;breaking into telecom operators all over the world since 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Building trust where none exists&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust isn’t just a tech upgrade — it’s about habits. And three habits matter most: always verify, give only what’s needed and make sure problems can’t spread.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always verify:&lt;/strong&gt; Logging in isn’t the end of the check. Every person, device and system gets watched — where they’re connecting from, what they’re doing and if it all looks normal.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Least privilege:&lt;/strong&gt; The less power someone or something has, the less damage they can do if things go sideways. Tightening that up slashes risk — no fancy new tools required.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Segment the network:&lt;/strong&gt; Stop trouble from spreading. Slice networks into smaller, isolated zones — micro-segments. When networks are divided this way, potential breaches can be minimised.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The elephant in the room: legacy tech&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest — legacy infrastructure isn’t going anywhere. Network hardware built decades ago still runs the show, designed for nonstop uptime when trust used to be automatic. Swapping it all out for something new? That’s a massive risk, not to mention wildly expensive. But pretending you can just leave everything as is — that’s worse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, what actually works? You wrap old systems in modern “security shells.” Think secure gateways, centralized authentication and session monitoring. These layers let you boost security now, without gambling with service outages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust isn’t about chasing some perfect setup. It’s about uplifting security posture, step by step. Every verified connection, every workload you isolate, makes your network tougher.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Compliance that works across borders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust doesn’t toss out your compliance rules — it builds on them. Whether you’re dealing with ISO 27001, the NIST Cybersecurity Framework, the EU’s NIS2 Directive or any other local telecom regulation, the bottom line stays the same: keep checking your risks, control who gets in and prove you’re on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once you bake zero trust into these frameworks, compliance stops being a headache. Instead of just ticking boxes, compliance becomes part of everyday security. As threats shift, your protections shift with them. No matter where your network lives, you’re covered and ready for inspection.&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="measurable-momentum-6-kpis-for-the-first-180-days"&gt;Measurable momentum: 6 KPIs for the first 180 days&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Executives don’t want vague promises — they want proof. In the first six months of rolling out zero trust, here’s what you actually track:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list" start="1"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You see fewer privileged accounts floating around.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Strange activity gets spotted faster.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Access approvals don’t drag on — governance finally moves at the speed of business.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;More endpoints and workloads are under watch.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;There’s a drop in hackers sneaking around your network.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;IT and OT teams? They’re running real joint-response drills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These aren’t just stats to show off. They prove zero trust isn’t hype — it works. Progress you can point to and build on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;From buzzword to baseline&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust isn’t just talk anymore. It’s how you measure if a network’s really secure. For telecom, adopting it isn’t for show — it’s survival.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner says that by 2027, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/apac/security-risk-management-australia/featured-topics/zero-trust-architecture" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;70% of organizations will start with zero trust for security&lt;/a&gt;. That’s up from less than 20% today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’re still clinging to old perimeter defenses, you’re fighting yesterday’s battles. The leaders see zero trust as a journey. They’re building the networks we’ll all count on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095382/telecom-security-reboot-why-zero-trust-is-the-only-way-forward.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.05</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-776)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-777)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grafana security advisory (AV25-778)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688) – Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JPMorgan, Citi, Morgan Stanley assess fallout from SitusAMC data breach</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095182/jpmorgan-citi-morgan-stanley-assess-fallout-from-situsamc-data-breach.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Chase, Citi, and Morgan Stanley are among the major US banks assessing potential customer data exposure following a cyberattack on SitusAMC, a third-party vendor that processes residential mortgage data for hundreds of financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The New York-based company discovered the breach on November 12 and confirmed on November 22 that attackers accessed information from its systems, &lt;a href="https://www.situsamc.com/databreach" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to a company advisory&lt;/a&gt;. SitusAMC said the compromised data includes corporate information such as accounting records and legal agreements, and that “certain data relating to some of our clients’ customers may also have been impacted.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The scope, nature and extent of such impact remains under investigation by the Company and its third-party advisors,” the advisory said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The New York Times reported Saturday that JPMorgan Chase, Citi, and Morgan Stanley were among institutions notified by SitusAMC about potential client data exposure, citing five people briefed on the incident.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When contacted by CSO, JPMorgan declined to comment on the breach. Citi and Morgan Stanley did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="fbi-says-no-operational-impact-reported"&gt;FBI says no operational impact reported&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FBI Director Kash Patel told The New York Times that the bureau is working with affected organizations to assess the breach. Kash said that the FBI has not yet found any operational impact on banking services and is continuing to investigate the matter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SitusAMC, which employs approximately 5,000 people and is owned by several private equity firms, provides loan origination, servicing, and regulatory compliance services to major lenders. The company’s role in mortgage processing involves handling extensive personal information, including Social Security numbers, financial account details, and employment records, as found on loan applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company said that the incident is now contained and services remain fully operational. No encrypting malware was involved, indicating threat actors focused on data exfiltration rather than ransomware deployment, according to the advisory.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The scope of the breach remains under investigation. SitusAMC said it implemented several security measures following the incident, including credential resets, disabling remote access tools, updating firewall rules, and enhancing security settings.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="third-party-breaches-accelerating"&gt;Third-party breaches accelerating&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SitusAMC incident is part of a broader trend of increasing cyberattacks targeting third-party vendors in the financial services sector. Third parties accounted for 30% of data breaches in 2024, a 15% increase from 2023, according to Venminder’s State of Third-Party Risk Management 2025 &lt;a href="https://www.venminder.com/blog/third-party-cybersecurity-risks-in-financial-services" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt;. The survey found 49% of organizations experienced third-party cybersecurity incidents last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The financial services sector has seen particularly heavy vendor-related cyberattack activity. &lt;a href="https://www.finra.org/rules-guidance/guidance/cybersecurity-advisory-third-party-provider-risks"&gt;FINRA observed&lt;/a&gt; a large increase in incidents during the first half of 2024, with threat actors targeting vulnerabilities in system management tools and technology products used by third-party providers. Notable incidents in 2024 included data breaches at Microsoft, Snowflake, and Dropbox that had a widespread impact on financial services firms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In October, the New York Department of Financial Services issued &lt;a href="https://www.dfs.ny.gov/industry-guidance/industry-letters/il20251021-guidance-managing-risks-third-party" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;guidance&lt;/a&gt; emphasizing that regulated entities remain fully responsible for cybersecurity when outsourcing to service providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SEC also amended Regulation S-P in 2024 to require firms’ incident response programs to include written policies for overseeing service providers through due diligence and monitoring. The regulation requires firms to establish, maintain, and enforce written policies reasonably designed to require oversight of service providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FINRA has also reminded member firms of their supervisory obligations related to outsourcing to third-party vendors. The self-regulatory organization noted that firms have an obligation to establish and maintain a supervisory system for any activities or functions third-party vendors perform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="investigation-continues"&gt;Investigation continues&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company has established a dedicated email for inquiries and said that it will provide updates to clients as the investigation progresses. The advisory did not specify how many institutions or customers may be affected or give a timeline for completing the forensic investigation. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are in direct, regular contact with our clients about this matter,” SitusAMC said in the statement. “We remain focused on analyzing any potentially affected data and will provide updates directly to our clients as our investigation progresses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095182/jpmorgan-citi-morgan-stanley-assess-fallout-from-situsamc-data-breach.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New ClickFix attacks use fake Windows Update screens to fool employees</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096241/new-clickfix-attacks-use-fake-windows-update-screens-to-fool-employees.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs and Windows admins should disable the ability of personal computers to automatically run commands to block the latest version of the ClickFix social engineering attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This advice comes from researchers at Huntress, &lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/blog/clickfix-malware-buried-in-images" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;who this week warned&lt;/a&gt; that a new version of ClickFix-based attacks, where employees are tricked into running malicious commands, is circulating.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest tactics of this campaign include steganography — hiding malware in the pixels of an image — and a “highly convincing” fake Windows Update screen that asks the user to open a Run prompt, then paste in and run a malicious command.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That command delivers the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3993289/feds-and-microsoft-crush-lumma-stealer-that-stole-millions-of-passwords.html" target="_blank"&gt;LummaC2&lt;/a&gt; and Rhadamanthys infostealers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress notes that its report comes after the November 13 &lt;a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Operation Endgame law enforcement takedowns&lt;/a&gt; targeting the Rhadamanthys infrastructure. As of November 19, multiple active domains continued to host the Windows Update Lure page associated with the Rhadamanthys campaign. All of these lures point to the same hex-encoded URL structure previously linked to the deployment of Rhadamanthys, although it appears this payload is no longer being hosted. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first step defenders should take is to stop the ability of this malware to run, says the report. “The most effective way to mitigate ClickFix is by disabling the Windows Run box,” says Huntress, either by modifying the Windows Registry or deploying GPO (group policy object) rules to block interaction with the Windows Run box.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After that, the report recommends the standard response for fighting all social engineering attacks: Effective employee security awareness training. “Ensure users are trained on the ClickFix methodology,” says the report, “emphasizing that legitimate CAPTCHA or Windows Update processes will never require pasting and running commands.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="clickfix-warnings"&gt;ClickFix warnings&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/08/21/think-before-you-clickfix-analyzing-the-clickfix-social-engineering-technique/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;have been warning about ClickFix attacks&lt;/a&gt; (sometimes called pastejacking) since at least early 2024. They often start with a phishing lure that pulls the victim to a realistic fake landing page that purports to be a Windows Update page or a government department website. The heart of the attack is in giving users instructions that involve clicking on prompts and copying, pasting, and running commands directly in  the Windows &lt;em&gt;Run&lt;/em&gt; dialog box, Windows Terminal, or Windows PowerShell. This leads to the downloading of scripts that launch malware.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Two new tactics are used in the latest ClickFix campaign, says Huntress:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the use since early October of a fake blue Windows Update splash page in full-screen, displaying realistic “Working on updates” animations that eventually conclude by prompting the user to follow the standard ClickFix pattern: open the Run prompt (Win+R), then paste and run the malicious command.&lt;br /&gt;Why would an employee do this? Because the request is part of an alleged test to prove the victim is human. A screen saying “Human Verification. Follow 3 quick steps to verify you’re not a robot.” is displayed. It’s like a CAPTCHA request, which is familiar to employees these days. In this case, the three steps are: press the Windows button + R (which opens the Run box); press CTRL + V (which pastes in a command that was automatically copied to the clipboard); and then press Enter to “verify” (which actually runs the command that triggers downloading of scripts).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;steganography, which conceals the final malware stages within an image. Rather than simply appending malicious data to a file, the malicious code is encoded directly within the pixel data of PNG images, relying on specific colour channels to reconstruct and decrypt the payload in memory;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an email, report co-author Ana Pham said steganography is not new to malware operations. “What stands out here is the implementation: rather than simply appending malicious data to an image file, this campaign encodes the payload directly into the RGB pixel values of PNG images, extracting shellcode by reading specific color channels and applying XOR decryption. It’s a more involved approach than basic file-appending techniques, designed to evade signature-based detection.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Windows Update-themed tactic is particularly effective because it mimics something users expect to see: a full-screen Windows Update splash page with realistic animations, she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Given how convincing this lure is compared to standard ‘robot verification’ pages, it’s reasonable to expect other threat actors will adopt similar approaches,” she added. “The source code for these lures contains Russian-language comments and isn’t heavily obfuscated, meaning it could be shared or copied by other groups relatively easily.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attacks-are-now-rampant"&gt;Attacks are now ‘rampant’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ClickFix has become rampant among Huntress’ customers, she said, and is one of the most prevalent threats seen this year. In the past six months, the company has seen a 313% increase in ClickFix-related incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress responded to 76 separate incidents tied to this specific campaign over a one month period from late September through October, with attacks targeting organizations across multiple regions, including the United States, Europe/Middle East/Africa, and Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What ties the incidents together is a specific indicator, Pham said: the initial payload, which ultimately delivers the steganographic loader, always contains a URL where the second octet is encoded in hexadecimal format.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Palo Alto Networks Unit 42 threat intelligence division have also reported seeing more ClickFix attacks. &lt;a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/preventing-clickfix-attack-vector/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In a July report&lt;/a&gt;, they said attackers lure victims into copying and pasting commands to apply quick fixes to common computer issues such as performance problems, missing drivers, or pop-up errors. Fake tech support forums are one way these attack start. Threat actors have also been known, in other campaigns, to use fake DocuSign and Okta single-sign-on pages to trick users. Payloads include infostealers, remote access trojans (RATS), or tools that disable security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This delivery method bypasses many standard detection and prevention controls” says the Palo Alto report. “There is no exploit, phishing attachment, or malicious link. Instead, potential victims unknowingly run the command themselves, through a trusted system shell. This method makes infections from ClickFix more complicated to detect than drive-by downloads or traditional malware droppers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In yet another instance, researchers at NCC Group today &lt;a href="https://www.nccgroup.com/research-blog/fake-captcha-led-to-lumma/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;issued this report&lt;/a&gt; on a ClickFix attack they discovered in May that involved a drive-by compromise and the use of a fake CAPTCHA popup, with the goal of installing the Lumma C2 Stealer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-csos-should-do"&gt;What CSOs should do&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But CSOs aren’t without defenses. One is disabling the Windows Run dialogue through registry modifications or Group Policy. As well, they should audit the RunMRU registry key (which keeps a copy of the most recently executed commands from the Run window) during investigations to check if users have executed suspicious commands through the Run dialog. Palo Alto Networks notes some key indicators for suspicious RunMRU contents could be obfuscated content, keywords related to the download and execution of payloads from unknown or suspicious domains, and keywords indicating calls to administrative interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pham also said leaders should deploy endpoint monitoring for suspicious process chains, particularly watching for &lt;em&gt;explorer.exe&lt;/em&gt; spawning &lt;em&gt;mshta.exe&lt;/em&gt;, or PowerShell with unusual command-line arguments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks also warned that some attackers aim to avoid exposing their activity in the RunMRU registry key by presenting instructions to launch a terminal for PowerShell (Windows 11) or Command Prompt (Windows 10). EDR telemetry or Windows Event Logs will show signs of this tactic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While security awareness training is important, it shouldn’t be the only line of defense, said Pham.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“ClickFix succeeds because it exploits user trust and habitual behavior,” she said. “Users instinctively trust CAPTCHA checks and Windows update screens as routine parts of their day. Even well-trained users can be caught off guard by a convincing full-screen Windows Update animation. The most effective [mitigation] approach combines user education with technical controls: disabling the Run dialog, monitoring for suspicious process behavior, and maintaining robust endpoint detection. Defense in depth matters here, training reduces the likelihood someone falls for the lure, but technical controls provide a safety net when they do.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At this time Huntress doesn’t have enough evidence to determine whether this specific campaign was run by a particular threat actor or multiple groups of threat actors, Pham noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096241/new-clickfix-attacks-use-fake-windows-update-screens-to-fool-employees.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 01:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qilin Ransomware Turns South Korean MSP Breach Into 28-Victim 'Korean Leaks' Data Heist</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/qilin-ransomware-turns-south-korean-msp.html</link>
      <description>South Korea's financial sector has been targeted by what has been described as a sophisticated supply chain attack that led to the deployment of Qilin ransomware.
"This operation combined the capabilities of a major Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) group, Qilin, with potential involvement from North Korean state-affiliated actors (Moonstone Sleet), leveraging Managed Service Provider (MSP)</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/qilin-ransomware-turns-south-korean-msp.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alliances between ransomware groups tied to recent surge in cybercrime</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096263/alliances-between-ransomware-groups-tied-to-recent-surge-in-cybercrime.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A seasonal surge in malicious activity combined with alliances between &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3509281/top-10-ransomware-groups-to-watch.html"&gt;ransomware groups&lt;/a&gt; led to a 41% increase in attacks between September and October. Cybercriminal group Qilin continues to be the most active &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563507/what-is-ransomware-how-it-works-and-how-to-remove-it.html"&gt;ransomware&lt;/a&gt; paddlers, responsible for 170 of 594 attacks (29%) in October, &lt;a href="https://insights.nccgroup.com/review-of-october-2025-threat-intelligence-report%20"&gt;NCC Group reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sinobi and Akira followed with 15% of ransomware attacks rounding up the top three most active ransomware groups in October 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ramp-up in ransomware attacks follows several months of relative stability in the number of attacks from April to August, including a dip between April and June.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Activity began to pick up at the end of the Northern Hemisphere summer, with September recording a 28% month-on-month increase – momentum that has now accelerated into October’s spike, NCC reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The October surge indicates that threat actors are intensifying their operations ahead of what is typically the most active period for cyber crime. “The fourth ‘golden quarter’ of the year sees peak consumer spending from Black Friday, Cyber Monday, and Christmas, presenting greater opportunity for cyber threat actors,” according to NCC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NCC Group’s stats are derived from actively monitoring leak sites favoured by each ransomware group. Of the 594 attacks in October, industrials remained the most targeted sector, with 28% (167) of all attacks. Consumer discretionary (which includes automotive manufacturers, retail businesses, and leisure facilities) suffered 124 attacks. Healthcare moved to third place with 64 attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;North America was hit hardest by ransomware attacks, suffering over half of these incidents (62%), compared to Europe (17%) and Asia (9%).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An annual &lt;a href="https://www.guidepointsecurity.com/newsroom/active-ransomware-groups-reach-an-all-time-high-guidepoint-security-finds/"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; from Guidepoint Security found a 57% year-over-year increase in active ransomware groups. At the same time ransomware victim numbers have stabilized at approximately 1,500-1,600 per quarter since Q4 2024, according to figures from Guidepoint.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ransomware-groups-alliances-axis-of-evil"&gt;Ransomware groups’ alliances: axis of evil&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;New players and alliances between ransomware groups contributed to the overall increase in ransomware attacks in October.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, the &lt;a href="https://flashpoint.io/blog/lockbit-5-0-analysis-technical-deep-dive-into-the-raas-giants-latest-upgrade/"&gt;newly relaunched LockBit 5.0 group&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4070290/lockbit-dragonforce-and-qilin-form-a-cartel-to-dictate-ransomware-market-conditions.html"&gt;aligned itself with other prominent ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) groups DragonForce and Qilin.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alliances between threat groups enable the sharing of tools, infrastructure and tactics to make their attacks more effective.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The alliance between LockBit, DragonForce and Qilin combines technical expertise, resources and infrastructure, creating a network capable of sustaining large-scale ransomware operations whilst complicating attribution and response for organisations and law enforcement,” according to NCC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although no coordinated attacks have been confirmed yet these loose alliances could act as a recruiting tool for affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The partnership is also likely aimed at rebuilding LockBit’s reputation within the cybercrime community, reassuring affiliates of its continued relevance and operational capacity following the 2024 law enforcement disruptions,” NCC adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, new entrants in the form of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4054790/ransomware-upstart-the-gentlemen-raises-the-stakes-for-ot%E2%80%91heavy-sectors.html"&gt;The Gentlemen ransomware group&lt;/a&gt; burst onto the threat landscape with 21 attack claims against healthcare, financial services and IT firms, among others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Part of the reason we are seeing more ransomware groups and variants in the landscape is the increasingly lowered technical barrier to entry for cyber crime,” according to NCC. “Ransomware builders have been consistently leaked or released, meaning that threat actors with low levels of technical sophistication are still able to conduct effective campaigns.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ransomware-groups-change-tactics-to-evade-law-enforcement"&gt;Ransomware groups change tactics to evade law enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest quarterly &lt;a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/tr-rapid7-q3-2025-threat-landscape-report/"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; from Rapid7 also found that newly forged alliances are leading to a spike in ransomware activity while adding that tactical innovations, from refined extortion to double extortion and use of zero day, are also playing a part in increased malfeasance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The quarter also saw 88 active ransomware groups, up from 65 in Q2 and 76 in Q1, signalling an increase in activity as well as highlighting the changing shape of a febrile threat environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Groups such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079316/cross-platform-ransomware-qilin-weaponizes-linux-binaries-against-windows-hosts.html"&gt;Qilin&lt;/a&gt;, SafePay, and WorldLeaks led a wave of alliances targeting industries like business services, manufacturing, and healthcare, Rapid7 reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These same groups began experimenting with file-less operations, single-extortion data leaks, and affiliate service offerings such as ransom negotiation assistance, where a more senior member of the group partners with a less experienced player to extort the victim.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber extortion incident response firm Coveware reports that remote access compromise, phishing/social engineering, and software vulnerability exploitation remain at the core of intrusion activity, but the distinctions between them are increasingly blurred.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Adversaries increasingly obtain access not just by logging into a system, but by convincing someone else to provision it for them,” Coveware explains. “Campaigns that blurred these lines, such as those impersonating SaaS support teams or abusing help-desk processes to gain OAuth authorization, demonstrated how human trust can be engineered into a technical foothold.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Credential-based intrusions through VPNs, cloud gateways, and SaaS integrations continued to serve as the prime vector of ransomware attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Coveware Q3 2005 ransomware &lt;a href="https://www.coveware.com/blog/2025/10/24/insider-threats-loom-while-ransom-payment-rates-plummet#payments"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; identified Akira and Qilin as the two most prominent ransomware variants doing the rounds. Some ransomware groups are rebranding as data-theft-only outfit, ditching file encryption as an extortion tactic, Coveware adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="review-and-reinforce-cybersecurity-measures"&gt;Review and reinforce cybersecurity measures&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Matt Hull, head of threat intelligence at NCC Group, said more than 200 ransomware variants have been identified so far this year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As ransomware activity accelerates and notable attacks continue to cause widespread economic and operational disruption, vigilance is more critical than ever. Organisations should use this moment to reinforce their security measures and test incident response plans,” Hull said. “Proactive monitoring, staff awareness, and secure backups remain key as we move into the year’s peak threat season.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096263/alliances-between-ransomware-groups-tied-to-recent-surge-in-cybercrime.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neue ClickFix-Kampagne nutzt Fake-Windows-Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096763/neue-clickfix-kampagne-nutzt-fake-windows-updates.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Windows Update" class="wp-image-4000198" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/winUpdate.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Cyberkriminelle nutzen eine gefälschte Windows-Update-Seite, um Mitarbeiter anzugreifen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;PixieMe / Shutterstock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forscher des Security-Anbieters Huntress sind kürzlich auf eine neue ClickFix-Kampagne gestoßen, die auf Mitarbeiter in Unternehmen zielt. Laut &lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/blog/clickfix-malware-buried-in-images" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Forschungsbericht &lt;/a&gt;haben die Angreifer ihre Malware dabei in den Pixeln eines Bildes versteckt, das eine Windows-Update-Seite vortäuscht. Dort werden die Benutzer aufgefordert, auf Ausführen zu klicken, um einen bösartigen Befehl einzufügen und auszuführen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieser Befehl liefert Infostealer LummaC2 und Rhadamanthys aus. Huntress weist darauf hin, dass sein Bericht nach dem 13. November veröffentlicht wurde, als der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089207/operation-endgame-schaltet-schadsoftware-ab.html" target="_blank"&gt;Ermittlungserfolg gegen Rhadamanthys&lt;/a&gt; bekannt gegeben wurde. Demnach hosteten mehrere aktive Domains noch am 19. November die gefälschte Windows Update -Seite, die mit der Rhadamanthys-Kampagne in Verbindung steht. „Alle Fake-Seiten verweisen auf dieselbe codierte URL-Struktur, die zuvor mit dem Einsatz von Rhadamanthys in Verbindung stand“, so die Forscher. Die Payload wird jedoch offenbar nicht mehr gehostet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="clickfix-angriffe-sind-nichts-neues"&gt;ClickFix-Angriffe sind nichts Neues&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experten &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4018769/clickfix-attacken-bedrohen-unternehmenssicherheit.html" target="_blank"&gt;haben bereits zuvor vor ClickFix-Angriffen&lt;/a&gt; (manchmal auch als „Pastejacking“ bezeichnet) gewarnt. Sie beginnen oft mit einem Phishing-Köder, der das Opfer auf eine realistisch aussehende gefälschte Landing Page lockt, die vorgibt, eine Windows Update-Seite oder eine Website einer Regierungsbehörde zu sein. Der Kern des Angriffs besteht darin, den Benutzern Anweisungen zu geben, die das Klicken auf Eingabeaufforderungen und das Kopieren, Einfügen und Ausführen von Befehlen direkt im Windows-Dialogfeld „Ausführen“, Windows Terminal oder Windows PowerShell beinhalten. Dies führt zum Herunterladen von Skripten, die Malware starten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ana Pham von Huntress betont gegenüber CSO, dass Steganografie für Malware-Operationen nichts Neues ist. „Das Besondere daran ist die Umsetzung: Anstatt einfach nur schädliche Daten an eine Bilddatei anzuhängen, verschlüsselt diese Kampagne die Payload direkt in den RGB-Pixelwerten von PNG-Bildern, extrahiert Shellcode durch das Auslesen bestimmter Farbkanäle und wendet eine XOR-Entschlüsselung an.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dies sei aufwendiger als einfache Techniken zum Anhängen von Dateien, die darauf ausgelegt sind, signaturbasierte Erkennung zu umgehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die Taktik mit dem Windows Update-Motiv ist besonders effektiv, weil sie etwas nachahmt, was die Nutzer erwarten: eine Vollbild- -Seite von Windows Update mit realistischen Animationen“, sagt sie. „Der Quellcode dieser Köder enthält Kommentare in russischer Sprache und ist nicht stark verschleiert, sodass er relativ leicht von anderen Gruppen geteilt oder kopiert werden kann.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forscher der NCC Group haben kürzlich einen weiteren &lt;a href="https://www.nccgroup.com/research-blog/fake-captcha-led-to-lumma/"&gt;Bericht&lt;/a&gt; über einen ClickFix-Angriff veröffentlicht, den sie im Mai 2025 entdeckt haben. Konkret geht es dabei um eine Drive-by-Kompromittierung und die Verwendung eines gefälschten CAPTCHA-Popups – mit dem Ziel, den Lumma C2 Stealer zu installieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tipps-zum-schutz"&gt;Tipps zum Schutz&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der erste Schritt zur Verteidigung gegen Clickfix-Angriffen besteht laut dem Huntress-Experten Pham darin, die Ausführung der Malware zu unterbinden. „Die effektivste Methode zur Abwehr von ClickFix ist die Deaktivierung des Windows-Ausführungsfelds“, so Huntress, „entweder durch Änderungen in der Windows-Registry oder durch Einsatz von GPO-Regeln (Group Policy Object), um die Interaktion mit dem Windows-Ausführungsfeld zu blockieren.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zudem wird eine Standardmaßnahme zur Bekämpfung aller Social-Engineering-Angriffe empfohlen: eine effektive Schulung der Mitarbeiter zum Thema Sicherheitsbewusstsein. „Stellen Sie sicher, dass die Anwender die ClickFix-Methodik kennen“, heißt es in dem Bericht. „Betonen Sie, dass legitime CAPTCHA- oder Windows-Update-Prozesse niemals das Einfügen und Ausführen von Befehlen erfordern.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Außerdem sollten CISOsSie den RunMRU-Registrierungsschlüssel (der eine Kopie der zuletzt ausgeführten Befehle aus dem Ausführungsfenster speichert) überprüfen, um festzustellen, ob Benutzer verdächtige Befehle über den Ausführungsdialog ausgeführt haben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pham empfiehlt außerdem den Einsatz von Endpoint-Monitoring überwachung für verdächtige Prozessketten –  insbesondere mit Blick auf Fälle, in denen explorer.exe mshta.exe oder PowerShell mit ungewöhnlichen Befehlszeilenargumenten startet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Sicherheitsbewusstseinstrainings sind zwar wichtig, sollten aber nicht die einzige Verteidigungslinie sein“, so Pham. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4096763/neue-clickfix-kampagne-nutzt-fake-windows-updates.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-779)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-780)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-781)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25-782)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.44</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-784)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-783)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-785)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Dark Reading Virtual Event] Cybersecurity Outlook 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/dark-reading-virtual-event-cybersecurity-outlook-2026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/dark-reading-virtual-event-cybersecurity-outlook-2026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 23.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
