<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:18:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-689)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-690)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ericsson security advisory (AV25-691)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-692)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-694)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-583) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-695)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Software Development Teams Can Securely and Ethically Deploy AI Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.securityweek.com/how-software-development-teams-can-securely-and-ethically-deploy-ai-tools/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To deploy AI tools securely and ethically, teams must balance innovation with accountability—establishing strong governance, upskilling developers, and enforcing rigorous code reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com/how-software-development-teams-can-securely-and-ethically-deploy-ai-tools/"&gt;How Software Development Teams Can Securely and Ethically Deploy AI Tools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.securityweek.com"&gt;SecurityWeek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.securityweek.com/how-software-development-teams-can-securely-and-ethically-deploy-ai-tools/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol welcomes the European Investment Bank to its secure information exchange network</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</link>
      <description>The European Investment Bank (EIB) has today joined Europol’s Secure Information Exchange Network Application (SIENA), marking a new step in the cooperation between the two institutions to protect the EU’s financial interests and combat serious crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-welcomes-european-investment-bank-to-its-secure-information-exchange-network</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-666) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-015 - Vulnerability impacting Microsoft Windows Server Update Services - CVE-2025-59287</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global experts advance the joint fight against crypto-enabled crime</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</link>
      <description>The criminal use of cryptocurrency is becoming increasingly professionalised, but so too is the global response. Participants at the 9th Global Conference on Criminal Finances and Cryptoassets emphasised three priorities: developing common standards, deepening cooperation and investing in capacity. These are essential if authorities and industry are to keep pace with evolving threats and recover illicit cryptoassets at scale.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/global-experts-advance-joint-fight-against-crypto-enabled-crime</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden hosts naval exercise with 200 special tactics operators</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</link>
      <description>Preparing to fight terrorism on land and seaThe exercise scenario focused on the deployment of special intervention units and naval assets during day- and night-time, simulating terrorist and hostage incidents on board of cruise liners and ferries. Day after day, the participants faced new challenges on the water and on some of the archipelago’s many islands, slowly preparing them for...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake number, real damage: Europol urges action against caller ID spoofing</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</link>
      <description>Europol is calling for a coordinated European response to tackle caller ID spoofing, an in increasingly common tool, used for online fraud and social engineering scams. Caller ID spoofing occurs when criminals falsify the information displayed on phones, making numbers appear legitimate to deceive victims. This practice is driving substantial financial and societal harm, with an estimated EUR 850 million lost worldwide each year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Appeals Court lowers burden of proof for data breach lawsuits</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082749/us-appeals-court-lowers-burden-of-proof-for-data-breach-lawsuits.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An October decision of the 4th US Circuit Court of Appeals in Virginia has — yet again — altered the risk calculus of data breaches by easing litigants’ ability to successfully sue breached companies in limited situations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The case involved an insurance company data breach that resulted in the driver’s license information of almost 3 million customers being leaked. Until this appellate decision, most courts had ruled that having certain types of data stolen alone is not sufficient to prove damages. With such data, plaintiffs must provide proof of actual damage or evidence of actual fraud, the courts have mostly ruled.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Whereas theft of private data, such as medical records, has automatically been considered damaging, most data available from a driver’s license, for example, is public, with even a driver’s license number not helpful to a fraudster, unless joined with other information to enable identity theft. Courts have ruled that plaintiffs must prove thieves had indeed accessed multiple pieces of information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 4th Circuit softened that, ruling that because the attackers placed the information on the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564313/what-is-the-dark-web-how-to-access-it-and-what-youll-find.html"&gt;dark web&lt;/a&gt;, that suggested a greater risk of actual fraud. Thieves willing to pay for such data wouldn’t be willing to pay if they didn’t have access to other data to complete fraudulent activity. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The dark web, an anonymous online network for unregulated content and markets, is not a traditional method of communicating information like a newspaper or radio broadcast,” the &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/opinion/10704605/christopher-holmes-v-elephant-insurance-company/?q=ELEPHANT+INSURANCE+COMPANY"&gt;4th Circuit judges ruled&lt;/a&gt;. “But, not dissimilar to the internet more generally, it is a forum accessible to all — or at least to those with some degree of proficiency with computers. Information listed on it thus either reaches, or is sure to reach, the public or is close to doing so.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moreover, because one of the plaintiffs alleged the information was found to be for sale on the dark web, rather than published openly, which would limit its exposure, the judges explored whether the existence of a paywall should make a difference in terms of proving harm and concluded that it didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We do not see why this should make a difference. One classic example of publicity in public-disclosure tort cases is listing information in a newspaper,” the 4th Circuit judges ruled. “Yet many newspapers are only accessible with payment, too. We see no reason to treat the internet differently. Paywalled or not, information listed on the internet is ordinarily accessible to many.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The panel also clarified what constitutes data being sensitive: “Undoubtedly, a driver’s license number is unlike the details of an affair or a medical condition. People do not consider their driver’s licenses embarrassing and hand them to bartenders and waiters and police officers without hesitation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-cisos-should-respond"&gt;How CISOs should respond&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attorneys watching the case said there are various implications for what CISOs should do differently given the panel’s ruling. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, a directory of former government and military specialists, said this decision “is yet another reason why &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4046242/a-cisos-guide-to-monitoring-the-dark-web.html"&gt;CISOs should monitor the dark web&lt;/a&gt;. It may be an early warning that they may be getting a lawsuit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That dark web information may also provide critical guidance for lawyers negotiating with plaintiffs. If the data is definitely not on the dark web, there is a better chance for dismissal and therefore a better chance that a lowball settlement offer may be accepted. But if the data appears on the dark web, that quickly changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For plaintiffs whose data was breached but not publicly disclosed, the court found no standing because the risk of future misuse was deemed too speculative. Emotional distress and time spent monitoring accounts were not concrete injuries without actual misuse or public exposure,” Levine said. “This reinforces a high bar for plaintiffs in data breach cases who haven’t yet suffered tangible consequences.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This decision also forces CISOs to reevaluate how financially exposed the enterprise will be should a breach happen, said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/raschcyber/"&gt;Mark Rasch&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who specializes in technology legal issues. Prior to this 4th Circuit decision, “a lot of enterprises thought that a data breach might be no big deal because the victims can’t really demonstrate harm, so we don’t need to worry.” This decision changes that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The court created a new “publication versus theft” dynamic, Rasch said, where a dark web publication of the information may be enough for a case to proceed. To be clear, the panel’s decision involved whether plaintiffs would be allowed to proceed to discovery and other early stages of the court process. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/douglasabrush/"&gt;Douglas Brush&lt;/a&gt;, a special master with the US federal courts, said that a critical factor behind these legal shifts is a flood of lawsuits initiated instantly when an enterprise announces a breach, long before meaningful details are known.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs have thought “‘if we lose any of this data, there’s blood in the water,’” Brush said. “The line CISOs must monitor is the shift from private possession to public accessibility. CISOs should track and document what becomes public, not just what was taken: screenshots, hashes, first-seen timestamps, and linkage to internal systems. That record now drives standing, class scope, and exposure.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The case could unintentionally motivate attackers to threaten enterprises with dark web publication, giving them leverage to extort more money by suggesting that failure to pay will make the attackers publish and thereby strengthen plaintiffs’ cases against the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082749/us-appeals-court-lowers-burden-of-proof-for-data-breach-lawsuits.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-696)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-696</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-696</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-697)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-697</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-697</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-698)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-698</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-698</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–699)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-700)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-701)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Tomcat security advisory (AV25-702)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV25-703)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-704)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-705)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-705</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-705</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-706)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-706</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-016 Internet-accessible industrial control systems (ICS) abused by hacktivists</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-016-internet-accessible-industrial-control-systems-ics-abused-hacktivists</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins security advisory (AV25-707)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/jenkins-security-advisory-av25-707</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker security advisory (AV25–708)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/docker-security-advisory-av25-708</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.14</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV25-693) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-709)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-709</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-710)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-710</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-629) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-629</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does aligning security to the business really mean?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080670/what-does-aligning-security-to-the-business-really-mean.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As part of his company’s AI center of excellence, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/timsattler/?originalSubdomain=de"&gt;Tim Sattler&lt;/a&gt; works to identify where and how the technology can provide measurable benefits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’re discussing opportunities,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That Jungheinrich AG’s AI team is doing so is hardly remarkable. What’s notable is that Sattler, CISO for the German manufacturer of warehouse equipment and tech solutions, is part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s a role security chiefs don’t typically play.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sattler sees his membership in the AI center of excellence as evidence that he and his security team are in lockstep with the business and its strategic vision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I see my role as not only seeing all the risks but also all the opportunities that AI presents. So I get out of the risk corner and really see the big picture,” he explains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He took the same approach when ChatGPT arrived, at which time he and his team did a deep dive into large language models “to figure out how the technology worked, to understand the risks, and the new business opportunities it would create so we could say, ‘Here are the rules; here’s how you can try it out and play around with it.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And he’s doing much the same with quantum computing, explaining that board members have sought out his and his security staffers’ opinions on the technology and its potential, not just its &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552701/the-cisos-guide-to-establishing-quantum-resilience.html"&gt;cybersecurity implications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They knew we were the right people to talk to first about quantum because we have proven that we see ourselves in this advisory role,” Sattler says. “Very often the business [unit leader] only sees opportunities, and external advisers may be very sales-driven, so both may not be very objective. But we [in security] have a neutral position, seeing the risks and rewards. This is now the role of the CISO and the security organization.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sattler says serving in such a capacity demonstrates that security and the business are aligned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Alignment to me means that information security supports the strategy of the organization,” says Sattler, who also serves as a board director with the governance association ISACA. “That means we know what the goals of the organization are, what the company wants to achieve, we understand the business environment, what the competition is doing, what the trends are in the industry. Those are all things security needs to know to support innovation and growth and to support the organization in achieving its goals. And that means security can’t just focus on risk. We also need to see the opportunities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="alignment-a-security-department-imperative"&gt;Alignment: A security department imperative&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The idea of alignment is big in security today. A single internet search proves as much, producing countless results that contain some variation of “security-business alignment.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yet research shows that many CISOs aren’t in sync with the rest of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.ey.com/en_gl/insights/consulting/how-can-cybersecurity-go-beyond-value-protection-to-value-creation"&gt;2025 EY Global Cybersecurity Leadership Insights Study&lt;/a&gt;, for example, shows that only 13% of CISOs “were consulted early when urgent strategic decisions were being made” and “58% of CISOs and cybersecurity executives say it is difficult to articulate their value beyond risk mitigation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the &lt;a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/newsroom/press-releases/2025/splunk-report-cisos-gain-influence-in-the-c-suite-and-boardrooms-worldwide.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Splunk 2025 CISO Report&lt;/a&gt; found gaps between how CISOs and boards perceive priorities. For example, the report found that 52% of surveyed board members think CISOs spend most of their time on business enablement but only 34% of CISOs agreed that that was the case. And 55% of board members said business acumen was a highly valuable skill for CISOs, but only 40% of CISOs ranked it as a skill they should develop.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Given such disconnects, it’s worth asking: What does aligning security to the business really mean? Why is it important? And what are strategies that CISOs can use to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If CISOs want to successfully align security with their business, they need to make alignment more than a mantra, says &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/katell-thielemann"&gt;Katell Thielemann&lt;/a&gt;, distinguished vice president analyst at research firm Gartner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s not enough to say it; you actually have to do it,” she explains. “There is a contingent of cybersecurity that sees itself as an island, implementing defense in depth in every corner of the organization, adopting all these frameworks and standards, but there is diminishing returns in doing that. So instead of saying, ‘This is our cybersecurity discipline and we’re doing all these things because the benchmarks tell us to,’ CISOs have to align their efforts to their organization’s business model.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="indicators-of-alignment"&gt;Indicators of alignment&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One barometer of security-business alignment in action, Thielemann says, is when security teams engage with the business and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3979024/the-8-security-metrics-that-matter-most.html"&gt;use business metrics to determine security’s effectiveness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As an example, she points to the partnership between security and engineering at a manufacturing plant that had devices using software no longer supported by the vendor. The two teams worked together to implement needed security measures, such as segmentation, that wouldn’t interfere with operations but added the necessary security. Knowing to schedule security work during plant downtime further demonstrated the alignment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That’s showing security knows the business and is not just doing cybersecurity as a discipline,” Thielemann says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To align, she says, security leaders must “know the objectives the business has and use those to shape strategy, whether it’s cost containment, going into new markets, adopting cloud. The playbook starts from understanding the organizational priorities and then layering in what threat actors are doing in that industry and what could go wrong, what is the risk we can live with, and understanding and articulating the business impact of security incidents.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ey.com/en_us/people/ayan-roy"&gt;Ayan Roy&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Americas cybersecurity competency leader at professional services firm EY, cites another example of alignment involving one company acquiring another as part of a strategy to enter new markets. The company’s CISO, knowing that building trust with customers was critical to growth post-merger, devised a strategy to strengthen the acquired company’s security to the levels necessary to ensure successful integration, corporate expansion, and growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="file:///C:/Users/Owner/Documents/Rob%20T.%20Lee"&gt;Robert T. Lee&lt;/a&gt;, chief AI officer and chief of research at security training and certification firm SANS, says alignment can also be seen in other ways, such as when and how security works with the business. For example, CISOs who recognize the need to boost security while reducing friction often have their security departments work with business units at the earliest stages of initiatives. Security teams integrated into R&amp;amp;D units so “they’re able to deploy things with much more or a trust model” is another sign of alignment, Lee says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Alignment in all of information security really focuses on the idea of supporting operations. It’s about risk management with an emphasis on enabling operations,” says &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__www.linkedin.com_in_jamesjaurez_&amp;amp;d=DwMFAg&amp;amp;c=qwHaVVscXk_NBWd7DQFk0g&amp;amp;r=L0JdBfO3GPsCEs_j1venmQ&amp;amp;m=fEB7A6mijDdSaPpFqRNQf_JjhIIGQDDY5E6XtppQ4jOUnQzj2121QZDVNBCTkVgR&amp;amp;s=kZJ-nZzFIrfkb2-bTnF95Ik7WoWxPaBsuJph6kjwqzw&amp;amp;e="&gt;Dr. James Jaurez&lt;/a&gt;, National University’s department chair of cybersecurity and technology&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And there is value in security-business alignment. According to the 2025 EY Global Cybersecurity Leadership Insights Study, “cybersecurity contributes 11% to 20%, or a median of US$36M, in value to each enterprise-wide strategic initiative it is involved in.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="lack-of-alignment-persists-for-many"&gt;Lack of alignment persists for many&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, as the EY study found, alignment exists in a fraction of organizations. And as Jaurez says, just as there are indicators of security-business alignment, there are signs when it’s absent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One indicator, he says, is being “over secure,” where the costs of the security measures and the friction they introduce into the organization’s work processes and operations exceed the value they provide. Another is when security leaders don’t know or can’t articulate the organization’s vision or strategic goals, he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Others point to security feeling left out or brought into initiatives after they’re under way as indicators that alignment is missing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When security is not aligned, security is reacting to changes rather than shaping changes,” says &lt;a href="(35)%20Matt%20G.%20%7C%20LinkedIn"&gt;Matt Gorham&lt;/a&gt;, leader of PwC’s Cyber and Risk Innovation Institute. “But when security isn’t chasing the business it’s because it’s at the table from the beginning and is saying, ‘Here’s how I can help the business grow and grow securely.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080670/what-does-aligning-security-to-the-business-really-mean.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-711)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-711</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress security advisory (AV25-712)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/progress-security-advisory-av25-712</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-713)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-713</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-714)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-714</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-714</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-715)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-715</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-715</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-716)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-716</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-716</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-717)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-717</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-717</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–718)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-718</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-718</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-719)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-720)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-720</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-720</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubiquiti security advisory (AV25-721)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubiquiti-security-advisory-av25-721</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubiquiti-security-advisory-av25-721</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
