<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 22:20:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-763)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–764)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-765)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe tightens the net on sanctions evasion</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</link>
      <description>Europol is reinforcing its support to EU Member States in enforcing EU sanctions, as criminal networks develop ever more sophisticated methods to bypass restrictive measures linked to Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe-tightens-net-sanctions-evasion</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strike against synthetics: authorities seize tonnes of chemicals in Central and Eastern Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/strike-against-synthetics-authorities-seize-tonnes-of-chemicals-in-central-and-eastern-europe</link>
      <description>Emerging trends and strategies to combat synthetic drug trafficking were key topics at Europol’s annual Drugs Conference last week. In this context, the agency has supported two major operations in recent weeks targeting the entire supply chain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/strike-against-synthetics-authorities-seize-tonnes-of-chemicals-in-central-and-eastern-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-767)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-768)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.32</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-769)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 arrested for smuggling migrants from Türkiye to France and Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</link>
      <description>On 13 November 2025, the German Federal Police, in close cooperation with French border police and with the support of Europol and Eurojust, have dismantled a criminal network believed to have smuggled nearly 600 people into Europe between 2021 and 2023.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Python Bootstrap Scripts Create Domain-Takeover Risk in Multiple PyPI Packages</title>
      <link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/legacy-python-bootstrap-scripts-create.html</link>
      <description>Cybersecurity researchers have discovered vulnerable code in legacy Python packages that could potentially pave the way for a supply chain compromise on the Python Package Index (PyPI) via a domain takeover attack.
Software supply chain security company ReversingLabs said it found the "vulnerability" in bootstrap files provided by a build and deployment automation tool named "zc.buildout."
"The</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://thehackernews.com/2025/11/legacy-python-bootstrap-scripts-create.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 21:57:00 +0530</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-770)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-771)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-772)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-773)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-766) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI browsers can be tricked with malicious prompts hidden in URL fragments</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097087/ai-browsers-can-be-tricked-with-malicious-prompts-hidden-in-url-fragments.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have demonstrated another indirect prompt injection attack against AI-powered browsers and browser assistants that could lead to phishing, sensitive data exfiltration, credential theft, or malware downloads. The attack, dubbed HashJack, relies on rogue prompts added to URLs after the hash (#) symbol, also known as a named anchor or URL fragment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“HashJack is the first known indirect prompt injection that can weaponize any legitimate website to manipulate AI browser assistants,” researchers from Cato Networks said in the &lt;a href="https://www.catonetworks.com/blog/cato-ctrl-hashjack-first-known-indirect-prompt-injection/"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. “As a result, AI browsers —  including Comet (Perplexity), Copilot for Edge (Microsoft), and Gemini for Chrome (Google) — can be used to enable a wide range of malicious attacks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-client-side-attack"&gt;A client-side attack&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The # character inside a URL has multiple uses: The portion after it tells the browser to jump to a specific section of the loaded page; it can tell JavaScript code on the page what to display in an in-page dynamic navigation scenario; or it can be used to save state information about the user interface, such as user-selected options.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One important aspect is that URL fragment data is never sent to the web server or over the network. It’s only meant for the browser or the code already loaded on the client side. And it turns out that since AI browser assistants are designed to analyze the currently open website for context, they also read the URL fragments passed after #, and these can hide malicious prompts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The client-side nature of this attack means traditional network defenses, such as IPS/IDS and network firewalls, can’t detect it. Server logs don’t capture the portion of URLs after # because it’s never sent to the server, and browser defenses like Content Security Policy (CSP) don’t trigger because nothing on the actual web page is changed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tricking-users-into-clicking-poisoned-links"&gt;Tricking users into clicking poisoned links&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HashJack is essentially a social engineering attack because it relies on tricking users to click on specially crafted URLs inside emails, chats, websites, or documents. However, this attack can be highly credible because it points to legitimate websites.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine a spoofed email that claims to be from a bank advising customers about suspicious activity in their accounts. Hovering over the link included in the email shows that it points to the bank’s real website, HTTPS and everything, but it’s a long link and somewhere in it there’s the # character followed by a prompt for the AI assistant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many users are likely to trust such a message since it points to the real bank’s website and because long links with a lot of parameters and paths in them are not unusual. But the prompt that follows the # symbol will cause the AI browser assistant to provide attacker-altered instructions to the user, such as calling an attacker-controlled phone number or WhatsApp link for further customer support about the supposed situation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In another scenario, a prompt included in the link can tell an AI browser that acts like an agent —  for example, Perplexity’s Comet —  to take information about the user’s account, transaction history, phone number, and so on from the opened bank site and append it as parameters in a request to the attacker’s server.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other attacks could involve the prompt causing the AI assistant to display fake information that would mislead the user: fake investment advice promoting a certain stock, fabricated news, dangerous medical advice like wrong doses for medicine, malicious instructions that could open a backdoor on the computer, instructions to re-authenticate that include a link to a phishing site, a link to download malware, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;URL fragments cannot modify page content. They are only used for in-page navigation using the code that’s already there, so they are normally harmless. However, it now turns out that they can be used to modify the output of in-browser AI assistants or agentic browsers, which gives them an entirely new risk profile.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This discovery is especially dangerous because it weaponizes legitimate websites through their URLs,” the researchers said. “Users see a trusted site, trust their AI browser, and in turn trust the AI assistant’s output-making the likelihood of success far higher than with traditional phishing.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Different behavior across AI assistantsThe impact was different between the tested AI assistants and across the various scenarios. For example, while prompt injections managed to influence the text output on all the products tested, injecting malicious links proved harder on Gemini Assistant for Chrome, where some links were rewritten as search URLs, and on Edge with Microsoft Copilot, which prompted for additional confirmation when clicking on links in messages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perplexity’s Comet, which is an agentic browser that does more than a built-in AI assistant, was the most susceptible one because it also could fetch attacker URLs in the background, with context information attached as parameters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and Perplexity deployed fixes, but Google did not consider the HashJack technique a vulnerability because it views this as part of intended behavior. It’s worth noting that Cato also tested Claude for Chrome and OpenAI’s Operator browser, but the HashJack technique didn’t work on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097087/ai-browsers-can-be-tricked-with-malicious-prompts-hidden-in-url-fragments.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall ransomware attacks offer an M&amp;A lesson for CSOs</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097078/sonicwall-ransomware-attacks-offer-an-ma-lesson-for-csos.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The recent ransomware attacks on organizations with SonicWall SSL VPNs may teach more lessons than just the need for patch management and identity and access control. Some of the victim firms had vulnerable SonicWall devices on their IT networks as legacies of past mergers or acquisitions, suggesting infosec leaders need to be more involved in preparing for M&amp;amp;A deals or risk their organizations being stung by hackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the conclusion &lt;a href="https://reliaquest.com/blog/threat-spotlight-akira-ransomwares-sonicwall-campaign-creates-enterprise-m&amp;amp;a-risk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;from a report this week by researchers at ReliaQuest.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They looked at a series of attacks between June and October using the Akira ransomware strain to target SonicWall SSL VPNs, and found a link: In almost every incident, hackers gained a foothold on an enterprise network by compromising a SonicWall device inherited from a smaller acquired business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When asked, ReliaQuest wouldn’t say how many incidents it had investigated. But the report does say that in each case, IT wasn’t aware the devices were currently in their environment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Standard M&amp;amp;A due diligence is not enough,” says the report. “Security teams must proactively secure inherited technologies, prioritizing early visibility into new environments, like remote access tools, to address risky configurations and outdated credentials before attackers exploit them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The warning isn’t new. Experts have been saying for years that examining a potential acquisition’s finances isn’t enough. Scrutinizing its IT assets also has to be involved, so boards understand both the financial and the cyber risks of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Exhibit A: The discovery in 2018 by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567795/marriott-data-breach-faq-how-did-it-happen-and-what-was-the-impact.html" target="_blank"&gt;Marriott that data on hundreds of millions of guests from the reservation system of its Starwood chain of hotels&lt;/a&gt; had been stolen. Marriott bought Starwood in 2016. Its network had been infiltrated two years earlier, and the breach was undetected for four years, even after the Marriott acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security leaders do need to be involved in the M&amp;amp;A process,” said &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/fred-chagnon" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fred Chagnon&lt;/a&gt;, a principal research director at Info-Tech Research, which did a case study on the Marriott-Starwood incident.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One reason why CSOs/CIOs and their equivalents aren’t brought in, he said, is that cyber risk is invisible compared to the hard numbers that can be found in financial records. As a result, “we’ve had difficulty in this industry in communicating cyber risks as financial liabilities” to CEOs and boards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT leaders have to push the message that security risk is enterprise risk, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, he added, the board has to be reminded that it is responsible for assessing the cyber as well as the financial risks of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related content: &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/415233/why-and-when-cios-deserve-a-seat-at-the-ma-negotiating-table.html" target="_blank"&gt;Why, and when, CIOs deserve a seat at the M&amp;amp;A negotiating table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Should infosec leaders be asked to be part of an M&amp;amp;A team, the actual assessment of the potential acquisition should be contracted to a third party expert, Chagnon added. That’s because the security team won’t have time to do it themselves, and the other side will likely be more willing to divulge sensitive IT information to a third party than to a competitor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The majority of M&amp;amp;A activities still follow a security checklist approach, noted&lt;a href="https://cypfer.com/team-member/ed-dubrovsky/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt; Ed Dubrovski&lt;/a&gt;, chief operating officer of incident response firm Cypfer, “which essentially is really a glorified third party vendor assessment. Such activities meet the check-in-the-box requirements but do nothing really to address the real core of the issue: lack of current and relevant information about possible risks.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those doing cybersecurity assessments of a potential acquisition should start with an inventory or list of IT assets before asking if the organization has an information security policy and underlying policies, he added. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After an acquisition, CSOs should treat the new network as a third party connection request and keep it segmented until the core risks have been quantified before attempting to integrate environments, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The reality is that the combined risk posture is [only] as good as the riskiest party,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity posture of an acquisition should be a high priority for inspection during the due diligence period, agreed &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fsmontenegro/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fernando Montenegro&lt;/a&gt;, vice president and cybersecurity practice lead at advisory firm Futurum, regardless of the size of the business being acquired.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The security team must be properly connected to the rest of the organization, including the corporate development (corpdev) group that typically spearheads mergers and acquisitions, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The challenge here is that security teams should work with corpdev to have the right framework to analyze these deals, including interviews with key executives at the target company, access to any audit/compliance documentation, and a thorough look at the digital footprint and internal state of the acquired company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ideally, he added, the program includes both ‘outside-in’ and ‘inside-out’ perspectives on the potential acquisition, a thorough review of their security program, history of any security incidents, key third-party relationships they may have, and more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On top of that, there will be numerous considerations about what the IT integration will look like, including network connectivity and business application connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In its report, ReliaQuest notes that SonicWall devices are often used by small and mid-sized firms, which are often M&amp;amp;A targets of larger companies. However, it said, it can’t be sure firms were targeted by Akira operators because they’d swallowed organizations that had SonicWall devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It did say that in the incidents examined, once inside the victims’ networks, the attackers immediately looked for privileged accounts, such as those originating from old managed service provider (MSP) or administrator logins, that had been transferred over during the M&amp;amp;A process. “Crucially, these credentials were often unknown to the acquiring company, and left unmonitored and unrotated post-acquisition,” the report says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We asked ReliaQuest how often vulnerabilities in technology acquired from an M&amp;amp;A cause later breaches of security controls. In response, a spokesperson said, “the fact that we’ve seen consecutive breaches of Akira targeting smaller organizations where they are leveraging vulnerabilities means that larger organizations should address the risks during onboarding and understand the scope before purchasing.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097078/sonicwall-ransomware-attacks-offer-an-ma-lesson-for-csos.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-774)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-775)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 suspects arrested in two blows against human trafficking networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</link>
      <description>France and Spain: disrupting a Chinese human trafficking networkConducted jointly by France and Spain, this operation targeted a Chinese organised crime group involved in trafficking human beings for sexual exploitation. The network, active for several years, coordinated sexual exploitation rings across France and multiple EU Member States. Members of the network rented apartments online for short terms, a modus operandi...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/29-suspects-arrested-in-two-blows-against-human-trafficking-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 arrests in Bulgaria in a large art trafficking investigation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</link>
      <description>On 19 November 2025, a coordinated effort led by Bulgarian authorities and supported by Europol, resulted in the dismantling of a criminal network involved in large-scale trafficking of cultural goods across Europe and beyond. This operation was conducted under the framework of a Europol operational taskforce. The action day involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Albania, France, Germany, Greece,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and partner countries combat online radicalisation on gaming platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</link>
      <description>Conducted on 13 November 2025, this operational action by the European Union Internet Referral Unit (EU IRU) involved the referral of thousands of URLs leading to dangerous and illicit online material. This includes around 5 408 links to jihadist content, 1 070 links to violent right-wing extremist and terrorist content, and 105 links to racist and xenophobic content.This joint action...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUR 47 million in crypto traced to disrupt digital piracy services</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November, Europol, in collaboration with the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional), organised an "Intellectual Property Crime Cyber-Patrol Week”. A total of 30 investigators participated in this operation hosted at the EUIPO headquarters in Alicante, Spain, where they used advanced Open-Source Intelligence Techniques (OSINT) and cutting-edge online investigative tools...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the winners of the 2025 Europol photo competition</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</link>
      <description>Three awards were given out, each decided by a different group of voters:the international law enforcement community represented at Europol’s headquarters,members of the public,and the Heads of Communication of the European law enforcement authorities.The winners of Capture25The Europol Community Vote by the Liaison Bureaux went to Johan Jacob Kleist from Denmark with his photo of a ‘police officer patrolling beneath...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16.6 million packages of fake and harmful toys taken off EU markets</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</link>
      <description>Fake toys are poisoning, deafening and injuring children across Europe, while causing major losses to the EU economy. 26 countries, coordinated by Europol, co-led by France, Spain and Romania, and supported by the EUIPO and OLAF, have once again led initiatives to take down the producers and importers of counterfeit toys. With the global toy market valued at up to EUR 300 billion annually, it also remains the second-most counterfeited industry globally.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/166-million-packages-of-fake-and-harmful-toys-taken-eu-markets</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-776)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-777)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grafana security advisory (AV25-778)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help4U: A new digital platform to support young people facing online sexual abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</link>
      <description>A new digital platform, Help4U, developed by Europol and CENTRIC, has been launched to support children and teenagers facing sexual abuse or online harm. Designed to be simple, private, and accessible, Help4U supports young people with finding trusted advice, understanding their rights, and connecting with people who can help. The platform offers clear, practical guidance for anyone under 18 who needs help, as well as information for parents, teachers, and professionals supporting them.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSPM buyer’s guide: How to choose the best cloud security posture management tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-security-posture-management-cspm-explained"&gt;Cloud security posture management (CSPM) explained&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud security posture management (CSPM) combines threat intelligence, detection, and remediation that works across complex collections of cloud-based applications. After companies move to the cloud, many are under the impression that their cloud hosting providers are solely responsible for security, a misconception that can lead to data breaches and other security issues. While the responsibility for securing cloud infrastructure falls to cloud services providers, it’s up to customers to configure the cloud and secure their applications and sensitive corporate data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But securing cloud-based apps and data isn’t simple as there are many threat vectors that operate across neat defensive boundaries. This is why many enterprises have found a need to expand their posture management to more comprehensive products such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573629/cnapp-buyers-guide-top-tools-compared.html"&gt;cloud-native application protection platforms&lt;/a&gt; (CNAPP) or secure service edge (SSE) product lines. CNAPP integrates CSPM with other tools that include &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/557365/what-is-a-cloud-access-security-broker-and-why-do-i-need-one.html"&gt;cloud access security brokers (CASBs)&lt;/a&gt; and tools that directly protect cloud workloads, APIs and infrastructure and include those from vendors such as Wiz, Palo Alto Networks’ Cortex line, Tenable, Crowdstrike and others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SSE products are more network-focused and integrate CSPM with a different set of tools including software-defined wide area networking, secure web gateways and zero trust network access and include vendors such as Zscaler, Cisco, Palo Alto Networks’ Prisma line, Fortinet and Netskope.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ Download our editors’ PDF &lt;a href="https://us.resources.csoonline.com/resources/download-our-cloud-security-posture-management-platform-cspm-enterprise-buyers-guide/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;cloud security posture management (CSPM) enterprise buyer’s guide&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; today! ]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="in-this-buyers-guide"&gt;In this buyer’s guide&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud security posture management (CSPM) explained&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to look for in cloud security posture management (CSPM) tools&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Leading vendors for cloud security posture management (CSPM)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What to ask your cloud security posture management (CSPM) provider&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Essential reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s where &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574539/how-automation-in-cspm-can-improve-cloud-security-2.html"&gt;CSPM tools&lt;/a&gt; can help. These tools continuously and automatically check for misconfigurations that can result in data leaks and data breaches. CSPM tools manage cloud security risks on an ongoing basis and ensure compliance in the cloud so enterprises can continuously make any necessary changes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CSPM solutions use best practices and compliance (PCI, SOC2, etc.) templates to identify drifts and insecure configurations in cloud infrastructure (AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud) in the compute, storage, and network areas,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrascser/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Andras Cser&lt;/a&gt;, a principal analyst at Forrester Research. “CSPM tools can alert and optionally remediate the insecure configurations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSPM tools look at workloads to see what’s happening and they provide context, so organizations know which of the vulnerabilities or issues is most important, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/charliewinckless/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Charlie Winckless&lt;/a&gt;, a senior director analyst at Gartner. “These tools enable companies to prioritize which risks are real, which risks are important, and which risks they may be able to delay fixing a little bit,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cloud technologies have been classified as infrastructure as a service (IaaS), platform as a service (PaaS) and software as a service (SaaS). The differences among these three designations are becoming blurred to the point where the labels don’t have much meaning anymore. As enterprises purchase more diverse cloud offerings, the notion of having a single tool such as CSPM that covers all these bases becomes appealing. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-to-look-for-in-cloud-security-posture-management-cspm-tools"&gt;What to look for in cloud security posture management (CSPM) tools&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations evaluating various CSPM tools should ensure that they cover all the cloud platforms they’re using, says Winckless. “You want to be able to normalize the configuration risks across the major cloud platforms,” he says. “Most organizations that are purchasing these tools will probably be multicloud. They’ll be using at least two clouds, maybe more, since the cloud providers themselves do offer some of this functionality built into their platforms.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Philip Bues, cloud security research manager at IDC, says the new reality for most organizations is a hybrid multicloud environment, “so you want something that’s going to be able to give you really deep visibility throughout all the environments and workloads that you have. And that’s what the CSPM solution should be able to provide you.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other features organizations should look for in CSPM tools include the following:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive threat detection:&lt;/strong&gt; Because threats in multicloud environments are complex, these tools must gather threat intelligence from multiple sources to give companies clear views of their risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated data security:&lt;/strong&gt; Keeping data safe in the cloud requires a multipronged defense that gives companies deep visibility into the state of their data. This includes enabling organizations to monitor how each storage bucket is configured across all their storage services to ensure their data isn’t inadvertently exposed to unauthorized applications or users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated alert remediation:&lt;/strong&gt; Organizations must ensure that the CSPM tools they select can automate routine security monitoring, audits, and remediations across their cloud environments. This allows security teams to prioritize and remediate the risks that can potentially cause the most damage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="benefits-of-cspm-tools"&gt;Benefits of CSPM tools&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSPM tools offer multiple benefits that help companies boost security, minimize their risk exposure in cloud environments, and reduce costs. These benefits include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proactively identifying and addressing risks before cybercriminals can exploit them using real-time visibility and automatic detection of vulnerabilities, misconfigurations, and security gaps.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Continuously monitor configurations as they relate to industry benchmarks and standards to ensure compliance with best practices and regulations.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Automating policy enforcement and remediation, which cuts the time and expense of manually resolving security issues across cloud environments.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Integrating devops workflows with CSPM processes to embed security throughout the software development life cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="pitfalls-of-cspm-tools"&gt;Pitfalls of CSPM tools&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are some pitfalls that companies need to be aware of when it comes to CSPM tools, including:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not understanding the requirements of CSPM tools:&lt;/strong&gt; This is one of the biggest mistakes that organizations can make when they’re shifting workloads to the cloud because things that weren’t connected before are now interconnected, says IDC’s Bues. The best way to implement CSPM tools is to ensure teams receive the proper training and proper awareness for how this solution is supposed to work within the environment. “You don’t want to have the security team with little or no cloud experience or developers with limited security experience trying to manage this new CSPM solution,” he says. “You should have the developers and the security team working together because everyone has different needs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not opting for a multicloud CSPM tool: &lt;/strong&gt;Another mistake companies make is selecting tools that offer a one-size-fits-all approach offered by public cloud vendors that don’t offer a unified view across all their cloud environments. Organizations should opt for CSPM tools that provide multicloud monitoring and protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinking they’re too small or not mature enough: &lt;/strong&gt;A company that assumes it’s too small or not mature enough to consider security will always put the business at risk as it typically only thinks about security after an issue or breach occurs. However, companies of all sizes should ensure they protect their assets across teams by implementing CSPM tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leading-vendors-for-cloud-security-posture-management-cspm"&gt;Leading vendors for cloud security posture management (CSPM)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vendors have been incorporating CSPM functions into their overall CNAPP or SSE platforms, including CrowdStrike, Palo Alto Networks, Wiz, Zscaler and Tenable. This means that the modern standalone CSPM tool has all but disappeared. One extreme example is Check Point Systems, who has gotten out of CSPM entirely and has taken its CNAPP efforts to integrate with Wiz’ product line. But it is important to start with this function as you investigate how to protect your cloud estate, and to help with these efforts, we have highlighted a few of the CSPM tools based on discussions with analysts and our own independent research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/platform/singularity-cloud-cspm/"&gt;SentinelOne Singularity CSPM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is part of a collection of integrated modules that together comprise a comprehensive CNAPP solution. You can pinpoint cloud misconfigurations and monitor changes continuously to public clouds from AWS, Azure and Google Cloud. It also includes an offensive detection engine called Verified Exploit Paths and AI-based threat-detection research to help augment its protective features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sweet.security/product/runtime-cspm"&gt;Sweet.Security Runtime CNAPP’s&lt;/a&gt; CSPM&lt;/strong&gt; module is just part of a comprehensive CNAPP solution that offers application, data and API security modules. It monitors changes in near real-time and helps to remediate cloud workload misconfigurations and protects development pipelines. It combines its runtime instrumentation with other metadata to provide overall risk assessment scoring. It also offers a unified management of security issues, such as exposed APIs that are linked to misconfigured identities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tenable.com/cloud-security/solutions/cspm"&gt;Tenable CSPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is part of its overall cloud security platform, which integrates a wide collection of tools including the traditional CNAPP suite along with more development-oriented protection for AI, code pipelines, data and threat detection tools. It provides continuous security scans across AWS, Azure and Google Cloud along with producing audit reports and integration with its cloud infrastructure entitlement management tools as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="questions-to-ask-your-cloud-security-posture-management-cspm-provider"&gt;Questions to ask your cloud security posture management (CSPM) provider&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When investigating the best CSPM fit for your enterprise security needs, ask potential vendors these questions:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can you calculate your baseline so you can track changes to your cloud-based assets?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Does the CSPM platform work for all three of the major public clouds (Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, and Microsoft Azure) as well as various Kubernetes and other container-based implementations? What about support for common SaaS apps such as Box, Salesforce, ServiceNow, and Workday? Each product’s coverage varies. Some products place agents in your cloud, some use read-only access to scan your environment and resources, and some have writing access to enable changes to remediate issues in your accounts.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How real-time is it for notifications about these changes, policy violations, and other unusual events? Does it track misconfigured weak security groups, remote access, app control mistakes, and network changes? All cloud providers offer built-in activity monitoring, but if you use multiple clouds, you want your CSPM platform to parse this rich supply of data and make actionable sense of it.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How real-time is it to automate remediation? The best CSPM platforms will continuously scan for vulnerable systems and some offer ways that they can detect when a new virtual machine has created an insecure situation for example.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What other security and notification tools does it integrate with, such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/524286/what-is-siem-security-information-and-event-management-explained.html"&gt;security information event management (SIEM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570673/5-tips-for-getting-started-with-soar.html"&gt;security orchestration, automation, and response (SOAR)&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;How many compliance/auditing reporting frameworks are supported on each cloud provider? Each tool supports a different framework collection, which isn’t necessarily the same across all the clouds either to make things harder for you, too.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;What is the cost? Some vendors offer a limited free trial or tier; others charge per host or in more complex ways that might mean a surprise when the bill comes due. Few are like Sysdig that offer a public and transparent pricing webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="essential-reading"&gt;Essential reading&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573629/cnapp-buyers-guide-top-tools-compared.html"&gt;CNAPP buyers guide: Top tools compared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2075321/top-12-data-security-posture-management-tools.html"&gt;Top 12 data security posture management (DSPM) tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574539/how-automation-in-cspm-can-improve-cloud-security-2.html"&gt;How automation in CSPM can improve cloud security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1303467/is-your-cloud-security-strategy-ready-for-llms.html"&gt;Is your cloud security strategy ready for LLMs?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/202183/what-is-data-governance-a-best-practices-framework-for-managing-data-assets.html"&gt;What is data governance? Best practices for managing data assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story was first published in October 2023 and updated in November 2025.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/657138/how-to-choose-the-best-cloud-security-posture-management-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688) – Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Teams’ guest chat feature exposes cross-tenant blind spot</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097381/microsoft-teams-guest-chat-feature-exposes-cross-tenant-blind-spot.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A newly highlighted flaw in Microsoft’s cross-tenant collaboration model shows that once a user accepts a guest invitation in Teams, their Defender for Office 365 protections are dropped entirely, leaving them exposed inside an external tenant even while logged in with their home account.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Ontinue threat researcher Rhys Downing, one of Microsoft’s recently enabled features, “MC1182004,” that allows Teams users to initiate chats with any email address, opens an attack vector for threat actors who know cross-tenant security limitations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many organizations assume their controls ‘follow’ the user wherever they go,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/julianbrownlowdavies/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Julian Brownlow Davies&lt;/a&gt;, senior vice president, offensive security strategy &amp;amp; operations at Bugcrowd. “In reality, attackers can spin up a poorly secured tenant, invite your users in with what looks like a perfectly legitimate Microsoft Teams email, and deliver links and files that never touch your own Defender stack at all.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This means the full suite of Defender protections, including URL scanning, safe links, file sandboxing, and zero-hour auto purge, can simply be disabled, turning a harmless-looking collaboration invite into an attack path.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft did not immediately respond to CSO’s request for comments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;New default triggers architectural flaw&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Downing explained in a &lt;a href="https://www.ontinue.com/resource/blog-microsoft-chat-with-anyone-understanding-phishing-risk/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that the issue isn’t a software bug in Teams, but an architectural reality of cross-tenant collaboration. When a user joins another tenant as a guest, the hosting (resource) tenant’s security settings apply–not the user’s original (home) tenant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, all protections provided by Defender for Office 365 are bypassed if the resource tenant has them disabled or never had them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making an attack easier is the default-enabled feature in Teams, &lt;a href="https://mc.merill.net/message/MC1182004" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MC1182004&lt;/a&gt;, that allows users to start a chat with any email address, even if the recipient isn’t yet part of Teams. That means attackers can simply spin up a Microsoft 365 tenant, invite victims via email, and deliver phishing links or malware-all without triggering the victim’s own security stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Davies echoed Downing’s argument that this is an architectural consequence of how &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/648486/beware-of-overly-permissive-azure-ad-cross-tenant-synchronization-policies.html"&gt;cross-tenant collaboration&lt;/a&gt; works. “At Bugcrowd, we see the same pattern across crowdsourced testing programs, particularly in our Red Team engagements: much of the risk now lives in the connectivity between tenants, identity systems, and collaboration tools, rather than in the individual apps themselves,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mitigations include vetting collaborations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jason Soroko, senior fellow at Sectigo, warns that this is not a mere “bypass bug,” but a blind spot in many organizations’ mental model of cross-tenant risk. “Security teams should respond by treating external guest access as a trust boundary that needs explicit governance rather than a convenience feature that can stay on by default,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Restricting B2B guest invitation to a vetted allow-list of trusted partner domains, and implementing cross-tenant access policies in Microsoft Entra ID to block suspicious guest-tenant access was recommended by Downing to stay ahead of this inherent threat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another key mitigation includes disabling the default “chat with Anyone” feature in Teams, which allows unsolicited external invitations to reach users. This is a practical step for many organizations that can simply do so through the Teams admin center by tightening external policies. Together with the Entra ID &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4060101/entra-id-vulnerability-exposes-gaps-in-cloud-identity-trust-models-experts-warn.html"&gt;warning&lt;/a&gt; from September, the disclosure underscores that a real danger sits in the gaps across Microsoft tenants, where convenience defaults and misplaced trust continue to outpace security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097381/microsoft-teams-guest-chat-feature-exposes-cross-tenant-blind-spot.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow is in talks to buy identity security firm Veza for over $1 billion: report</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097423/servicenow-is-in-talks-to-buy-identity-security-firm-veza-for-over-1-billion-report-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow is reportedly in advanced talks to acquire Veza, an identity security startup, for more than $1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For ServiceNow customers deploying AI agents across their organizations, the acquisition would address a critical gap: controlling what those agents can access and do. Veza’s technology maps permissions across enterprise systems, showing exactly which users, applications, and AI agents have access to what data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deal could be announced next week, The Information &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/servicenow-advanced-talks-buy-security-startup-least-1-billion" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The deal would follow ServiceNow’s &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3842626/servicenow-to-acquire-moveworks-to-strengthen-agentic-ai-and-enterprise-search.html"&gt;$2.85 billion acquisition of Moveworks&lt;/a&gt;, announced in March. That purchase brought AI assistants and enterprise search capabilities to ServiceNow’s platform. Adding Veza would provide the identity security layer needed to govern those AI systems as they access data across cloud services, SaaS applications, and internal systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow and Veza did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="managing-machine-identities"&gt;Managing machine identities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow said in March that it deployed thousands of AI agents for customers across IT, HR, customer service, and security operations. As these agents take on more autonomous tasks, enterprises face mounting pressure to understand what they can access and whether those permissions align with security policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“ServiceNow is trying to build an enterprise platform where AI agents don’t just chat, but actually take meaningful actions inside the business,” said Akshat Tyagi, associate practice leader at HFS Research. “Moveworks gave them a strong automation layer, but trust and governance were the missing pieces. Handing over real-time authority to agents unless identity, permissions, and access rules are rock solid is a bluff no enterprise wants to play.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza addresses what security experts call the non-human identity problem. Every AI agent, API integration, and automated workflow creates service accounts and tokens that need management, according to the company. In most enterprises, these machine identities far outnumber human users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza’s Authorization Graph technology maps permissions across systems to show not just who has access, but what they can effectively do with that access. According to its website, the company manages more than 20 billion permissions for customers, including Blackstone, Expedia, and Workday. Veza has raised $235 million since its inception in 2020 and employed more than 190 people as of April 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tyagi said existing identity and access management tools were designed for human accounts but struggle with machine identities, API keys, and autonomous agents making real-time decisions. “This creates blind spots around privilege sprawl and cross-system access paths,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The two companies already work together. ServiceNow Ventures &lt;a href="https://veza.com/company/press-room/veza-strategic-announcement-servicenow-capitalone/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;invested in Veza in August 2023&lt;/a&gt; alongside Capital One Ventures. The companies have more than 250 joint customers, the report added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="customer-integration-questions"&gt;Customer integration questions&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For those joint customers, the acquisition would mean significant changes in how the two systems work together. Enterprises using both ServiceNow and Veza today run them as separate systems. Integration would allow ServiceNow’s AI agents to natively query and enforce access policies based on Veza’s permission intelligence, without customers building custom connections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That integration will take time, according to Tyagi. “ServiceNow is already a big and complex system, and adding a full identity security engine won’t be instant plug-and-play,” he said. Customers should expect changes to licensing and the introduction of new modules as the two platforms merge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations using Veza without ServiceNow will want clarity on whether the product remains available as a standalone offering. Those using ServiceNow with other identity vendors will need to know if their existing tools remain supported or if ServiceNow will push customers toward its own integrated stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ServiceNow unveiled AI agents for security and risk management at its &lt;a href="https://www.servicenow.com/company/media/press-room/ai-driven-security-and-risk.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Knowledge 2025 conference&lt;/a&gt; in May, positioning them as tools for autonomous enterprise defense. Veza would provide the authorization controls those security agents need to safely investigate and remediate threats across systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Veza treats access as a relationship problem, connecting identities, permissions, and data to show effective access rather than just theoretical permissions, according to Tyagi.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="market-implications"&gt;Market implications&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acquisition would give ServiceNow a more complete offering against rivals building AI-powered enterprise platforms. Salesforce, Microsoft, and Oracle all offer AI agents, but none had combined front-end automation with identity security in the way ServiceNow was attempting with Moveworks and Veza, according to Tyagi.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This deal can shake up the identity security landscape because it pulls deep authorization intelligence into a major enterprise platform instead of keeping it as a standalone specialty,” Tyagi said. Standalone identity vendors like CyberArk, SailPoint, and Okta may face pressure to find their own platform partnerships or acquisition targets, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097423/servicenow-is-in-talks-to-buy-identity-security-firm-veza-for-over-1-billion-report-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security researchers caution app developers about risks in using Google Antigravity</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097698/security-researchers-caution-app-developers-about-risks-in-using-google-antigravity.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google’s Antigravity development tool for creating artificial intelligence agents has been out for less than 11 days and already the company has been forced to update the known issues pages after security researchers discovered what they say are vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mindgard.ai/blog/google-antigravity-persistent-code-execution-vulnerability" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to a blog from Mindgard&lt;/a&gt;, one of the first to discover problems with Antigravity, Google isn’t calling the issue it found a security bug. But Mindgard says a threat actor could create a malicious rule by taking advantage of Antigravity’s strict direction that any AI assistant it creates must always follow user-defined rules.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Author Aaron Portnoy, Mindgard’s head of research and innovation, says that after his blog was posted, Google replied on November 25 to say a report has been filed with the responsible product team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Still, until there is action, “the existence of this vulnerability means that users are at risk to backdoor attacks via compromised workspaces when using Antigravity, which can be leveraged by attackers to execute arbitrary code on their systems. At present there is no setting that we could identify to safeguard against this vulnerability,” Portnoy wrote in his blog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even in the most restrictive mode of operation, “exploitation proceeds unabated and without confirmation from the user,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked for comment, a Google spokesperson said the company is aware of the issue reported by Mindguard, and is working to address it. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an email, Mindgard’s Portnoy told &lt;em&gt;CSOonline&lt;/em&gt; that the nature of the flaw makes it difficult to mitigate. “Strong identity would not help mitigate this issue, because the actions undertaken by Antigravity are occurring with the identity of the user running the application,” he said. “As far as the operating system can tell, they are indistinguishable. Access management control could possibly do so, but only if you were able to restrict access to the global configuration directory, and it may have downstream impact on Antigravity’s functionality.” For example, he said, this could cause Model Context Protocol (MCP), a framework for standardizing the way AI systems share data, to malfunction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The attack vector is through the source code repository that is opened by the developer,” he explained, “and doesn’t need to be triggered through a prompt.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other researchers also have found problems with Antigravity:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.deadbits.ai/p/indirect-prompt-injection-in-ai-ides" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Adam Swanda says he discovered and disclosed &lt;/a&gt;to Google an indirect prompt injection vulnerability. He said Google told him the particular problem is a known issue and is expected behavior of the tool.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;another researcher who goes by the name Wunderwuzzi &lt;a href="https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2025/security-keeps-google-antigravity-grounded/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blogged about discovering five holes&lt;/a&gt;, including data exfiltration and remote command execution via indirect prompt injection vulnerabilities. &lt;br /&gt;This blog notes that, according to Google’s Antigravity Known Issues page, &lt;a href="https://bughunters.google.com/learn/invalid-reports/google-products/4655949258227712/antigravity-known-issues" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company is working on fixes for several issues.  &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Asked for comment about the issues reported in the three blogs, a Google spokesperson said, “We take security issues very seriously and encourage reporting of all vulnerabilities so we can identify and address them quickly. We will continue to post &lt;a href="https://bughunters.google.com/learn/invalid-reports/google-products/4655949258227712/antigravity-known-issues" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;known issues&lt;/a&gt; publicly as we work to address them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-is-antigravity"&gt;What is Antigravity?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Antigravity is an integrated application development environment (IDE), released on November 18, that leverages the Google Gemini 3 Pro chatbot. “Antigravity isn’t just an editor,” &lt;a href="https://antigravity.google/blog/introducing-google-antigravity?utm_source=deepmind.google&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=gdm&amp;amp;utm_content=" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google says&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s a development platform that combines a familiar, AI-powered coding experience with a new agent-first interface. This allows you to deploy agents that autonomously plan, execute, and verify complex tasks across your editor, terminal, and browser.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Individuals — including threat actors — can use it for free.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Antigravity streamlines workflows by offering tools for parallelization, customization, and efficient knowledge management, the company says, to help eliminate common development obstacles and repetitive tasks. Agents can be spun up to tackle routine tasks such as codebase research, bug fixes, and backlog tasks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="agent-installs-the-malware"&gt;Agent installs the malware&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem Mindgard discovered involves Antigravity’s rule that the developer has to work within a trusted workspace or the tool won’t function. The threat manifests through an attacker creating a malicious source code repository, Portnoy says. “Then, if a target opens it (through finding it on Github, being social engineered, or tricked into opening it) then that user’s system becomes compromised persistently.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malicious actor doesn’t have to create an agent, he explained. The agent is part of Antigravity and is backed by the Google Gemini LLM. The agent is the component that is tricked into installing the backdoor by following instructions in the malicious source code repository that was opened by the user.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In Antigravity,” Mindgard argues, “’trust’ is effectively the entry point to the product rather than a conferral of privileges.” The problem, it pointed out, is that a compromised workspace becomes a long-term backdoor into every new session. “Even after a complete uninstall and re-install of Antigravity,” says Mindgard, “the backdoor remains in effect. Because Antigravity’s core intended design requires trusted workspace access, the vulnerability translates into cross-workspace risk, meaning one tainted workspace can impact all subsequent usage of Antigravity regardless of trust settings.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For anyone responsible for AI cybersecurity, says Mindguard, this highlights the need to treat AI development environments as sensitive infrastructure, and to closely control what content, files, and configurations are allowed into them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="process-perplexing"&gt;Process ‘perplexing’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In his email, Portnoy acknowledged that Google is now taking some action. “Google is moving through their established process, although it was a bit perplexing on the stop-and-start nature. First [the reported vulnerability] was flagged as not an issue. Then it was re-opened. Then the Known Issues page was altered in stealth to be more all encompassing. It’s good that the vulnerability will be reviewed by their security team to ascertain its severity, although in the meantime we would recommend all Antigravity users to seriously consider the vulnerability found and means for mitigation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Adam Swanda says in his blog that he was able to partially extract an Antigravity agent’s system prompt, enough to identify a design weakness that could lead to indirect prompt injection. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="highlights-broader-issues"&gt;Highlights broader issues&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem is, the prompt tells the AI to strictly follow special XML-style tags that handle privileged instructions in a conversation between a user and the chatbot, so there would be no warning to the user that special, and possibly malicious, instructions were retrieved. When the agent fetches external web content, Swanda says, it doesn’t sanitize these special tags to ensure they are actually from the application itself and not untrusted input. An attacker can embed their own special message in a webpage, or presumably any other content, and the Antigravity agent will treat those commands as trusted system instructions. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This type of vulnerability isn’t new, he adds, but the finding highlights broader issues in large language models and agent systems:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLMs cannot distinguish between trusted and untrusted sources;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;untrusted sources can contain malicious instructions to execute tools and/or modify responses returned to the user/application;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;system prompts should not be considered secret or used as a security control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="advice-to-developers"&gt;Advice to developers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Swanda recommends that app development teams building AI agents with tool-calling:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assume all external content is adversarial. Use strong input and output guardrails, including tool calling; Strip any special syntax before processing;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;implement tool execution safeguards. Require explicit user approval for high-risk operations, especially those triggered after handling untrusted content or other dangerous tool combinations;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;not rely on prompts for security. System prompts, for example, can be extracted and used by an attacker to influence their attack strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, Portnoy recommends that developers work with their security teams to ensure that they sufficiently vet and assess the AI-assisted tools that they are introducing to their organization. “There are numerous examples of using AI-assisted tools to accelerate development pipelines to enhance operational efficiency,” he said. “However, from experience, security in bleeding-edge (recently dropped) tools is somewhat of an afterthought. Thinking seriously about the intended use case of the AI tool, what data sources it can access, and what it is connected to are fundamental to ensuring you remain secure.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097698/security-researchers-caution-app-developers-about-risks-in-using-google-antigravity.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU ‘Chat Control’ proposals should be red flag to businesses everywhere</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097728/eu-chat-control-proposals-should-be-red-flag-to-businesses-everywhere.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data privacy campaigners have warned that any celebration of the news that the European Union (EU) has abandoned its plans to break end-to-end encryption in mobile messaging apps could be short-lived.  According to one expert, this announcement should be a “red flag” to organizations operating within Europe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There has been a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2154094/chat-apps-end-to-end-encryption-threatened-by-eu-legislation.html" target="_blank"&gt;long-standing threat to end-to-end encryption&lt;/a&gt; within Europe, as tech companies have battled with legislators over the EU Council’s attempt to limit messages shared by child sexual abusers through scanning of communications. Hoping to calm companies’ fears, on November 26, the &lt;a href="https://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/press/press-releases/2025/11/26/child-sexual-abuse-council-reaches-position-on-law-protecting-children-from-online-abuse/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Council issued a statement&lt;/a&gt; saying that all monitoring of communications will be performed by providers on a voluntary basis. It also announced a modified approach to the automated scans, dubbed &lt;a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/posts/chat-control/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chat Control&lt;/a&gt; by privacy campaigners, as a new way of tackling child abuse online.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, privacy campaigner and former member of European parliament &lt;a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Patrick Breyer&lt;/a&gt; noted, “the enterprise aspect was often overlooked in this debate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While there has been plenty of talk about the protection of individuals, Breyer said that, for CISOs and enterprises, the EU proposals should be a red flag. He pointed out there could be a real risk of the leakage of sensitive data. “The technology has high error rates. For a corporation, a ‘false positive’ could mean that confidential internal documents, code, or strategic plans are flagged and sent to external authorities or police forces without the company’s knowledge,&lt;strong&gt;”&lt;/strong&gt; he said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breyer has been a long time critic of the EU proposals, and feels that the move to voluntary monitoring of communications is not enough protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;The headlines are misleading: Chat Control is not dead, it is just being privatized&lt;strong&gt;,”&lt;/strong&gt;  wrote &lt;a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/reality-check-eu-council-chat-control-vote-is-not-a-retreat-but-a-green-light-for-indiscriminate-mass-surveillance-and-the-end-of-right-to-communicate-anonymously/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Breyer on his website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;What the Council endorsed today is a Trojan Horse. By cementing ‘voluntary’ mass scanning, they are legitimizing the warrantless, error-prone mass surveillance of millions of Europeans by US corporations, while simultaneously killing online anonymity through the backdoor of age verification.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Breyer’s position is supported by another digital privacy group, European Digital Rights (EDRi). It posted &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/european-digital-rights_chatcontrol-csaregulation-encryption-activity-7399432202427748352-Psot/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a statement on LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; saying that digital rights may still be at risk. “We want to be absolutely certain that lawmakers don’t leave loopholes that would lead to harm,” it said. “For example, the Council text would have been better if it expressly rejected the use of ‘client-side scanning’ tools, as a lot of discretion is still left to national authorities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In particular, EDRi drew attention to the possibility of voluntary monitoring. “This means that Big Tech companies can decide to scan your personal messages, without suspicion that you’re doing anything wrong, and apply error-prone predictive AI tools to look for evidence of abuse. This sort of scanning already happens, with very little transparency and oversight, and no proper legal basis,” said the organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And for corporations looking to protect their intellectual data and maintain secure communications, the threat is very real, said Breyer. “In short: If this proposal passes, no European company can guarantee the confidentiality of its communications any more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097728/eu-chat-control-proposals-should-be-red-flag-to-businesses-everywhere.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSO in eigener Sache: Mit Smart Answers zu mehr Information</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095215/cso-in-eigener-sache-mit-smart-answers-zu-mehr-information.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 5350w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2642127909.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Mit Smart Answers werden alle Ihre Fragen bei uns auf der CSO-Website beantwortet.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;witsarut sakorn – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie können CISOs ihre Karriere pushen? Welche Auswirkungen haben Ransomware-Angriffe auf Unternehmen? Wie läuft die Kommunikation nach einem Cyberangriff ab? Diese und viele weitere Fragen beantworten wir Ihnen auf der Website der CSO über unser neues KI-Tool “Smart Answers”.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO Smart Answers" class="wp-image-4096495" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-26-084908.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Smart Answers ist in allen Artikeln auf CSO.de eingebaut.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bei Smart Answers handelt es sich um einen Chatbot, der Leserinnen und Lesern dabei helfen soll, drängende Fragen der Security-Community zu beantworten, Inhalte auf unseren Webseiten zu entdecken und sich eingehend mit wichtigen IT- und Leadership-Themen zu befassen, die für Security-Entscheiderinnen und -Entscheider wichtig sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Tool ist praktisch in allen Artikeln auf der Website der CSO eingebettet. Um loszulegen, können Sie Ihre Fragen direkt in das Smart-Answers-Suchfeld eingeben. Alternativ können Sie auch aus einer Reihe zum Thema passender, vorkonfektionierter Fragen auswählen, um tiefer in ein Thema einzusteigen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO Smart Answers" class="wp-image-4096498" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-26-084621.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Klar strukturiert gibt Smart Answers Antworten auf Ihre Fragen&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In den Antworten finden Sie Links zu den Quelldokumenten sowie zusätzliches Informationsmaterial und Artikelempfehlungen. Darüber hinaus können Sie weitere Detailfragen stellen, um noch tiefer in ein bestimmtes Thema einzusteigen. Alternativ schlagen wir Ihnen außerdem weitere Fragen vor, über die Sie zusätzliche Aspekte zu dem von Ihnen angefragten Thema beleuchten können.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="CSO Smart Answers" class="wp-image-4096500" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-26-090752.png?w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Über die Quellenangaben zu den Antworten von Smart Answers können Sie Inhalte prüfen und tiefer in bestimmte Themen eintauchen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Smart Answers basiert auf einer Generative-AI-Plattform, die in Zusammenarbeit mit unserem Partner Miso.ai entwickelt wurde. Das KI-Tool greift ausschließlich auf redaktionelle Inhalte aus dem Netzwerk unserer deutschsprachigen Medienmarken zurück – CIO, COMPUTERWOCHE, CSO und ChannelPartner – und wurde mit Fragen trainiert, die für professionelle IT-Anwender aus Unternehmen relevant sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wir haben uns viel Mühe gegeben, um sicherzustellen, dass Smart Answers eine hochwertige Benutzererfahrung bietet. Die Antworten basieren ausschließlich auf Artikeln, die von unseren Journalistinnen und Journalisten verfasst wurden. Smart Answers verwendet keine Daten aus &lt;a href="https://a1.adform.net/C/?bn=85522444;gdpr=%24%7Bgdpr%7D;gdpr_consent=%24%7Bgdpr_consent_50%7D" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;externen Quellen. Hinter den Kulissen wurden umfangreiche Tests durchgeführt, um das Modell zu trainieren, sodass wir davon überzeugt sind, Ihnen mit Smart Answers zuverlässige Informationen für Ihre Arbeit an die Hand geben zu können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="probieren-sie-smart-answers-aus-und-teilen-sie-ihr-feedback"&gt;Probieren Sie Smart Answers aus und teilen Sie Ihr Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wie bei allen von KI generierten Inhalten empfehlen wir jedoch, diese zu überprüfen. Wir haben intensiv mit unserem Partner Miso.ai zusammengearbeitet, um „Halluzinationen“ zu vermeiden. Irreführende oder falsche Informationen, die ausgegeben werden können, wenn die Antwort nicht bekannt ist oder die zur Beantwortung der Frage erforderlichen Daten unvollständig sind, sollten so weitgehend ausgeschlossen sein. Wenn Smart Answers Ihre Frage nicht beantworten kann, teilt Ihnen das KI-Tool dies mit. Angezeigt wird außerdem, wenn die Antwort von Smart Answers vor allem auf Inhalten beruht, die vor dem Jahr 2020 veröffentlicht wurden. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wir laden Sie ein, mit Smart Answers zu experimentieren. Stellen unser neues KI-Tool auf die Probe. Wir hoffen, ihnen damit weiteren wertvollen Content und Input für Ihre Arbeit zur Verfügung stellen zu können. Und wir sind natürlich gespannt auf Ihr Feedback. Teilen Sie uns gerne Ihre Erfahrungen mit Smart Answers mit und schicken Sie uns Ihre Anmerkungen an julia.mutzbauer@csoonline.com.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095215/cso-in-eigener-sache-mit-smart-answers-zu-mehr-information.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-779)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-779</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-780)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-780</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-781)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-781</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25-782)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-782</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empathetic policy engineering: The secret to better security behavior and awareness</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4092639/empathy-meets-it-security-the-path-to-active-compliance.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#_ftnref1" id="_ftn1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In many companies, IT security guidelines encounter resistance because employees perceive them as obstructive or impractical. This makes implementation difficult, undermines effectiveness, and strains collaboration between the security department and business units.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, instead of being seen as a partner, cybersecurity is often perceived as a hindrance — a fatal security risk. For CISOs, this means that, in addition to technically sound guidelines, acceptance in everyday work is crucial. A new approach with empathetic policy engineering and strategic security communication can help foster a sustainable security culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="it-security-work-pressure-and-social-influences"&gt;IT security: Work pressure and social influences&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many IT departments believe that users are poorly motivated to comply with security guidelines. Companies rely on sanctions and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;security awareness training&lt;/a&gt; to enforce compliance. However, a two-day experiment investigating the impact of security designs on policy-compliant user behavior revealed that while participants initially had a positive attitude toward security guidelines, these guidelines became increasingly perceived as a hindrance under rising work pressure, leading to more frequent violations. Stress and situational factors had a noticeable influence on the participants’ security-related behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Safe behavior therefore does not arise solely from knowledge transfer, but depends heavily on individual risk assessment and concrete everyday situations. Users do not always act as the guidelines prescribe — often not out of unwillingness, but because other factors outweigh or are considered more important. Ambitious goals, time pressure, and the need for seamless collaboration frequently conflict with abstract security requirements. These conflicts of interest quickly lead to tensions between security, IT, and other departments. This ultimately jeopardizes the security culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security managers can counteract this by addressing three points.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-conduct-stakeholder-analysis"&gt;1. Conduct stakeholder analysis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs should first ask themselves why users are not behaving securely. A variety of factors play a role here: For example, users may not be aware of the threat, may not see the benefits of secure behavior, or may perceive security measures as hindering their work. There may also be a conflict of interest with the users’ goals, or they may be under time pressure. Often, the resources are simply lacking — for example, if regulations require secure data exchange with suppliers and customers, but employees are not provided with a platform for such data exchange — or there may be a lack of role models in the environment&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before implementing security measures, it is important to identify and balance conflicting goals and priorities among the various stakeholder groups (IT department, technical departments, management, administration, production staff). This can be done, for example, through stakeholder analysis — a method from business informatics used to ascertain the preferences of all stakeholders involved. The more security managers know about the realities of work and the goals of the different departments, the better they can tailor security measures accordingly — leading to greater acceptance and ultimately successful implementation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-design-security-guidelines-with-the-user-in-mind"&gt;2. Design security guidelines with the user in mind&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Insecure behavior is often blamed on users, when the problem often lies in the measure itself. In IT security research, the focus is often on individual user behavior — for example, on whether secure behavior depends on personality traits. The question of how well security measures actually fit the reality of work — that is, how likely they are to be accepted in everyday practice — is neglected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For every threat, there are usually several available security measures. But differences in effort, acceptance, compatibility, or complexity are often not taken into account in practice. Instead, security or IT departments often make decisions based solely on technical aspects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To establish effective IT security policies, they must not only be technically correct — they must also be sensible and practical from an employee perspective. The key to this lies in empathetic policy engineering: Security guidelines should be designed so that they are understandable, accepted, and compatible with everyday work goals. This is best achieved when employees are involved in the development process early on — including their conflicting goals and practical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A subsequent pilot project helps to identify potential stumbling blocks and obstacles early on and to adjust the measures accordingly. It has proven effective to start with the “early adopters” — that is, the group of users who are open to innovations and can subsequently provide constructive feedback. This should be taken into account before the large-scale rollout. In this way, a safety culture can develop that is effective — and actually practiced in everyday work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-communicate-with-respect"&gt;3. Communicate with respect&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Safety measures and guidelines are often communicated in a way that doesn’t resonate with users’ work reality because they don’t aim to engage employees and motivate them: for example, through instructions, standard online training, or overly playful formats like comics that employees don’t take seriously. A “respect approach” works better: It relies on communication on equal terms, instead of prohibitions and punishments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The crucial difference: Employees are treated as competent, responsible adults. The focus is on an empathetic understanding of their needs and work realities — without losing sight of safety goals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are several techniques for successfully communicating safety policies and avoiding conflicts:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tactical empathy:&lt;/strong&gt; This creates recognition, strengthens trust, and thus ensures that employees feel heard and are willing to accept security-relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Help me to help you’instead of ‘No’:&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of enforcing security requirements, CISOs can use targeted “how” questions to encourage users to think about the proposed solutions. If users have change requests regarding the security requirements, security shouldn’t simply say “no.” It’s helpful to ask what the employees themselves suggest to both comply with security requirements and enable efficient work. This creates a dialogue and makes it easier to find a compromise acceptable to all parties involved&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical experience instead of dry theory:&lt;/strong&gt; A training concept that relies on direct experience confronts participants with realistic scenarios — such as cyberattacks like phishing, ransomware, or USB attacks. They experience firsthand, in a realistic environment that replicates typical workplaces in small and midsize enterprises, how cyberattacks unfold. This creates a deep, lasting understanding of IT security. Instead of lectures, the focus is on people and their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cisos-as-shapers-of-an-effective-security-culture"&gt;CISOs as shapers of an effective security culture&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The limited success of many security measures is not solely due to the users — often it’s unrealistic requirements, a lack of involvement, and inadequate communication. For security leaders, this means: Instead of relying on education and sanctions, a strategic paradigm shift is needed. They should become a kind of empathetic policy architect whose security strategy not only works technically but also resonates on a human level. They create frameworks in which secure decisions are naturally integrated into everyday work. This requires a good sense of conflicting objectives, communication on equal terms — and the ability to anchor security as a shared value within the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4092639/empathy-meets-it-security-the-path-to-active-compliance.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-784)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-784</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-783)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-783</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CSO guide to top security conferences</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/559539/the-cso-guide-to-top-security-conferences.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is nothing like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/539824/data-protection-security-conferences-why-go.html"&gt;attending a face-to-face event&lt;/a&gt; for career networking and knowledge gathering, and we don’t have to tell you how helpful it can be to get a hands-on demo of a new tool or to have your questions answered by experts. Fortunately, plenty of great &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/1622033/2022-new-zealand-tech-conference-and-event-guide.html"&gt;conferences&lt;/a&gt; are coming up in the months ahead. If keeping abreast of security trends and evolving threats is critical to your job — and we know it is — then attending some top-notch security conferences is on your must-do list for 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From major events to those that are more narrowly focused, this list from the editors of CSO, will help you find the security conferences that matter the most to you. We’ll keep it updated with new conferences so check back often. While we don’t expect this calendar to be comprehensive, we do aim to have it be highly relevant. If there’s something we’ve missed, let us know. You can email your additions, corrections and updates to &lt;a href="mailto:samira_sarraf@foundryco.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samira Sarraf&lt;/a&gt;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="december-2025"&gt;December 2025&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.passwordscon.org/"&gt;PasswordsCon&lt;/a&gt;, Prague, Czech Republic: 1-3 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://it-security-summit.com/munich/"&gt;IT Security Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Munich, Germany and virtual: 1-5 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/dallas-2025"&gt;SANS Dallas 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US and virtual: 1-6 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://heliview.com/state-cyber-security-sweden/"&gt;State of Cyber Security 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Stockholm, Sweden: 2 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/austin-tx-2025/"&gt;FutureCon Austin Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 4 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.conf42.com/devsecops2025"&gt;Conf42 DevSecOps 2025&lt;/a&gt;, virtual: 4 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cybersecuritysummit.com/summit/jacksonville25/"&gt;3rd Annual Jacksonville Cybersecurity Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Florida, US: 4 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsidescapetown.co.za/"&gt;BSides Cape Town&lt;/a&gt;, Cape Town, South Africa: 6 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.riskgcc.com/"&gt;#Risk GCC&lt;/a&gt;, Dubai, UAE: 8-9 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/na/identity-access-management-us"&gt;Gartner Identity &amp;amp; Access Management Summit 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 8-10 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://msspalertlive.com/2025"&gt;MSSP Alert Live&lt;/a&gt;, Maryland, US: 8-10 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/nashville-tn-2025/"&gt;FutureCon Nashville Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Tennessee, US: 10 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://luma.com/defenders-tour-arlington"&gt;Defenders Tour: SecOps Workshop&lt;/a&gt;, Virginia, US: 11 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/cyber-defense-initiative-2025"&gt;SANS Cyber Defense Initiative 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Washington D.C., US: 12 – 17 December&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="january-2026"&gt;January 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/nashville-winter-2026"&gt;SANS Nashville Winter 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Tennessee, US: 12-17 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/los-angeles-ca-2026/"&gt;Los Angeles Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and California, US: 15 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://identityshield.miniorange.com/"&gt;IdentityShield Summit&lt;/a&gt; ‘26, Pune, India: 16-17 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/dallas-tx-2026/"&gt;Dallas Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 22 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSidesPanamá&lt;/a&gt;, Panama city, Panama: 23-24 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/cyber-threat-intelligence-summit-2025/?msc=summit-home"&gt;SANS Cyber Threat Intelligence Summit &amp;amp; Training&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and Virginia, US: 26 January – 2 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.americanconference.com/cybersecurity-law/"&gt;Cybersecurity Law and Compliance&lt;/a&gt;, Washington, DC, US: 28 – 29 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/chicago-il-2026/"&gt;Chicago Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and Illinois, US: 29 January&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="february-2026"&gt;February 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cybersec-asia.net/"&gt;Cybersec Asia Shield your Core&lt;/a&gt;, Bangkok, Thailand: 4-5 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.intelliguards.com/intellic0n-speakers"&gt;Intellic0n&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 5-6 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cruisecon.com/"&gt;CruiseCon&lt;/a&gt;, departs from Florida, US: 7-12 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hackcon.org/hackcon21"&gt;HackCon&lt;/a&gt;, Oslo, Norway: 9-10 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://anz.cs4ca.com/"&gt;#CS4CA ANZ&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, Australia: 10-11 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://planetcybersec.com/021126-conference/"&gt;Planet Cyber Sec Conference&lt;/a&gt;, California, US: 11 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/detroit-mi-2026/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Detroit Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Michigan, US: 19 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSidesGalway&lt;/a&gt;, Galway, Ireland: 21 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cosac.net/apac/"&gt;Cosac APAC&lt;/a&gt;, Melbourne, Australia: 24-26 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSides Seattle&lt;/a&gt;, Washington State, US: 27-28 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="march-2026"&gt;March 2026&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cyberflorida.org/sunshine/"&gt;CyberBay 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Florida, US: 12-13 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/sans-osint-summit-2025/"&gt;SANS OSINT Summit &amp;amp; Training&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and Virginia, US: 16-22 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://heliview.com/security-leadership/"&gt;Security Leadership 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Utrecht, Netherlands: 24 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="april-2026"&gt;April 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cyphercon.com/"&gt;Cyphercon&lt;/a&gt;, Wisconsin, US: 1-2 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="may-2026"&gt;May 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.devopsbootcamp.net/cybersecfest-saopaulo"&gt;CyberSecFest SP&lt;/a&gt;, São Paulo, Brazil: May TBC&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/559539/the-cso-guide-to-top-security-conferences.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-785)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-785</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI admits data breach after analytics partner hit by phishing attack</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097488/openai-admits-data-breach-after-analytics-partner-hit-by-phishing-attack-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI has suffered a significant data breach after hackers broke into the systems of its analytics partner Mixpanel and successfully stole customer profile information for its API portal, the companies have said in coordinated statements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://mixpanel.com/blog/sms-security-incident/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a post by Mixpanel CEO Jen Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, the incident took place on November 8 when the company “detected a smishing campaign and promptly executed our incident response processes.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Smishing is a form of phishing-by-SMS against targeted employees, popular with hackers because text messages bypass normal enterprise controls. This gave the attackers access to Mixpanel’s system, allowing them to steal a range of metadata relating to platform.openai.com account profiles:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name provided to OpenAI on the API account &lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Email address associated with the API account&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Approximate location based on API user browser (city, state, country)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Operating system and browser used to access the API account&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Referring websites&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Organization or User IDs associated with the API account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We proactively communicated with all impacted customers. If you have not heard from us directly, you were not impacted,” said Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/mixpanel-incident/"&gt;separate OpenAI post&lt;/a&gt;, Mixpanel shared the affected customer dataset with it on November 25. After review, OpenAI had terminated its use of Mixpanel, it said, implying that this might be permanent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident affects some customers with platform.openai.com accounts, but not users of ChatGPT or other OpenAI products, OpenAI said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are in the process of notifying impacted organizations, admins, and users directly. While we have found no evidence of any effect on systems or data outside Mixpanel’s environment, we continue to monitor closely for any signs of misuse,” OpenAI said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This was not a breach of OpenAI’s systems. No chat, API requests, API usage data, passwords, credentials, API keys, payment details, or government IDs were compromised or exposed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-should-customers-react"&gt;How should customers react?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are three levels of concern here: which OpenAI API customers are affected, how attackers might use stolen data if they are, and the possibility, however hypothetical, that more valuable data such as API keys or account credentials could be at risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the first issue, as noted above, both companies have said they have contacted customers caught up in the breach without specifying how many users are affected. OpenAI has set up an email address customers can use if they have further questions: mixpanelincident@openai.com. Mixpanel has set up an equivalent contact address: support@mixpanel.com⁠.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, if &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567531/the-biggest-data-breach-fines-penalties-and-settlements-so-far.html"&gt;decades of data breaches&lt;/a&gt; have taught the world anything it’s that companies don’t always know the full extent of a data breach even when they say they do. For that reason, it would be wise for OpenAI customers who have not been contacted to conduct the same security review as those that have.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI said that customers should be on their guard for phishing attacks targeting breached email addresses and to check that messages that appear to be sent from OpenAI’s domain are genuine. They should also turn on multi-factor authentication (MFA).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If phishing sounds generic, in the context of an API connection the dangers are more specific and include more nuanced fake alerts for things like billing, quota messages, and suspicious logins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to OpenAI, there is no need for customers to rotate or reset account credentials or API keys, which attackers could use to steal data or consume services. Despite this, cautious developers are likely to ignore this and rotate and reset credentials because this removes the risk. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several organizations involved in API and AI security have offered more detailed breakdowns of recommendations in the light of the OpenAI-Mixpanel incident, including &lt;a href="https://www.ox.security/blog/openai-mixpanel-3rd-party-data-breach/"&gt;Ox Security&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://dev.to/alifar/the-openai-mixpanel-security-incident-explained-2ok5"&gt;Dev Community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="downstream-attack-surface"&gt;Downstream attack surface&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenAI uses external analytics platforms such as Mixpanel to track how customers interact with models through the API. This includes which models a customer selects plus basic metadata such as location and email ID listed above. It does not track the user ‘payload’, that is chatbot queries and responses being sent to the model from a browser, which are encrypted.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The latest incident underlines that the security of the primary platform is only one part of the risk: secondary platforms and partners are a backdoor that can expose even careful organizations, as some Salesforce customers have seen with &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4046407/attackers-steal-data-from-salesforce-instances-via-compromised-ai-live-chat-tool.html"&gt;data breaches at its partner Salesloft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack surface exposed by AI platforms is bigger than it looks, a security and governance challenge enterprises should assess before jumping in with both feet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4097479/openai-admits-data-breach-after-analytics-partner-hit-by-phishing-attack.html"&gt;Infoworld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4097488/openai-admits-data-breach-after-analytics-partner-hit-by-phishing-attack-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-786)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-786</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-787)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-787</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-788)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-788</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer security advisory (AV25-789)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/geoserver-security-advisory-av25-789</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
