<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 06:41:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>OTF GRIMM: Swedish organiser of serious violence arrested in Iraq</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</link>
      <description>A High-Value Target under Europol-supported Operational Taskforce GRIMM was arrested in Iraq following long-term cooperation between the Swedish Police Authority and Iraqi law enforcement authorities. The 21-year-old suspect, a Swedish national who was listed on the EU Most Wanted list, is identified as a key organiser of serious violence directed at Sweden from abroad.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-014)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-015)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-016)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-017)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-018)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–019)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-001 – Vulnerabilities affecting n8n – CVE-2026-21858, CVE-2026-21877 and CVE-2025-68613</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Agencies shape future cooperation and mark 25 years of the Fundamental Rights Charter</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</link>
      <description>Europol Deputy Executive Director for Governance, Jurgen Ebner, joined the Heads of EU Justice and Home Affairs Agencies in Vienna to reflect on joint achievements and align their future cooperation with the wider EU priorities.Marking the 25th anniversary of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, they adopted a joint statement pledging to intensify efforts to uphold and promote fundamental rights...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-agencies-shape-future-cooperation-and-mark-25-years-of-fundamental-rights-charter</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The culture you can’t see is running your security operations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118141/the-culture-you-cant-see-is-running-your-security-operations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here’s what nobody admits: Your firewall isn’t the problem. Your SIEM isn’t the problem. That shiny new EDR tool you just bought? Also, not the problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The problem is Steve from accounting, who uses “Password123” because he can’t be bothered to remember anything more complex. The problem is your CISO, who talks about zero trust but still approves exceptions for the CEO’s personal devices. The problem is the unspoken rule that security slows things down, so everyone ends up finding workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the famous quote, attributed to Peter Drucker goes – Culture eats strategy for breakfast. In cyber operations, it eats your security posture for lunch. We learned this the hard way three years ago when a mid-sized financial firm hired a colleague to figure out why they kept getting phished despite spending millions on awareness training. Their policies were pristine. Their tech stack was impressive. Their incident response plan could’ve won awards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But their culture? Rotten to the core.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The thing about culture is that it exists in layers. What you see on the surface tells you almost nothing about what’s actually happening. You need to understand three distinct dimensions: observable, non-observable and implicit. Miss any one of them, and you’re building your security program on quicksand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="observable-culture-the-stuff-you-can-actually-see"&gt;Observable culture: The stuff you can actually see&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Observable culture is everything tangible. Your policies. Your procedures. The security awareness posters in the break room. The mandatory training modules everyone clicks through while checking their phones.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where most organizations stop. They write a 47-page security policy, mandate annual training, deploy some monitoring tools and call it a day. Box checked. Compliance achieved. Everyone goes home feeling good about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Except none of it matters if people don’t actually follow through.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Observable elements include your formal security protocols, your incident response plans and your access controls. They include visible behaviors like password hygiene, device management and whether people actually report suspicious emails. They include the technology you deploy and how you communicate about threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can measure this stuff. You can audit it. You can put it in a spreadsheet and show it to the board.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But observable culture is the easiest to fake. People learn to perform security theatre. They know what they’re supposed to do. They know what gets measured. So they do just enough to avoid getting flagged while continuing their risky behaviors in the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/544343/compliance-target-the-breach-that-should-ve-never-happened.html"&gt;Target’s 2013 breach&lt;/a&gt;. They had a $1.6 million FireEye malware detection system. The system did exactly what it was supposed to do. It detected the malware. It sent alerts. Multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the security team ignored the alerts. They had policies and procedures. They had the technology. But the observable layer was disconnected from actual practice. The tools were there, but the follow-through wasn’t. The breach exposed 40 million credit card numbers and cost Target over $200 million in settlements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The impact on cyber operations was catastrophic. The tools didn’t fail. The observable culture, the visible security apparatus, existed in a vacuum. Having security controls is meaningless if your operational culture treats alerts as noise. Target’s incident response plan looked great on paper. But when alerts fired, nobody acted. The gap between documented procedure and actual behavior created a blind spot large enough to drive a truck through.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That financial firm we mentioned? Their observable culture looked perfect. Everyone completed their training. Policies were documented and signed. Security tools were deployed and configured.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But when we dug deeper, we found developers routinely turning off security controls because they “slowed down deployments.” We found executives sharing credentials because “it’s faster than waiting for access requests.” We even found an entire shadow IT ecosystem that nobody wanted to acknowledge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The observable layer gives you structure. Structure without substance is just theatre.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="non-observable-culture-the-hidden-drivers"&gt;Non-observable culture: The hidden drivers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now we get interesting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Non-observable culture is everything happening inside people’s heads. Their beliefs about cyber risk. Their attitudes toward security. Their values and priorities when security conflicts with convenience or speed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where the real decisions get made.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can’t see someone’s belief that “we’re too small to be targeted” or “security is IT’s job, not mine.” You can’t measure their assumption that compliance equals security. You can’t audit their gut feeling that reporting a mistake will hurt their career.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But these invisible forces shape every security decision your people make.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Non-observable culture includes beliefs about the likelihood and severity of threats. It includes how people weigh security against productivity. It includes their trust in leadership and their willingness to admit mistakes. It includes all the cognitive biases that distort risk perception.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Optimism bias makes people think breaches happen to other companies. Availability bias makes recent incidents loom larger than systemic vulnerabilities. Confirmation bias makes people see what they expect to see and ignore contradictory evidence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/550056/sony-hacked-in-feb-knew-about-huge-security-flaws-before-cybersecurity-train-wreck.html"&gt;Sony’s 2014 breach&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t a tech failure. It was a belief failure. People saw security as IT’s job, not theirs. So they clicked phishing links, shared credentials and treated threats as unlikely because “we make movies.” North Korean attackers didn’t need fancy exploits. They used that non-observable culture. Result: 100TB leaked. Unreleased films, personal data, executive emails. Networks stayed down for weeks, production stalled and trust took a beating. No firewall can fix a culture that thinks it won’t be targeted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At that financial firm, the non-observable culture was toxic. Developers believed security was an obstacle to innovation. Executives believed cyber risk was purely technical and could be solved by buying more tools. Staff felt that admitting security concerns would make them look incompetent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nobody said these things out loud. But everyone acted on them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The gap between what people say they believe and what they actually think is where security programs go to die. You can mandate all the training you want. If people fundamentally believe security doesn’t apply to them, they’ll find ways around every control you implement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="implicit-culture-the-deepest-layer"&gt;Implicit culture: The deepest layer&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here’s where it gets really uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implicit culture is the stuff nobody talks about because nobody even realizes it’s there. The unspoken assumptions. The invisible norms. The “way things are done here” that everyone knows but nobody questions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the most powerful layer because it operates below conscious awareness. People don’t choose to follow implicit norms. They do. Automatically. Without thinking.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implicit culture includes unspoken beliefs like “security slows us down” or “leadership doesn’t really care about this.” It contains hidden power dynamics that determine who can challenge security decisions and who can’t. It includes the organizational identity that shapes how people see themselves and their work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It includes psychological safety, or the lack thereof. Can people raise concerns without fear? Can they admit mistakes without punishment? Can they challenge assumptions without being labelled difficult?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567833/equifax-data-breach-faq-what-happened-who-was-affected-what-was-the-impact.html"&gt;Equifax’s 2017 breach&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t just a missed patch. It was a cultural failure. A critical Apache Struts flaw was disclosed, and security teams were warned to patch. Yet the unspoken rule was that security emails were noise, and uptime trumped fixes. Security had no absolute authority to stop work until the patch landed. So the vulnerability sat for months, visible and ignored. Attackers exploited it, exposing data on 147 million people, including Social Security numbers. Trust collapsed. Leadership changed. Equifax later agreed to settlements totalling more than $700 million. And nobody owned the risk decision!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At that financial firm, the implicit culture was brutal. There was an unspoken assumption that business units were more critical than security teams. There was an invisible hierarchy in which anyone with sufficient seniority could overrule security recommendations. There was a hidden belief that admitting vulnerability was a sign of weakness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nobody wrote these rules down. Nobody explicitly taught the new hires. But everyone learned them within weeks of starting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Implicit culture is why change is so hard. You can rewrite policies overnight. You can deploy new tools in a matter of weeks. But shifting deeply embedded assumptions? That takes years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And if you don’t address this layer, nothing else sticks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="shifting-all-three-dimensions"&gt;Shifting all three dimensions&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How do you actually change culture?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can’t just pick one dimension and hope the others follow. They’re interconnected. Change in one without the others creates misalignment and confusion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Start by making the invisible visible. You can’t fix what you can’t see. Conduct culture audits. Run anonymous surveys. Bring in external facilitators who can spot blind spots you’ve normalized. Ask uncomfortable questions and actually listen to the answers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Leadership has to model the behavior you want to see. Don’t just talk about it. Actually do it. Visibly. Consistently. When leaders admit mistakes, it creates permission for everyone else to do the same. When leaders prioritize security over convenience, it signals what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Embed security into daily operations. Not as a separate function that people have to remember. As part of how work gets done. DevSecOps isn’t just a buzzword. It’s about making security the default path, not the exception.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Build continuous learning into your culture. Threats evolve. Your understanding needs to evolve, too. Post-incident reviews shouldn’t be about blame. They should be about building organizational memory and getting smarter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fix your incentives. If you reward speed over security, people will choose speed. If you punish people for reporting problems, they’ll stop reporting. Ensure consequences for negligence are transparent and fair, while also ensuring people feel safe raising concerns.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At that financial firm, we spent six months working through all three layers. We didn’t just update policies. We surfaced hidden beliefs through facilitated discussions. We identified implicit assumptions and challenged them openly. We changed how leadership talked about and acted on security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It was messy. It was uncomfortable. But it worked.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-reality"&gt;The reality&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In practice, technical controls are easy. Culture is hard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can buy tools. You can write policies. You can mandate training. But you can’t mandate belief. You can’t purchase trust. You can’t deploy psychological safety.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Target had the tools but not the operational discipline. Sony had the policies but not the shared belief that security mattered. Equifax knew, but lacked the cultural permission to act on it. Each breach happened at a different cultural layer. Each costs hundreds of millions. Each could have been prevented not by better technology but by better culture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Culture change requires patience, consistency and a willingness to confront uncomfortable truths. It requires leaders who are willing to examine their own assumptions and behaviors. It requires organizations that value honesty over appearances.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Observable culture provides structure. Non-observable culture offers motivation. Implicit culture includes the foundation. You need all three.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The organizations that survive are those where security is woven into their cultural DNA, where risk intelligence is instinctive rather than imposed, where people make good security decisions because it’s simply how things are done.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s the real work. Not buying another tool. Not writing another policy, but building a culture where security isn’t something people do. It’s something they are.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118141/the-culture-you-cant-see-is-running-your-security-operations.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-020)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-021)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV26-022)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-023)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-025)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neue EU-Schwachstellen-Datenbank gestartet</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118661/neue-eu-schwachstellen-datenbank-gestartet.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 8960w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2692564999.jpg?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Die neue GCVE-Datenbank soll das Schwachstellenmanagement effizienter und einfacher machen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Summit Art Creations – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mit &lt;a href="https://db.gcve.eu/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;db.gcve.eu&lt;/a&gt; stellt die GCVE-Initiative (Global Cybersecurity Vulnerability Enumeration) ab sofort eine kostenfreie, öffentlich zugängliche Datenbank für IT-Sicherheitslücken bereit. Ziel ist es, die Abhängigkeit von US-Datenbanken zu beenden und die digitale Souveränität in &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3985557/neue-eu-schwachstellen-datenbank-geht-an-den-start.html" target="_blank"&gt;Europa&lt;/a&gt; zu stärken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="gcve-datenbank-soll-schwachstellenmeldung-erleichtern"&gt;GCVE-Datenbank soll Schwachstellenmeldung erleichtern&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Plattform führt Informationen aus verschiedenen öffentlichen Ressourcen zusammen. Dazu zählen die Quellen des GCVE Numbering Authority (GNA)-Modells. Es löst die traditionelle, zentrale Vergabe von Schwachstellen-Kennungen (CVE IDs) ab. Zudem werden Daten von weiteren anerkannten Schwachstellenverzeichnissen genutzt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der dezentrale Ansatz ermöglicht es, Schwachstellen-Kennungen autonom zu vergeben und zu veröffentlichen, ohne auf eine zentrale Freigabe warten zu müssen. Insgesamt werden derzeit mehr als 25 unterschiedliche Datenquellen eingebunden. Die erfassten Schwachstellendaten werden normalisiert, strukturiert und durchsuchbar aufbereitet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus bietet die offene API eine nahtlose Integration in bestehende Compliance-Tools und Risikomanagement-Systeme. Sicherheitsverantwortliche, Wissenschaftler, Computer Security Incident Response Teams, Softwareanbieter und Open-Source-Entwickler sollen dadurch in die Lage versetzt werden, Sicherheitsmeldungen ökosystemübergreifend effizienter nachzuverfolgen und auszuwerten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118661/neue-eu-schwachstellen-datenbank-gestartet.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK authorities warn of pro-Russia groups targeting critical infrastructure, local government</title>
      <link>https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/uk-warn-pro-russia-critical-infrastructure/809992/</link>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgproxy.divecdn.com/hShcOaRXNX0Y6AYUlIi-4bMTITtclb5CPUZfmwLxrhM/g:ce/rs:fill:1600:900:1/Z3M6Ly9kaXZlc2l0ZS1zdG9yYWdlL2RpdmVpbWFnZS9HZXR0eUltYWdlcy0xMzI0NzAwMzY1LmpwZw==.webp" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The alert comes just over a month after a joint advisory from CISA, the FBI and Western allies citing hacktivist activity against OT providers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cybersecuritydive.com/news/uk-warn-pro-russia-critical-infrastructure/809992/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.69</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:58:23 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-026)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV26-027)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-028)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.76</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-029)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-030)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-031)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-032)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.81</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mandiant pushes organizations to dump insecure NTLMv1 by releasing a way to crack it</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118800/mandiant-pushes-organizations-to-dump-insecure-ntlmv1-by-releasing-a-way-to-crack-it.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google’s Mandiant security division has come up with an unusual tactic to persuade organizations to stop using the aged and hugely insecure NTLMv1 authentication protocol: publish a data lookup that makes cracking NTLMv1 credentials trivial for attackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The intention, Mandiant explained, is to draw attention to the fact that, despite decades of evidence that NTLMv1 (NT LAN Manager version 1) is insecure, organizations continue to use it. Anyone can use Mandiant’s Net-NTLMv1 pre-computed rainbow table lookup, downloadable from the Google Cloud Research Dataset &lt;a href="https://research.google/resources/datasets/?dataset_types=other&amp;amp;search=Net-NTLMv1&amp;amp;" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;portal&lt;/a&gt;, to map a given server response to reconstruct a real NT hash.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hashes, of course, are mathematical representations of real passwords, but are just as useful to criminals when exploited using techniques such as &lt;em&gt;pass-the-hash&lt;/em&gt;. The benefit is time and money saved: Mandiant reckons its rainbow table allows the recovery of an NTLMv1 key in 12 hours using a computer costing $600, rather than relying on third party services or expensive hardware to brute-force the keys.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;None of this makes NTLMv1 less secure or easier to target than it already is. Mandiant’s hope is that the release of the table will serve as a reminder that the problem exists, prompting organizations to finally &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2097636/ridding-your-network-of-ntlm.html" target="_blank"&gt;rip out NTLMv1&lt;/a&gt; from their networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This legacy protocol leaves organizations vulnerable to trivial credential theft, yet it remains prevalent due to inertia and a lack of demonstrated immediate risk,” the company &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/net-ntlmv1-deprecation-rainbow-tables/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said in its announcement&lt;/a&gt;. “By releasing these tables, Mandiant aims to lower the barrier for security professionals to demonstrate the insecurity of Net-NTLMv1.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="long-fallback"&gt;Long fallback&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NTLMv1 is a 1990s challenge-response protocol used to authenticate Windows NT users to Active Directory (AD). Based on 1980’s Data Encryption Standard (DES) encryption, it was updated to the more secure NTLMv2 in 1996 before being completely replaced by Kerberos. Unfortunately, legacy protocols like NTLMv1 don’t just disappear, and are retained as a fallback in case they are needed by older applications. That fallback has turned out to last decades.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What evidence does Mandiant have that organizations are still using NTLMv1? The first is anecdotal: “Mandiant consultants continue to identify its use in active environments,” the company noted in last week’s announcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Secondly, cyberattackers regularly target it. For example, a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1311455/malicious-email-campaign-steals-ntlm-hashes.html" target="_blank"&gt;2024 campaign&lt;/a&gt; by the TA577 threat group targeted NTLM hashes by using booby-trapped emails to send challenge-response authentication requests to internal SMB resources such as legacy printers.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A more recent incident involved an authentication relay attack aimed at a specific NTLM vulnerability, &lt;a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/en-us/blog/analyzing-ntlm-ldap-authentication-bypass-vulnerability/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-54918&lt;/a&gt;, which came only weeks after Microsoft announced that it was finally &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/topic/upcoming-changes-to-ntlmv1-in-windows-11-version-24h2-and-windows-server-2025-c0554217-cdbc-420f-b47c-e02b2db49b2e" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;removing NTLMv1 support&lt;/a&gt; from Windows Server 2025 and Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="primary-hurdle-knowing-its-still-there"&gt;Primary hurdle: Knowing it’s still there&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/robfinn/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Finn&lt;/a&gt;, International vice president at supply chain security company Chainguard, even security-aware organizations could be caught out by NTLMv1.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Legacy protocols like NTLMv1 are buried deep within third-party firmware. A security team might deprecate NTLMv1 at the OS level, only to have a legacy printer driver or industrial sensor reintroduce it via an unpatched, decades-old library,” he said. “For most companies, the primary hurdle isn’t just knowing NTLMv1 is insecure, it’s knowing that it’s still there.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because resources such as printers are not externally exposed, it is tempting to assume they are beyond the reach of attackers. Despite this, NTLMv1 can still be targeted from outside the network using relay or coercion techniques, by, for example, triggering authentication via a phishing attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attackers don’t need to know you’re using it. They just have to poke the system to find out. Fundamentally, organizations keep legacy protocols active not because they want to, but because they fear breaking a mission-critical legacy app,” said Finn.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite Microsoft recommending that organizations upgrade to NTLMv2 and Kerberos for more than two decades, it appears not everyone got the memo. “In crypto terms, NTLMv1 isn’t just old, it’s archaeological,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rob-a-03b0b4201/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Rob Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, head of reactive consulting services at Reliance Cyber. “NTLMv1 is still enabled, not because it is needed today, but because it was needed once, and nobody is quite brave enough to turn it off and see what breaks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite those fears, organizations need to take action. “Scan for its use, find out why it is in use, register it as a high risk and get to work removing it, with achievable deadlines,” he advised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118800/mandiant-pushes-organizations-to-dump-insecure-ntlmv1-by-releasing-a-way-to-crack-it.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.83</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Intune update isn’t optional — it’s a kill switch for outdated apps</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118902/this-intune-update-isnt-optional-its-a-kill-switch-for-outdated-apps-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises using Intune mobile application management (MAM) beware: Your apps won’t run soon if you haven’t planned ahead.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is updating its Intune MAM to support new security requirements &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/intune/intune-service/fundamentals/in-development#update-to-the-latest-intune-company-portal-for-android-intune-app-sdk-for-ios-and-intune-app-wrapper-for-ios" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starting January 19 or “soon after”&lt;/a&gt;, requiring that all iOS-wrapped apps, iOS SDK-integrated apps, and the Intune Company Portal for Android be updated to the latest Intune versions to keep them secure and running.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This means that enterprises that haven’t updated to the latest versions will be blocked from launching their apps altogether. And, this may not just include custom apps wrapped in Intune MAM, but other frequently-used ones such as Outlook and Teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Simply put, “If you want your stuff to work, get it updated and pushed,” said &lt;a href="https://www.beauceronsecurity.com/blog/tag/David+Shipley" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt; of Beauceron Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="whats-being-updated-in-ios-android"&gt;What’s being updated in iOS, Android&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Intune is a core component of the Microsoft Modern Workplace. Its &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/1700964/microsoft-intune-explained-unified-endpoint-management.html" target="_blank"&gt;MAM features&lt;/a&gt; help enterprises secure their data on both corporate and personal devices. Using it, IT teams can manage corporate apps like Outlook or Teams without having to manage the entire device. This type of unified endpoint management (UEM) supports feature deployments, updates, and retirement of apps, while also protecting corporate data and preventing data leaks, with (ideally) minimal disruption for the user.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With Monday’s hard deadline, Microsoft will enforce &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/intune/intune-service/apps/app-protection-policy" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;stricter security requirements&lt;/a&gt; within the UEM — but only for approved users. Those without the latest app protection supported Microsoft or third-party apps will “be blocked from launching their apps,” the company warned. Microsoft announced the required updates several months ago in the Microsoft 365 Admin Center.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Apple users, Monday’s full stop means:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iOS line-of-business (LOB) and custom iOS apps using the Intune App SDK must update to SDK version 20.8.0 or later for apps compiled with Xcode 16, and to 21.1.0 or later for apps compiled with Xcode 26.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Apps using the wrapper must update to the new version of the Intune App Wrapping Tool for iOS: version 20.8.1 or later for apps built with XCode 16; and version 21.1.0 or later for apps built with XCode 26.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s a little simpler for Android users: Once one Microsoft app with an updated SDK is on the device and the company portal is updated to version 5.0.6726.0 or later, other Android apps will update.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tenants with policies targeted to both iOS and Android apps should notify their users that they need to update, and ensure Microsoft apps such as Teams and Outlook are up-to-date, Microsoft advised. Admins can also enable conditional launch settings to block apps using older versions of the SDK or to warn users if they are using older versions of apps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Admins can also proactively ensure that users are not blocked while doing work on their phones. In the Microsoft Intune admin center, they can navigate to &lt;em&gt;Apps &amp;gt; Monitor &amp;gt; App protection status&lt;/em&gt; to review the app and SDK versions users are running.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We recommend to always update your Android and iOS apps to the latest SDK or app wrapper to ensure that your app continues to run smoothly,” Microsoft emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Overall, the company advised enterprises to use &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/entra/identity/conditional-access/policy-all-users-approved-app-or-app-protection#require-approved-client-apps-or-app-protection-policy-with-mobile-devices" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;conditional access policies&lt;/a&gt; so that only apps with app protection policies enabled can access corporate resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="supporting-new-security-tools-and-why-enterprises-should-have-updated-yesterday"&gt;Supporting new security tools (and why enterprises should have updated yesterday)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With its new security updates, Microsoft has wrapped controls around existing custom apps that businesses have built, Beauceron’s Shipley explained. These enable features such as requiring a PIN or biometric authentication inside the app, restricting data sharing with other managed apps, and selectively wiping corporate data from apps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This [update] may be because there’s some risk with the older versions not doing what they should’ve been doing for protections,” Shipley noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He pointed out that Microsoft has been signaling this update since 2025 and already pushed back implementation from mid-December 2025 to this week. Also, it’s interesting to note that this change may not just impact custom apps wrapped in Intune MAM, but Outlook, Teams, and others applications as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The long and short of it is, what Redmond wants is what Redmond gets when it finally puts a foot down, like it appears to have in this case,” said Shipley.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This deadline shouldn’t come as a surprise to IT teams who stayed on top of things, noted &lt;a href="https://www.infotech.com/profiles/fritz-jean-louis" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fritz Jean-Louis&lt;/a&gt;, principal cybersecurity advisor at Info-Tech Research Group. Microsoft has been deprecating various parts of Intune, and how it connects from an infrastructure perspective, for some time now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Like many other things, if you’re not actively managing [with] the right amount of due diligence, you will be impacted by this,” said Jean-Louis, noting that employees dealing with work tasks on their phones (either remotely or on-premises) will experience outages without the updates. “It’s going to seriously impact users if this has not been adequately addressed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From an IT perspective, if they’re not ready for the new versioning, admins should contact Microsoft as soon as possible and determine whether mitigations can be put in place until their team is ready.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If users experience issues, they should contact their official IT service desk, Jean-Louis advised. They should not attempt to self-resolve by, say, going to a random site and blindly entering a user ID and password to receive updates. Threat actors may be lying in wait, using this type of opportunity to deploy malware “fixes.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Threat actors are always looking for this sort of major change to take advantage,” he noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4118887/this-intune-update-isnt-optional-its-a-kill-switch-for-outdated-apps.html" target="_blank"&gt;Computerworld&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118902/this-intune-update-isnt-optional-its-a-kill-switch-for-outdated-apps-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU vulnerability database goes live</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118848/new-eu-vulnerability-database-launched.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A free, publicly accessible database for IT security vulnerabilities, the &lt;a href="https://db.gcve.eu/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;db.gcve.eu&lt;/a&gt;, has been created by GCVE (Global Cybersecurity Vulnerability Enumeration). The aim is to end dependence on US databases and strengthen digital sovereignty in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The initiative came together after a brief scare over the possible discontinuation of the Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) program in 2025. The risk got many concerned f&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4008708/beyond-cve-the-hunt-for-other-sources-of-vulnerability-intel.html" target="_blank"&gt;orcing the cybersecurity industry to start thinking of alternatives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="gcve-database-aims-to-facilitate-vulnerability-reporting"&gt;GCVE database aims to facilitate vulnerability reporting&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The platform brings together information from various public resources. These include the sources of the GCVE Numbering Authority (GNA) model. It replaces the traditional, centralized assignment of vulnerability identifiers (CVE IDs). Data from other recognized vulnerability directories is also used.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The decentralized approach makes it possible to assign and publish vulnerability identifiers autonomously without having to wait for central approval. A total of more than 25 different data sources are currently integrated. The vulnerability data collected is normalized, structured, and made searchable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, the open API offers seamless integration into existing compliance tools and risk management systems. This should enable security officers, scientists, computer security incident response teams, software providers, and open-source developers to track and evaluate security reports more efficiently across ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118848/new-eu-vulnerability-database-launched.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the future of security starts with who, not where</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118753/why-the-future-of-security-starts-with-who-not-where.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For a long time, cybersecurity was pretty straightforward: Guard the edges, and everything inside should be fine. Firewalls, DMZs, VPNs — these were the go-to tools. Back then, it worked. Apps lived in data centers, and everyone showed up at the office. But that world disappeared before most companies even noticed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Remote work, cloud adoption and distributed applications slowly dissolved the network edge. And attackers took advantage of that gap long before defenders adapted. Verizon’s annual &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir/"&gt;Data Breach Investigations Report&lt;/a&gt; repeatedly shows that a large portion — often over 80% — of modern breaches involve compromised credentials, not network flaws.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That number says a lot. It tells us the perimeter didn’t just shift — it collapsed around identity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The old perimeter: Strong walls, weak assumptions&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Traditional security assumed one thing: “If someone is inside the network, they can be trusted.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That assumption worked when offices were closed environments and systems lived behind a single controlled gateway. But as Microsoft highlights in its &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/security-insider/threat-landscape/microsoft-digital-defense-report-2024"&gt;Digital Defense Report&lt;/a&gt;, attackers have moved almost entirely toward identity-based attacks because stealing credentials offers far more access than exploiting firewalls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In other words, attackers stopped trying to break in. They simply started logging in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cloud + remote work = No perimeter&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now, with remote work and the cloud, there’s no real perimeter left. People connect from home Wi-Fi, personal laptops, airports, coffee shops — you name it. At the same time, company data and workloads are scattered across AWS, Azure, Google Cloud and various SaaS platforms. The old rules just don’t fit anymore.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is no single “inside” anymore. There is only identity — the user behind the request.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why modern security frameworks, including NIST’s &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/207/final"&gt;Zero Trust Architecture guidelines (SP 800-207)&lt;/a&gt;, emphasise identity as the primary control point rather than the network.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Identity is now the primary attack surface&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity brings convenience, but it also brings complexity — and complexity attracts attackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People reuse passwords.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;MFA fatigue attacks work far too often.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Privileged accounts get over-granted. Contractors keep access long after their projects end.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Service accounts multiply with no owner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Okta’s recent &lt;a href="https://www.okta.com/the-state-of-secure-identity-report/"&gt;State of Identity Security report&lt;/a&gt; points out that identity misuse has become one of the fastest-growing attack vectors in enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity is no longer just a log-in step. It’s now the attacker’s first target.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Zero trust made identity the first door to lock&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zero trust isn’t about paranoia. It’s about verification. Never trust, always verify only works if identity sits at the center of every access decision.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s why CISA’s &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/zero-trust-maturity-model"&gt;zero trust maturity model&lt;/a&gt; outlines identity as the foundation on which all other zero trust pillars rest — including network segmentation, data security, device posture and automation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A strong identity-based perimeter includes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MFA everywhere&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;SSO to reduce password fatigue&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Role-based access controls&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Privileged Access Management&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Device trust tied to user identity&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Continuous monitoring of user behaviour&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Adaptive, risk-based access policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the future — this is what’s expected today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Identity done right requires real discipline&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When identity becomes the perimeter, it can’t be an afterthought. It needs to be treated like core infrastructure. That means:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity has to be engineered, not patched together.&lt;/strong&gt; Lifecycle processes must be streamlined — joiners, movers and leavers must be tightly controlled.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privilege needs to be what people earn, not what they start with.&lt;/strong&gt; Excess-access is still one of the top contributors to breaches.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication methods need to evolve yearly.&lt;/strong&gt; Static MFA policies won’t survive dynamic threats.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring must follow behavior, not networks.&lt;/strong&gt; Suspicious activity often hides in user patterns, not traffic flows.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity ownership must be shared across security, IT and the business.&lt;/strong&gt; Identity doesn’t succeed unless everyone is accountable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner has been emphasising this shift for years, calling identity “the new security perimeter” in multiple research publications aimed at CISOs and enterprise architects&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Where we’re heading next&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity is already at the centre of modern cybersecurity, but its role is only going to grow stronger. Over the next few years:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passwords will fade out in favour of passkeys and biometrics.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Machine identities will become as critical as human identities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Access decisions will adapt in real time based on behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Identity platforms will become the central nervous system of enterprise security.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Zero Trust will mature from architecture diagrams into everyday practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations that invest in strong identity foundations won’t just improve security — they’ll improve operations, compliance, resilience and trust. Because when identity is solid, everything else becomes clearer: who can access what, who is responsible for what and where risk actually lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The companies that struggle will be the ones trying to secure a world that no longer exists — a perimeter that disappeared years ago.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Identity isn’t just the new perimeter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s the new beginning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Everything starts here now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118753/why-the-future-of-security-starts-with-who-not-where.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrashFix attack hijacks browser failures to deliver ModelRAT malware via fake Chrome extension</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119047/crashfix-attack-hijacks-browser-failures-to-deliver-modelrat-malware-via-fake-chrome-extension.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security researchers have uncovered a malicious browser extension campaign, dubbed CrashFix, that deliberately crashes victims’ browsers and then uses the resulting confusion to trick users into running attacker-supplied commands.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The activity, attributed to a threat cluster Huntress calls KongTuke, involves a fake Chrome &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118607/five-chrome-extensions-caught-hijacking-enterprise-sessions.html" target="_blank"&gt;extension&lt;/a&gt; posing as an ad-blocking tool but ultimately delivering a novel malware payload.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The extension, which Huntress identified as NexShield-Advanced Web Protection, was distributed through look-alike branding and deceptive metadata designed to resemble a legitimate browser security tool, uBlock Origin Lite ad blocker. After installation, it remains inactive for a period of time, likely to evade immediate suspicion, before intentionally destabilizing the browser by exhausting system resources and triggering repeated crashes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once the browser becomes unusable, victims are presented with a fake “repair” prompt instructing them to paste and execute a command to resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;From fake protection to forced failure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Huntress’ analysis, the malicious extension does not immediately perform malicious actions. Instead, it waits approximately an hour after installation before initiating the crash routine. The extension repeatedly opens connections and consumes memory until the browser becomes unresponsive, forcing users to restart or troubleshoot what appears to be a legitimate failure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The extension sets up to two timers: the first triggers once after a 60-minute delay, and the second fires every 10 minutes after the initial trigger,” Huntress researchers said in a blog &lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/blog/malicious-browser-extention-crashfix-kongtuke" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;. “This timing strategy is in place so that when a user installs the extension, nothing malicious happens immediately. Sixty minutes later, the malicious payload activates, and every 10 minutes thereafter, the payload continues to execute.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On relaunch, the victim receives an alert claiming the browser encountered a critical error and requires manual remediation. Victims are instructed to open the Windows Run dialog and paste a command already copied to the clipboard. This command launches the next stage of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress emphasized that this technique mirrors a growing trend in “&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3610611/rising-clickfix-malware-distribution-trick-puts-powershell-it-policies-on-notice.html"&gt;ClickFix&lt;/a&gt;”-style attacks, where users are socially engineered into executing malicious code themselves under the guise of system recovery or security remediation. ClickFix techniques have been observed across multiple DPRK-linked campaigns, including variants associated with the long-running&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4098699/contagious-interview-attackers-go-full-stack-to-fool-developers.html"&gt; Contagious Interview&lt;/a&gt; operation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Payload delivery&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When the user executes the supplied commands, a multistage infection process begins that ultimately deploys a previously undocumented Python-based remote access trojan, which the researchers dubbed ModelRAT. The malware establishes persistence and enables remote control of the infected system.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Huntress’ telemetry suggested differing behavior based on the environment. Systems joined to a domain were more likely to receive the full payload chain, while non-domain systems sometimes received lighter or incomplete stages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers also drew parallels between the CrashFix execution flow and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574617/5-top-threats-from-2022-most-likely-to-strike-in-2023.html#:~:text=Drive%2Dby%20downloads%20alive%20and%20well%20with%20SocGholish"&gt;SocGholish&lt;/a&gt; (FakeUpdates) campaigns, noting the shared reliance on user-driven execution rather than technical exploitation. As with SocGholish activity, the attacker’s success depends on convincing the victim to manually run a command under the guise of remediation or system recovery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recommendations included removing untrusted or look-alike browser extensions and reinforcing guidance against manually executing “fix” commands prompted by browser errors. The researchers also shared indicators of compromise (IOCs) tied to the malicious extension, command execution, and follow-on activity to aid detection and response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119047/crashfix-attack-hijacks-browser-failures-to-deliver-modelrat-malware-via-fake-chrome-extension.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.28</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Airlock Digital Announces Independent TEI Study Quantifying Measurable ROI &amp; Security Impact</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119592/airlock-digital-announces-independent-tei-study-quantifying-measurable-roi-security-impact.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.airlockdigital.com/forrester-tei-report?utm_campaign=download-2025dec1-forresterteireport&amp;amp;utm_medium=third-party&amp;amp;utm_source=ap" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airlock Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a leader in proactive application control and endpoint security, announced the release of &lt;a href="https://www.airlockdigital.com/forrester-tei-report?utm_campaign=download-2025dec1-forresterteireport&amp;amp;utm_medium=third-party&amp;amp;utm_source=ap" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Total Economic Impact (TEI) of Airlock Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an independent study commissioned by Airlock Digital and conducted by &lt;strong&gt;Forrester Consulting&lt;/strong&gt;. The study demonstrates a significant &lt;strong&gt;224% return on investment (ROI)&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;$3.8 million net present value (NPV)&lt;/strong&gt; over three years for organizations adopting Airlock Digital’s allowlisting approach. These findings underline both the financial and security value of Airlock Digital’s solution.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Airlock-Digital-Bann-Cr.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 499w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Airlock-Digital-Bann-Cr.jpg?resize=300%2C108&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Airlock-Digital-Bann-Cr.jpg?resize=150%2C54&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Airlock-Digital-Bann-Cr.jpg?resize=444%2C159&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="499" height="179" sizes="auto, (max-width: 499px) 100vw, 499px"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Cyber NewsWire&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Forrester’s TEI methodology evaluates the potential financial impact of technology investments by aggregating insights from customer interviews and modeling a composite organization representative of global organizations. According to the study, Airlock Digital enabled:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;224% ROI&lt;/strong&gt; over three years&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$3.8M net present value&lt;/strong&gt; based on quantified benefits versus costs&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;25% reduction in overall risk of security breaches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero breaches reported&lt;/strong&gt; by interviewed organizations after deploying Airlock Digital&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant operational efficiencies&lt;/strong&gt; with reduced administrative overhead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Cottingham, Co-founder and CEO at Airlock Digital, said: &lt;/strong&gt;“For modern enterprises, trust cannot be assumed… it must be enforced. Allowlisting and application control give organizations the power to run only what they trust, blocking all malware and ransomware before they can execute. For us, the Forrester Consulting TEI study reinforces the importance of our mission at Airlock Digital, which is to deliver proactive endpoint security that makes application control not just possible, but effortless. It’s why we have become synonymous with this critical layer of cyber defense—and why every organization needs it at the core of their security strategy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As cyberattacks continue to grow in scale and sophistication, more organizations are turning to application control and allowlisting as foundational components of a proactive security strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; Traditional reactive security tools attempt to detect and block threats after execution attempts are made—often too late to prevent compromise. Allowlisting reverses this paradigm, enforcing a Deny by Default posture that ensures only trusted and approved software is permitted to run. This approach dramatically reduces the attack surface, curbs the spread of malware and ransomware, and helps organizations meet increasingly stringent regulatory and compliance requirements. Airlock Digital’s modern, operationally friendly implementation of allowlisting enables security teams to adopt this strategy without the administrative complexity historically associated with legacy tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The study highlights that Airlock Digital helps organizations strengthen their security posture, lower ongoing maintenance costs, and improve software inventory management while keeping operational and administrative burden low. The study noted that a single security analyst can effectively manage Airlock Digital policies in much less time than traditional solutions require, contributing to cost savings and improved productivity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Dillon, CRO at Airlock Digital said: &lt;/strong&gt;“The Forrester Consulting TEI study gives security leaders, in our opinion, clear, independent validation of the impact delivered by Airlock Digital. Forrester Consulting calculated the benefits to include a 224% ROI and fast payback — and most importantly — participating organizations reported zero breaches after implementation. Airlock Digital combines simplicity with enterprise-grade scale, enforcing a Deny by Default posture that blocks untrusted code, including malware and ransomware. For organizations ready to move from reactive defenses to proactive prevention, Airlock Digital provides a quantified and operationally efficient path forward — requiring, according to the Forrester Consulting study, only 2.5 hours per week to manage. We’d be glad to walk you through the findings.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Airlock Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.airlockdigital.com/forrester-tei-report?utm_campaign=download-2025dec1-forresterteireport&amp;amp;utm_medium=third-party&amp;amp;utm_source=ap" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Airlock Digital&lt;/a&gt; delivers market-leading allowlisting and application control solutions that empower enterprises to enforce a Deny by Default security posture. Trusted globally across industries, Airlock Digital enables organizations to prevent unauthorized code execution, simplify compliance, and strengthen cyber-resilience without sacrificing performance or user productivity. This approach minimizes attack surfaces and helps organizations align their cybersecurity strategies with government frameworks and standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users can download the full Forrester TEI study: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.airlockdigital.com/forrester-tei-report?utm_campaign=download-2025dec1-forresterteireport&amp;amp;utm_medium=third-party&amp;amp;utm_source=ap" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.airlockdigital.com/forrester-tei-report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP of Marketing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erin Welke&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airlock Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;erin.welke@airlockdigital.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119592/airlock-digital-announces-independent-tei-study-quantifying-measurable-roi-security-impact.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third Party Risk Management: So vermeiden Sie Compliance-Unheil</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495375/third-party-risk-management-so-vermeiden-sie-compliance-unheil.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Third Party Risk Management hilft Unternehmen, das Risiko von Compliance-Verstößen zu vermeiden." src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3386821/1200x.jpg" title="Third Party Risk Management hilft Unternehmen, das Risiko von Compliance-Verstößen zu vermeiden." width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Third Party Risk Management hilft Unternehmen, das Risiko von Compliance-Verstößen zu vermeiden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Diyajyoti – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Zeiten der Digitalisierung ist es für Unternehmen unerlässlich, auf die Unterstützung von Drittanbietern zurückzugreifen. Sei es im Bereich der IT-Infrastruktur oder bei der Datenverarbeitung – externe Dienstleister helfen dabei, Geschäftsprozesse effektiver und effizienter zu gestalten. Doch mit der Zusammenarbeit mit Dritten geht auch ein Risiko einher. Unternehmen sollten deshalb ein Third Party Risk Management (TPRM) etablieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="was-ist-third-party-risk-management"&gt;Was ist Third Party Risk Management?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;TPRM ist ein strategischer Ansatz, der darauf abzielt, das Risiko der Zusammenarbeit mit Drittanbietern zu identifizieren, zu bewerten und zu steuern. Er hilft Unternehmen, die Risiken im Zusammenhang mit ihren Drittanbietern besser zu verstehen und zu managen, um Compliance-Verstöße zu vermeiden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Warum ist TPRM wichtig? “Unternehmen müssen beispielsweise überprüfen, ob ihre Drittanbieter den SOC2-Prüfungsstandard einhalten. Dieser soll sicherstellen, dass Drittanbieter sensible Kundendaten vor unbefugtem Zugriff schützen”, erklärt GreenPages-Manager Pasteris und ergänzt: “Auch Datenschutzgesetze wie die DSGVO sind in dieser Hinsicht relevant. Wenn Sie selbst compliant sind, nutzt Ihnen das überhaupt nichts, wenn Ihr Drittanbieter sich an nichts hält.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesetipp:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492170/third-party-risk-management-5-wege-mit-drittanbietern-unterzugehen.html" target="_blank" title="5 Wege, mit Drittanbietern unterzugehen"&gt;5 Wege, mit Drittanbietern unterzugehen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="kernkomponenten-einer-effektiven-tprm-strategie"&gt;Kernkomponenten einer effektiven TPRM-Strategie&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Thrid Party Risk Managment sollte Folgendes enthalten:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risikoidentifikation und -bewertung: &lt;/strong&gt;Der erste Schritt im TPRM-Prozess ist die Identifikation und &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492180/cyber-risk-assessments-risikobewertung-hilft-cisos.html" target="_blank" title="Bewertung der Risiken"&gt;Bewertung der Risiken&lt;/a&gt;, die mit der Zusammenarbeit mit Drittanbietern verbunden sind. Dies umfasst die Analyse der Sicherheitsmaßnahmen, Datenschutzpraktiken und Compliance-Standards der Drittanbieter. Unternehmen sollten eine detaillierte Due Diligence durchführen, um potenzielle Schwachstellen und Risiken zu identifizieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vertragsmanagement: &lt;/strong&gt;Ein weiterer wichtiger Aspekt des TPRM ist die Implementierung von Vertragsklauseln, die die Verantwortlichkeiten der Drittanbieter hinsichtlich Compliance-Verstößen definieren. Es ist wichtig, dass Unternehmen klare Erwartungen an ihre Drittanbieter haben und dass diese Erwartungen in schriftlicher Form niedergelegt werden. Dies hilft Unternehmen, sich vor rechtlichen Konsequenzen im Falle von Compliance-Verstößen durch Drittanbieter zu schützen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Überwachung und Audits: &lt;/strong&gt;Eine effektive TPRM-Strategie umfasst auch die kontinuierliche Überwachung von Drittanbietern, um sicherzustellen, dass sie weiterhin den Anforderungen entsprechen. Diese kann durch regelmäßige Audits und Prüfungen erfolgen. Unternehmen sollten sicherstellen, dass sie über die notwendigen Ressourcen und Tools verfügen, um die Einhaltung der Compliance-Standards durch ihre Drittanbieter zu überprüfen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schulung und Sensibilisierung: &lt;/strong&gt;Die Schulung und Sensibilisierung der Mitarbeiter über die Risiken und Anforderungen des TPRM ist ebenfalls entscheidend. Mitarbeiter sollten verstehen, warum TPRM wichtig ist und wie sie dazu beitragen können, die Risiken zu minimieren. Regelmäßige Schulungen und Workshops können dazu beitragen, das Bewusstsein für TPRM zu stärken und sicherzustellen, dass alle Mitarbeiter die Compliance-Standards einhalten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="best-practices-fr-ein-erfolgreiches-tprm"&gt;Best Practices für ein erfolgreiches TPRM&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese vier Tipps helfen bei der TPRM-Umsetzung: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Etablierung klarer Richtlinien und Verfahren: &lt;/strong&gt;Unternehmen sollten klare Richtlinien und Verfahren für das TPRM entwickeln und implementieren. Diese sollten alle Aspekte des TPRM abdecken, einschließlich der Auswahl von Drittanbietern, der Vertragsgestaltung, der Überwachung und der Berichterstattung.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutzung von Technologie:&lt;/strong&gt; Der Einsatz von Technologie kann das TPRM erheblich erleichtern. Es gibt zahlreiche Tools und Plattformen, die Unternehmen dabei unterstützen, die Risiken zu identifizieren, zu bewerten und zu überwachen. Diese Tools können auch bei der Automatisierung von Audits und Berichterstattungen helfen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration des TPRM in das Enterprise Risk Management (ERM): &lt;/strong&gt;Das TPRM sollte nicht isoliert betrachtet werden, sondern in das umfassende Risikomanagement des Unternehmens integriert werden. Dies stellt sicher, dass alle Risiken, einschließlich derjenigen, die von Drittanbietern ausgehen, ganzheitlich betrachtet und gemanagt werden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regelmäßige Überprüfung und Aktualisierung:&lt;/strong&gt; Die TPRM-Strategie sollte regelmäßig überprüft und bei Bedarf aktualisiert werden, um sicherzustellen, dass sie den aktuellen Bedrohungen und Compliance-Anforderungen entspricht. Unternehmen sollten proaktive Maßnahmen ergreifen, um ihre TPRM-Strategie kontinuierlich zu verbessern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sichere-geschftsprozesse-mit-tprm"&gt;Sichere Geschäftsprozesse mit TPRM &lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Third Party Risk Management ist ein wesentlicher Bestandteil der Compliance-Strategie jedes Unternehmens, das mit Drittanbietern zusammenarbeitet. Durch die Implementierung einer effektiven TPRM-Strategie können Unternehmen das Risiko von Compliance-Verstößen durch Drittanbieter minimieren und sich vor rechtlichen Konsequenzen schützen. Die Identifikation und Bewertung von Risiken, das Vertragsmanagement, die kontinuierliche Überwachung und die Schulung der Mitarbeiter sind entscheidende Komponenten eines erfolgreichen TPRM. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank" title="Sie möchten regelmäßig über wichtige Themen rund um Cybersicherheit informiert werden? Unser kostenloser Newsletter liefert Ihnen alles, was Sie wissen müssen."&gt;Sie möchten regelmäßig über wichtige Themen rund um Cybersicherheit informiert werden? Unser kostenloser Newsletter liefert Ihnen alles, was Sie wissen müssen.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495375/third-party-risk-management-so-vermeiden-sie-compliance-unheil.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.89</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For cyber risk assessments, frequency is essential</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117003/cyber-risk-assessments-risk-assessment-helps-cisos.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From a certain age, many people regularly visit their doctor for check-ups. In this way, risks and dangers can be identified early and appropriate measures taken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The same applies to cybersecurity: Regular risk assessments help security teams identify vulnerabilities and areas for improvement. Unfortunately, such assessments are not carried out universally.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="advantages-of-a-cyber-risk-assessment"&gt;Advantages of a cyber risk assessment&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs benefit from the following advantages when they integrate cybersecurity risk assessments into their work:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identifying vulnerabilities:&lt;/strong&gt; A cyber risk assessment helps to identify security gaps in a company’s IT infrastructure, networks, and systems. This provides the opportunity to eliminate these vulnerabilities before they can be exploited by cybercriminals.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize risk management measures:&lt;/strong&gt; Not every system is critical, and not all of a company’s data is equally important. The results of the risk assessment clarify which assets and systems are most critical and at the highest risk of attack. Based on this, security managers can prioritize their measures and thus allocate their resources more effectively to address the most critical risks first.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meeting compliance requirements:&lt;/strong&gt; Almost every company must comply with various data protection and data security regulations, such as the GDPR or the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS). Many of these legal requirements explicitly demand specific risk assessments, such as a data protection impact assessment under the GDPR. Risk assessments help to meet the compliance requirements of various regulations. This ensures that the necessary security standards are met and that potential fines or legal consequences for violations are avoided.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make smart decisions and reduce costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Cyber ​​risk assessments give companies a comprehensive understanding of their cyber risks. This allows them to make informed decisions about risk mitigation strategies, thereby reducing the likelihood of a successful and costly cyberattack. Furthermore, it enables them to make targeted and therefore more effective investments in their cybersecurity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-look-at-data-risk"&gt;A look at data risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The target of most cyberattacks is a company’s data — with enormously costly consequences: According to IBM’s &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/de-de/reports/data-breach"&gt;Cost of a Data Breach Report 2025&lt;/a&gt;, a data breach caused an average of $4.44 million in damages. Therefore, it is crucial to take a close look at data and the risks it faces.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is all the more important because, unlike infrastructure and other systems, data is not “uncompromising.” Servers can be reconfigured, cloud instances rebuilt. But once stolen, data remains in the hands of cybercriminals. Backups offer no protection against this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An analysis of nearly 10 billion cloud objects, conducted as part of data risk assessments at more than 700 companies across various industries worldwide, reveals the risks that data is generally exposed to. According to the analysis, one in 10 data sets in the cloud is accessible to all employees. This creates an internal radius that significantly increases the potential damage from a ransomware attack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, a lack of multifactor authentication (MFA) also makes it easier for attackers to compromise internally exposed data: &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/de-de/partner-center/security/security-at-your-organization"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; has found that more than 99% of compromised accounts do not have MFA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These general findings already highlight the biggest problem areas. Nevertheless, it is important to determine the individual data risk and identify weaknesses within the framework of a data risk assessment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies typically don’t know what data they possess, where it’s stored, or who has access to it. Only with this fundamental information can they identify their risks and take targeted measures. The time investment is manageable, at around two to four hours, and a comprehensive report provides immediately actionable recommendations. Furthermore, the assessment process often uncovers additional security issues, ranging from ongoing cyberattacks to Kerberos passwords that are up to 15 years old.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regularly conducted cyber risk assessments allow for clear and verifiable documentation of progress in data security — also for management. CISOs finally have a tool at their disposal that makes their cybersecurity successes visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117003/cyber-risk-assessments-risk-assessment-helps-cisos.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-033)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-033</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-033</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-034)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-034</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-034</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-035)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-035</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-035</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–036)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-036</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-036</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-037)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-037</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-037</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-038)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-038</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-038</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-039)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-039</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-039</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-040)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-040</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-040</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV26-041)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-041</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-041</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Spot at RSAC 2026 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 17561518.87</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
