<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:31:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-681)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-681</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-681</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–682)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-682</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-682</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.45</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-683)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-683</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-683</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-485) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-485</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-485</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-684)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-684</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-684</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectWise security advisory (AV25-685)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-685</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/connectwise-security-advisory-av25-685</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory (AV25-640) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-av25-640</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data sovereignty proof: How to verify controls like ‘Project Texas’</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078816/data-sovereignty-proof-how-to-verify-controls-like-project-texas.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As data sovereignty laws fracture the global internet, CSOs are scrutinizing ambitious new compliance blueprints, with their success or failure set to redefine security architectures for a generation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/house-tiktok-bill-bytedance-chinese-communist-party-social-media-26d648cd"&gt;Project Texas&lt;/a&gt;” may just be the most visible attempt to realign a &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37359767/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;global platform’s data, access and governance with U.S. jurisdiction&lt;/a&gt; and oversight. In practice, it is an in-country operating model: sensitive U.S. user data is localized, access is brokered under U.S. law and an external operator provides independent infrastructure and controls. The name nods to Texas and the U.S. infrastructure anchor; the stakes are global.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I have sat in rooms where a press release swore data was safe behind a new “sovereign” wall, then an auditor asked a simpler question: “Can you show me, right now, where the data is, who touched it and under what authority?” In that moment, architecture becomes language and evidence becomes reputation. This isn’t about slogans. It is about designing systems that leave fingerprints: every access mediated, every key anchored, every event written in ink that cannot be erased.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Headlines tout data sovereignty pledges like Project Texas, but security leaders win by turning them into auditable evidence. A Kearney study found that &lt;a href="https://www.kearney.com/service/digital-analytics/article/demystifying-data-sovereignty" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;78% of executives say they struggle to interpret sovereignty rules&lt;/a&gt; consistently across markets. The mandate is shifting from making promises to providing proof — verifiable controls for zero-trust access, in-region keys, immutable logs and continuous validation that regulators and customers can trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Verification regimes work best when they serve everyone’s interests.&lt;/strong&gt; The reporting company wants a process that does not impose too many burdens or interrupt workflow while allowing it to demonstrate compliance. Oversight bodies want hard data that is difficult to fake and indicates adherence to the regime. Finally, these systems need to be simple enough to be sustained over time.” — &lt;strong&gt;J. Michael Daniel&lt;/strong&gt;, President &amp;amp; CEO, Cyber Threat Alliance and former Special Assistant to President Obama and Cybersecurity Coordinator on the National Security Council Staff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-gap-between-policy-and-proof"&gt;The gap between policy and proof&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Big platforms pledge regional data segregation. That’s good for comms. But in the SOC and audit room, what matters is demonstrable proof. A 2025 Nutanix report found that &lt;a href="https://www.nutanix.com/theforecastbynutanix/business/data-sovereignty-drives-enterprise-it-decisions" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;over 80% of IT leaders cite data sovereignty as a primary driver for new cloud architecture decisions&lt;/a&gt; — exactly what Project Texas embodies. Can you show that sensitive data stayed in-region, was accessed for a valid purpose, with the right keys?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Closing this gap requires five concrete, testable data sovereignty controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-put-a-broker-in-the-blast-radius-zero-trust-data-gating"&gt;1. Put a broker in the blast radius (zero-trust data gating)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For verifiable control, implement zero-trust data gating by brokering all sensitive data access through a policy decision point (PDP), an identity-aware proxy/API gateway using ABAC (who, what, where, why). This gateway strictly enforces attribute-based rules, banning all direct access to contain the blast radius of any potential breach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Build this control using your cloud provider’s core services:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;pre class="wp-block-code"&gt;&lt;code&gt;OCI API Gateway + OCI IAM + Logging/Audit (or equivalents such as AWS API Gateway/ALB + IAM + CloudTrail/CloudWatch, Azure API Management + Entra ID + Monitor/Activity Log, GCP API Gateway/Apigee + Cloud IAM + Cloud Audit Logs)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Treat 100% PDP coverage for sensitive flows as the benchmark. This proves you have eliminated backdoors, collapsing insider risk and lateral movement by ensuring no compromised account can move freely. Ultimately, it provides the board with a single, auditable source of truth for all data access.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Sovereignty isn’t just a region on a map — it’s an operating model.&lt;/strong&gt; The hard part isn’t promises, it’s proving every week that keys stay in-country, access is brokered and there are no side paths.” — &lt;strong&gt;Ian Rogers&lt;/strong&gt;, Co-Founder and Data Sovereignty Expert, TEAM Cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image: Project Texas Vanilla" class="wp-image-4078818" height="1024" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/project-texas-vanilla.png?w=791" width="791" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Michelle Buckner&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-cryptographically-enforce-location-in-region-keys"&gt;2. Cryptographically enforce location (in-region keys)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enforce location by anchoring encryption to in-region keys, making jurisdiction a property of the cryptographic root. This means generating and storing all cryptographic keys within hardware security modules (HSMs) located inside the required jurisdiction, under dual control and geo-fencing every key operation, instead of soft keys in app code, global KMS with single-admin control or cross-border decrypt/unwrap by default.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The critical signal of success is achieving “keys in-region = 100%,” backed by attested logs from the HSM. This provides a mathematical backstop, ensuring that events like undersea cable cuts, foreign cloud breaches or extraterritorial legal demands become non-events for your protected data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-guarantee-immutable-audit-trails"&gt;3. Guarantee immutable audit trails&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By establishing immutable audit trails, you practically guarantee the integrity of your evidence. This is achieved by streaming all critical logs — from your access gateways, key management systems and data platforms — into append-only, write-once-read-many (WORM) storage that cannot be altered.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The essential metric is achieving lineage coverage greater than 95%, ensuring this timeline is queryable in minutes, not days. This creates an incontrovertible record, giving you the definitive ability to answer any auditor’s question about who accessed what data, from where and under what authority, in near real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-continuously-validate-for-control-drift"&gt;4. Continuously validate for control drift&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Prevent control drift with continuous validation. Proactively test sovereignty safeguards with scheduled red team exercises that simulate cross-border exfiltration and run automated canaries that alert on any policy breach; for example, a decryption attempt from a blocked region. Embed policy-as-code in the CI/CD pipeline so any change that creates an unbrokered data path fails before it ships. Track a simple health metric: canary violations at zero over a rolling 30 days. Most sovereignty programs do not fail on design; they fail when operational rigor erodes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-enable-third-party-attestation"&gt;5. Enable third-party attestation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The final pillar, third-party attestation, transforms internal proofs into externally verifiable evidence. This involves providing regulators and customers with independent assurance without exposing intellectual property. It is achieved through machine-readable policy feeds, read-only portals for log and lineage data and cryptographic proofs from your in-region HSMs. The ultimate validation comes from allowing auditors to witness live red/blue team drills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This approach fundamentally flips the model from a trust-us narrative to a repeatable, technical verification that anyone can test for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-90-day-data-sovereignty-blueprint"&gt;The 90-day data sovereignty blueprint&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 0:&lt;/strong&gt; Inventory sensitive data, enable WORM logging, choose a PDP pattern&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 30:&lt;/strong&gt; Front sensitive stores with the PDP, localize keys, publish initial PDP coverage and keys in-region metrics&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 60:&lt;/strong&gt; Wire policy-as-code into CI/CD, deploy canaries, build v1 of the attestation bundle for a mock audit&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 90:&lt;/strong&gt; Operationalize continuous validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-future-ai-and-automated-verification"&gt;The future: AI and automated verification&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Sovereignty you can’t prove is just a promise.&lt;/strong&gt; The next step is turning intent into verification — and then making verification automatic: In the near-term, AI agents will pre-check controls before deployment and auto-assemble attestation evidence and answer audit questions in plain language with hash-stamped, reproducible proofs.” — &lt;strong&gt;Craig McLellan&lt;/strong&gt;, Founder &amp;amp; CEO, ThinkOn; Data Sovereignty Architect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Emerging strategies will make proof cheaper and stronger.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI control validators&lt;/strong&gt;: Before a release goes live, smart checks compare the rules you say you enforce with what’s actually in your infrastructure-as-code and data catalogs. If they find an unapproved data path, the CI/CD pipeline blocks the deploy.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous evidence bundling:&lt;/strong&gt; Background agents regularly collect the right logs — policy-engine decisions, KMS/HSM key activity and data lineage — and create a hash-stamped, audit-ready package. If anything drifts, they raise a high-priority alert.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural-language audits:&lt;/strong&gt; You can ask, “Show all access to Alpha-US data last week,” and get a reproducible report of who accessed what, when and why, with tamper-evident exports.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy-preserving compute:&lt;/strong&gt; Sensitive jobs are run in confidential computing with hardware attestation and can produce zero-knowledge proofs that data was processed “in region with key X” without exposing the data or the code.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attestable vendors and verifiable routes: &lt;/strong&gt;Suppliers publish machine-readable proof of their controls that you can ingest into a trust dashboard and the network provides signed path records to show traffic stayed in-country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cso-bottom-line"&gt;The CSO bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity leadership across IAM, supply chain and AI shows a consistent pattern: simple, measurable controls prevent complex crises. Data sovereignty is no different. A 2025 Pure Storage survey reported that &lt;a href="https://www.purestorage.com/company/newsroom/press-releases/data-sovereignty-emerges-as-critical-business-risk-in-new-geopolitical-era-in.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;92% of global executives now view data sovereignty as a top-tier business risk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you can’t measure it, you can’t promise it. If you can’t prove it, you didn’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Engineer for verifiability by design. Replace press releases with evidence: brokered access, in-region keys, immutable logs and continuous validation. This is how security leaders turn public commitments into durable trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078816/data-sovereignty-proof-how-to-verify-controls-like-project-texas.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden hosts naval exercise with 200 special tactics operators</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</link>
      <description>Preparing to fight terrorism on land and seaThe exercise scenario focused on the deployment of special intervention units and naval assets during day- and night-time, simulating terrorist and hostage incidents on board of cruise liners and ferries. Day after day, the participants faced new challenges on the water and on some of the archipelago’s many islands, slowly preparing them for...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/sweden-hosts-naval-exercise-200-special-tactics-operators</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 30 potential victims identified in action against human trafficking enabled online</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</link>
      <description>From 15 to 19 September 2025, Europol supported the fourth edition of the EMPACT Trafficking in Human Beings (THB) Hackathon, an action week against human trafficking enabled online. It was led by Dutch authorities, with the support of Germany and the United Kingdom, and brought together 73 specialists from 26 countries across the world. Eurojust also participated in the action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/over-30-potential-victims-identified-in-action-against-human-trafficking-enabled-online</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s borders go digital</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</link>
      <description>The Entry/Exit System (EES) is the new IT system that digitally records the entry and exit of non-EU nationals travelling to 29 European countries for short stays. The system has already recorded over 300 000 movements, with the number continuing to grow daily. The EES began implementation on 12 October 2025 and will be fully operational by 10 April 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europe’s-borders-go-digital</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15th EDEN Event: Data Protection and Cybersecurity in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>The 15th Europol Data Protection Experts Network (EDEN) conference took place from 21 to 22 October 2025 at the University of Malta’s Valletta Campus. Jointly organised by the Academy of European Law (ERA) and EDEN, and co-hosted by the Maltese Police Force and the University of Malta, the event gathered senior policymakers, data protection officers, law enforcement officials and academics from across Europe.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/15th-eden-event-data-protection-and-cybersecurity-in-law-enforcement</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake number, real damage: Europol urges action against caller ID spoofing</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</link>
      <description>Europol is calling for a coordinated European response to tackle caller ID spoofing, an in increasingly common tool, used for online fraud and social engineering scams. Caller ID spoofing occurs when criminals falsify the information displayed on phones, making numbers appear legitimate to deceive victims. This practice is driving substantial financial and societal harm, with an estimated EUR 850 million lost worldwide each year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/fake-number-real-damage-europol-urges-action-against-caller-id-spoofing</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aisuru Botnet Shifts from DDoS to Residential Proxies</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/10/aisuru-botnet-shifts-from-ddos-to-residential-proxies/</link>
      <description>Aisuru, the botnet responsible for a series of record-smashing distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks this year, recently was overhauled to support a more low-key, lucrative and sustainable business: Renting hundreds of thousands of infected Internet of Things (IoT) devices to proxy services that help cybercriminals anonymize their traffic. Experts says a glut of proxies from Aisuru and other sources is fueling large-scale data harvesting efforts tied to various artificial intelligence (AI) projects, helping content scrapers evade detection by routing their traffic through residential connections that appear to be regular Internet users.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/10/aisuru-botnet-shifts-from-ddos-to-residential-proxies/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-686)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-686</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-686</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-687)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-687</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-687</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five central suspects arrested in whole-sale cocaine trafficking case</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</link>
      <description>Between 1 and 2 October, the Colombian Police (Policia Nacional de Colombia) and the Spanish Guardia Civil, supported by Europol, targeted five key suspects, linked to the so-called Clan del Golfo, allegedly responsible for whole-sale cocaine trafficking operations from South America to Europe. In particular, the criminal network oversaw first-hand the production, transportation and distribution of cocaine throughout the entire logistics chains. To support field activities on the action day, Europol deployed two experts to Colombia and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/five-central-suspects-arrested-in-whole-sale-cocaine-trafficking-case</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-689)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-689</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From CLICK to CRIME: investigating intellectual property crime in the digital age</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</link>
      <description>The conference “From CLICK to CRIME: Investigating Intellectual Property Crime in the Digital Age” was held on 22 and 23 October 2025 in Sofia, Bulgaria. Jointly organised by Europol, the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and Bulgaria’s General Directorate Combating Organised Crime (GDBOP), the event highlighted the vital importance of collaboration in tackling online crime. The participants reaffirmed the importance of strong collective efforts in tackling online-enabled intellectual property crime to protect consumers, safeguard creativity and uphold trust in the digital economy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/click-to-crime-investigating-intellectual-property-crime-in-digital-age</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-690)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-690</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ericsson security advisory (AV25-691)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ericsson-security-advisory-av25-691</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-692)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-692</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV25-693)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av25-693</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-694)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-694</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.78</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV25-583) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av25-583</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-695)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-695</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>70% of CISOs say internal conflicts more damaging than cyberattacks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079876/70-of-cisos-say-internal-conflicts-more-damaging-than-cyberattacks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Roughly 70% of security executives believe internal conflicts during a crisis cause more problems than the cyberattack itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;CISO-CEO tension, unclear authority, unrehearsed scenarios, and communication gaps between key teams cripple breach response despite major investments in tools and talent,” concludes the &lt;a href="https://cytactic.com/resources/cybersecurity-incident-response-management-report-2025/"&gt;Cytactic 2025 State of Cyber Incident Response Management (CIRM) Report&lt;/a&gt;, based on a survey of 480 senior US cybersecurity leaders. “Blurred authority and shifting responsibilities frequently delay response efforts, creating more disruption than the attackers themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But analysts and security specialists say much of the problem stems from alignment and perception issues that have taken hold well before cyberattacks require all-hands response, such as the incorrect belief that everything a CISO proposes slows down operations, making it harder to achieve revenue targets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security experts advise CISOs to consider such perception problems when setting security strategies and communicating cybersecurity’s value to colleagues and the board. For example, by emphasizing authentication behavioral analytics and other forms of passwordless protections, CISOs can show how their approaches deliver better protections with less friction, thereby helping lines of business (LOBs) to do their jobs securely and without unnecessary end-user effort.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.forrester.com/analyst-bio/jeff-pollard/BIO10584"&gt;Jeff Pollard&lt;/a&gt;, a vice president and principal analyst at Forrester, says another factor that undermines CISO-LOB and CISO-CEO relationships is the way that enterprise compensation is determined, a process that unintentionally sets CISOs on a collision course with LOB execs, the CEO, and the CFO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Think about the CEO and the LOB executives. They all have a P&amp;amp;L because they run a line of business. The vast majority of CISOs, however, have a budget but no P&amp;amp;L. That is a drastic difference,” Pollard says, adding that this common situation makes the CISO’s department look like just a cost center.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To fix that disconnect, Pollard says, CISOs must remind their CEO and LOB colleagues — loudly and often — that security initiatives indeed deliver revenue, marketshare, and customer retention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Every single customer that is rolling into those lines of business” are “filling out third-party risk management questionnaires and they are looking at audits,” Pollard says. “What CISOs are failing to do is showcasing that fact by saying things like, ‘When we bought that tool, it was not because we were bored. It was because one of your customers was asking, ‘Hey! What are you doing about web attacks on services from you that we use?’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pollard continues: “That’s where CISOs help with revenue. It’s because somewhere there is a customer — and probably a big one — who wanted it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pollard advises security leaders to tell their CEOs and business colleagues, “‘I am not introducing friction. I am delivering what our customers are forcing us to do.’ Showcase the reasonwhy you are doing what you are doing. ‘Because it’s your customers who are asking for these things.’”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, a former federal prosecutor who today serves as executive director of FormerGov, a directory of former government and military specialists, argues that the differing approaches of different company executives should also be spun as a good thing. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You want to have the conflict. The different incentives and motivations and expertise allow different ways of thinking about the company and finding ways to make it successful,” Levine explains. “The first thing is to not see that conflict as the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/cj-dietzman-cissp-cisa/"&gt;CJ Dietzman&lt;/a&gt;, senior vice president at Alliant Insurance Services, says CISOs also need to focus on what every LOB needs and try to address that. In other words, put the business first and address cybersecurity within that context. If CISOs can help their LOB exec colleagues deliver to their targets, cybersecurity will have their loyalty and support — which will go a long way toward easing internal tensions when a cyber crisis arises. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Know your business, CISO,” Dietzman says. “You should never lead with cybersecurity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079876/70-of-cisos-say-internal-conflicts-more-damaging-than-cyberattacks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do CISOs need to rethink service provider risk?</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4075982/do-cisos-need-to-rethink-service-provider-risk.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly half (47%) of organizations reported a cyberattack or data breach involving a third-party accessing their network in the 12 months to mid-2025, according to Imprivata and Ponemon &lt;a href="https://www.imprivata.com/2025-ponemon-report"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. As organizations increasingly rely on services providers to help manage critical systems and security operations – from cloud infrastructure and data platforms to managed security and AI services – the risk of exposure also grows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security leaders face mounting pressure from boards to provide assurance about &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4002765/third-party-risk-management-is-broken-but-not-beyond-repair.html"&gt;third-party risks&lt;/a&gt;, while services provider vetting processes are becoming more onerous — a growing burden for both CISOs and their providers. At the same time, AI is becoming integrated into more business systems and processes, opening new risks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs may be forced to rethink their vetting processes with partners to maintain a focus on risk reduction while treating partnerships as a shared responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-vetting-services-providers-is-growing-more-complex"&gt;Why vetting services providers is growing more complex&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Managed services providers (MSP) help augment internal resources, achieve cost savings, provide round-the-clock coverage and fill specialist gaps. More than half of organizations (52%) turn to MSPs when their number of security tools becomes unmanageable and 51% rely on them to evolve their cybersecurity strategy as they grow, according to &lt;a href="https://www.barracuda.com/reports/msp-customer-insight-report-2025"&gt;Barracuda’s&lt;/a&gt; MSP Customer Insight Report 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Naturally, such critical reliance requires comprehensive vetting processes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Christina Cruz, director of cybersecurity at media investment company Advance, describes a comprehensive process that includes industry frameworks, GRC checks, privacy, data protection, incident response, business continuity and disaster recovery plans. It must identify who’s in the leadership, whether there’s a dedicated cybersecurity function, risk assessments, security controls, software development lifecycle, vulnerability management, resiliency, service-level agreements and other contractual obligations from the service provider.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s a very extensive framework we use — and those are only the high-level categories,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The services outsourced are also becoming more complex, from security operation centers to threat hunting and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/649714/incident-response-lessons-learned-from-the-russian-attack-on-viasat.html"&gt;incident response&lt;/a&gt;. There’s now also data management that stretches from designing and architecting systems through to day-to-day operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This can include data warehousing, monitoring and reporting, security metrics and providing tuning for applications,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A recent project involved a six-month timeline for consulting, design, and managing a Snowflake environment, which included risk assessments, legal negotiations, project management, and moving towards a steady state. “Performing and evaluating a risk assessment and validating they can meet the technical requirements, going through the contractual agreement, and moving into the implementation phase and steady state was a very big lift,” she tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="should-risk-assessment-be-about-questionnaires-or-conversation"&gt;Should risk assessment be about questionnaires or conversation?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;David Stockdale, director of cybersecurity at the University of Queensland (UQ), needs services providers to understand the make-up and complexity of a higher education institution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Because of the size and research intensity of the university, we tend to build a lot in-house. Where we do use service providers, it’s usually for specific layers on top of our own services,” he says. “Researchers have different requirements to corporate or teaching units, so a cookie-cutter approach doesn’t work. The providers we work with have to understand that and be willing to adapt.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk evaluation is embedded across UQ’s procurement and governance processes for all third parties. The process goes through multiple layers of governance. “Risk evaluations for third parties are consolidated up into the cyber risks, which are then consolidated up into IT risks, and then into university-wide risks. Every three months we review the whole of UQ’s risk register, with a summary going to the board quarterly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When looking to engage a services provider, his vetting process starts with building relationships first and then working towards a formal partnership and delivery of services. He believes dialogue helps establish trust and transparency and underpin the partnership approach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A lot of that is ironed out in that really undocumented process. You build up those relationships first, and then the transactional piece comes after that.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stockdale says the evaluation cycle must stay flexible to allow for emerging risks. He stresses that effective vetting depends on realism and partnership. “I’m a great believer in putting yourself in the other person’s shoes,” he says. “If you were in their position, would you share that information or allow that audit? Probably not. So, it’s about building a relationship where there’s trust, openness, and a lot more to-ing and fro-ing of information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From the vendor’s side, partnership is equally critical and guides formal assurance and shared responsibility around managing risk. Fred Thiele, Interactive CISO, says that assurance depends on more than just the data that’s gathered in questionnaires. It needs to include the engagement that follows. He encourages CISOs to use the vetting process to open a dialogue about shared risk and ongoing improvement, not just tick boxes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If your questions stop once the form is complete, you’ve missed the chance to understand how a partner really thinks about security,” Thiele says. “You learn a lot more from how they explain their risk decisions than from a yes/no tick box.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Transparency and collaboration are at the heart of stronger partnerships. “You can’t outsource accountability, but you can become mature in how you manage shared responsibility,” Thiele says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="questions-that-can-guide-cisos-in-the-vetting-process"&gt;Questions that can guide CISOs in the vetting process&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thiele believes many enterprises have built elaborate risk frameworks that satisfy auditing but struggle to turn them into meaningful assurance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He cautions about a growing “cottage industry” of third-party risk tools and compliance templates that create paperwork rather than partnership. “They drive behavioral change over time, but how much they actually improve posture is questionable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In his experience, vetting practices reveal as much about an organization’s maturity as they do about a provider’s security posture. Thiele’s list of suggested questions will guide CISOs to get a handle on service provider security in the vetting stage:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership and accountability: Who is accountable for cybersecurity, where do they report, and how often to the executive or board?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Framework and standards for cybersecurity policy: Do you align with recognized frameworks and how do you validate your alignment? Have you performed a SOC audit and if so, to what level?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Risk management: How do you identify, assess, and prioritize cyber risks in your environment?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Data protection: How do you protect customer data at rest, in transit, and in use?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Access control: How do you ensure only authorized people can access your systems and customer data?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Incident response: What is your process for a cyber incident that impacts customers and how quickly do you notify impacted parties?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Third-party risk: How do you assess the security of your own suppliers and partners?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Testing and assurance: Do you regularly test your security posture? Please provide y/n for the following and share high-level results if possible: penetration testing, crisis management exercises, IT general controls, SOC1/SOC2.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Training: What training regime is in place for ensuring your employees stay current on cyber threats and how to prevent them?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Continuous improvement: Biggest security improvement in the past 12 months and what’s planned for the next 12?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I really like the first, second, and last because they show whether the leadership is engaged, the frameworks are real, and the organization is actually improving,” Thiele says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-far-is-too-far-for-transparency"&gt;How far is too far for transparency?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What happens when organizations want access to sensitive information such as pen test results or vulnerability reports? Negotiations typically happen with an NDA in place, but there are still limits. Transparency and trust can sometimes take negotiation from both sides.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Thiele, a request to view the enterprise risk register may be a ‘no’ but a request to review pen test results at a high level, the answer is more likely to be a ‘yes’. “We’re happy to give you a summary, but not the detailed findings. It’s not that we’re hiding anything — it’s that the less detail that’s out there, the better,” Thiele tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With requests for reports and completing detailed assessments with 200+ questions, the contract needs to warrant the time and effort to fulfil the requirements. “We’ve started to put bounds around it,” he says. “If it’s a multimillion-dollar engagement, sure. But if it’s small, we’ll point them to our online portal instead.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Stockdale’s case, after being given assurances and naively accepting them, he now requests solid evidence. In practice, that means as part of due diligence, UQ’s cybersecurity team now prefers standards-based assurance. In the past, they’ve asked for pen test results and sometimes been refused. “So we tend to go for that more standards-based approach — ISO 27001, SOC 2 — as part of our third-party risk assessment.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-adds-risk-and-new-ways-to-assess-it"&gt;AI adds risk — and new ways to assess it&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI is another area where organizations are increasingly engaging with services providers and a paradox when it comes to risk assessments. On the one hand, it has the potential to automate parts of the process, save time and identify gaps or other issues. At the same time, AI is spreading into more tools and services, which are expanding the risk surface for organizations. Security teams are having to adapt, and quickly, to take account of generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’re now very focused on evaluating any potential partner for the use of generative AI and it’s a new category that’s been added to our evaluation,” Cruz says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With AI, Cruz has started to monitor vendors acquiring ISO 42001 certification for AI governance. “It’s a trend I’m seeing in some of the work that we’re doing,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cruz says a steering committee handles big-picture oversight and a working group develops recommendations and more of the hands-on execution. “Depending on the recommendations coming out of that group, we update specific areas in our program to incorporate the requirements needed to govern the use of AI and also protect the organization’s data. The important point is that it takes a cross-functional group within an organization to build out what’s needed and what should be evaluated and reported on,” Cruz adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thiele says generative AI can assist organisations to research and verify prospective partners. “With Gen AI, you can surface a lot of what’s already in the public domain — certifications, breach disclosures, even employee profiles — and use that to check whether what you’re being told actually holds up,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The same technology that creates risk can also improve visibility, helping CISOs cut through generic assurances and spot inconsistencies before contracts are signed. “It’s there to enhance the conversation, not replace it,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4075982/do-cisos-need-to-rethink-service-provider-risk.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step aside, SOC. It’s time to ROC</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078696/step-aside-soc-its-time-to-roc.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Looking back on my years in national defense, one lesson stands out above the rest: speed and coordination are everything. Waiting until the dust settles to act after an attack can mean major setbacks at best, or dire consequences at worst. The same rings true in enterprise cybersecurity. Reactive decisions post-breach are often too late to prevent financial losses or business disruptions. The stakes are especially high when the target is critical infrastructure — think hospitals, regional power grids or major transportation systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This philosophy should be how we approach cyber risk as an industry. Rather than focusing only on defense after the fact, we at Resilience encourage organizations to rethink how they address their cyber risk. Part of that rethinking means taking a hard look at the status quo — specifically how enterprises have historically managed security monitoring and incident response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="traditional-soc-in-a-nontraditional-world"&gt;Traditional SOC in a nontraditional world&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For decades, the security operations center (SOC) has been the industry standard, serving as the nerve center for tracking alerts and triaging incidents. The typical SOC playbook is designed to contain or remediate issues after the fact by applying a patch or restoring a backup, but they don’t anticipate or prevent the next hit. That structure leaves executives without the proper context or language they need to make financially sound decisions about their risk exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen too many real-world consequences of this disconnect. A traditional SOC culture can train organizations to view security as a back-office technical issue. Alerts come in, analysts respond, tickets get closed, end of story. But the broader business context rarely enters the picture, which makes it difficult for technical teams to secure swift leadership buy-in when tough trade-offs arise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In our portfolio alone, we’ve witnessed a ransomware attack force a regional hospital network to divert patients for hours because IT teams couldn’t get immediate executive approval to shut down affected systems. In another instance, a global manufacturer delayed patching a critical vulnerability because leadership wasn’t convinced the downtime cost was worth it — that was, until attackers exploited the vulnerability weeks later. There is clearly a high cost associated with siloing cyber risk and treating it as a purely technical problem rather than a business one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I felt there had to be a better solution. Enter: the ROC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-is-a-roc"&gt;What is a ROC?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At its core, the Resilience Risk Operations Center (ROC) is a proactive intelligence hub. Think of it as a fusion center in which cyber, business and financial risk come together to form one clear picture.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the idea of a ROC isn’t entirely new — versions of it have existed across government and private sectors — the latest iterations emphasize collaboration between technical and financial teams to anticipate, rather than react to, threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With this approach, the ROC continuously consolidates real-world attack, claims and business intelligence data into a single operating environment. Then we bring experts from across disciplines — including threat hunters, claims experts, underwriters, data scientists and risk engineers — into the same room, both literally and figuratively, to assess the situations at hand. That collaboration allows us to spot vulnerabilities faster, understand their potential financial impact and take action before attackers can exploit them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What sets this approach apart is the integration of technical and financial perspectives. A SOC might issue an alert on a high-severity vulnerability, but a ROC layers in actuarial data and breach costs to show what that risk means in dollars and cents. It’s amazing how quickly decisions get made when a critical vulnerability is framed in real-world financial terms that anyone can understand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="inspired-by-the-us-air-force"&gt;Inspired by the US Air Force&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The principles behind the ROC didn’t emerge out of thin air. They were very much inspired by my time in the US Air Force working with the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Air_Operations_Center" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;air operations center (AOC)&lt;/a&gt;. An AOC serves as the central command hub for coordinating air, space and cyber missions. This approach is not just about monitoring radar screens or weather patterns. It’s about fusing together intelligence from every domain — satellite imagery, troop movements, communications intercepts and more — into a single operating picture that everyone can act on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What struck me most was how the AOC broke down silos. Pilots, intelligence analysts, logistics officers and cyber operators all sat side by side, working from the same shared intelligence. That diversity of expertise meant we were going beyond reacting to events to anticipating them, planning contingencies and making decisions that balanced immediate threats with long-term objectives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This approach offers a useful comparison for enterprises handling cyber risk today. In the corporate world, threat intelligence usually lives in the SOC, insurance data sits with the finance team, and business risk assessments gather dust in board reports. Rarely do those streams converge into one centralized decision-making hub. The ROC framework aims to change that by promoting collaboration and shared understanding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="change-doesnt-come-easy"&gt;Change doesn’t come easy&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, building the ROC wasn’t all smooth sailing. Just like military adversaries, cyber criminals are constantly evolving and improving. Scarier yet, just a single keystroke by a criminal actor can set off a chain reaction of significant disruptions. That makes trying to anticipate their next move feel like playing chess against an opponent who is changing the rules mid-game.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There was also the challenge of breaking down the existing silos between cyber, risk and financial teams. Bridging those disciplines was essential to driving positive material change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The solution was twofold, starting with designing a ROC that leveraged advanced models to identify the most financially damaging threats. That lets the ROC prioritize based on true impact rather than overblown FUD generated by media hype or vendor marketing. These insights are then mapped against each client’s unique infrastructure in order to pinpoint the vulnerabilities most likely to be exploited, calculate their financial cost and recommend tailored strategies to reduce risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The second key was building in positive feedback loops that continuously improve performance. Threat intelligence, claims data and client activity inform each other in near real time, sharpening the models’ output and accelerating response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="real-world-success"&gt;Real-world success&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first few months of the ROC’s operations showed clear signs that the model could work at scale. In April 2024, Palo Alto Networks disclosed a zero-day vulnerability in a global VPN product. Within hours, the ROC was synthesizing data across our clients’ environments to identify who was at risk. The vulnerability hunting team sent immediate alerts and recommended actions, enabling clients to disable vulnerable systems before attackers could strike. Those who didn’t receive alerts or make the suggested changes faced weeks of remediation and higher losses. That contrast underscored how combining operational vigilance with financial insight can materially reduce risk in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="looking-ahead"&gt;Looking ahead&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For me, resilience has always meant more than trying to protect against all possible threats. It’s about aligning cyber defenses with financial outcomes, so that when — not if — a breach occurs, companies can absorb the hit and continue to operate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ROC concept represents the first real step in that journey towards cyber resilience. It’s not as a single product or platform, but as a strategic shift toward integrated, financially informed cyber defense. By fusing intelligence across technical and financial domains, this model can shift cybersecurity from a reactive function into a proactive discipline that helps leaders make faster, smarter decisions under pressure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4078696/step-aside-soc-its-time-to-roc.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersicherheit ist größte Herausforderung für die Finanzbranche</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080078/cybersicherheit-ist-groste-herausforderung-fur-die-finanzbranche.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cyberangriff auf Finanzbranche" class="wp-image-4080088" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_1657454410.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Cyberangriffe stellen viele Banken und Versicherungen vor große Probleme.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Golden Dayz – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Systemkritische Branchen wie die Finanzindustrie geraten immer häufiger ins Visier von Cyberkriminellen. Die Anzahl der Cyberangriffe hat sich in diesem Bereich im Vergleich zum Jahr 2021 versechsfacht. Das geht aus einer aktuellen Umfrage des Beratungs- und Softwarehauses PPI hervor, für die hierzulande 50 Banken und 53 Versicherungen befragt wurden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;64 Prozent der Befragten sehen Cyberattacken als größte Herausforderung – noch vor der Digitalisierung und der Verschlechterung der Kreditqualität (bei Banken), beziehungsweise der zunehmenden Regulatorik (bei Versicherungen). Ein Grund dafür dürfte die mangelnde Sensibilisierung im Unternehmen sein.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="probleme-bei-der-cyberabwehr-von-banken-und-versicherungen"&gt;Probleme bei der Cyberabwehr von Banken und Versicherungen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;49 Prozent der befragten Versicherer und sogar 68 Prozent der befragten Banken gaben zu, dass es schwierig für sie ist, bei den Mitarbeitenden ein Bewusstsein für Cyberrisiken zu schaffen. Zudem räumten 56 Prozent der Befragten ein, dass ihnen die Echtzeiterkennung von Cyberangriffen schwerfällt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Laut Studie werden die Angriffe zunehmend komplexer und zielen auf Schwachstellen in Systemen und Prozessen. In den meisten Fällen installieren die Angreifer eine Schadsoftware: 33 Prozent der befragten Banken und 21 Prozent der Versicherer geben dies als häufigste Angriffsart an. Auf Platz zwei steht die Unterbrechung der IT-Systeme (16 beziehungsweise 21 Prozent).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„Die Zahl der Cyberangriffe wird weiterhin zunehmen“, mahnt Andreas Bruckner, Experte für IKT-Risikomanagement bei der PPI. Dem Experten zufolge ist der Reifegrad der Prävention und Erkennung von Cyberangriffen bei den Banken insgesamt höher als bei den Versicherungen. „Doch auch sie müssen ihre Resilienz laufend anpassen“, betont er. Entscheidend sei, Prävention und Erkennung nicht isoliert, sondern als integrierte Managementaufgabe zu verstehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;„&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3995010/in-der-security-geht-es-vor-allem-um-resilienz.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cyberresilienz&lt;/a&gt; ist längst kein reines IT-Thema mehr, sondern ein strategischer Wettbewerbsfaktor“, so Bruckner. „Wer Governance, IKS und Automatisierung konsequent ausbaut, schützt nicht nur Daten und Prozesse, sondern auch das Vertrauen von Kunden und Aufsicht.“&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3804883/dora-umsetzung-halt-banken-cisos-auf-trab.html" target="_blank"&gt;DORA-Umsetzung hält Banken-CISOs auf Trab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080078/cybersicherheit-ist-groste-herausforderung-fur-die-finanzbranche.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime-as-a-service takedown: 7 arrested</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</link>
      <description>An action day performed in Latvia on 10 October 2025 led to the arrest of five cybercriminals of Latvian nationality and the seizure of infrastructure used to enable crimes against thousands of victims across Europe. During the operation codenamed ‘SIMCARTEL’, law enforcement arrested two further suspects, took down five servers and seized 1 200 SIM box devices alongside 40 000 active SIM cards. Investigators from Austria, Estonia and Latvia, together with their colleagues at Europol und Eurojust, were able to attribute to the criminal network more than 1 700 individual cyber fraud cases in Austria and 1 500 in Latvia, with a total loss of several million euros. The financial loss in Austria alone amounts to around EUR 4.5 million, as well as EUR 420 000 in Latvia.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/cybercrime-service-takedown-7-arrested</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlas browser exploit lets attackers hijack ChatGPT memory</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080144/atlas-browser-exploit-lets-attackers-hijack-chatgpt-memory.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Days after cybersecurity analysts &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4078115/enterprises-should-not-install-openais-new-atlas-browser-analysts-warn.html" target="_blank"&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; enterprises against installing OpenAI’s new Atlas browser, researchers have discovered a vulnerability that allows attackers to infect systems with malicious code, granting themselves access privileges, or deploy malware. The development raises immediate questions about the enterprise readiness of AI-native browsers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4077980/has-openai-shown-us-a-future-for-safari.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;Atlas&lt;/a&gt; browser has come under scrutiny after researchers at LayerX Security revealed that attackers could exploit the flaw to inject malicious instructions directly into a user’s ChatGPT memory and potentially execute remote code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To prevent attackers from exploiting the vulnerability, LayerX has reported the exploit to OpenAI without sharing any additional technical information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-the-exploitation-works"&gt;How the exploitation works&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The exploit works in five steps. In the first step, a user logs in to ChatGPT, and an authentication cookie or token is held in their browser. In the next step, the user clicks on a malicious link that leads them to a compromised web page, Or Eshed, co-founder and CEO of LayerX, &lt;a href="https://layerxsecurity.com/blog/layerx-identifies-vulnerability-in-new-chatgpt-atlas-browser/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;explained&lt;/a&gt; in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the next step, the malicious page invokes a Cross-Site Request Forgery (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/520886/application-security-threat-watch-cross-site-request-forgery-csrf.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;CSRF&lt;/a&gt;) request to take advantage of the user’s pre-existing authentication into ChatGPT. In the fourth step, the CSRF exploit then injects hidden instructions into ChatGPT’s memory, without the user’s knowledge, thereby tainting the core LLM memory.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the fifth step, the tainted memories are invoked when the user queries ChatGPT, allowing deployment of malicious code that can give attackers control over systems or code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT’s &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/1611984/chatgpt-will-remember-what-you-did-last-summer.html?utm=hybrid_search"&gt;memory&lt;/a&gt; is a useful tool designed for the AI chatbot to remember details such as users’ queries, chat, and activities, preferences, style notes, and respond with personalized and relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Memory is account‑level and persists across sessions, browsers, and devices, so a single successful lure follows the user from home to office and from personal to corporate contexts,” said &lt;a href="https://ankura.com/experts-and-advisors/amit-jaju" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amit Jaju&lt;/a&gt;, global partner/senior managing director – India at Ankura Consulting. “In BYOD or mixed‑use environments, that persistence re‑triggers risky behaviors even after a reboot or browser change, expanding blast radius beyond a single endpoint. This is especially concerning where personal ChatGPT accounts are used for work tasks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaju added that adoption inside enterprises is currently very low. Atlas just launched, is macOS‑only, and enterprise access is off by default. So, exposure is limited to pilots and unsanctioned installations. But business workspaces have it available by default, so spillover into work use is plausible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-detect-a-hit"&gt;How to detect a hit&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Detecting a memory-based compromise in ChatGPT Atlas is not like hunting for traditional malware. There are no files, registry keys, or executables to isolate. Instead, security teams need to look for behavioral anomalies such as subtle shifts in how the assistant responds, what it suggests, and when it does so.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There are clues, but they sit outside the usual stack. For example, an assistant that suddenly starts offering scripts with outbound URLs, or one that begins anticipating user intent too accurately, may be relying on injected memory entries. When memory is compromised, the AI can act with unearned context. That should be a red flag,” said &lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, CEO and chief analyst at Greyhound Research.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He added, from a forensic perspective, analysts need to pivot toward correlating browser logs, memory change timestamps, and prompt-response sequences. Exporting and parsing chat history is essential. SOC teams should pay close attention to sequences where users clicked on unknown links followed by unusual memory updates or AI-driven agent actions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As this is not a plug-and-play detection problem, redemption and mitigation start with keeping Atlas disabled for the enterprise by default. In Business, it should be confined to tightly scoped pilots with non‑sensitive data. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaju added that for monitoring, enterprises should add detections for AI‑suggested code, fetching remote payloads, unusual egress after ChatGPT usage, and session‑riding behaviors in SaaS. He also suggested enabling web filtering on newly registered or uncategorized domains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The moment an Atlas user’s memory is compromised, the threat resides in the cloud-bound identity, not in any one machine. That is why the response must start with the account. Memory must be cleared. Credentials should be rotated. All recent chat history should be reviewed for signs of tampering, hidden logic, or manipulated task flow, noted Gogia.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="are-ai-browsers-safe"&gt;Are AI browsers safe?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Along with identifying the vulnerability, LayerX &lt;a href="https://layerxsecurity.com/blog/layerx-finds-that-perplexitys-comet-browser-is-up-to-85-more-vulnerable-to-phishing-and-web-attacks-than-chrome/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; that ChatGPT Atlas is also not equipped to stop phishing attacks. In the tests conducted by the company, ChatGPT Atlas had a failure rate of over 94%. Of the total 103 in-the-wild attacks, 97 attacks went through successfully.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The results were not very promising for other AI browsers, which the company tested last month. Perplexity’s Comet and Genspark were only able to stopped only 7% phishing attacks, while only Arc browser’s Dia was able to stop around 46% attacks. The traditional browsers, such as Edge and Chrome, on the other hand, are relatively well equipped and were able to stop about 50% of phishing attacks using their out-of-the-box protections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080144/atlas-browser-exploit-lets-attackers-hijack-chatgpt-memory.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copilot diagrams could leak corporate emails via indirect prompt injection</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080154/copilot-diagrams-could-leak-corporate-emails-via-indirect-prompt-injection.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has patched an indirect prompt injection flaw in Microsoft 365 Copilot that could have allowed attackers to steal sensitive data using clickable Mermaid diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to findings published by security researcher Adam Logue, the exploit could be triggered through specially crafted Office documents containing hidden instructions. When processed by Copilot, these prompts caused the assistant to fetch recent enterprise emails, convert them into a hex-encoded string, and embed that data into a clickable diagram created with the diagramming tool Mermaid.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When a user clicks what looks like a legitimate “login” button in the diagram, the encoded data would to sent to an attacker-controlled server, Logue noted in a blog &lt;a href="https://www.adamlogue.com/microsoft-365-copilot-arbitrary-data-exfiltration-via-mermaid-diagrams-fixed/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft patched the flaw by removing the ability for interactive hyperlinks in Mermaid diagrams within Copilot chats. “This effectively mitigated the data exfiltration risk,” Logue confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Diagram trick for data leak&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Logue laid out a multi-stage attack chain starting with a seemingly benign Office document (for example, an Excel sheet) containing visible content alongside hidden white-text instructions on a second sheet. These hidden prompts redirect Microsoft 365 Copilot away from its intended summarization task and instead instruct it to call its internal tool “search-enterprise_emails” to retrieve recent tenant emails.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The retrieved content is then hex-coded, broken into 30-character chunks (to satisfy rendering constraints), and embedded into a diagram created via Mermaid. That diagram is styled to look like a “login button” and contains a hyperlink pointing to an attacker-controlled server.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Logue was able to demonstrate (in a proof of concept), creating financial sheets with crafted instructions in white text. A successful exploit led the user to the attacker-controlled login. “When I asked M365 Copilot to summarize the document, it no longer told me it was about financial information and instead, responded with an excuse that the document contained sensitive information and couldn’t be viewed without proper authorization or logging in first,” Logue said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The bigger threat of indirect prompt injection&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident underscores that the risk goes beyond simple “prompt injection,” where a user types malicious instructions directly into an AI. Here, the attacker hides instructions inside document content that gets passed into the assistant without the user’s awareness. Logue described how the hidden instructions use progressive task modification (e.g, “first summarise, then ignore that and do X”) layered across spreadsheet tabs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the disclosure exposes a new attack surface where the diagram-generation feature (Mermaid output) becomes the exfiltration channel. Logue explained that clicking the diagram opened a browser link that quietly sent the encoded email data to an attacker-controlled endpoint. The transfer happened through a standard web request, making it indistinguishable from a legitimate click-through in many environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“One of the interesting things about mermaid diagrams is that &lt;a href="https://mermaid.js.org/config/directives.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;they also include support for CSS&lt;/a&gt;,” Logue noted. “This opens up some interesting attack vectors for data exfiltration, as M365 Copilot can generate a mermaid diagram on the fly and can include data retrieved from other tools in the diagram.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent disclosures highlight a surge in indirect prompt injection attacks, where &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053107/ai-prompt-injection-gets-real-with-macros-the-latest-hidden-threat.html"&gt;hidden macros&lt;/a&gt; in documents or &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4069887/github-copilot-prompt-injection-flaw-leaked-sensitive-data-from-private-repos.html"&gt;embedded comments&lt;/a&gt; in pull requests hijack AI-driven workflows and extract data without obvious user action. These trends underscore that tools like diagram generators or visual outputs can soon become stealthy channels for exfiltration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4080154/copilot-diagrams-could-leak-corporate-emails-via-indirect-prompt-injection.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.23</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – October 2025 monthly rollup (AV25-666) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-october-2025-monthly-rollup-av25-666</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.24</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-015 - Vulnerability impacting Microsoft Windows Server Update Services - CVE-2025-59287</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-015-vulnerability-impacting-microsoft-windows-server-update-services-cve-2025-59287</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.27</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How evolving regulations are redefining CISO responsibility</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079450/how-evolving-regulations-are-redefining-ciso-responsibility.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs face increasing personal and criminal liability for improper or incomplete risk management and disclosure during cyber incidents. The SEC, DOJ and international regulators are targeting executives who knowingly omit or distort cyber risk information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="increasing-attacks-on-iot-and-ot-device-vulnerabilities"&gt;Increasing attacks on IoT and OT device vulnerabilities&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks are increasingly driven by software vulnerabilities embedded in OT and IoT devices. The &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir/"&gt;2025 Verizon Data Breach Investigations Report&lt;/a&gt; noted that 20% of breaches were vulnerability-based, which is a close second to credential abuse, accounting for 22% of breaches. Year over year, breaches resulting from software vulnerabilities increased by 34%.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The dramatic rise in device vulnerability-based cyberattacks has precipitated growing regulatory compliance requirements and legal actions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="growing-regulatory-scrutiny"&gt;Growing regulatory scrutiny&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Governments and industry bodies worldwide are tightening cybersecurity mandates to improve accountability and resilience across the digital ecosystem. Emerging regulations include the &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/executive-order-14028-improving-nations-cybersecurity"&gt;US Executive Order 14028 on Cybersecurity in the US&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://nis2directive.eu/"&gt;NIS2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.european-cyber-resilience-act.com/"&gt;Cyber Resilience Act (CRA)&lt;/a&gt; in the EU as well as their peers around the world. Regulators are mandating device Software Bill of Materials documentation and vulnerability awareness, as these elements help enterprises to proactively manage risk in their device portfolios.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, the regulatory burden sits with the device manufacturers; however, the owners of these devices are also liable when they are breached.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-cisos-are-being-held-responsible-for"&gt;What CISOs are being held responsible for:&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inability to disclose an accurate inventory of impacted assets.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Inadequate governance, including third-party risk management.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Providing misleading or incomplete board communications on risk posture.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Not reporting on breaches accurately and promptly.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Certifying compliance (SOX, ISO 27001) without verifying reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprises-refining-governance-compliance-and-risk-approaches"&gt;Enterprises refining governance, compliance, and risk approaches&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises are making policy and resource changes to meet the evolving threat and liability landscape. A &lt;a href="https://investors.fastly.com/news/news-details/2025/Fastly-Research-Reveals-93-of-Organizations-Working-to-Reduce-CISO-Liability-Risk/default.aspx"&gt;Fastly report of 1,800 IT leaders&lt;/a&gt; shows 93% of organizations have updated policies to address CISO liability:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;41% involve CISOs more deeply in strategic board decisions.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;38% provide increased legal support for security teams.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;38% impose additional scrutiny on security disclosures from regulators.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;21% remind CISOs that they “are not above the law.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Enterprises are also working to provide CISOs with improved technical tools to address security and associated liability risks. Boards and leadership teams are evolving their CISOs’ capabilities from rapid incident response to proactive cyber risk management in response to the regulatory emphasis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-need-for-better-asset-inventory-and-intelligence"&gt;The need for better asset inventory and intelligence&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A central component of proactive security management is the complete documentation of IoT devices, including their attack surfaces and software vulnerabilities. Inventory information is scattered across fragmented organizational silos and third-party partners. It must be manually gathered, consuming significant time and human resources to correlate and maintain the intelligence needed to secure and document IoT devices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-somosid-solution"&gt;The SomosID solution&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As an FCC-trusted administrator, Somos maintains identity information for over 7 billion phone numbers. These digital identifiers help enable trusted communications every day. In the same way that Somos has long ensured integrity and trust in numbering, Somos is extending this expertise into the IoT ecosystem with SomosID for IoT. SomosID device intelligence service correlates and maintains critical intelligence for IoT devices, including: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inventory and Identity&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Software information, including SBOM and vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Other asset attributes, including communication capabilities and certifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By linking the discipline of managing trusted digital identifiers with comprehensive IoT device intelligence, Somos helps enterprises and service providers establish a verifiable chain of trust across both human and machine communications. The resulting dataset facilitates proactive security, device portfolio planning, technical support and compliance reporting. It is meant to be provided not only to the enterprises that own the devices but also to their service providers to facilitate operations and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Explore how SomosID can help organizations like yours reduce your CISO liability and strengthen your compliance posture.  &lt;a href="mailto:connect@somos.com"&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt; today to schedule a demo or &lt;a href="https://info.somos.com/20251030-CISOLiabilityin2025_LP01-RegistrationPage.html"&gt;join our complimentary Webinar&lt;/a&gt; on November 13 from 2 PM to 2:30 PM ET to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079450/how-evolving-regulations-are-redefining-ciso-responsibility.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Bill of Material umsetzen: Die besten SBOM-Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492152/software-bill-of-material-umsetzen-die-8-besten-sbom-tools.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Nur wenn Sie wissen, was drinsteckt, können Sie sich sicher sein, dass alles mit rechten Dingen zugeht. Das gilt für Fast Food wie für Software. " src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3353396/1200x.jpg" title="Nur wenn Sie wissen, was drinsteckt, können Sie sich sicher sein, dass alles mit rechten Dingen zugeht. Das gilt für Fast Food wie für Software. " width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Nur wenn Sie wissen, was drinsteckt, können Sie sich sicher sein, dass alles mit rechten Dingen zugeht. Das gilt für Fast Food wie für Software. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Geka – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Um Software abzusichern, muss man wissen, was in ihrem Code steckt. Aus diesem Grund ist eine Software Bill of Material, SBOM oder Software-Stückliste heute unerlässlich. Der SolarWinds-Angriff sowie die Log4j-Schwachstelle haben verdeutlicht, wie wichtig es ist, die Sicherheit von Softwarelieferketten in den Fokus zu nehmen – insbesondere, wenn es um Open Source Software geht. &lt;a href="https://www.sonarsource.com/open-source-maintainer-survey-2023.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Einer Umfrage&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) des Open-Source-Unternehmens Tidelift zufolge enthalten heute 92 Prozent aller Anwendungen Open-Source-Komponenten. Eine durchschnittliche, moderne Applikation besteht demnach sogar zu 70 Prozent aus quelloffener Software.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Antwort auf die potenziellen Risiken sind – wenn es nach der &lt;a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/tools/the-state-of-software-bill-of-materials-sbom-and-cybersecurity-readiness/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Linux Foundation"&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, der &lt;a href="https://openssf.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Open Source Security Foundation"&gt;Open Source Security Foundation&lt;/a&gt; und &lt;a href="https://www.openchainproject.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="OpenChain"&gt;OpenChain&lt;/a&gt; geht – SBOMs: Formale und maschinenlesbare Metadaten, die ein Softwarepaket und seinen Inhalt eindeutig identifizieren. Die Software-Stücklisten können auch andere Informationen enthalten, etwa Copyright- oder Lizenzdaten. Dabei ist eine Software Bill of Material so konzipiert, dass sie organisationsübergreifend ausgetauscht werden kann. Besonders hilfreich ist eine SBOM, um die Transparenz über die von den Teilnehmern einer &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492023/supply-chain-risk-management-so-wird-ihre-lieferkette-resilient.html" target="_blank" title="Softwarelieferkette"&gt;Softwarelieferkette&lt;/a&gt; gelieferten Komponenten zu gewährleisten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="sbom-best-practices"&gt;SBOM – Best Practices&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eine SBOM sollte beinhalten:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;die Open-Source-Bibliotheken der Anwendung;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plugins, Erweiterungen und andere Zusatzmodule;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;von In-House-Entwicklern selbst geschriebenen Quellcode;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Informationen über die Versionen dieser Komponenten, ihren Lizenzierungs- und Patch-Status;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;automatische kryptografische Signatur und Überprüfung von Komponenten;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;automatische Scans, um SBOMs als Teil der CI/CD-Pipeline zu erstellen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dabei sollte eine Software Bill of Material ein einheitliches Format verwenden. Zu den gängigen SBOM-Formaten gehören:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software Package Data Exchange (SPDX),&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software Identification (SWID) Tagging und&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;OWASP CycloneDX.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bislang hat sich keiner der drei Standards von den anderen abgesetzt und einen De-facto-Industriestandard geschaffen. Um SBOMs praktikabel zu machen, sollte die SBOM-Erstellung nicht nur automatisiert, sondern in die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495227/schwachstelle-in-argo-cd-cloud-infrastruktur-in-gefahr.html" target="_blank" title="CI/CD-Pipeline"&gt;CI/CD-Pipeline&lt;/a&gt; integriert werden. Oder wie die National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) es &lt;a href="https://www.ntia.doc.gov/files/ntia/publications/copado_-_2021.06.17.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="ausdrückt"&gt;ausdrückt&lt;/a&gt; (PDF): “Das ultimative Ziel ist es, SBOMs in Maschinengeschwindigkeit zu generieren.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="software-bill-of-materials-use-cases"&gt;Software Bill of Materials – Use Cases&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Auch bei SBOMs gibt es drei verschiedene Anwendungsfälle. Im Allgemeinen sind das:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softwarehersteller&lt;/strong&gt; verwenden SBOMs, um Erstellung und Wartung der von ihnen gelieferten Software zu unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softwareeinkäufer&lt;/strong&gt; nutzen SBOMs, um sich vor dem Kauf abzusichern, Rabatte auszuhandeln und Implementierungsstrategien aufzusetzen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softwarebetreiber&lt;/strong&gt; nutzen SBOMs für das Vulnerability- und Asset-Management, um Lizenzen und Compliance zu managen und Abhängigkeiten und Risiken in Sachen Software und Komponenten schnell zu identifizieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gartner &lt;a href="https://anchore.com/sbom/gartner-innovation-insights-sboms/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="geht davon aus"&gt;geht davon aus&lt;/a&gt;, dass bis zum Jahr 2025 60 Prozent der Unternehmen, die Software für kritische Infrastrukturen entwickeln oder beschaffen, SBOMs vorschreiben und standardisieren werden. Heute liegt dieser Wert bei weniger als 20 Prozent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="empfehlenswerte-sbom-tools"&gt;Empfehlenswerte SBOM-Tools&lt;/h1&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bei drei verschiedenen SBOM-Formaten und einer Vielzahl von Metadaten, die innerhalb einer Software Bill of Material verfolgt werden können, ist es nicht verwunderlich, dass es kein SBOM-Tool gibt, das sämtliche Bedürfnisse erfüllt. &lt;a href="https://anchore.com/sbom/gartner-innovation-insights-sboms/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Gartner empfiehlt"&gt;Gartner empfiehlt&lt;/a&gt;, Tools zu verwenden, die folgende Funktionen mitbringen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SBOMs während des Build-Prozesses erstellen;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quellcode und Binärdateien (wie Container-Images) analysieren;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SBOMs bearbeiten;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SBOMs in lesbaren Formaten anzeigen, vergleichen, importieren und validieren;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SBOM-Inhalte von einem Format oder Dateityp in andere übersetzen, beziehungsweise die Informationen zusammenführen; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Einbindung anderer Tools über APIs und Bibliotheken;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Keines der folgenden acht Tools erfüllt (bislang) all diese Empfehlungen. Wir empfehlen Ihnen, die Tools auszuprobieren und anschließend zu ermitteln, welches für Ihre Zwecke am besten geeignet ist. Diese acht SBOM-Tools verdienen Ihre Aufmerksamkeit:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://anchore.com/sbom/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Anchore"&gt;Anchore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Unternehmen ist bereits seit sechs Jahren im SBOM-Business tätig. Die Grundlage des Unternehmens bilden zwei Open-Source-Projekte:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Syft ist ein Tool mit Kommandozeilen-Interface und eine Bibliothek, um SBOMs aus Container-Images und Dateisystemen zu erzeugen. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grype ist ein einfach zu integrierendes Tool, um Container-Images und Dateisysteme auf Schwachstellen zu scannen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zusammen können diese beiden Werkzeuge Software-Stücklisten in jeder Phase des Entwicklungsprozesses erzeugen, von Quellcode-Repositories und CI/CD-Pipelines bis hin zu Container-Registries und Laufzeiten. Diese SBOMs werden in einem zentralen Repository aufbewahrt, um vollständige Transparenz und kontinuierliches Monitoring zu gewährleisten – auch nach der Bereitstellung. Die Tools von Anchore unterstützen CycloneDX, SPDX und das proprietäre SBOM-Format von Syft. Das Anbieterunternehmen bündelt seine SBOM-Funktionalität in der Plattform Anchore Enterprise 4.0 Software SCM (Supply Chain Management).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://fossa.com/lp/simplify-sbom-generation-fossa" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="FOSSA"&gt;FOSSA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Flaggschiff-Programme von FOSSA sind ein Open Source License Compliance Manager und ein Open Source Vulnerability Scanner. Der Ansatz von FOSSA sieht vor, dass Sie das SBOM-Tool in Ihr bevorzugtes Versionskontrollsystem wie GitHub, BitBucket oder GitLab integrieren. Sie können auch die CLI von FOSSA verwenden und das Tool lokal ausführen oder es in Ihre CI/CD-Pipeline integrieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In jedem Fall identifiziert FOSSA im Rahmen eines Projektscans automatisch sowohl direkte als auch indirekte Abhängigkeiten in der Codebasis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.gitlab.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GitLab (ehemals Rezilion)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beim DevSecOps-Anbieter ist SBOM Teil seiner ganzheitlichen Software-Sicherheits- und Schwachstellen-Systeme. Dynamic SBOM verwendet eine dynamische Laufzeitanalyse, um die Angriffsfläche Ihrer Software zu monitoren. Es sucht also ständig nach bekannten Schwachstellen in den Komponenten. Neben der Bereitstellung eines Live-Inventars aller Softwarekomponenten in Ihren CI/CD-, Staging- und Produktionsumgebungen wird Ihre SBOM ständig aktualisiert. Sie können Ihre Software Bill of Material im CycloneDX-Format und als Excel-Tabelle exportieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nach der Übernahme durch GitLab wurden die SBOM-Funktionalitäten von Rezilion im Jahr 2022 &lt;a href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2022/03/23/gitlab-rezilion-integration-reduces-vulnerability-backlog-identifies-exploitable-risks-to-fix/"&gt;in die DevSecOps-Plattform integriert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mend.io/sca/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Mend"&gt;Mend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Früher unter dem Namen WhiteSource bekannt, bietet Mend eine Vielzahl von SCA-Tools (Software Composition Analysis) an. Eine SBOM-Funktionalität ist in das SCA-Toolset integriert. Die Lösung von Mend ist weniger ein Entwicklerprogramm oder ein CI/CD-Tool – sondern vielmehr ein Open-Source-Lizenz- und Sicherheitsmechanismus für Programmierer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mit Hilfe von Mend lassen sich sämtliche Softwarekomponenten tracken, direkte und indirekte Abhängigkeiten identifizieren, Schwachstellen aufdecken, Remediationspfade bereitstellen und automatisch SBOM-Einträge aktualisieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/opensbom-generator/spdx-sbom-generator" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="SPDX SBOM Generator"&gt;SPDX SBOM Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieses eigenständige Open-Source-Tool tut das, was sein Name verspricht: SPDX-SBOMs aus aktuellen Paketmanagern oder Build-Systemen erstellen. Sie können seine CLI verwenden, um SBOM-Daten aus Ihrem Code zu erzeugen. Das Tool erzeugt Berichte über Komponenten, Lizenzen, Copyrights und Sicherheitsreferenzen Ihres Codes. Diese Daten werden in der SPDX v2.2-Spezifikation exportiert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.startleftsecurity.com/tauruseer-application-security-posture-management-platform" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Start Left Security"&gt;Start Left Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieses SBOM-Tool wird als Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) angeboten. Auf der Grundlage einer patentierten, anwendungszentrierten Integrationsmethodik kombiniert das ehemals unter dem Namen TauruSeer bekannte Angebot seine Cognition-Engine-Sicherheitsüberprüfung mit SBOM. Das Paket hilft Ihnen, Ihren Code für Ihre Entwickler und Kunden abzusichern und zu tracken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/tern-tools/tern" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Tern Project"&gt;Tern Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieses quelloffene SBOM-Projekt lässt sich gut mit SPDX SBOM Generator kombinieren. Anstatt mit Paketmanagern oder Build-Systemen zu arbeiten, erzeugt dieses SCA-Tool und die Python-Bibliothek eine SBOM für Container-Images und Docker-Dateien. Darüber hinaus lassen sich auch SBOMs im SPDX-Format erzeugen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vigilant-ops.com/products/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Vigilant Ops"&gt;Vigilant Ops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dieser Cybersicherheitsanbieter aus dem Healthcare-Bereich konzentriert sich mit seiner InSight-Plattform auf Software-Stücklisten. Seine SaaS-Plattform generiert und pflegt zertifizierte SBOMs und sorgt für deren authentifizierten Austausch. Sie bietet Sicherheit durch kontinuierliche Schwachstellenüberwachung. Die SBOM-Zertifizierung verwendet patentierte Algorithmen, um sicherzustellen, dass alle Komponenten validiert und Schwachstellen verlinkt sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Sicherheitsfunktionen können auch für SBOMs verwendet werden, die von anderen Programmen erstellt wurden. Diese werden sowohl im Ruhezustand als auch während der Übertragung verschlüsselt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unser kostenloser Newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492152/software-bill-of-material-umsetzen-die-8-besten-sbom-tools.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notable post-quantum cryptography initiatives paving the way toward Q-Day</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/654887/11-notable-post-quantum-cryptography-initiatives-launched-in-2023.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The point at which quantum computers will be capable of breaking existing cryptographic algorithms — known as “Q-Day” — is approaching. Some security experts believe &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/652972/mastercard-preps-for-the-post-quantum-cybersecurity-threat.html"&gt;Q-Day&lt;/a&gt; will occur within the next decade, potentially leaving all digital information vulnerable under current encryption protocols.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While a decade may seem far away, post-quantum cryptography (PQC) is fast becoming a high priority for the security community, as it works to understand, build, and implement encryption that can withstand post-quantum threats and attacks of the future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“PQC migration provides an opportunity to re-evaluate the larger cybersecurity landscape,” Dylan Rudy, lead scientist with Booz Allen’s quantum sciences team, tells CSO. “By integrating new PQC algorithms into a zero-trust architecture, cybersecurity infrastructure can be redesigned into a new crypto agility framework.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At issue is the fact that quantum computers of sufficient power could undermine the mathematical underpinnings of current encryption methods. Experts predict sufficiently powerful quantum computers are years away but &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3487766/cisos-urged-to-prepare-now-for-post-quantum-cryptography.html"&gt;early preparations are needed&lt;/a&gt; not least because the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3552701/the-cisos-guide-to-establishing-quantum-resilience.html"&gt;upgrade process is far from trivial&lt;/a&gt; and may take years in many environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Particularly for those in high-security sectors, where the threat of “harvest now, decrypt later” attacks is keenly felt, waiting for “oven ready” post-quantum encryption products and services to mature is a bad decision. Early adopters can take advantage of hybrid products and services that exist today, as they enable them to start migrating immediately, rather than waiting for updated internet protocols.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are the latest developments on recently launched initiatives, programs, standards, and resources aimed at helping with the creation, development of, and migration to PQC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;NIST ratifies post-quantum encryption standards&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In August 2024, NIST (US National Institute of Standards and Technology) &lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3486075/nist-finally-settles-on-quantum-safe-crypto-standards.html"&gt;approved three post-quantum cryptography algorithms for mainstream development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As part of the announcement, NIST approved ML-KEM, formerly known as CRYSTALS-Kyber, for general encryption and key exchange. ML-DSA (Module-Lattice-Based Digital Signature Algorithm, formerly known as &lt;strong&gt;CRYSTALS-Dilithium&lt;/strong&gt;) and SLH-DSA (Stateless Hash-Based Digital Signature Algorithm, &lt;strong&gt;SPHINCS+&lt;/strong&gt;) were also given the go-ahead as the basis for digital signatures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All three algorithms are capable of withstanding attacks from both classical and (future) quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In March 2025, NIST selected &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/News/2025/hqc-announced-as-a-4th-round-selection"&gt;HQC for standardization&lt;/a&gt;. The code-based Key Exchange Mechanism offers a backup or alternative to ML-KEM for encryption and key exchange.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other algorithms are still being evaluated but the approval of the four algorithms as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573083/nist-names-new-post-quantum-cryptography-standards.html"&gt;standards for post-quantum encryption&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3487766/cisos-urged-to-prepare-now-for-post-quantum-cryptography.html"&gt;gives engineers the building blocks&lt;/a&gt; they need for future technology development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is an important milestone, but a complex one for us to navigate,” Andersen Cheng, founder and chairman of Post-Quantum, tells CSO. “While these announcements mark a step change in the world’s journey to becoming quantum secure, it does not mean that the entire internet ecosystem is now protected.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF), which defines how the internet is built, used, and secured, will play a key role in developing the standards that harness post-quantum encryption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“NIST’s standards should motivate organizations to take the quantum threat seriously,” says Markus Pflitsch, CEO and founder at Terra Quantum. “By standardizing PQC algorithms, NIST provides a roadmap for organizations worldwide to transition to quantum-resistant cryptographic systems. Companies will now need to prepare for this migration from classical to post-quantum cryptography and invest in their long-term data security by ensuring they are NIST-compliant.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="industry-heavyweights-line-up-behind-pqc"&gt;Industry heavyweights line up behind PQC&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/strong&gt; became the first mainstream browser to &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2024/09/a-new-path-for-kyber-on-web.html"&gt;support hybrid post‑quantum key exchanges&lt;/a&gt; by default late last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The approach combines classical elliptic-curve encryption, for backwards compatibility, with lattice-based PQC derived from ML-KEM.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other industry giants — including Amazon and &lt;a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2024-08-13-ibm-developed-algorithms-announced-as-worlds-first-post-quantum-cryptography-standards"&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt; — have also begun laying foundations for quantum-safe cryptography. For example, IBM has pushed ahead with efforts to integrate post-quantum cryptography into many of its products, such as IBM z16 and IBM Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/08/20/quantum-safe-security-progress-towards-next-generation-cryptography/"&gt;testing PQC in Azure&lt;/a&gt;. AWS has published &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/aws-post-quantum-cryptography-migration-plan/"&gt;PQC integration guides&lt;/a&gt; for developers, and &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/en-gb/pqc/"&gt;Cloudflare has begun supporting PQC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="quantum-leap"&gt;Quantum leap&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent technology advances are boosting the capabilities of quantum computing and therefore bringing forward the need to roll out quantum-resistant cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In December 2024, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/research/google-willow-quantum-chip/"&gt;Google unveiled Willow&lt;/a&gt;, a new quantum chip that marks a significant step forward in scalable quantum computing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Unlike previous architectures, Willow demonstrates that increasing the number of qubits can effectively reduce error rates — a major hurdle in building large-scale quantum systems,” says Florent Michel, head of cryptography at Optalysys, a UK-based developer of optical computing hardware. “While further research is needed to validate its scalability, Willow offers a promising new direction, reinforcing the need for quantum-resilient cryptographic solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last February &lt;a href="https://news.microsoft.com/source/features/innovation/microsofts-majorana-1-chip-carves-new-path-for-quantum-computing/"&gt;Microsoft introduced Majorana 1&lt;/a&gt;, the world’s first quantum processor based on topological qubits. Long theorized as a potential solution to quantum error correction, topological qubits had previously remained elusive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Microsoft claims to have achieved practical realisation of this technology, a milestone that, despite ongoing debate in the research community, could accelerate the timeline for viable quantum computers,” Michel says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Linux Foundation’s grand alliance to take on PQC&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Linux Foundation launched the &lt;a href="https://pqca.org/"&gt;Post-Quantum Cryptography Alliance (PQCA)&lt;/a&gt; in February 2024, bringing together industry giants and researchers to tackle the cryptographic security challenges posed by future quantum computers. The effort is geared toward developing software packages that support PQC standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Founding members of the alliance include AWS, Cisco, Google, IBM, NVIDIA, QuSecure, SandboxAQ, and the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The PQCA will engage in various technical projects to support its objectives, including the development of software for evaluating, prototyping, and deploying new post-quantum algorithms,” according to a &lt;a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press/announcing-the-post-quantum-cryptography-alliance-pqca"&gt;statement by The Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. “By providing these software implementations, the foundation seeks to facilitate the practical adoption of post-quantum cryptography across different industries.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In January 2025, the PQCA &lt;a href="https://pqca.org/news/2025/post-quantum-cryptography-alliance-brings-accelerated-computing-to-post-quantum-cryptography-with-nvidia-cupqc/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that its open source project, Open Quantum Safe (OQS), integrates the &lt;a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/cupqc"&gt;NVIDIA cuPQC library&lt;/a&gt;, offering GPU-accelerated implementations of cryptographic primitives that are safe against attacks from future quantum computing technology.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tech community launches PQC Coalition to drive understanding, adoption&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In September 2023, a community of technologists, researchers, and expert practitioners launched the &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20230926448615/en/Post-Quantum-Cryptography-Coalition-Launches"&gt;PQC Coalition&lt;/a&gt; to drive progress toward broader understanding and public adoption of PQC algorithms. Founding coalition members include IBM Quantum, Microsoft, MITRE, PQShield, SandboxAQ, and the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://pqcc.org/"&gt;PQC Coalition&lt;/a&gt; will apply its collective technical expertise and influence to facilitate global adoption of PQC in commercial and open-source technologies. Coalition members will contribute their expertise to motivate and advance interoperable standards and technical approaches and step forward in providing critical outreach and education.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The coalition will focus on four workstreams:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advancing standards relevant to PQC migration&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Creating technical materials to support education and workforce development&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Producing and verifying open-source, production-quality code, and implementing side-channel resistant code for industry verticals&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Ensuring cryptographic agility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;CISA, NSA, NIST issue PQC migration resource&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In August 2023, the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), National Security Agency (NSA), and NIST &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/2023-08/Quantum%20Readiness_Final_CLEAR_508c%20(3).pdf"&gt;published a factsheet&lt;/a&gt; on the impacts of quantum capabilities. It urged all organizations, especially those that support critical infrastructure, to develop a quantum-readiness roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Quantum-Readiness: Migration to Post-Quantum Cryptography” outlined how organizations can prepare a cryptographic inventory, engage with technology vendors, and assess their supply chain reliance on quantum-vulnerable cryptography in systems and assets. The factsheet also provides recommendations for technology vendors whose products support the use of quantum-vulnerable cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“PQC is about proactively developing and building capabilities to secure critical information and systems from being compromised through the use of quantum computers,” says Rob Joyce, director of NSA cybersecurity. “The transition to a secured quantum computing era is a long-term intensive community effort that will require extensive collaboration between government and industry. The key is to be on this journey today and not wait until the last minute.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;X9 announces initiative to create PQC assessment guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In June 2023, the Accredited Standards Committee X9 &lt;a href="https://x9.org/x9-launches-effort-to-create-post-quantum-cryptography-assessment-guidelines-participants-sought/"&gt;announced a new initiative&lt;/a&gt; to create PQC assessment guidelines to act as a roadmap for PQC transitions. It invited participants to take part in the effort.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When completed, the X9 guidelines might be used by organizations as a self-assessment tool, an informal assessment of a third-party service provider, or an independent assessment by a qualified information security professional, X9 said. An auditor or regulator might also refer to the assessment guidelines which could form a foundation for crypto agility standardization, it added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It will be important to have PQC assessment guidelines available before transitions are underway, for consistency to make the process as smooth as possible and the outcomes optimal,” says Michael Talley, chair of the X9F1 Cryptographic Tools working group.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;X9 followed up with &lt;a href="https://x9.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/New-X9-Report-Supplies-Guidance-on-Migrating-to-Post-quantum-Cryptography-Safely-and-Cost-effectively-FINAL.pdf"&gt;guidance, aimed at financial industry management&lt;/a&gt;, on how to migrate to post-quantum cryptography “safely and cost effectively” in August 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;NCCoE addresses preparing for the adoption of new PQC algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In April 2023, the US National Cybersecurity Council of Excellence (NCCoE), a collaboration of cybersecurity experts from the public and private sectors, released a draft publication addressing preparation for adopting new PQC algorithms. &lt;a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/news-insights/nccoe-releases-preliminary-draft-nist-sp-1800-38a-migration-post-quantum-cryptography"&gt;Migration to Post-Quantum Cryptography&lt;/a&gt; extended the typical message of urgency to plan for migration seen in federal mandates to members of the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NCCoE said it would be engaging with industry collaborators, regulated industry sectors, and the US government to bring awareness to the issues involved in migrating to post-quantum algorithms and to prepare the crypto community for migration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;QuSecure pioneers live satellite quantum-resilient cryptographic communications link through space&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In March 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.qusecure.com/qusecure-launches-live-end-to-end-satellite-quantum-resilient-link-through-space/"&gt;quantum security vendor QuSecure claimed&lt;/a&gt; to have accomplished the first known live, end-to-end quantum-resilient cryptographic communications satellite link through space. It marked the first time US satellite data transmissions had been protected from classical and quantum decryption attacks using PQC, according to the company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The quantum-secure communication to space and back to Earth was made through a &lt;a href="https://www.starlink.com/"&gt;Starlink&lt;/a&gt; satellite working with a leading global system integrator (GSI) and security provider.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is significant because data shared between satellites and ground stations travels through the air and traditionally has been vulnerable to theft, leaving satellite communications even more accessible than typical internet communications, the vendor said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ietf-launches-working-group-to-coordinate-quantum-resistant-cryptographic-protocols"&gt;IETF launches working group to coordinate quantum-resistant cryptographic protocols&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In January 2023, the IETF launched the &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/wg/pquip/about/"&gt;Post-Quantum Use In Protocols&lt;/a&gt; (PQUIP) working group to coordinate the use of cryptographic protocols that are not susceptible to large quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The idea of the working group is to be a standing venue to discuss PQC from an operational and engineering side,” said Sofia Celi, co-chair of PQUI. “It is also a venue of last resort to discuss PQC-related issues in IETF protocols that have no associated maintenance on other working groups that the IETF has.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The IETF said the working group has been set up on an experimental basis, and in two years, it intends to review it for rechartering to continue or else closure. In August 2023, the group published the &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-pquip-pqc-engineers/"&gt;Post-Quantum Cryptography for Engineers&lt;/a&gt; paper to provide an overview of the current threat landscape and the relevant algorithms designed to help prevent those threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In September 2025, the &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-uta-pqc-app/"&gt;IETF published guidance&lt;/a&gt; for implementing post-quantum key exchanges and digital signatures in TLS 1.3 and related standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Migration roadmaps&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agencies such as the &lt;a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/news/pqc-migration-roadmap-unveiled"&gt;UK’s National Cyber Security Centre&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/csrc/media/Presentations/2025/nist-pqc-the-road-ahead/images-media/rwcpqc-march2025-moody.pdf"&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt; in the US, and the &lt;a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/coordinated-implementation-roadmap-transition-post-quantum-cryptography"&gt;European Commission&lt;/a&gt; have outlined phased roadmaps for enterprises to complete migration to post-quantum cryptography by 2035.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts urge enterprises to prepare for PQC by taking an inventory of cryptographic assets, mapping algorithmic dependencies, and aligning migration plans to NIST’s post-quantum standards, among other measures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The ongoing &lt;a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/crypto-agility-considerations-migrating-post-quantum-cryptographic-algorithms"&gt;‘Migration to PQC’ project from NIST’s NCCoE&lt;/a&gt; has also brought much-needed structure to the process, especially with September’s white paper that mapped PQC discovery and migration capabilities to frameworks like the Cybersecurity Framework 2.0 and NIST SP 800-53,” says Rik Ferguson, VP of security intelligence at Forescout. “That’s helping organizations understand where they stand and what practical steps to take.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Industry &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4074154/cisos-face-quantum-leap-in-prioritizing-quantum-resilience.html"&gt;adoption of post-quantum encryption technologies&lt;/a&gt; is building but remains uneven.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Around 8.5% of all SSH servers now support PQC key exchange, rising to 26% for OpenSSH specifically, but other technologies, such as TLS 1.3, are lagging behind,” according to Ferguson. “And when we look at unmanaged environments like IoT, OT, and medical devices, the numbers drop off sharply, often below 10%.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/654887/11-notable-post-quantum-cryptography-initiatives-launched-in-2023.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 7 agentic AI use cases for cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079887/top-7-agentic-ai-use-cases-for-cybersecurity.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Agentic AI promises to revolutionize a wide range of IT operations and services, including cybersecurity. While the technology, which accomplishes specific tasks with no human supervision, may seem intimidating to some CISOs, a growing number of cybersecurity leaders are discovering that agentic AI is less complex and easier to deploy than they initially believed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As agentic AI becomes more mature, its potential in cybersecurity is particularly compelling,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandra-mcleod-7a6a61b/"&gt;Sandra McLeod&lt;/a&gt;, CISO at Zoom, noting that many cybersecurity use cases are a strong fit for AI because they take advantage of the technology’s ability to operate at a scale and speed human teams can’t match.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI can process massive volumes of data continuously without experiencing fatigue, making it ideal for monitoring environments where human attention would eventually taper off, McLeod explains. “It’s especially useful for addressing problems that are either too large in scope or too low in priority for already-stretched security teams,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Additionally, AI’s ability to respond in real-time means it can act much faster than humans, helping to reduce the blast radius of an attack or minimize the time a threat remains undetected. “By handling high-volume or time-sensitive tasks, AI allows humans to focus on more strategic, higher-value work,” McLeod adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Is your organization ready to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4064158/agentic-ai-in-it-security-where-expectations-meet-reality.html"&gt;add agentic AI&lt;/a&gt; to its cybersecurity arsenal? Here are seven top use cases for your consideration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-autonomous-threat-detection-and-response"&gt;1. Autonomous threat detection and response&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A standout use case for agentic AI in cybersecurity is autonomous threat detection and response, which offers the ability to detect, protect, contain and recover from threats at unprecedented speed and scale, says &lt;a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/blog/authors/john-scimone/"&gt;John Scimone&lt;/a&gt;, president and CSO at Dell Technologies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This includes spotting and disrupting intrusion attempts autonomously in real-time by making security and IT changes to mitigate risks,” he explains. “Essentially, agentic AI can operate as a real-time, autonomous cyber defense agent.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks are increasingly &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053251/ai-powered-autonomous-ransomware-campaigns-are-coming-say-experts.html"&gt;executed by autonomous agents&lt;/a&gt; operating at the speed of light, far outpacing human response capabilities, Scimone says. The primary value of autonomous threat detection lies in speed and scale — two critical factors where traditional methods fall short. “Agentic AI will level the playing field by enabling defenders to respond with equal speed and expansive breadth,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-security-operations-center-support"&gt;2. Security operations center support&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3840447/security-operations-centers-are-fundamental-to-cybersecurity-heres-how-to-build-one.html"&gt;Security operations centers (SOCs)&lt;/a&gt; are a great use case for agentic AI because they serve as the frontline for detecting and responding to threats, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/naresh-persaud-3791111/"&gt;Naresh Persaud&lt;/a&gt;, principal, cyber risk services, at Deloitte.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With thousands of incidents to triage daily, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4056178/your-soc-is-the-parachute-will-it-open.html"&gt;SOCs are experiencing mounting alert fatigue&lt;/a&gt;. “Analysts can spend an average of 21 minutes or longer per ticket to remediate,” says Persaud, noting that documenting cases and collecting forensic data is a time-consuming task, while tracking vulnerabilities and user access anomalies can be a complex process. “What’s more, the volume of incidents is expected to rise as attackers increasingly employ AI to launch attacks on a broader scale.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Persaud believes that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4042494/how-ai-is-reshaping-cybersecurity-operations.html"&gt;adding agentic AI to SOCs&lt;/a&gt; makes sense given that agents can be trained to handle detection, utilize &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/228501/natural-language-processing-nlp-explained.html"&gt;natural language processing (NLP)&lt;/a&gt; to produce case documentation, integrate with identity systems to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3822459/what-is-anomaly-detection-behavior-based-analysis-for-cyber-threats.html"&gt;correlate anomalous access&lt;/a&gt;, and perform automated remediation. “More important, agentic AI SOC analysts can allow SOCs to scale geometrically as work volume fluctuates.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-automated-triage-and-enriched-of-security-event-logs"&gt;3. Automated triage and enriched of security event logs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.radware.com/blog/author/pascalg/"&gt;Pascal Geenens&lt;/a&gt;, director of threat research for cybersecurity services firm Radware, says that automated triage, combined with enriched security event logs, form a strong AI agentic use case.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Imagine an AI agent that autonomously collects indicators of compromise [IOCs] from multiple threat feeds, correlates them with internal telemetry, enriches the data with context from OSINT and CTI [cyber threat intelligence] repositories, and then drafts a structured alert for an analyst.” Instead of waiting for a SOC team to pivot manually across different platforms, the agent executes the pivoting automatically, flags anomalies, and prepares a recommended response playbook.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Geenens believes his suggested approach, like many agentic AI use cases presented here, addresses two major cybersecurity pain points: scale and speed. “Analysts are drowning in alerts and lack the time to connect dots across multiple sources,” he says. Agentic AI can effectively supplant repetitive, high-volume correlation tasks. More important, it closes the gap between detection and mitigation, enabling analysts to focus on validation and strategy rather than operations. “In practice, this doesn’t replace humans, but amplifies expertise while cutting through noise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-augmenting-security-talent"&gt;4. Augmenting security talent&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another big problem in cybersecurity doesn’t involved technology — it’s the current talent gap, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3613339/cybersecuritys-oversimplification-problem-seeing-ai-as-a-replacement-for-human-agency.html"&gt;AI agents provide that most practical answer&lt;/a&gt;, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahul-ramachandran-in/"&gt;Rahul Ramachandran&lt;/a&gt;, generative AI product management director at Palo Alto Networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI agents can act as force multiplier for your swamped security teams, automating the endless maintenance needed to keep your security posture solid and troubleshooting complex issues across your many different security tools,” he explains. “This frees up your best people to focus on critical threats instead of manual, repetitive work.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity talent gap isn’t a temporary trend — it’s a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3810857/the-cybersecurity-skills-gap-reality-we-need-to-face-the-challenge-of-emerging-tech.html"&gt;persistent reality&lt;/a&gt; we’ll be facing for years, Ramachandran warns. “You simply can’t hire your way out of this problem,” he adds. “Using AI agents is a strategic decision to invest in your existing team, making them more productive, more effective and, ultimately, happier.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-protecting-brands-against-fraud"&gt;5. Protecting brands against fraud&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fake domains have always been a headache, says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarunasbruzas/?originalSubdomain=lt"&gt;Šarūnas Bružas&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of office equipment services provider Deskronic. “An AI agent can scan for new domain registrations that appear similar to your company, grab screenshots, perform WHOIS checks, and even draft takedown requests.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bružas reports that an AI agent recently helped him catch a phishing site in less than 20 minutes from launch. “That would have normally taken days, during which time customers could have lost data and money,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another strong use case is detecting scam ads on social media. “Scammers run Facebook or Instagram ads that impersonate your brand, and an AI agent can alert you immediately so you can have them taken down before too many customers click,” he adds&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Such incidents happen quickly, and a manual team can’t keep up with the volume, Bružas says. Every hour a phishing site or scam ad is up increases the risk for fraud while damaging customer trust. “With agents always scanning for fake sites and ads, it will take less time to detect scams, and the human team is then free to focus on review instead of routine monitoring,” he notes. “In the end, this will make work smoother, limit the time attackers have to strike, and keep customers safer.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-help-desk-support"&gt;6. Help desk support&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AI agents can be used to automate common and repetitive help desk tasks, such as provisioning access to applications or troubleshooting authentication issues, freeing team members to respond quickly to requests that may not be as straightforward, says &lt;a href="https://www.guidepointsecurity.com/blog/author/ed-dunnahoeguidepointsecurity-com/"&gt;Ed Dunnahoe&lt;/a&gt;, vice president of innovation at cybersecurity services firm GuidePoint Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the context of infrastructure, agents may also be able to speed-up the process of performing root cause analysis by parsing system logs more quickly, correlating results across data sources, and giving human engineers a major head start on their investigation,” he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-autonomous-real-time-zero-trust-policy-enforcement"&gt;7. Autonomous real-time zero-trust policy enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every end user has a unique profile, reflecting specific behaviors, privileges, and risk scores, says &lt;a href="https://www.druva.com/about/leadership/stephen-manley"&gt;Stephen Manley&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at cyber resilience platform provider Druva.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Agents can monitor those users and, if there’s a deviation, can push changes to what that user can access, force a re-authentication, or even temporarily sandbox that user,” he says. This becomes even more important, he adds, for organizations that are striving for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/564201/what-is-zero-trust-a-model-for-more-effective-security.html"&gt;zero trust&lt;/a&gt;, “because you can have agents monitor non-human actors, such as other AI agents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079887/top-7-agentic-ai-use-cases-for-cybersecurity.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.94</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volvo’s recent security breach: 5 tips to speed incident response while preserving forensic integrity</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079615/volvos-recent-security-breach-5-tips-to-speed-incident-response-while-preserving-forensic-integrity.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In August 2025, Volvo Group North America disclosed that it had been impacted by a data breach originating in its third-party HR software provider, Miljödata. Although Volvo insisted its internal systems remained untouched, the timeline of detection and disclosure raises questions about forensic readiness and incident-response maturity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Miljödata first detected suspicious activity on August 23, three days after what appeared to have been the initial intrusion. It wasn’t until September 2 that they confirmed Volvo data had been exfiltrated and only then did they notify Volvo. That nearly two-week lag between detection and verified data exfiltration invites speculation around both forensic delay and communication gaps.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The breached data reportedly included Social Security numbers and other sensitive employee identifiers, classic crown-jewel data that can immediately trigger identity theft, regulatory scrutiny and class-action litigation. Volvo has offered its employees 18 months of identity-protection services, but such downstream measures are only damage control. What really matters in high-stakes incidents is how quickly and thoroughly your forensic response is conducted within the first 48 to 72 hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From over a decade of experience, including time as a computer forensic specialist at the Ohio Bureau of Criminal Investigation, one thing is clear: In breaches involving sensitive data, a slow or shaky response isn’t just a strategic misstep; it’s a litigation vector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Below are five key recommendations to help organizations respond rapidly and preserve forensic integrity, even when the breach begins in someone else’s network.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-integrate-forensics-from-day-zero-not-as-an-afterthought"&gt;1. Integrate forensics from day zero, not as an afterthought&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All too often, organizations treat forensic collection as something that is brought in after a breach has been confirmed. A mature incident-response (IR) program embeds forensic readiness in its playbooks:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and catalog your evidence sources in advance (endpoints, memory, logs, cloud assets)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Stage scripts or agents that can snapshot memory and archive logs immediately when an IR trigger fires&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Make forensic collection part of containment, not something you tack on afterward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern approaches and even &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/61/r3/final" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST’s updated guidance&lt;/a&gt; emphasize that evidence gathering should begin during, not after, containment. Too many organizations wait for clean “proof of impact” before launching forensics and by then, critical volatile artifacts (such as memory, file metadata and process chains) may be lost or overwritten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Embedding forensics from day zero also sharpens board-level visibility. When executives are briefed with clear, time-stamped evidence early in the crisis, decisions about disclosure, containment and external engagement become fact-driven instead of speculative.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-align-ir-and-forensic-goals-via-shared-metrics-and-priorities"&gt;2. Align IR and forensic goals via shared metrics and priorities&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A perennial tension in breach response is that incident responders often want to restore systems quickly, while forensic teams wish to preserve every trace. If priorities aren’t aligned in advance, you risk destroying evidence by rebooting endpoints, rotating logs or committing irreversible changes. To prevent that:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define shared metrics in your IR playbooks, e.g., “no endpoint reboot before memory capture,” or “logs preserved for 72 hours minimum.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Escalate conflicts immediately to legal or leadership roles during incident execution.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Rehearse these tradeoffs in tabletop exercises, simulating situations where speed versus evidence preservation must be balanced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hybrid DFIR frameworks increasingly emphasize that restoration and forensics shouldn’t be sequential silos; they must be integrated. The newer NIST SP 800-61 Revision 3 even &lt;a href="https://securityboulevard.com/2025/06/nist-launches-updated-incident-response-guide/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;abandons rigid life cycle models in favor of integrating detect, respond and recover functions with forensic awareness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This alignment also requires that legal and compliance teams sit at the same table. Counsel should help codify thresholds for evidence retention that satisfy both regulatory expectations (e.g., GDPR’s breach-notification timelines) and litigation discovery rules.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-automate-collection-and-triage-to-reduce-human-delay"&gt;3. Automate collection and triage to reduce human delay&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Manual forensic collection is slow and error-prone. The faster you automate snapshotting, log ingestion, metadata extraction and initial triage, the sooner you can surface smoking-gun artifacts before they vanish. Key practices:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trigger forensic scripts or agents automatically upon IR event indicators (e.g., suspicious endpoint alerts).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Use machine-learning or heuristic classifiers in the initial triage to flag anomalous files, processes or timeline anomalies, helping analysts prioritize their tasks effectively. Recent research from &lt;a href="https://www.futureengineeringjournal.com/uploads/archives/20250714190246_FEI-2025-4-018.1.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Future Engineering Journal&lt;/a&gt; supports this for DFIR tasks.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Hash, timestamp and ledger are all artifacts automatically used to strengthen the chain of custody.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Automation also helps prevent human error, especially under stress, and ensures consistency in handling large-scale evidence. In a breach like Volvo’s, the faster you can parse which employee records, SSNs or identifiers were exposed, the better your legal and mitigation posture will be.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The newest generation of DFIR platforms even integrates with SIEM and SOAR systems to trigger evidence capture the moment an anomaly crosses a defined confidence threshold. That fusion of security automation and forensic control will soon become a baseline expectation in cyber insurance underwriting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-manage-third-party-risk-with-prepared-ir-contracts-and-coordination"&gt;4. Manage third-party risk with prepared IR contracts and coordination&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Volvo’s case is emblematic of a supply-chain breach. The forensic clock started ticking in Miljödata’s systems well before Volvo had visibility. To anticipate this:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contractually require your vendors to grant timely access (for forensic analysis), synchronized metrics (e.g., time-to-notification) and early handoff of data/images in breach scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Maintain joint IR runbooks with high-risk vendors so teams know exactly who activates what when, without renegotiation under duress.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Conduct tabletop exercises jointly with vendors to test whether your coordination works under pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When the vendor becomes the root cause, you don’t want to waste hours negotiating access or waiting for them to assemble logs. That delay can destroy evidence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The average enterprise now relies on dozens of SaaS and HR platforms that process sensitive data. Yet few have verified what happens if a vendor refuses forensic access or hides behind legal review. The NIST Cybersecurity Supply Chain Risk Management guidance and frameworks, such as &lt;a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/82890.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ISO 27036&lt;/a&gt;, emphasize the importance of contractual preparation, but adoption lags significantly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Equally important is establishing reciprocal reporting obligations. If your data appears in a vendor’s compromise, you should be notified within hours, not weeks, so that you can activate your own containment and legal teams immediately.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-rethink-reporting-communication-and-escalation-for-legal-risk"&gt;5. Rethink reporting, communication and escalation for legal risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Even the most technically perfect response can fail if messaging is mishandled. Misleading or incomplete statements make you vulnerable to reputational damage, regulatory backlash and plaintiff claims. Here’s how to safeguard:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Involve legal, compliance and general counsel within hours, not days. They should guide messaging consistent with the forensic state of fact-finding.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Document every decision to isolate, restore or alter systems, including the evidence and logic behind it, to show defensible reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Delay absolutes. Avoid statements like “no internal systems were impacted” until you have forensic confirmation. In Volvo’s case, early statements of non-compromise risk appear to be cover-ups.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Map out regulatory and litigation exposure immediately (privacy, negligence, vendor liability) and design forensic returns to support or rebut each claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Poor or delayed public reporting can magnify the damage, even if your internal forensic work was impeccable. The narrative matters. Regulators, such as the FTC, SEC and the European Data Protection Board, now scrutinize timeliness as closely as technical containment. In the U.S., the SEC’s 2023 cyber-incident rule &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/rules/final/2023/33-11216.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;requires disclosure within four business days of determining materiality&lt;/a&gt; — an almost impossible window without forensic readiness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-speed-and-integrity-matter"&gt;Why speed and integrity matter&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In high-profile breaches, the differentiator is often not so much that a violation occurred, but how it was handled. A well-executed forensic response can mitigate claims of negligence, demonstrate that contaminated systems were correctly isolated and limit the exposure window. That’s especially true when sensitive employee data (SSNs, identifiers) are involved.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Volvo’s case, the nearly two-week lag between Miljödata’s detection and data confirmation warrants scrutiny. Whether it reflected a process gap or a focus on continuity over investigation, the delay increased legal exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The lesson: forensic readiness, automation, pre-arranged vendor coordination and disciplined communication aren’t optional.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations that invest in these capabilities also gain secondary benefits. Faster forensic cycles reduce downtime, improve insurer confidence and strengthen the credibility of post-incident reporting to regulators and the public.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-broader-takeaway"&gt;The broader takeaway&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Volvo-Miljödata incident is a microcosm of a growing trend: third-party breaches are accelerating and accountability is shifting downstream. Gartner predicts that by 2026, 60% of security incidents will originate from vendor ecosystems. Yet only a fraction of enterprises have built forensic clauses or joint IR drills into their vendor management programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs and CIOs, the immediate imperative is clear:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treat forensic readiness as part of cyber resilience, not a post-mortem investigation.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Embed automation and logging in every high-risk workflow.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Rehearse multiparty breach scenarios that include vendors, counsel and communications.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Design transparency into your playbook. The truth will come out; you must ensure it’s supported by evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ultimate measure of maturity isn’t avoiding every breach. It’s how quickly you can reconstruct the truth, contain the damage and communicate with credibility. An organization’s ability to act fast and cleanly under duress is often the difference between “too little, too late” and a responsible, accountable response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4079615/volvos-recent-security-breach-5-tips-to-speed-incident-response-while-preserving-forensic-integrity.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-696)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-696</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-696</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-697)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-697</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-697</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-698)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-698</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-698</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.54</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–699)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-699</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-700)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-700</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp security advisory (AV25-701)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hashicorp-security-advisory-av25-701</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.25</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Tomcat security advisory (AV25-702)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/apache-tomcat-security-advisory-av25-702</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.26</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV25-703)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av25-703</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.41</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV25-704)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av25-704</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
