<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 05:40:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-044)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV26-045)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-046)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-048)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-002 -Vulnerability affecting GNU Inetutils Telnetd - CVE-2026-24061</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OTF GRIMM: Swedish organiser of serious violence arrested in Iraq</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</link>
      <description>A High-Value Target under Europol-supported Operational Taskforce GRIMM was arrested in Iraq following long-term cooperation between the Swedish Police Authority and Iraqi law enforcement authorities. The 21-year-old suspect, a Swedish national who was listed on the EU Most Wanted list, is identified as a key organiser of serious violence directed at Sweden from abroad.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST’s AI guidance pushes cybersecurity boundaries</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123196/nists-ai-guidance-pushes-cybersecurity-boundaries.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For years, US cybersecurity guidance rested on a reassuring premise: New technologies introduce new wrinkles, but not fundamentally new problems. Artificial intelligence, according to that view, is still software, just faster, more complex, and more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The controls that protect traditional systems, the thinking went, can largely be adapted to protect AI, too. That assumption surfaced at a recent National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) &lt;a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/get-involved/attend-events/cyber-ai-workshop-2"&gt;workshop on AI and cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI systems in many ways are just smart software, fancy software with a little bit extra,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/victoriayanpillitteri/"&gt;Victoria Pillitteri&lt;/a&gt;, supervisory computer scientist in the Computer Security Division at NIST, told attendees as she summarized that long-standing view. “That means we can leverage the robust body of [cybersecurity] knowledge that already exists with some modifications, with some considerations, but we do not and should not start from scratch,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But as discussions during the event turned to AI agents and adversarial manipulation, that concept began to fray. Experts described ways in which AI strains the fundamental assumptions those frameworks rely on, namely that systems behave deterministically, that boundaries between components are stable, and that humans remain firmly in control.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Those concerns are now moving beyond internal discussion and into public standards development. On Jan. 8, NIST’s Center for AI Standards and Innovation (CAISI) issued a &lt;a href="https://public-inspection.federalregister.gov/2026-00206.pdf"&gt;formal Request for Information (RFI)&lt;/a&gt; on the secure practices and methodologies of AI agent systems, one of the most challenging aspects of AI &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4089732/rethinking-identity-for-the-ai-era-cisos-must-build-trust-at-machine-speed.html"&gt;when it comes to identity management and cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The RFI focuses on AI systems capable of taking autonomous actions that affect real-world environments and explicitly asks for input on novel risks, security practices, assessment methods, and deployment constraints.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, what should matter is that NIST is shifting from a broad, &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.600-1.pdf"&gt;principle-based AI risk management&lt;/a&gt; framework toward more operationally grounded expectations, especially for systems that act without constant human oversight. What is emerging across NIST’s AI-related cybersecurity work is a recognition that AI is no longer a distant or abstract governance issue, but a near-term security problem that the nation’s standards-setting body is trying to tackle in a multifaceted way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nists-wide-ranging-cybersecurity-and-ai-portfolio"&gt;NIST’s wide-ranging cybersecurity and AI portfolio&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although the purpose of the workshop was to solicit feedback specifically on NIST’s preliminary Cybersecurity Framework Profile for Artificial Intelligence (&lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2025/NIST.IR.8596.iprd.pdf"&gt;Cyber AI Profile&lt;/a&gt;), which is an adaptation of the community profiles emerging from &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework"&gt;NIST’s Cybersecurity Framework&lt;/a&gt;, experts addressed many other NIST practices and methodology initiatives that deal with AI-related threats and security opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These efforts show how NIST is attacking AI security from multiple angles — development, deployment, identity, privacy, and adversarial abuse — and include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Risk Management Framework. &lt;/strong&gt;Released on Jan. 26, 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework"&gt;NIST’s AI RMF&lt;/a&gt; was developed to better manage risks to individuals, organizations, and society associated with AI. “What we’re trying to do with the AI Risk Management Framework is understand how we trust AI, which operates in many ways differently in some of these tasks that we know very well,” particularly regarding how high-impact applications affect cybersecurity, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mcs729/"&gt;Martin Stanley&lt;/a&gt;, principal researcher for AI and cybersecurity at NIST, said at the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Center for AI Standards and Innovation (CAISI). &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/caisi"&gt;NIST’s CAISI&lt;/a&gt; serves as the “industry’s primary point of contact within the US government to facilitate testing and collaborative research related to harnessing and securing the potential of commercial AI systems,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/maiahamin/"&gt;Maia Hamin&lt;/a&gt;, a technical staff member of CAISI, the center that develops best practices and standards for improving AI security and collaboration. It also “leads evaluations and assessments of US and adversary AI systems, including adoption of foreign models, potential security vulnerabilities, or potential for foreign influence,” she told workshop attendees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIST AI 100-2 E2025, Adversarial Machine Learning: A Taxonomy and Terminology of Attacks and Mitigations. &lt;/strong&gt;This &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/ai/100/2/e2025/final"&gt;NIST report&lt;/a&gt;, published in March 2025,provides a taxonomy of concepts and defines terminology in the field of adversarial machine learning (AML). “Adversarial machine learning or adversarial AI is the field that studies attacks on AI systems that exploit the statistical and data-driven nature of this technology,” NIST research team supervisor &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/avassilev/"&gt;Apostol Vassilev&lt;/a&gt; said at the workshop. “Hijacking, prompt injection, indirect prompt injection, data poisoning, all these things are part of the field of study of adversarial AI,” he clarified.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dioptra. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://pages.nist.gov/dioptra/"&gt;Dioptra&lt;/a&gt; is a NIST software test platform for assessing the trustworthy characteristics of AI. “You have multiple dimensions along which you want to analyze these as you want to identify how accurate they are for a particular task,” &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/harold-booth-38ba4539/"&gt;Harold Booth&lt;/a&gt;, NIST supervisory computer scientist, said at the event. “You want to be able to identify how robust they are to various kinds of attacks,” Booth said. “You want to know how well they do against various kinds of data sets.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIST SP 800-218A, Secure Software Development Practices for Generative AI and Dual-Use Foundation Models: An SSDF Community Profile. &lt;/strong&gt;The &lt;a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-218A.pdf"&gt;AI SSDF community profile&lt;/a&gt; adds “practices, tasks, recommendations, considerations, notes, and informative references that are specific to AI model development throughout the software development life cycle.” NIST’s Booth told the workshop attendees, “This particular profile is very focused on what is new with respect to doing development for AI systems. So all the concerns that exist for normal software development still pertain. But what we were really focused on was what’s new.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PETs Testbed. &lt;/strong&gt;NIST’s &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/applied-cybersecurity/privacy-engineering/pets-testbed"&gt;PETs Testbed&lt;/a&gt; provides the capability to investigate privacy-enhancing technologies (PETs) and their respective suitability for specific use cases, helping organizations evaluate and manage privacy risks. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gshowarth/"&gt;Gary Howarth&lt;/a&gt;, who leads the privacy engineering program at NIST, said that within a few weeks, NIST will release a new version of its privacy framework that is complementary to AI risk management and cybersecurity threat modeling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIST Special Publication 800-63 Digital Identity Guidelines. &lt;/strong&gt;NIST recently updated its 2017 &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/identity-access-management/projects/nist-special-publication-800-63-digital-identity-guidelines"&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on digital identity to better embrace the process and technical requirements for meeting digital identity assurance levels, given the rapid pace of digital technical change. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-galluzzo-a100563b/"&gt;Ryan Galluzzo&lt;/a&gt;, identity program lead for NIST Applied Cybersecurity Division, stressed at the workshop that “AI agents are starting to change the kind of context and conversation around traditional cybersecurity controls. Within the context of this project, our intent is really to focus on those issues of access, those issues of how to identify agents that are operating within my enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-limits-of-ai-is-just-software"&gt;The limits of ‘AI is just software’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIST’s instinct to frame AI as an extension of traditional software allows organizations to reuse familiar concepts — risk assessment, access control, logging, defense in depth — rather than starting from zero. Workshop participants repeatedly emphasized that many controls do transfer, at least in principle.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But some experts argue that the analogy breaks down quickly in practice. AI systems behave probabilistically, not deterministically, they say. Their outputs depend on data that may change continuously after deployment. And in the case of agents, they may take actions that were not explicitly scripted in advance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs, the risk is not that AI is unrecognizable, but that it appears recognizable enough to lull organizations into applying controls mechanically. Treating AI as “just another application” can obscure new failure modes, particularly those involving &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110008/top-cyber-threats-to-your-ai-systems-and-infrastructure.html"&gt;indirect manipulation through data or prompts&lt;/a&gt; rather than direct exploitation of code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI agent systems really face a range of security threats and risks,” CAISI’s Hamin said at the workshop. “Some of these overlap with traditional software, but others kind of arise from the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4109999/agentic-ai-already-hinting-at-cybersecuritys-pending-identity-crisis.html"&gt;unique challenge of combining AI model outputs&lt;/a&gt;, which are non-deterministic, with the affordances and abilities of software tools.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cisos-should-watch-out-for-framework-fatigue"&gt;CISOs should watch out for framework fatigue&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In kicking off the workshop, NIST senior policy advisor &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kmegas/"&gt;Katerina Megas&lt;/a&gt; explained that NIST reached out to the CISO community to ask them what they need in terms of AI security guidance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Before we started down any path, we spoke to the CISO community, and we asked them, ‘So how are you all dealing with artificial intelligence? How is this affecting your day-to-day? Is this something that keeps you up at night?’ And overwhelmingly, the answer was yes, this is absolutely something that is top of mind for us. Our leadership is asking us, what are we doing?” she said at the event.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the CISOs also told NIST that they were overwhelmed with AI documentation. A lot of these publications had some overlap, but were not identical, Megas said. “If you were a consumer of all of these documents, it was very difficult for you to look at them and understand how they relate to what you are doing and also understand how to identify where two documents may be talking about the same thing and where they overlap.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If the guidance is super long, then people may not actually use it,” one workshop attendee, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/naveenkm94/"&gt;Naveen Konrajankuppam Mahavishnu&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder and CTO at Aira Security, tells CSO, suggesting that much of the material can be reduced to more digestible components.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We can have a very detailed version, maybe a hundred pages long, but also have some sort of checklist that kind of summarizes the entire 100-page paper or something into a few pages where people can easily consume it, and then they can start implementing it,” Mahavishnu says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123196/nists-ai-guidance-pushes-cybersecurity-boundaries.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV26-049)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol report: evolving tactics in maritime cocaine trafficking operations</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</link>
      <description>A new Europol report published today provides a comprehensive analysis of the evolving tactics employed by criminal networks to traffic cocaine into Europe via maritime routes. The report, 'Diversification in Maritime Cocaine Trafficking Modi Operandi', provides an in-depth analysis of the shifting tactics employed by organised crime networks, which continue to exploit vulnerabilities and evade detection.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-report-evolving-tactics-in-maritime-cocaine-trafficking-operations</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU’s answer to CVE solves dependency issue, adds fragmentation risks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123225/eus-answer-to-cve-solves-dependency-issue-adds-fragmentation-risks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The security community has offered broad support for the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118848/new-eu-vulnerability-database-launched.html"&gt;creation of an EU-hosted vulnerability database&lt;/a&gt; as a means of reducing dependence on US databases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, some experts have expressed concerns that the potential fragmentation of security intelligence risks impeding rapid vulnerability identification and remediation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Global Cybersecurity Vulnerability Enumeration database (&lt;a href="https://gcve.eu/"&gt;GCVE.eu&lt;/a&gt;) aggregates vulnerability advisories from more than 25 public sources into a single, searchable resource. Entries are normalized, structured, and cross-referenced across identifiers (e.g., CVE IDs, GCVE IDs, vendor IDs).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The platform is hosted by Computer Incident Response Center Luxembourg (CIRCL) in a Luxembourg-based data centre, with co-funding from the EU’s Federated European Team for Threat Analysis (FETTA) project.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The emergence of GCVE.eu follows a funding scare that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3963190/cve-program-faces-swift-end-after-dhs-fails-to-renew-contract-leaving-security-flaw-tracking-in-limbo.html"&gt;threatened the continuation of the long-established Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) program last year&lt;/a&gt;. The CVE program — which underpins the US National Vulnerability (NVD) database — is operated by the Mitre Corp., with funding from the cyber division of the US Department of Homeland Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="combatting-flaw-fragmentation-mapping-and-interoperability"&gt;Combatting flaw fragmentation: Mapping and interoperability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaya Baloo, co-founder, COO, and CISO at vulnerability remediation startup AISLE, says that GCVE must prioritize mapping and interoperability with CVE entries in order to be viable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Without enforceable interoperability commitments, ‘independent allocation’ becomes a polite way of saying defenders will need to check multiple incompatible systems to know if they’re vulnerable,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;David Lindner, CISO at application security vendor Contrast Security, agreed that GCVE poses a risk of creating a new silo that mirrors but doesn’t align with the NVD.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For a CISO the hard part is preventing identification collision where teams waste time triaging the same vulnerability under two different flags,” says Lindner. “To avoid this confusion and make the project viable the GCVE must prioritize an automated cross-mapping standard that bridges these databases in real-time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Simply switching from the US-run NVD to a European GCVE fails to solve the problem of dependency but only succeeds in changing the location of the silo, according to Lindner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Success requires a federated approach where vendors and researchers contribute to a unified intelligence layer ensuring that no matter which database claims the entry the industry sees a single actionable truth rather than a fragmented mess,” Lindner argues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Brian Blakley, CISO at Bellini Capital, warns that if GCVE offers only duplication without differentiation then it is liable to create a headache for security practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most security teams are already struggling with noise,” Blakley notes. “Any new database really needs to improve data quality, timeliness, or context and not just replicate identifiers under a different flag.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GCVE has cross-vulnerability referencing built in, with both automated and human-curated mechanisms, an approach most experts quizzed by CSO would minimise confusion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Zbyněk Sopuch, CTO of data security vendor Safetica, was more upbeat arguing that GCVE is designed to be backwards compatible with CVE, so “existing data is preserved and independent entries are allowed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The gray areas arise in scope, ID formats, and fragmented tracking, and there are steps that the GSVE can take to ensure that critical data is shared and received,” says Sopuch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="coordinated-disclosure"&gt;Coordinated disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nik Kale, principal engineer and product architect at Cisco Systems, says GCVE’s main challenge comes from building a platform that the security community can rely on for coordinated disclosure and remediation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Viability depends far more on governance than on the data itself,” Kale says. “That includes clear attribution rules, transparent CNA processes, predictable decision-making, and an explicit commitment to synchronization rather than fragmentation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US-run NVD system is long established so any parallel system must either federate cleanly with that existing infrastructure or provide clear operational advantages that justify switching, according to Kale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Researchers will gravitate toward whichever system enables the fastest, most reliable coordinated disclosure,” says Kale. “Vendors, meanwhile, need confidence that vulnerability records will be handled consistently regardless of where they originate.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Representatives of the GCVE project told CSO that CIRCL has both the relevant experience, &lt;a href="https://gcve.eu/process/"&gt;governance structures&lt;/a&gt;, and backing to make the database successful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CIRCL has been operating multiple services and open-source projects for more than 15 years, with sustained financial and in-kind support from the public sector, private sector, and EU and international organisations,” they explain. “GCVE.eu implements a level of governance that enables efficient operation, rapid delivery, and, most importantly, distributed allocation of identifiers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GCVE.eu has been fully functional and operational for several months. “We already deliver &lt;a href="https://www.vulnerability-lookup.org/"&gt;Vulnerability-Lookup&lt;/a&gt; as a complete open-source software and provide a reference database that facilitates the work of many organisations involved in vulnerability management,” GCVE tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="empowering-security-researchers"&gt;Empowering security researchers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Fabian Gasser of cybersecurity consultancy Cyway says that GCVE brings benefits in removing the single point of failure inherent in reliance on the US-led CVE system while democratising vulnerability publishing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GCVE gives “more of a voice to independent security researchers, who can now also agree or disagree with vendor-self-assessments,” according to Gasser.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Daniel dos Santos, senior director and head of research at cybersecurity vendor Forescout, says that its &lt;a href="https://www.forescout.com/resources/exposing-the-exploited-a-quantitative-analysis-of-vulnerabilities-under-the-radar/"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; found a significant number of vulnerabilities without CVE IDs and even some that are exploited by threat actors. The GCVE has the potential to more quickly flag up exploited vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The GCVE DB has the advantage of aggregating several sources of vulnerability information and having a decentralized system of numbering authorities,” according to dos Santos.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="redundancy"&gt;Redundancy&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ferhat Dikbiyik, chief research and intelligence officer at cyber risk intelligence firm Black Kite, says the launch of GCVE is welcome following the funding scares of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For years, we treated the US-led CVE system as an immutable backbone,” Dr. Dikbiyik says. “When that backbone showed signs of stress due to budget politics, the world realized that relying on a single, centralized thread for vulnerability tracking was a strategic risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Localized vulnerability databases are already a reality in other regions, such as China.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Chinese platform is generally faster at indexing vendor disclosures and provides additional information compared to the US alternative,” says Martin Jartelius, AI product director at cybersecurity vendor Outpost24.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the GCVE to move from a regional project to a global standard, the focus must shift to integration with enterprise security tools, Dr. Dikbiyik argues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A database is only as valuable as the tools that use it,” says Dr. Dikbiyik. “To make this project viable, we need to see security vendors, scanner providers, and GRC platforms treat the GCVE not as an extra feature, but as a core data source.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The GCVE is less about competition and more about ensuring continuity, so that vulnerability disclosures don’t hinge on a single point of failure, according to Crystal Morin, senior cybersecurity strategist at Sysdig.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The success of the EU [vulnerability database] will be measured by how it complements existing efforts and supports faster triage, a smaller backlog, risk prioritization, and consistent access to quality data for the security community,” Morin says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123225/eus-answer-to-cve-solves-dependency-issue-adds-fragmentation-risks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reports of GDPR violations have risen sharply</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122281/reports-of-gdpr-violations-have-risen-sharply.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to a recent &lt;a href="https://www.dlapiper.com/en/insights/publications/2026/01/dla-piper-gdpr-fines-and-data-breach-survey-january-2026"&gt;report by law firm DLA Piper&lt;/a&gt;, organizations are increasingly being reported for violations of the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/562107/general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr-requirements-deadlines-and-facts.html"&gt;General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the study, the average number of daily reports has risen above 400 for the first time since the GDPR came into force across the EU on May 25, 2018. With 443 reports of violations per day, the number in 2025 was 22% higher than the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the data does not allow for any definitive conclusions about the causes of this increase, according to DLA Piper. The law firm believes that geopolitical tensions, the multitude of new technologies available to cyber threat actors, and a number of new laws mandating the reporting of security incidents are likely among the key factors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="e1-2-billion-in-gdpr-fines"&gt;€1.2 billion in GDPR fines&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to DLA Piper, the total amount of fines, at around €1.2 billion, was roughly the same as the previous year. However, this high sum also demonstrates that European data protection authorities remain willing to impose substantial fines. Since the GDPR came into effect, a total of €7.1 billion in fines has been levied.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Broken down by country, Ireland, where US tech giants like Apple, Google, and Meta have their EU headquarters, once again leads the enforcement statistics: The total fines imposed by the Irish Data Protection Commission have reached €4.04 billion since the GDPR came into force in May 2018.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This includes the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567531/the-biggest-data-breach-fines-penalties-and-settlements-so-far.html"&gt;highest fine ever imposed under the GDPR&lt;/a&gt;, amounting to €1.2 billion against Meta Platforms Ireland Ltd. Furthermore, in April 2025, TikTok Technology Ltd. was fined €530 million for transferring personal user data to China.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, DLA Piper points out that the risks of GDPR compliance are not limited to administrative fines. There is also the risk of subsequent claims for damages. Several landmark rulings by the CJEU and national European courts have addressed GDPR-related compensation claims — particularly regarding the requirements for claims for non-material damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4122281/reports-of-gdpr-violations-have-risen-sharply.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA chief uploaded sensitive government files to public ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124320/cisa-chief-uploaded-sensitive-government-files-to-public-chatgpt.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The acting director of the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency uploaded sensitive government contracting documents to a public version of ChatGPT last summer, triggering automated security alerts and raising questions about AI governance at the agency responsible for defending federal networks and critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Madhu Gottumukkala, who has led CISA since May 2025, uploaded at least four documents marked “for official use only” to OpenAI’s ChatGPT platform between mid-July and early August, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2026/01/27/cisa-madhu-gottumukkala-chatgpt-00749361" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Politico reported&lt;/a&gt;. The documents contained contracting information not intended for public release.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity sensors detected the activity in early August, generating several alerts in the first week alone, according to the report citing four Department of Homeland Security officials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident occurred despite Gottumukkala having personally requested special permission to use ChatGPT shortly after joining CISA. At the time, the AI tool was blocked for most DHS employees over concerns that sensitive information could be retained outside federal systems, the report added, citing the DHS officials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Data entered into the public version of ChatGPT can be incorporated into the model’s training data and exposed to hundreds of millions of users. Unlike DHS-approved AI tools with controls preventing inputs from leaving federal networks, the public ChatGPT retains uploaded information on OpenAI servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprise-ai-governance-failures-exposed"&gt;Enterprise AI governance failures exposed&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident highlights systemic failures in how government agencies, and by extension, enterprises, manage AI tool exceptions for senior officials, security analysts said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“FOUO is not classified, but it is still sensitive government information,” said Arjun Chauhan, practice director at Everest Group. “Uploading it to a public AI tool creates real exposure: loss of data control, expanded exposure surface, secondary misuse risk, and policy boundary collapse.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The pattern mirrors early enterprise incidents where employees pasted confidential material into ChatGPT, Chauhan said. The critical difference is that controls reportedly existed at CISA, and the breach occurred through an exception pathway. “That highlights a core governance failure. Exceptions and senior access are often where AI controls break down.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Federal agencies now have &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/646291/if-you-dont-already-have-a-generative-ai-security-policy-theres-no-time-to-lose.html"&gt;AI policies&lt;/a&gt; and governance bodies, but the gap appears to be in execution rather than intent, according to Chauhan. Safe, approved AI tools are not always the default or most usable option, and enforcement varies by role and seniority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sunil Varkey, advisor at Beagle Security, said the incident reflects a broader organizational challenge. “Leadership teams may reference these tools positively for learning, productivity, and communication refinement, which unintentionally normalizes their use,” he said. “As a result, such platforms have rapidly become de facto productivity applications without being treated with the governance rigor typically applied to enterprise systems handling sensitive information.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The tension between convenience and security often drives such incidents, Varkey added. Because “for official use only” data is not formally classified, users frequently underestimate its operational, contractual, or reputational impact.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jaishiv Prakash, director analyst at Gartner, said the biggest risk when officials upload FOUO-marked documents to public AI platforms is losing control over the data. “You have no visibility into how long it’s retained, whether it can ever be deleted, or if it becomes exposed during legal holds or discovery.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations must provide employees with licensed, governed AI platforms featuring supplier-agreed data residency, strict no-training guarantees, and minimal retention, Prakash said. “Without that, people will continue turning to public AI tools out of convenience, putting sensitive information at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="leadership-credibility-questioned"&gt;Leadership credibility questioned&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The uploads triggered an internal DHS assessment involving the department’s then-acting general counsel Joseph Mazzara and chief information officer Antoine McCord, along with CISA’s chief information officer Robert Costello and chief counsel Spencer Fisher, the report said. The outcome has not been disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the report, CISA spokesperson Marci McCarthy confirmed that Gottumukkala received approval to use ChatGPT under DHS safeguards and described the usage as “short-term and limited.” She said he last used the tool in mid-July 2025 under an authorized temporary exception and that CISA’s default policy blocks ChatGPT access unless an exception is granted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fact that automated alerts triggered shows controls can detect misuse, analysts said, but the incident occurring at the leadership level raises accountability questions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Because this involves the head of the civilian cybersecurity agency, the impact is largely reputational,” Chauhan said. “Leaders set behavioral norms. Deviations undermine compliance culture and weaken credibility when advising other agencies and critical infrastructure operators.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The ChatGPT incident adds to mounting controversies surrounding Gottumukkala’s brief tenure. In December, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/12/21/cisa-acting-director-madhu-gottumukkala-polygraph-investigation-00701996" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Politico reported&lt;/a&gt; that he failed a counterintelligence polygraph test in late July and that DHS subsequently suspended six career staffers, characterizing the polygraph as “unsanctioned.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA has &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829710/firing-of-130-cisa-staff-worries-cybersecurity-industry.html"&gt;lost a significant number of its workforce&lt;/a&gt; since the Trump administration took office, with personnel dropping from over 3,300 to around 2,200 through buyouts, early retirements, and layoffs. The agency faces proposed budget cuts of nearly $500 million for fiscal year 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gottumukkala previously served as South Dakota’s chief information officer under then-Governor Kristi Noem, now DHS secretary. CISA did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124320/cisa-chief-uploaded-sensitive-government-files-to-public-chatgpt.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large migrant smuggling operation in Bulgaria leads to 16 arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</link>
      <description>A Bulgarian-led investigation, carried out in close cooperation with the Hellenic Police and supported by Europol, has led to the dismantlement of an organised criminal network involved in smuggling of migrants from Türkiye via Bulgaria and onward through Serbia or Romania towards Western European countries. The investigation was conducted within the framework of a regional Operational Taskforce established to target migrant smuggling networks using Bulgaria as a transit country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/large-migrant-smuggling-operation-in-bulgaria-leads-to-16-arrests</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – January 2026 quarterly rollup (AV26-042) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.61</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti patches two actively exploited critical vulnerabilities in EPMM</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125196/ivanti-patches-two-actively-exploited-critical-vulnerabilities-in-epmm.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT software company Ivanti released patches for its Endpoint Manager Mobile (EPMM) product to fix two new remote code execution vulnerabilities already under attack in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are aware of a very limited number of customers whose solution has been exploited at the time of disclosure,” the company said in &lt;a href="https://forums.ivanti.com/s/article/Security-Advisory-Ivanti-Endpoint-Manager-Mobile-EPMM-CVE-2026-1281-CVE-2026-1340?language=en_US"&gt;a security advisory&lt;/a&gt; that identifies the new flaws as CVE-2026-1281 and CVE-2026-1340.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both issues are described by Ivanti as code injection issues that can be exploited without authentication and are rated 9.8 out of 10 on the CVSS severity scale. The flaws involve EPMM’s In-House Application Distribution and Android File Transfer Configuration features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="stand-alone-patches-and-exploit-details-available"&gt;Stand-alone patches and exploit details available&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ivanti has not released new fully patched versions of EPMM, but rather version-specific stand-alone patches that need to be applied manually. The patches are packaged as rpm files and can be installed with the &lt;code&gt;install rpm url [patch_url]&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The RPM_12.x.0.x patch is applicable to EPMM software versions 12.5.0.x, 12.6.0.x, and 12.7.0.x. It is also compatible with the older 12.3.0.x and 12.4.0.x versions. Meanwhile the RPM_12.x.1.x patch is applicable to versions 12.5.1.0 and 12.6.1.0.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The RPM script does not survive a version upgrade,” the company warns. “If after applying the RPM script to your appliance, you upgrade to a new version you will need to reinstall the RPM. The permanent fix for this vulnerability will be included in the next product release: 12.8.0.0.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the Ivanti Sentry gateway product that secures traffic between mobile devices and back-end enterprise systems is not directly affected by these vulnerabilities, EPMM appliances do have command execution permission on Sentry gateways. As such, if an EPMM deployment has been compromised, the attackers might have compromised Ivanti Sentry as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers from penetration testing firm WatchTowr reverse engineered the patches and were able to figure out where the vulnerabilities are located and how to exploit them. A &lt;a href="https://labs.watchtowr.com/someone-knows-bash-far-too-well-and-we-love-it-ivanti-epmm-pre-auth-rces-cve-2026-1281-cve-2026-1340/"&gt;detailed write-up&lt;/a&gt; is available on the company’s blog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="exploit-detection-and-remediation"&gt;Exploit detection and remediation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ivanti published &lt;a href="https://forums.ivanti.com/s/article/Analysis-Guidance-Ivanti-Endpoint-Manager-Mobile-EPMM-CVE-2026-1281-CVE-2026-1340?language=en_US"&gt;a separate document&lt;/a&gt; with guidance on how to scan EPMM appliances for potential compromise through these vulnerabilities. First off, the Apache Access Log found at &lt;code&gt;/var/log/httpd/https-access_log&lt;/code&gt; could have evidence of attempted or successful execution of these vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company advises triaging logs with the &lt;code&gt;^(?!127\.0\.0\.1:\d+ .*$).*?\/mifs\/c\/(aft|app)store\/fob\/.*?404&lt;/code&gt; regular expression and looking for HTTP 404 error response codes as well as GET requests with parameters that have bash commands.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The most common is the introduction of, or modification of, malicious files to introduce web shell capabilities,” the company said. “Ivanti has commonly seen these changes target HTTP error pages, such as 401.jsp. Any requests to these pages with POST methods or with parameters should be considered highly suspicious. Analysts who are performing forensic inspection of the disk should also review for unexpected WAR or JAR files being introduced to the system.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One thing to note is that attackers regularly delete logs to hide their tracks and that on systems with high utilization the logs might be rotated multiple times a day. That’s why customers are strongly advised to use the Data Export features to forward logs from the EPMM appliance to their SIEM system or other log aggregators.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For any appliance that you suspect may be impacted, Ivanti recommends reviewing:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPMM administrators for new or recently changed administrators&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Authentication configuration, including SSO and LDAP settings&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;New pushed applications for mobile devices&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Configuration changes to applications you push to devices, including in-house applications&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;New or recently modified policies&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Network configuration changes, including any network configuration or VPN configuration you push to mobile devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After restoring a compromised EPMM appliance from clean backups, customers should reset the password of any local EPMM accounts, reset the password of any LDAP and/or KDC service accounts used to perform lookups, revoke and replace the public certificate used on the EPMM deployment and reset the password for any other internal or external service accounts configured on the EPMM solution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because EPMM has command execution on Sentry and Sentry is a product that routes traffic from mobile devices to internal network systems, the systems that Sentry can access should also be reviewed for signs of compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125196/ivanti-patches-two-actively-exploited-critical-vulnerabilities-in-epmm.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roughly half of employees are using unsanctioned AI tools, and enterprise leaders are major culprits</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124775/roughly-half-of-employees-are-using-unsanctioned-ai-tools-and-enterprise-leaders-are-major-culprits-2.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Shadow AI, the secret, unapproved use of AI by employees, isn’t going away. In fact, workers are getting more brazen, and their employers often don’t seem to care.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a new BlackFog survey, nearly half (49%) of workers admit to adopting &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4086912/how-shadow-it-leaves-every-industry-in-the-dark.html" target="_blank"&gt;AI tools without employer approval&lt;/a&gt;, many using free versions with which they are freely sharing sensitive enterprise data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But perhaps more alarmingly, a wide majority — 69% of presidents and C-suite members and 66% of directors and senior VPs — seem to be OK with this, prioritizing speed over privacy as they race to adopt AI tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The efficiency gains and personnel cost savings are too large to ignore, and override any security concerns,” said &lt;a href="https://www.blackfog.com/dr-darren-williams-founder-ceo/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Darren Williams&lt;/a&gt;, BlackFog founder and CEO. The research is a “stark indication” of the wide use of unapproved AI tools in the enterprise, and also the “level of risk tolerance amongst employees and senior leaders.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="shadow-ai-by-the-numbers"&gt;Shadow AI by the numbers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.blackfog.com/blackfog-research-shadow-ai-threat-grows/"&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; of 2,000 workers at companies with more than 500 employees found that &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4044007/shadow-ai-is-surging-getting-ai-adoption-right-is-your-best-defense.html" target="_blank"&gt;shadow AI&lt;/a&gt; is rampant, and not much is being done to rein it in. Of those surveyed, 86% said they use AI on a weekly basis at work, the most common use cases being in technical support, sales (such as email marketing), and contracts. But more than one-third of them admitted to using the free versions of company-approved tools, raising questions about where sensitive corporate data is being stored and processed. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Furthermore:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;51% have connected AI tools to work systems or apps without the approval or knowledge of IT;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;63% believe it’s acceptable to use AI when there is no corporate-approved option or IT oversight;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;60% say speed is worth the security risk;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;21% think employers will simply “turn a blind eye” as long as they’re getting their work done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And the C-suite’s own use of shadow tools? That’s a little more difficult to gauge; they’re close-lipped about it, indicating a wider problem, Williams noted. “Senior executives often don’t want to admit they are using AI,” he said. Instead, they’re trying to prove how valuable they are without disclosing their own AI use.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just like workers elsewhere in the enterprise, “senior leaders are able to get more done faster than ever” with AI, he noted. For instance, he said, “you can draft a legal contract in seconds and get a lawyer to review, rather than spend weeks drafting and redrafting using external counsel.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Concerningly, when it comes to the tools workers are using, free versions tend to be the most popular. More than half (58%) of employees using non-approved tools rely on free versions, and 34% of those working at companies that do allow AI tools are also opting for the free version.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Non-paid is almost certainly worse because of the licensing and business models around them,” said Williams. “There is always a cost to using free tools; in this case it’s the value of your data.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And employees are not shy about loading sensitive data into &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117010/4-issues-holding-back-cisos-security-agendas.html" target="_blank"&gt;unsanctioned AI tools&lt;/a&gt;: 33% admit to sharing enterprise research or datasets; 27% to revealing employee data (such as salary or performance tracking); 23% to inputting company financial information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This becomes dangerous because virtually all free tools use ingested data to train their models, and some of the lower-tiered paid tools do, too, Williams pointed out. “And,” he said, “you cannot get this information back.” Paid enterprise plans typically allow companies to turn off training on their data, but not always. Admins must check this with their large language model (LLM) providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The big problem is the loss of intellectual property,” said Williams. And threat actors can get access to this information to profile and target an organization, breach their networks, and exfiltrate confidential data for extortion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The more data that is disclosed to LLMs, the more information is available [to threat actors] to build a better profile,” Williams noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enterprises-must-build-policies-around-ai-use"&gt;Enterprises must build policies around AI use&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many CEOs have been mandating AI adoption and are allocating capital throughout the business for this purpose, Williams noted. Executives are looking for cost savings as a strategic advantage and a way to quickly return shareholder value.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, security is an afterthought, he said. “Many companies have just chosen to ignore the problem, and have decided not to create a policy or see the value in paying for the technology, which is a very big mistake.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations are “flying blind,” and 99% have no way of even knowing what is happening in their environments because there are no products in place to measure it, he observed. This should raise serious red flags for security teams, and there must be greater oversight and visibility into these security blind spots.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Williams advised enterprises to audit what is going on inside their systems, measure the scope of the problem, define policies around AI use, and adopt governance frameworks to control it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Further, employees must be made aware of the risks. Many, CISOs included, don’t actually understand the extent of the problem and its broader implications. “Education is essential and doesn’t require a lot of work,” said Williams. On the other hand, implementing a policy and framework does, and enterprises first need to decide what risks they are willing to live with.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, he said, we are navigating an unprecedented time in history, with new technology advancing at such a rapid pace that the technologists themselves don’t even know where it is going. Enterprises must quickly understand the implications, and use AI responsibly to gain a strategic advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Just as the industrial revolution and the internet changed the way we worked, AI is doing the same,” said Williams. “In fact, we expect this to be an even bigger shift than either of those transitions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4124760/roughly-half-of-employees-are-using-unsanctioned-ai-tools-and-enterprise-leaders-are-major-culprits.html" target="_blank"&gt;CIO.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124775/roughly-half-of-employees-are-using-unsanctioned-ai-tools-and-enterprise-leaders-are-major-culprits-2.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 03:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human risk management: CISOs’ solution to the security awareness training paradox</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123230/human-risk-management-cisos-solution-to-the-security-awareness-training-paradox.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity guru Bruce Scheier is often quoted as saying, “People are the weakest link in the security chain.” No more accurate words have ever been spoken about cybersecurity. You can spend millions of dollars on firewalls, endpoint security tools, access controls, and data encryption, but one employee can cause a catastrophic security breach, simply by downloading a malicious file or clicking on a rogue link.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Industry research indicates that 70% to 90% of breaches are the result of employees succumbing to social engineering, making skills-based errors, sharing sensitive data with shadow IT services, or through a compromise of a privileged user. Oh, and things seem to be getting worse as adversaries &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3982379/deepfake-attacks-are-inevitable-cisos-cant-prepare-soon-enough.html"&gt;adopt sophisticated AI-based attacks like deepfakes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, this problem is well known. As a countermeasure, organizations spent around $6 billion on &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;security awareness training (SAT)&lt;/a&gt; in 2025. While some firms did so as a best practice, most did so to comply with industry or government regulations such as HIPAA (requires a “security awareness and training program” for all workforce members per 45 CFR § 164.308), GDPR (article 39(1)(b) tasks data protection officers with “awareness-raising and training of staff”), PCI (requirement 12.6 mandates a formal program to make all personnel aware of cardholder data security), and many others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Industry research indicates that SAT expenses will increase by an estimated 15% per year as organizations continue to invest in what Gartner calls “security behavior and culture programs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-security-awareness-training-paradox"&gt;The security awareness training paradox&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While security awareness training has become a CISO and HR staple, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/1246117/8-reasons-your-cybersecurity-training-program-sucks-and-how-to-fix-it.html"&gt;it continues to have questionable efficacy&lt;/a&gt;. Some organizations treat SAT as a checkbox exercise for regulatory compliance, with little regard to its value. Employees exacerbate this folly through “compliance theater,” clicking through tutorials as fast as possible &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/567841/5-reasons-users-hate-cybersecurity-awareness-training-and-how-to-make-them-love-it.html"&gt;to get them out of their way&lt;/a&gt;. Even studious employees can suffer from the “forgetting curve,” a psychological model that illustrates how information is lost over time when there is no attempt to retain it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In some cases, SAT can even be counterproductive. In some studies, employees who receive high grades with security awareness training become overly confident and complacent with their security behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my humble opinion, there’s a disillusioning situation here I call the security awareness training paradox. Despite regulatory compliance requirements and significant investment, SAT seems to deliver marginal benefits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Clearly, SAT is broken — even with peripheral improvements like synthetic phishing tools. So, what’s needed? Over the next few years, organizations should shift from static/sporadic security training to an emerging discipline called human risk management (HRM).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-is-human-risk-management"&gt;What is human risk management?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HRM is defined as a cybersecurity strategy that identifies, measures, and reduces the risks caused by human behavior. Simply stated, security awareness training is about what employees know; HRM is about what they do (i.e., their actual cybersecurity behavior).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To be more specific, HRM integrates into email security tools, web gateways, and identity and access management (IAM) systems to identify human vulnerabilities. Furthermore, it measures risk using behavioral data and pinpoints an organization’s riskiest users. HRM then seeks to mitigate these risks by applying targeted interventions such as micro-learning, simulations, or automated security controls. Finally, HRM monitors behavioral changes so organizations can track progress.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There’s a misconception out there that HRM and SAT are different animals, so organizations interested in HRM must budget for both. Wrong. In fact, leading HRM solutions from vendors such as Fable Security, KnowBe4, and Mimecast offer HRM products chock full of standard SAT material. They even provide specific training support for regulatory compliance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="democratizing-security-training-with-ai"&gt;Democratizing security training with AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I know what you’re thinking. HRM sounds like the latest buzz term coined by the cybersecurity industry marketing glitterati. Yeah, kind of true, but generic HRM has an AI-based partner riding shotgun. And unlike general industry AI hype, there’s research and expert agreement that AI is well positioned to change education as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In his book &lt;em&gt;Co-Intelligence: Living and Working with AI, &lt;/em&gt;University of Pennsylvania professor Ethan Mollick suggests that AI will deliver personalized learning at scale where AI acts as a “Socratic tutor” that “nudges” students toward excellence, provides simulations and role plays, and offers persona-based learning. In an HRM context, a “nudge” can be thought of as continuous micro-learning. A user clicks on a malicious link and is guided toward an appropriate security lesson aimed at reinforcing good hygiene and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Armed with AI, HRM will also understand habits and ways of learning. For example, Alice tends to learn best through written descriptions while Bob prefers watching videos. Leading HRM tools can also role play with users, gamifying cybersecurity training and playing on their competitive nature. Thus, HRM (with AI) has the potential to democratize expertise in a new and unique way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From an ROI perspective, HRM offers a much more granular approach to cyber-risk mitigation than standard SAT. CISOs and HR managers can report on improved cyber hygiene and behavior, rather than how many employees have been trained and past generic tests. Repeat offenders are not only identified but also provided with personalized training tools and attention. Ultimately, HRM makes it possible to show a direct correlation between training and a reduction in actual security incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To quote Aristotle, “We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a habit.” HRM is intended to personalize training to change behavior and habits. If Aristotle were a CISO, he’d surely see the logic in moving from generic SAT to HRM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4123230/human-risk-management-cisos-solution-to-the-security-awareness-training-paradox.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CSO guide to top security conferences</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/559539/the-cso-guide-to-top-security-conferences.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is nothing like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/539824/data-protection-security-conferences-why-go.html"&gt;attending a face-to-face event&lt;/a&gt; for career networking and knowledge gathering, and we don’t have to tell you how helpful it can be to get a hands-on demo of a new tool or to have your questions answered by experts. Fortunately, plenty of great conferences are coming up in the months ahead. If keeping abreast of security trends and evolving threats is critical to your job — and we know it is — then attending some top-notch security conferences is on your must-do list for 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;From major events to those that are more narrowly focused, this list from the editors of CSO, will help you find the security conferences that matter the most to you. We’ll keep it updated with new conferences so check back often. While we don’t expect this calendar to be comprehensive, we do aim to have it be highly relevant. If there’s something we’ve missed, let us know. You can email your additions, corrections and updates to &lt;a href="mailto:samira_sarraf@foundryco.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samira Sarraf&lt;/a&gt;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="february-2026"&gt;February 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cybersec-asia.net/"&gt;Cybersec Asia Shield your Core&lt;/a&gt;, Bangkok, Thailand: 4-5 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.intelliguards.com/intellic0n-speakers"&gt;Intellic0n&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 5-6 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cruisecon.com/"&gt;CruiseCon&lt;/a&gt;, departs from Florida, US: 7-12 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hackcon.org/hackcon21"&gt;HackCon&lt;/a&gt;, Oslo, Norway: 9-10 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://anz.cs4ca.com/"&gt;#CS4CA ANZ&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, Australia: 10-11 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://planetcybersec.com/021126-conference/"&gt;Planet Cyber Sec Conference&lt;/a&gt;, California, US: 11 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/detroit-mi-2026/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Detroit Cybersecurity Conference&lt;/a&gt;, Michigan, US: 19 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSidesGalway&lt;/a&gt;, Galway, Ireland: 21 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cosac.net/apac/"&gt;Cosac APAC&lt;/a&gt;, Melbourne, Australia: 24-26 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/st-louis-mo-2026/"&gt;St. Louis Futurecon Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;, Missouri, US: 26 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://federation.edu.au/icsl/icsl-conferences/mre-2025"&gt;Malware and Reverse Engineering Conference MRE 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Melbourne, Australia: 26-27 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsides.org/w/page/12194156/FrontPage"&gt;BSides Seattle&lt;/a&gt;, Washington State, US: 27-28 February&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://federation.edu.au/icsl/icsl-conferences/bsides-ballarat-2026"&gt;BSides Ballarat&lt;/a&gt;, Melbourne, Australia: 28 Feb-1 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="march-2026"&gt;March 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cloudsecurityexpo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cloud &amp;amp; Cyber Security Expo&lt;/a&gt;, London, UK: 4-5 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://athackctf.com/"&gt;@Hack&lt;/a&gt;, Montreal, Canada: 7-8 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/apac/security-risk-management-india"&gt;Gartner Security &amp;amp; Risk Management Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Mumbai, India: 9- 10 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/emea/identity-access-management-uk"&gt;Gartner Identity &amp;amp; Access Management Summit&lt;/a&gt;, London, UK: 9-10 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://us.cisionone.cision.com/c/eJwszktuAyEQBNDTDDus5jN8Fiy88QV8AAvoxkYBOwESJbePJsr2lapUGKTLGgyjIKwGMOB3xR4BrECNReTohAIsufi0kwUrjSeLidVgbLLKQzQegG5Cg0pZOAeubBpmRXqrH7zH2mhMbpLT3hqDluv2vdLpCFgLj7Xe56bOm7xs8jJXXNReObZTqq3V5329nvkn0Zifvdd1yq--yQvrhDXyQY3iJF4x_MHtHzZ1NiC9YSNcY68j3q5xjHjcqng_Nthcg6gfTY3SKAnEC6XCtbaO-4yC72CzzOhI7Zl9BfkbAAD__xfTXGc" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Billington State and Local CyberSecurity Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Washington, DC, US: 9-11 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ciprna-expo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Critical Infrastructure Protection &amp;amp; Resilience North America&lt;/a&gt;, Louisiana, US: 10-12 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/tampa-fl-2026/"&gt;FutureCon Tampa&lt;/a&gt;, Florida, US: 12 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://nextitsecurity.com/nordics-march-12-2026/"&gt;Next IT Security&lt;/a&gt;, Stockholm, Sweden: 12 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cyberflorida.org/sunshine/"&gt;CyberBay 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Florida, US: 12-13 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/apac/security-risk-management-australia"&gt;Gartner Security &amp;amp; Risk Management Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Sydney, Australia: 16-17 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/cyber-security-training-events/sans-osint-summit-2025/"&gt;SANS OSINT Summit &amp;amp; Training&lt;/a&gt;, virtual and Virginia, US: 16-22 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.secureworld.io/details/boston-ma-2025/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SecureWorld Charlotte&lt;/a&gt;, North Carolina, US: 18 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://futureconevents.com/events/philadelphia-pa-2026/"&gt;FutureCon Philadelphia&lt;/a&gt;, Pennsylvania, US: 19 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://asiseurope.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ASIS Europe&lt;/a&gt;, Antwerp, Belgium: 23-25 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://heliview.com/security-leadership/"&gt;Security Leadership 2026&lt;/a&gt;, Utrecht, Netherlands: 24 March&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://europe.forum-incyber.com/"&gt;InCyber Forum Europe&lt;/a&gt;, Lille, France: 31 Mar – 2 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="april-2026"&gt;April 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cyphercon.com/"&gt;Cyphercon&lt;/a&gt;, Wisconsin, US: 1-2 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/emea/security-risk-management-uae" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gartner Security &amp;amp; Risk Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Dubai, UAE: 5-7 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.secureworld.io/details/boston-ma-2026/"&gt;SecureWorld Boston&lt;/a&gt;, Massachusetts, US: 8-9 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://specterops.io/so-con/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpecterOps SO-CON 2025&lt;/a&gt;, Virginia, US: 13-14 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://nextitsecurity.com/benelux-april-2026/"&gt;Next IT Security&lt;/a&gt;, Amsterdam, Netherlands: 16 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://govdata.com.au/"&gt;Aus Gov Data Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Canberra, Australia: 21-23 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blackhat.com/asia-26/"&gt;Black Hat Asia&lt;/a&gt;, Marina Bay Sands, Singapore: 21-24 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sccybersecurity.com/cyber-security-summit-europe/"&gt;Third Party and Supply Chain Cyber Security Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Munich, Germany: 22-24 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.secureworld.io/details/houston-tx-2026/"&gt;SecureWorld Houston&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, US: 30 April&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="may-2026"&gt;May 2026&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.devopsbootcamp.net/cybersecfest-saopaulo"&gt;CyberSecFest SP&lt;/a&gt;, São Paulo, Brazil: May TBC&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/559539/the-cso-guide-to-top-security-conferences.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.18</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-050)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-050</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-050</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–051)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-051</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-051</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-052)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-052</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-052</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-053)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-053</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-053</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-054)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-054</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-054</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-055)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-055</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-055</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-056)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-056</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-056</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-057)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-057</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-057</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIS2: Lieferketten als Risikofaktor</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124984/nis2-lieferketten-als-risikofaktor.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt; srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2500w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=300%2C168&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=1240%2C697&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=854%2C480&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/shutterstock_2667391403.png?resize=444%2C250&amp;amp;quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="576" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;NIS2 verpflichtet CISOs die Sicherheit der Supply Chain stärker in den Blick zu nehmen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Summit Art Creations – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-illusion-der-eigenen-sicherheitszone"&gt;Die Illusion der eigenen Sicherheitszone&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Viele Unternehmen investieren heute erhebliche Mittel, um ihre interne IT abzusichern. Firewalls, Monitoring, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3842982/6-wichtige-punkte-fur-ihren-incident-response-plan.html" target="_blank"&gt;Incident-Response-Pläne&lt;/a&gt; und Awareness-Programme sind etabliert. Gleichzeitig wächst eine gefährliche Illusion: Die Annahme, dass sich Risiken innerhalb der eigenen Systemgrenzen kontrollieren lassen. Die Realität sieht anders aus. Moderne Geschäftsmodelle sind ohne externe IT-Dienstleister, Cloud-Services, Softwarelieferanten und spezialisierte Subunternehmen kaum noch denkbar.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Genau hier entstehen die größten Unsicherheiten. NIS2 greift diese Entwicklung auf und stellt klar, dass Cybersicherheit nicht an der eigenen Firewall endet. Die Richtlinie zwingt Unternehmen, ihre Lieferketten nicht nur technisch, sondern strategisch neu zu bewerten. Sie macht externe Abhängigkeiten zu einem integralen Bestandteil der Sicherheitsarchitektur und damit zu einer Führungsaufgabe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="nis2-verschiebt-den-fokus-von-systemen-auf-abhangigkeiten"&gt;NIS2 verschiebt den Fokus von Systemen auf Abhängigkeiten&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Kern verfolgt NIS2 einen klaren Ansatz. Risiken sollen dort adressiert werden, wo sie tatsächlich entstehen. Statistiken und Incident-Analysen zeigen seit Jahren, dass Angriffe zunehmend über Drittparteien erfolgen. Software-Updates, Wartungszugänge oder ausgelagerte Services dienen als Einfallstore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 reagiert darauf, indem sie Lieferketten explizit in den Geltungsbereich aufnimmt. Unternehmen sind verpflichtet, Risiken in Bezug auf ihre direkten Dienstleister und auch auf nachgelagerte Subunternehmen zu bewerten. Entscheidend ist nicht mehr, ob ein Vorfall intern oder extern ausgelöst wird, sondern welche Auswirkungen er auf kritische Dienste hat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Damit verabschiedet sich die Regulierung von einem rein technischen Sicherheitsverständnis. Sie fordert ein strukturiertes Management von Abhängigkeiten, das Risiken sichtbar macht und steuerbar hält.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4103179/nis2-umsetzen-ohne-im-papierkrieg-zu-enden.html" target="_blank"&gt;NIS2 umsetzen – ohne im Papierkrieg zu enden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="warum-lieferketten-besonders-anfallig-sind"&gt;Warum Lieferketten besonders anfällig sind&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4115440/shai-hulud-co-die-supply-chain-als-achillesferse.html" target="_blank"&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/a&gt; ist aus mehreren Gründen ein attraktives Ziel für Angreifer. Externe Partner verfügen häufig über privilegierte Zugänge, arbeiten mit sensiblen Daten oder sind tief in operative Prozesse eingebunden. Gleichzeitig unterliegen sie oft nicht denselben Sicherheitsstandards wie große Organisationen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hinzu kommt eine strukturelle Intransparenz. Unternehmen wissen oft nicht, welche weiteren Dienstleister ihre Partner einsetzen oder wie Zugriffe technisch umgesetzt sind. Diese fehlende Sichtbarkeit führt zu einer fragmentierten Sicherheitslage, in der Risiken zwar bekannt sind, aber nicht quantifizierbar bleiben.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 setzt genau hier an und verlangt nachvollziehbare Prozesse zur Identifikation, Bewertung und Überwachung dieser Risiken.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="der-bruch-mit-traditioneller-compliance"&gt;Der Bruch mit traditioneller Compliance&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Viele Organisationen sind es gewohnt, regulatorische Anforderungen formal zu erfüllen. Fragebögen werden verschickt, Zertifikate abgelegt, Checklisten abgehakt. Dieses Vorgehen erzeugt Dokumentation, aber keine Sicherheit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 macht deutlich, dass formale &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494023/cybersicherheitsvorschriften-so-erfullen-sie-ihre-compliance-anforderungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Compliance&lt;/a&gt; nicht ausreicht. Die Richtlinie verlangt eine wirksame Umsetzung von Sicherheitsmaßnahmen und eine nachweisbare Kontrolle ihrer Wirksamkeit. Das betrifft auch und insbesondere externe Partner.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Sicherheitskonzept, das sich ausschließlich auf Selbstauskünfte stützt, wird den Anforderungen nicht mehr gerecht. Gefordert ist ein realistisches Bild der tatsächlichen Sicherheitsreife entlang der Lieferkette.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="was-nis2-konkret-von-unternehmen-erwartet"&gt;Was NIS2 konkret von Unternehmen erwartet&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 formuliert keine technischen Detailvorgaben, sondern definiert klare Zielsetzungen. Unternehmen müssen Risiken identifizieren, priorisieren und angemessen behandeln. Für Lieferketten bedeutet das mehrere zentrale Aufgaben:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erstens müssen Abhängigkeiten systematisch erfasst werden. Welche Dienstleister sind für den Betrieb essenziell? Welche Daten verarbeiten sie? Welche Zugriffsrechte bestehen?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Zweitens sind angemessene Sicherheitsanforderungen zu definieren. Diese müssen zum Risiko passen und vertraglich verankert sein.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Drittens verlangt NIS2 eine kontinuierliche Überwachung. Risiken verändern sich. Geschäftsmodelle, Bedrohungslagen und technische Architekturen entwickeln sich weiter. Sicherheitsbewertungen dürfen daher kein einmaliges Projekt bleiben.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-rolle-des-ciso-unter-nis2"&gt;Die Rolle des CISO unter NIS2&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Für CISOs bedeutet NIS2 eine deutliche Erweiterung ihres Verantwortungsbereichs. Technische Exzellenz allein reicht nicht mehr aus. Gefragt sind Kommunikationsfähigkeit, Risikobewertung und die Fähigkeit, Sicherheitsanforderungen organisationsübergreifend durchzusetzen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495028/chief-information-security-officer-ein-neues-berufsbild-fur-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;CISO&lt;/a&gt; wird zum Vermittler zwischen Technik, Management, Einkauf und Recht. Er muss erklären, warum bestimmte Anforderungen notwendig sind, welche Risiken bestehen und welche Konsequenzen Untätigkeit haben kann. NIS2 stärkt diese Rolle, indem sie klare Verantwortlichkeiten definiert und die Bedeutung von Cybersicherheit auf Vorstandsebene verankert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="warum-viele-lieferkettenbewertungen-schief-gehen"&gt;Warum viele Lieferkettenbewertungen schief gehen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In der Praxis scheitern Lieferkettenbewertungen häufig an folgenden drei Punkten:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fehlende Priorisierung:&lt;/strong&gt; Unternehmen versuchen, alle Partner gleich zu behandeln und verlieren dabei den Fokus auf die wirklich kritischen Abhängigkeiten.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mangelnde Durchsetzbarkeit:&lt;/strong&gt; Sicherheitsanforderungen werden formuliert, aber nicht überprüft oder bei Abweichungen konsequent eingefordert.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organisatorische Silos:&lt;/strong&gt; Einkauf, IT und Recht agieren getrennt voneinander. Sicherheitsrisiken werden dadurch fragmentiert betrachtet und nicht ganzheitlich gesteuert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 macht deutlich, dass diese Ansätze nicht mehr ausreichen. Gefordert ist ein integriertes Risikomanagement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="kontrollmechanismen-mit-substanz"&gt;Kontrollmechanismen mit Substanz&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wirksame Kontrolle bedeutet nicht maximale Bürokratie. Entscheidend ist die Qualität der Maßnahmen. Für kritische Partner können das regelmäßige technische Assessments, strukturierte Audits oder klar definierte Eskalationsprozesse sein.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wichtig ist, dass Unternehmen die Fähigkeit behalten, Risiken eigenständig zu bewerten und nicht vollständig an Dritte auszulagern. NIS2 verlangt Verantwortungsübernahme, keine Delegation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kontrollmechanismen müssen zudem skalierbar sein. Nicht jeder Partner erfordert denselben Aufwand. Entscheidend ist die potenzielle Auswirkung eines Sicherheitsvorfalls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="lieferketten-als-strategischer-resilienzfaktor"&gt;Lieferketten als strategischer Resilienzfaktor&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unternehmen, die NIS2 als reine Compliance-Aufgabe betrachten, verschenken Potenzial. Eine realistische Bewertung von Lieferketten stärkt nicht nur die regulatorische Position, sondern erhöht die operative Stabilität. Transparente Abhängigkeiten, klare Sicherheitsanforderungen und funktionierende Kontrollprozesse reduzieren Ausfallrisiken und verbessern die Reaktionsfähigkeit im Ernstfall. Lieferketten werden damit vom Schwachpunkt zur strategischen Ressource.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="fazit-nis2-zwingt-zur-ehrlichkeit"&gt;Fazit: NIS2 zwingt zur Ehrlichkeit&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIS2 konfrontiert Unternehmen mit einer unbequemen Wahrheit. Cybersicherheit endet nicht an der eigenen Systemgrenze. Wer kritische Prozesse auslagert, bleibt dennoch verantwortlich.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Richtlinie fordert einen ehrlichen Blick auf Abhängigkeiten, Risiken und eigene Steuerungsfähigkeit. Für CISOs ist das eine Herausforderung, aber auch eine Chance. Lieferketten sind unter NIS2 keine Randnotiz mehr. Sie sind der Prüfstein für wirksame Cybersicherheit und nachhaltige Resilienz. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4124984/nis2-lieferketten-als-risikofaktor.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNU security advisory (AV26-047) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmarterTools security advisory (AV25-866) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/smartertools-security-advisory-av25-866</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startup Amutable plotting Linux security overhaul to counter hacking threats</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125145/startup-amutable-plotting-linux-security-overhaul-to-counter-hacking-threats.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing guaranteed to grab attention in the computer security world, it’s announcing yourself without fully explaining what it is you plan to do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This week, the Linux world got a taste of this enigmatic marketing ploy with the launch out of stealth of Berlin-based Linux security outfit Amutable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While its purpose is only vaguely defined in &lt;a href="https://amutable.com/blog/introducing-amutable" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the launch announcement&lt;/a&gt;, nobody could accuse it of lacking ambition: it plans to bring “determinism and verifiable integrity to Linux systems” to address the operating system’s security weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most tiny companies nobody has heard of would struggle to make the tactic work, but Amutable’s roster of founders is made up of several well-known Linux figures, headed by former Red Hat and Microsoft engineer &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lennart_Poettering" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lennart Poettering&lt;/a&gt; as chief engineer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Best known as the developer of the contentious but widely used Linux UEFI boot manager &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systemd"&gt;systemd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, he has alongside him two other ex-Microsoft employees, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopherk1/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Kühl&lt;/a&gt; as CEO, and &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christian-brauner/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Christian Brauner&lt;/a&gt; as CTO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A clue to Amutable’s plans lies in the announcement’s emphasis on some of its founders’ backgrounds in Kubernetes, &lt;em&gt;runc&lt;/em&gt;, LXC, Incus, and &lt;em&gt;containerd&lt;/em&gt;, all connected in different ways to the Linux container stack.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="verifiable-integrity"&gt;Verifiable integrity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Computing is full of security problems, and Linux is no exception to this rule, given convincing the protective free and open source software community of the wisdom of a radical new idea often turns out to be as big a challenge as the engineering itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While Linux distros on desktop computers remain a niche, the technology’s invisible domination of online platforms and cloud container orchestration tools makes it the most important operating system in the world.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That, not surprisingly, has made it a target for attacks, with cybercriminals taking advantage of vulnerabilities allowing privilege escalation, container escapes, and other exploits, as well as embedding backdoors in open source images across Linux’s complex supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judging from Amutable’s self-declared vision to bring “determinism and verifiable integrity to Linux system,” the founders see plenty of room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Today’s infrastructure approaches security reactively. Software agents watch for vulnerabilities and intrusions; attackers refine their evasion. These defensive approaches are costly, brittle, and ineffective,” the company said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Amutable’s mission is to deliver verifiable integrity to Linux workloads everywhere. We look forward to working towards this goal with the broader Linux community.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-cocktail-of-problems"&gt;A cocktail of problems&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue presents a rich cocktail of problems, the underlying causes of which are the difficulty of verifying that an image is as its developers intended and hasn’t been tampered with, while also maintaining a verifiable system state. Even existing security tools are struggling to keep up, with a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3971170/proof-of-concept-bypass-shows-weakness-in-linux-security-tools-claims-israeli-vendor.html" target="_blank"&gt;2025 proof-of-concept&lt;/a&gt; showing that it was possible to bypass leading Linux runtime security tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps what Amutable’s founders mean when they describe the need to “replace heuristics with rigor” to achieve “verifiable integrity.” An image should be cryptographically verifiable in advance, including, ideally, a hash record of every stage of the boot process as well as running continuous checks against a signed file manifest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In other words, instead of looking for a rogue file or suspicious behavior after the fact, the system would be able to verify itself deterministically.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Introduction of this model of verifiability into Linux might have mitigated a range of incidents, including a 2023 attack where attackers &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087323/runtime-bugs-break-container-walls-enabling-root-on-docker-hosts.html" target="_blank"&gt;exploited CVE-2022-42475&lt;/a&gt; in Fortinet’s FortiOS SSL-VPN function to implant malware. Or a more &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4087323/runtime-bugs-break-container-walls-enabling-root-on-docker-hosts.html" target="_blank"&gt;recent vulnerability (CVE-2025-31133)&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;runc&lt;/em&gt; Kubernetes container runtime that allowed attackers to break out of containers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the issue’s biggest impact was from the infamous &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2077692/dangerous-xz-utils-backdoor-was-the-result-of-years-long-supply-chain-compromise-effort.html" target="_blank"&gt;backdoor supply chain hack&lt;/a&gt; affecting the XZ Utils data compression library that was uncovered by chance in 2024.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-common-goal"&gt;A common goal&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security of the IT infrastructure is one of the top concerns for decades, and immutability, verification and full coverage of software supply chain throughout the lifecycle of an operating system or complete infrastructure are important contributions to achieve this,” noted &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mge1512/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Matthias G. Eckermann&lt;/a&gt;, director of product management, Linux at SUSE. He pointed out that SUSE is already delivering on this in multiple ways, including its certified Software Supply Chain and its Immutable OS with Transactional Updates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are looking forward to hearing more from Amutable and collaborating with them on the common goal of improving resiliency and security of open-source infrastructure software,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="technology-not-the-only-problem"&gt;Technology not the only problem&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Right now, where this goes and how Amutable will make money is up in the air, but it will attract attention.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security teams are trained to trust signed packages and verified sources. When the supply chain itself is compromised (like the XZ Utils backdoor in 2024), traditional security training doesn’t prepare defenders for that scenario,” commented &lt;a href="https://trainingcamp.com/author-cporter/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Porter&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of certification company Training Camp. “If they [Amutable] can simplify verification, it reduces the expertise burden on security teams who currently lack deep Linux platform knowledge.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, technology isn’t the only problem. “As Linux dominates cloud infrastructure, enterprises need security professionals who understand boot integrity, code signing, and verification, skills that aren’t covered in most certification programs,” said Porter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4125145/startup-amutable-plotting-linux-security-overhaul-to-counter-hacking-threats.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL security advisory (AV26-058)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/openssl-security-advisory-av26-058</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-059) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cyber-fortinet-security-advisory-av26-059</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.07</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-060)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-060</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-060</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.08</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-019 - Vulnerabilities impacting Fortinet products - FortiCloud SSO Login Authentication Bypass - CVE-2025-59718 and CVE-2025-59719 - Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-019-vulnerabilities-impacting-fortinet-products-forticloud-sso-login-authentication-bypass-cve-2025-59718-cve-2025-59719</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-061)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-062)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-062</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV26-063)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av26-063</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.17</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-064)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-064</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-065)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-065</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] B&amp;R security advisory (AV26-066)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-br-security-advisory-av26-066</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.80</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citrix security advisory (AV25-067)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/citrix-security-advisory-av25-067</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.82</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti security advisory (AV26-068) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ivanti-security-advisory-av26-068</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WatchGuard security advisory (AV26-069)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/watchguard-security-advisory-av26-069</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-070)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-070</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-071)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-071</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
