<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:39:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-021)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV26-022)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 160,000 Companies Notify Regulators of GDPR Breaches</title>
      <link>https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/160000-companies-regulator-gdpr/</link>
      <description>DLA Piper finds 22% increase in breached firms notifying European GDPR regulators</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/160000-companies-regulator-gdpr/</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-023)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-025)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 cyber questions to better vet IT vendors and reduce third-party risk</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119475/13-cyber-questions-to-better-vet-it-vendors-and-reduce-third-party-risk.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Increased reliance on IT service providers, digital tools, and third-party software is greatly expanding the enterprise attack surface, with noteworthy cyberattacks over the past year underscoring this fact. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In October 2025, Marks &amp;amp; Spencer terminated its longtime helpdesk deal with outsourcing giant Tata Consultancy Services following a cyberattack that cost the British retailer&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;an estimated &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3986579/aggressive-creative-hackers-behind-uk-breaches-now-eyeing-us-retailers.html"&gt;£300 million and temporarily shut down its online business.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In August, a Chinese threat group leveraged &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4053891/what-the-salesloft-drift-breaches-reveal-about-4th-party-risk.html"&gt;compromised OAuth tokens&lt;/a&gt; from third-party platform Salesloft Drift to exfiltrate sensitive business data — AWS keys, Snowflake tokens, passwords — from as many as 700 organizations. This came on the heels of a wave of attacks in which cybercriminal gang ShinyHunters &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4035701/we-too-were-breached-says-google-months-after-revealing-salesforce-attacks.html"&gt;pretended to be IT support personnel&lt;/a&gt; to trick users into connecting to malicious versions of Salesforce’s Data Loader, which was then used to exfiltrate data from Salesforce environments. All told, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4067846/extortion-gang-opens-data-leak-site-to-squeeze-victims-of-its-salesforce-attacks.html"&gt;1.5 billion Salesforce records&lt;/a&gt; were claimed to have been stolen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, back in April, a critical &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3971211/sap-netweaver-customers-urged-to-deploy-patch-for-critical-zero-day-vulnerability.html"&gt;zero-day vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; in SAP NetWeaver, one of the most widespread incidents involving an ERP platform, illustrated that enterprise software has become a prime target for attackers because their compromise directly impacts the revenue, operations, and reputation of an organization.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Adversaries continue to exploit the path of least resistance, increasingly targeting third-party providers and human vulnerabilities to bypass technical controls,” says Casey Corcoran, field CISO at Stratascale, the cybersecurity division of SHI International. “By compromising trusted vendors, attackers can move undetected for longer periods, exploiting established access points across multiple organizations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because these are newer avenues for attack, companies have been caught on their heels. “We don’t have enough preparation or defensive tools to rapidly detect and defend against these attacks, leading to a significant level of risk for lots of companies,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joswr1ght/"&gt;Joshua Wright&lt;/a&gt;, faculty fellow of the SANS Institute and technical director at Cyber Hack Challenges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnealfordii/"&gt;John Alford&lt;/a&gt;, CSO at TeraType, an adviser to pharmaceutical, financial, and SaaS firms on cybersecurity, compliance, audit and AI governance, says legacy mindsets are also to blame.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many organizations still defend their environments as if threats march up to the front gate when in reality the most effective attackers slip in through the service corridors that nobody monitors,” Alford says. “The Marks &amp;amp; Spencer situation proved this: A help desk workflow became a quiet passage into production because it relied on trust by default.” There appeared to be no strong caller verification processes, no step-up checks, and no guardrails on what support staff could change, he adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Salesforce ecosystem breaches demonstrate another common blind spot: Once attackers capture a token or exploit a permissive integration, they gain the full authority of a trusted insider. “Companies that rely on perimeter controls and MFA alone never see this risk because they are not watching the right places,” Alford says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-csos-role-in-vetting-it-vendors"&gt;The CSO’s role in vetting IT vendors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cyber obligations are already written into IT services and SaaS contracts, but “there are limits to what companies can do,” says &lt;a href="https://www.mayerbrown.com/en/people/l/lilley-stephen"&gt;Stephen Lilley&lt;/a&gt;, partner at law firm Mayer Brown. “Companies are unlikely to be able to impose cyber requirements that go beyond what is commonly seen in the relevant market. And even sophisticated companies still experience cyber incidents — meaning that IT providers, like their customers, are unable to entirely eliminate the risk from these attacks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although risk eradication is not possible, better mitigation is. Here, CSOs can play a crucial role.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CSOs are uniquely able to see across the full business process — data flows, dependencies, and downstream impact — but many organizations still don’t use that perspective to reassess third-party risk as reliance grows,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/cisorandygross/"&gt;Randy Gross&lt;/a&gt;, CISO for CompTIA. “Cross-functional collaboration is a core CSO imperative: partnering early with procurement, legal, IT, and business leaders so security, resilience, and exit risk are designed in, not bolted on.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When engagements are initiated at the business-unit level or come in below financial approval thresholds, CSOs may not even be aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In many organizations, security leaders are brought in only after a contract is executed or — worse — after a security issue arises,” says &lt;a href="https://www.clarkhill.com/people/melissa-k-ventrone/"&gt;Melissa Ventrone&lt;/a&gt;, leader of law firm Clark Hill’s cybersecurity, data protection, and privacy practice. “They should be involved … [and] their involvement does not need to slow the contracting process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, CSOs can act as a “pragmatic technology advisor” says CompTIA’s Gross, seeking critical information they are uniquely qualified to assess.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="vital-vendor-questions-cisos-should-ask"&gt;Vital vendor questions CISOs should ask&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To gain that critical information, security leaders and experts recommend CSOs ask IT partners the following cyber-specific questions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-what-attestation-will-you-provide-to-prove-proper-security-controls-are-in-place"&gt;1. What attestation will you provide to prove proper security controls are in place?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These are essential, says &lt;a href="https://onapsis.com/leadership/juan-pablo-perez-etchegoyen/"&gt;Juan Pablo Perez-Etchegoyen&lt;/a&gt;, CTO for cybersecurity and compliance platform Onapsis. Some of the most commonly used include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOC 2 Type II Report:&lt;/strong&gt; considered the gold standard audit for IT and cloud service providers&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISO/IEC 27001 certification:&lt;/strong&gt; an international standard for information security&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud Security Alliance STAR:&lt;/strong&gt; a registry specific to cloud providers that combines ISO 27001 with a controls matrix for cloud-related risks&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-specific attestations:&lt;/strong&gt; for example, HIPAA/HITRUST for handling healthcare data, or PCI DSS for storing or processing credit card data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-how-do-you-maintain-and-update-cybersecurity-controls-over-time-and-how-will-we-be-notified-of-material-changes"&gt;2. How do you maintain and update cybersecurity controls over time, and how will we be notified of material changes?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Would-be clients should have IT partners complete a detailed due diligence questionnaire and contractually obligate them to notify the company of any material changes that would require updates to their responses, advises Clark Hill’s Ventrone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“At a minimum, IT vendors should be prohibited from changing security controls that would decrease the security, protection, or resiliency of its systems and company data,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-who-on-your-team-is-capable-of-altering-our-identity-posture-and-what-prevents-a-social-engineered-request-from-triggering-that-action"&gt;3. Who on your team is capable of altering our identity posture, and what prevents a social engineered request from triggering that action?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs can begin with general access inquiries: what access the provider’s team has to customer systems and data, and how that access is segmented and secured, Stratascale’s Corcoran says. Access should be limited by role, with least privilege enforced and multifactor authentication, single sign-on, and network segmentation in place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Look for “logged, monitored, and immediately revocable access — ideally aligned with access control best practices from the NIST RMF function, which emphasizes least privilege and separation of duties,” Corcoran says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Then CSOs can get specific. “Many clients focus on firewalls, endpoint agents, and MFA while overlooking the trust pathways that attackers prefer to use,” Alford says. Help desk workflows, OAuth integrations, supplier support portals, and automation connectors typically get less scrutiny even though they can alter identity states or extract large volumes of data with a single action.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs should look for strictly defined role scopes, multi-step verification, step-up authentication, and approval chains for credential resets. “Anything short of that signals a blind spot that no amount of technical hardening will cover,” says Alford.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-how-can-we-verify-the-workflows-you-use-when-onboarding-offboarding-or-resetting-access-and-can-you-show-evidence-of-how-these-workflows-performed-last-quarter"&gt;4. How can we verify the workflows you use when onboarding, offboarding, or resetting access, and can you show evidence of how these workflows performed last quarter?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many companies underestimate how much operational trust they blindly hand over to providers. IT partners should offer workflow maps, execution logs, and testing records, not just policy documents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The most significant gaps appear in the places people assume are safe. I have seen mature organizations with strong 27001 programs, disciplined PCI controls, and well-run internal security teams fall to issues that lived entirely inside vendor workflows,” Alford notes. “Help desk resets, poorly scoped automation tokens, and inherited admin rights all surfaced in post-incident reviews as quiet pathways that no one had modeled.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Risk assessments should focus not just on servers and networks but identity workflows and human-operated processes as well. “When you widen the lens, you often discover controls that look strong on paper but behave differently in practice,” Alford says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-what-independent-testing-do-you-conduct-and-how-often-is-it-performed"&gt;5. What independent testing do you conduct, and how often is it performed?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT partners should have a third party run security tests and assessments, and provide copies or executive summaries of these vulnerability scans, penetration tests, and other audits at least annually and whenever there are material changes to their network, infrastructure, or security controls, Clark Hill’s Ventrone says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ThreatLocker CEO &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dannyjenkinscyber/"&gt;Danny Jenkins&lt;/a&gt; stresses frequency: “Threats are always evolving, so a once-a-year audit is not sufficient. All systems should be undergoing regular penetration testing and improvement.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-can-you-list-every-oauth-integration-and-privileged-api-relationship-in-your-service-and-explain-how-each-is-scoped-rotated-monitored-and-revoked"&gt;6. Can you list every OAuth integration and privileged API relationship in your service and explain how each is scoped, rotated, monitored, and revoked?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“OAuth integrations are often treated as harmless conveniences rather than high-privilege conduits,” Alford explains. “In reality, they function like a network of forgotten tunnels. They bypass the front gate entirely and connect systems deep inside the environment.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Companies should ask service partners to provide a token inventory, minimal scopes, finite lifetimes, and behavioral monitoring. Broad or permanent tokens are red flags, signaling elevated risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;7. If an attacker abused one of your processes &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; breaching your systems, what are your contractual and operational commitments?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These agreements often hand providers the practical ability to alter identity states, access sensitive data, or operate parts of the production environment. That level of delegated trust deserves the same scrutiny as hiring a senior operations leader,” says Alford. “When providers can reset passwords or manage OAuth integrations, the contract becomes a control document. It defines how risk will be shared and what evidence the client can demand.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Without CSO involvement, contractual clauses are usually weak. “They focus on uptime rather than security, and they rarely require the provider to support strong authentication, tamper-evident logging, or event-level transparency,” Alford adds. Clients should insist on obligations tied to process compromise, not just system compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="8-what-controls-govern-your-staffs-activity-in-our-environment-and-how-would-we-detect-if-a-privileged-session-deviated-from-expected-behavior"&gt;8. What controls govern your staff’s activity in our environment, and how would we detect if a privileged session deviated from expected behavior?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Modern attacks flow through trust relationships and soft operational processes,” Alford points out. “They exploit the places where no one expects danger — like help desks.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result, controls on vendor staff behavior and detection of deviations are critical. Companies should insist on session recording, real-time alerts, and segregation of duties, Alford advises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Rapid detection and revoking access can make all the difference in an incident,” Onapsis’ Perez-Etchegoyen adds. Continuous application-level monitoring, clear incident response procedures, and the ability to immediately disable users or integrations are key.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="9-how-will-you-isolate-our-assets-and-data-from-other-customers-including-identity-separation-automation-boundaries-and-admin-segregation"&gt;9. How will you isolate our assets and data from other customers — including identity separation, automation boundaries, and admin segregation?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs should seek architectural clarity and concrete mechanisms that limit blast radius, says Alford. They should also ask how the IT partner manages the cybersecurity risks posed by their value chains of vendors and subcontractors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“IT partners should have a robust vendor management program and conduct appropriate due diligence on their own service providers,” advises Ventrone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="10-how-quickly-will-you-notify-us-of-a-security-incident-that-impacts-our-data-or-systems"&gt;10. How quickly will you notify us of a security incident that impacts our data or systems?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The biggest gains come from simple steps,” says CompTIA’s Gross, including gaining clarity on how incidents are disclosed and outages are handled.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs should look for guaranteed notification within 24 to 72 hours, a tested incident response plan, and clearly defined breach reporting timelines and responsibilities written into the contract, says Stratascale’s Corcoran.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When an incident occurs, “IT partners should provide customers with sufficient information to perform their own threat analysis,” Alford says. “If an IT partner doesn’t provide the insight needed to identify attacks against their customers, then customer organizations can only rely on the detection and reporting capabilities of the hosting provider.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="11-how-do-you-identify-prioritize-and-remediate-vulnerabilities"&gt;11. How do you identify, prioritize, and remediate vulnerabilities?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Review of IT partner’s patching policies and remediation timelines should never be overlooked, as many cyberattacks exploit known vulnerabilities. “Slow patch cycles lead to supply chain disruptions, business operational issues, and even bankruptcy in some cases,” says Perez-Etchegoyen, who emphasizes SLAs related to critical patches and proof that fixes are validated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ventrone gives the example of a company that outsourced firewall management to a vendor. After a vulnerability in the firewall was exploited, the vendor ended up restoring the vulnerable version, resulting in a second compromise. In another example, a client found out that its IT partner, which had experienced a ransomware attack through its VPN, patched just once a month.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I literally could not believe this was considered sufficient,” Ventrone says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="12-do-you-carry-enough-cyber-insurance-to-cover-the-impact-to-all-your-customers"&gt;12. Do you carry enough cyber insurance to cover the impact to all your customers?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’re going to see a lot more attacks against SaaS providers,” says SANS Institute’s Wright. “Attackers have lots of motive here since the access obtained when a SaaS provider is compromised is significant, with lots of subsequent opportunity for ransomware, extortion, and direct harassment attacks against customers.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ventrone says clients should confirm their provider’s policy covers not only themselves but the full impact of a multi-customer incident.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="13-can-we-test-your-processes"&gt;13. Can we test your processes?&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attestations regarding cybersecurity testing and monitoring — such as regular penetration testing, 24/7/365 security monitoring, threat hunting — are essential, Wright says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Alford recommends going a step further. “Lots of firms do questionnaire-based reviews that confirm policies exist but rarely test how provider processes work in practice. They assume a support vendor has strong verification steps. They assume an integration partner follows least privilege. They assume a SaaS platform has adequate logging for delegated access,” says Alford, warning against presumptions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Verification through evidence, realistic scenarios, and process testing changes everything,” he says. “It exposes where risk actually lives and gives you the ability to design controls that match how attackers think rather than how documentation reads.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ongoing-diligence-necessary"&gt;Ongoing diligence necessary&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Recent incidents underscore that many organizations are not adequately managing third-party risk over the full lifecycle of their IT provider relationships,” notes Clark Hill’s Ventrone, adding that too often due diligence is treated as a one-time exercise, with insufficient ongoing oversight to ensure that security controls and procedures remain appropriate as systems evolve.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Stratascale’s Corcoran also notes that cyber due diligence often falls through the cracks. “Many client organizations still fall short in managing third-party risk because it’s often treated as a collateral duty, split between procurement and general risk functions rather than a dedicated, optimized process,” he says. “As a result, business stakeholders remain unsatisfied and critical risks go unmitigated, even as attackers increasingly exploit weaker links in the supply chain.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, partners in the IT ecosystem are being seen by cybercriminals to be those weaker links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119475/13-cyber-questions-to-better-vet-it-vendors-and-reduce-third-party-risk.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OTF GRIMM: Swedish organiser of serious violence arrested in Iraq</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</link>
      <description>A High-Value Target under Europol-supported Operational Taskforce GRIMM was arrested in Iraq following long-term cooperation between the Swedish Police Authority and Iraqi law enforcement authorities. The 21-year-old suspect, a Swedish national who was listed on the EU Most Wanted list, is identified as a key organiser of serious violence directed at Sweden from abroad.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/otf-grimm-swedish-organiser-of-serious-violence-arrested-in-iraq</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-026)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV26-027)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-028)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-029)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.46</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-030)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-031)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-032)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol signs Working Arrangement with the Argentine Republic</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</link>
      <description>In December, the Ministry of National Security of the Argentine Republic and the European Union Agency for Law Enforcement Cooperation (Europol) signed a Working Arrangement in order to support the Member States of the European Union and Argentina in preventing and combating serious and organised crime and terrorism.The Working Arrangement provides for a structured legal framework for cooperation and enhanced...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-signs-working-arrangement-argentine-republic</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operational Taskforce GRIMM: 193 arrests in 6 months tackling violence-as-a-service networks</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</link>
      <description>Launched in April 2025, the taskforce has been focused on combating the emerging trend of VaaS, where criminals outsource violent acts, often relying on young, inexperienced perpetrators. These individuals are groomed or coerced into committing a range of violent crimes, from acts of intimidation and torture to murder.What began as a growing issue in Sweden has now spread across Europe,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/operational-taskforce-grimm-193-arrests-in-6-months-tackling-violence-service-networks</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU reviews cybersecurity to limit danger from high-risk suppliers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120006/eu-reviews-cybersecurity-wants-to-reduce-risks-from-high-risk-suppliers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The European Commission has presented a new &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_26_105" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;cybersecurity package&lt;/a&gt; to strengthen the European Union’s resilience to increasing cyber and hybrid attacks from state and criminal actors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The key is to reduce risks from high-risk suppliers outside the EU, especially in critical infrastructure such as mobile networks, through a common and risk-based framework. The Commission’s news release did not mention any specific suppliers targeted by the measures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The move should make it possible to reduce the risk to sensitive parts of the EU’s IT ecosystem based on previous work on 5G security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An updated European Cybersecurity Certification Framework (ECCF) will also make it faster and easier to security test products and services. The package also simplifies compliance with existing cybersecurity rules to reduce the administrative burden, especially for small and medium-sized enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the EU’s cybersecurity agency, ENISA, will be strengthened, among other things by giving it a more central role in threat analysis, incident response, vulnerability management, and coordination within the EU.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The package of measures needs to be approved by the European Parliament and the EU Council of Ministers. Member states will then have one year to implement the changes in their national legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120006/eu-reviews-cybersecurity-wants-to-reduce-risks-from-high-risk-suppliers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misconfigured demo environments are turning into cloud backdoors to the enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120258/misconfigured-demo-environments-are-turning-into-cloud-backdoors-to-the-enterprise.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Internal testing, product demonstrations, and security training are critical practices in cybersecurity, giving defenders and everyday users the tools and wherewithal to prevent and respond to enterprise threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, according to new research from Pentera Labs, when left in default or misconfigured states, these “test” and “demo” environments are yet another entry point for attackers — and the issue even affects leading security companies and Fortune 500 companies that should know better.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers discovered that popular public training apps like Hackazon, Damn Vulnerable Web Application (DVWA), and OWASP Juice Shop have been frequently left accessible to the public internet, inadvertently exposing top vendors including Palo Alto Networks, Cloudflare, and F5.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is not theoretical research,” &lt;a href="https://il.linkedin.com/in/noamyaffe" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Noam Yaffe&lt;/a&gt;, Pentera’s senior researcher and offensive security team lead, wrote in a &lt;a href="https://pentera.io/blog/exposed-cloud-training-apps-pentera-labs/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;technical blog post&lt;/a&gt;. His team discovered “clear evidence” that these attack vectors are being exploited in the wild to enable crypto miners, webshells, and persistence mechanisms. The attackers are believed to be of Eastern European origin.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This research proves that labeling something as ‘training’ or ‘dev’ doesn’t make it invisible to attackers,” Yaffe noted. “If it’s on the internet and it has cloud credentials, it’s a target.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="exposing-crown-jewels-through-seemingly-harmless-labs"&gt;Exposing crown jewels through seemingly harmless labs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After identifying an exposed instance of Hackazon, a free, intentionally vulnerable test site developed by Deloitte, during a routine &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117003/cyber-risk-assessments-risk-assessment-helps-cisos.html" target="_blank"&gt;cloud security assessment&lt;/a&gt; for a client, Yaffe performed a five-step hunt for exposed apps. His team uncovered 1,926 “verified, live, and vulnerable applications,” more than half of which were running on enterprise-owned infrastructure on AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud platforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They then discovered 109 exposed credential sets, many accessible via a low-priority lab environment, tied to overly-privileged &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/518296/what-is-iam-identity-and-access-management-explained.html" target="_blank"&gt;identity access management (IAM)&lt;/a&gt; roles. These often granted “far more access” than a ‘training’ app should, Yaffe explained, and provided attackers:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrator-level access to cloud accounts, as well as full access to S3 buckets, GCS, and Azure Blob Storage;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The ability to launch and destruct compute resources and read and write to secrets managers;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Permissions to interact with container registries where images are stored, shared, and deployed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attackers maintained persistent access, moved laterally across networks, exploited cloud credentials and other sensitive information, and crypto-mined victim infrastructure. Further, Pentera’s researchers easily discovered active secrets such as Slack keys, GitHub tokens, and Docker Hub credentials, as well as real user data and proprietary source code.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alarmingly, in DVWA, 54% of instances discovered still used the default credentials ‘admin:password,’ and attackers could downgrade security settings in a single click (from “impossible” to “low”), making every built-in vulnerability “trivially exploitable,” Yaffe noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What began as a harmless lab could lead directly to an organization’s crown jewels,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="real-world-exploitations"&gt;Real-world exploitations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In one real-world instance, Pentera’s team discovered a misconfigured buggy web application (bWAPP) linked to Cloudflare cloud accounts running on Google Cloud Platform (GCP). bWAPP is a free, open source, deliberately insecure web app used for &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4119475/13-cyber-questions-to-better-vet-it-vendors-and-reduce-third-party-risk.html" target="_blank"&gt;training purposes&lt;/a&gt;. Querying GCP’s metadata services, the researchers were able to impersonate default service accounts and gain read access to “hundreds” of storage buckets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a DVWA linked to F5’s cloud accounts was found running on a GCP instance, again allowing the researchers to access numerous storage buckets containing logs and metric data. In addition, a misconfigured Palo Alto-linked DVWA app was identified running on AWS; Yaffe and his team used the attached IAM role and temporary credentials to gain full administrative access to the AWS account.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers also exfiltrated OAuth tokens for a GCP service account to assume its identity, and list and access specific bucket content. For instance, one “cloud_build” bucket stored .tgz files that attackers could easily download. The account was managed by an admin email and violated least privilege because it contained policy permission, Yaffe explained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Even though this was a ‘dev’/ ‘training’ account, it contained highly sensitive secrets, credentials, and API tokens,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In assessing these misconfigured, vulnerable applications, his team found “clear evidence” that they were already being fully exploited in the wild. Roughly 20% of the DVWA instances they discovered contained artifacts deployed by malicious actors, including:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XMRig Crypto Miner actively running, sending proceeds to attacker-controlled wallets, and configured to run silently without user knowledge;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A “sophisticated” watchdog script that maintained persistence even after a compromise had been discovered. This featured self-recovery, automated downloads, encrypted payload delivery, evidence deletion, and kill switches that threat actors could use to easily shut down operations;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;A PHP webshell that granted attackers the ability to read, write, delete, upload and download files; run operating system (OS) commands and scripts on remote machines; and access credentials, API keys, and other secrets embedded in source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All discoveries were responsibly disclosed to the impacted organizations and were subsequently mitigated prior to publication, Yaffe emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These weren’t isolated incidents; they represented an organized, ongoing exploitation campaign,” he warned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-enterprises-can-do-now"&gt;What enterprises can do now&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To defend against this widespread threat, Yaffe and his team developed SigInt, a Python-based, large language model (LLM)-powered autonomous reconnaissance framework. &lt;a href="https://github.com/noamYaffe1/SigInt" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The tool&lt;/a&gt;, which is available on GitHub, generates fingerprint signatures directly from a live target or GitHub repository, searches for matches, and applies confidence scoring. It also incorporates IP intelligence, cloud provider detection, attribution data, and provides analysis to support further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond this, Yaffe advised enterprises to “inventory everything” to establish a complete, up-to-date picture of all cloud resources, including ‘temporary’ and ‘test deployments,’ perform regular audits to scan for exposed services, and apply least privilege.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Never attach broad IAM roles to training or demo environments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Further, defenders should isolate training environments from production networks and apply the same monitoring and alerting to them as production environments, restrict their outbound internet access, document and enforce changes to default credentials pre-deployment, and set controls that expire temporary testing environments after a specified timeframe. “If it doesn’t have an end date, it will run forever,” Yaffe noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, he emphasized: “These are fixable problems. Basic hygiene … would have prevented every case we found.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120258/misconfigured-demo-environments-are-turning-into-cloud-backdoors-to-the-enterprise.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.86</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab 2FA login protection bypass lets attackers take over accounts</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120316/gitlab-2fa-login-protection-bypass-lets-attackers-take-over-accounts.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A critical two-factor authentication bypass vulnerability in the Community and Enterprise editions of the GitLab application development platform has to be patched immediately, say experts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The hole is one of five vulnerabilities patched Wednesday as part of new versions of GitLab. Three are ranked High in severity, including the 2FA bypass issue, while the other two are ranked Medium in severity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GitLab says the 2FA hole, &lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2026-0723" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-0723&lt;/a&gt;, if exploited on an unpatched system, could allow an individual with knowledge of a victim’s ID credentials to bypass two-factor authentication by submitting forged device responses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s this hole that has drawn the attention of experts, because of the implications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The goal of multifactor authentication is to protect login accounts with an extra verification step in case usernames and passwords are stolen. If a threat actor can access an account, they can do almost unlimited damage to IT systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the case of GitLab, if critical code is sitting in a developer’s account, a threat actor could compromise it, notes &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, head of Canadian-based security awareness training firm Beauceron Security. If that code is to be used in software that can be downloaded or sold to other organizations, then inserted malware could be spread in a supply chain attack. The latest example, Shipley said, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095578/new-shai-hulud-worm-spreading-through-npm-github.html" target="_blank"&gt;is the Shai-Hulud worm&lt;/a&gt;, which is spreading because a developer’s account in the npm registry was hacked.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If the code contains cloud secrets, he added, the threat actor could gain access to cloud platforms like Azure, Amazon Web Service, or Google Cloud Platform.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Discovery of the 2FA bypass hole “is a reminder that these [security] controls are important,” Shipley said in an interview. “They absolutely help reduce a number of risks: Brute force attacks, password spraying, and so forth. But they will never be infallible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is not the first time someone has found a clever way to get around 2FA challenges. We have a whole series of &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118607/five-chrome-extensions-caught-hijacking-enterprise-sessions.html" target="_blank"&gt;attacks around session cookie capture&lt;/a&gt; which are also designed to defeat 2FA. So it’s important to remember this when someone drops some Silver Bullet thinking that ‘This magic solution solves it [authentication]’ or ‘That’s the bad MFA. Here’s the new MFA.’ And I include [trusting only] Yubikeys,” he said. “Yubikeys are amazing. They’re the next generation of 2FA. But because they are made for humans, eventually they will have some flaws.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even if there weren’t flaws in these controls, employees might be tricked into giving up credentials through social engineering, he added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It would be easier for an attacker to use techniques like phishing to collect user credentials rather than forge a device credential to exploit this particular 2FA bypass, said &lt;a href="https://www.sans.org/profiles/dr-johannes-ullrich" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Johannes Ullrich&lt;/a&gt;, dean of research at the SANS Institute. But, he added, once the attacker has access to valid passwords, they can log in to the GitLab server and perform actions on the source code — download it, alter it or delete it — just as a legitimate user would.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-infosec-leaders-need-to-do"&gt;What infosec leaders need to do&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is why Cybersecurity 101 — layered defense — is vital for identity and access management, Shipley said. That includes forcing employees to have long, unique login passwords, monitoring the network for unusual activity (for example, if someone gets in without an MFA challenge recorded) and, in case all fails, an incident response plan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MFA bypass vulnerabilities are very common, noted Ullrich. “The core problem is usually that MFA was added later to an existing product,” he said, “and some features may not properly check if MFA was successfully completed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When testing a multifactor authentication solution, infosec leaders should always verify that an application has not marked authentication as completed after the username and password were verified. Enabling MFA should not relax password requirements, he asserted. Users must still pick unique, secure passwords and use password managers to manage them. Secure passwords will mostly mitigate any MFA failures, Ullrich said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Any vulnerability found in GitLab is significant, he added. GitLab is typically used by organizations concerned enough about the confidentiality of their code that they want to run the platform on premises. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="gitlab-strongly-recommends-upgrades"&gt;GitLab ‘strongly’ recommends upgrades&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In describing the patches released Wednesday, GitLab said it “strongly” recommends all self managed GitLab installations be upgraded to one of the three new versions (18.8.2, 18.7.2, 18.6.4) for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE). Those using GitLab.com or GitLab Dedicated –  a single tenant software-as-a-service version –  don’t have to take any action.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The other vulnerabilities fixed in Wednesday’s updates are:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-13927" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-13927&lt;/a&gt;, a denial of service issue in Jira Connect integration. If exploited on an unpatched system, it could allow an unauthenticated user to create a denial of service condition by sending crafted requests with malformed authentication data. It carries a CVSS severity score of 7.5;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-13928" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-13928&lt;/a&gt;, an incorrect authorization issue. If exploited on an unpatched system, it could allow an unauthenticated user to cause a denial of service condition by exploiting incorrect authorization validation in API endpoints.  It carries a CVSS severity score of 7.5;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2025-13335" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2025-13335&lt;/a&gt;, an infinite loop issue in Wiki redirects. Under certain circumstances, this hole could allow an authenticated user to create a denial of service condition by configuring malformed Wiki documents that bypass cycle detection. It has a CVSS score of 6.5;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2026-1102" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-1102&lt;/a&gt; – a denial of service issue in an API endpoint that could allow an unauthenticated user to create a denial of service condition by sending repeated malformed SSH authentication requests. It has a CVSS score of 5.3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In keeping with standard GitLab practice, details of the security vulnerabilities will be made public on an &lt;a href="https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab/-/issues/?sort=created_date&amp;amp;state=closed&amp;amp;label_name%5B%5D=bug%3A%3Avulnerability&amp;amp;confidential=no&amp;amp;first_page_size=100" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; 30 days after the release in which they were patched. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new versions also include bug fixes, some of which, GitLab said, may include database migrations. In cases of single-node instances, a patch will cause downtime during the upgrade. In the case of multi-node instances, admins who follow proper GitLab zero-downtime upgrade procedures can apply a patch without downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120316/gitlab-2fa-login-protection-bypass-lets-attackers-take-over-accounts.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.90</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 industrial-scale labs dismantled in the largest-ever operation against synthetic drugs</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</link>
      <description>A large-scale law enforcement action, conducted within the Europol-coordinated operation Fabryka, led to the dismantling of a criminal network operating across the European Union. On Friday, 16 January, coordinated efforts took place in Poland, as well as in Belgium, Germany, and the Netherlands. These actions targeted a network suspected of importing a large quantity of precursors used for the production of synthetic drugs in labs across multiple countries. Additionally, the network engaged in money laundering activities to further its illicit operations. The year-long operation Fabryka involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Belgium, Czechia, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland, and Spain.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/24-industrial-scale-labs-dismantled-in-largest-ever-operation-against-synthetic-drugs</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>73% of CISOs more likely to consider AI-enabled security solution</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120218/73-of-cisos-more-likely-to-consider-ai-enabled-security-solution.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISO’s are increasingly turning to AI-enabled security technologies to augment their organizations’ cyber defense and extend the capabilities of their teams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Foundry’s &lt;a href="https://foundryco.com/research/security-priorities/"&gt;latest Security Priorities Study&lt;/a&gt;, 73% of security decision-makers are now more likely to consider a security solution that uses artificial intelligence, up from 59% the year prior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs plan to leverage AI in a range of security functions, including malware detection, threat detection, anomaly detection, real-time risk prediction, and audit and compliance. They are also eyeing AI for automating security responses, performing authentication, ensuring data loss prevention, and improving enterprise system visibility.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="2025 Security Priorities Survey: Slide 24 AI Plans" class="wp-image-4074988" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/24-ai-plans-R-PP_CSO_Security_Priorities_2025_ec4a7b.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;CSO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Survey respondents cited AI-enabled benefits such as faster detection of unknown threats, accelerating response times, and automating security tasks to reduce employee workload. The findings are in line with an October 2025 study from management consultancy PwC, which found AI ahead of cloud security and data protection as the &lt;a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/news-room/press-releases/2025/pwc-digital-trust-insights.html"&gt;top cybersecurity investment priority for enterprises over the next 12 months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But cutting through the hype to ensure AI investments have optimal impact remains an issue. Experts quizzed by CSO said that security leaders should prioritize AI investment over the next 12 to 18 months to boost anomaly detection, enhance identity and access management, and automate response, but they should also be aware of potential pitfalls such as hallucinations, over-reliance on AI, and governance gaps when implementing AI in their security strategies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cutting-through-the-noise"&gt;Cutting through the noise&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/oliver-newbury-086b01aa/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Oliver Newbury&lt;/a&gt;, chief strategy officer at cyber resilience vendor Halcyon and previously CISO at Barclays, tells CSO that the “strongest uses of AI in security are the ones that improve visibility and reduce noise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Teams need clearer signals, earlier warnings, and quicker routes to certainty in the middle of an unfolding incident,” Newbury says. “AI that can sift large volumes of activity, highlight meaningful patterns, and present them in a way that analysts can act on immediately is where organizations see real benefit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Newbury adds: “These capabilities help shorten investigation time and support faster, confident decision-making during high-pressure situations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A human-led approach is no longer sufficient to deal with the increased complexity and volume of threats, many security experts contend. Strategic use of AI technology has the potential to recognize patterns of attack and offer analysts the ability to cut through the noise and make better decisions, freeing up time and resources to deal with higher-value security work and move beyond constant firefighting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most security teams are overloaded, and not because they lack tools, but because they lack time and clear signals,” Newbury says. “AI earns its keep in the areas where speed and pattern recognition genuinely outperform manual effort: behavioral anomaly detection, early-stage threat indicators, and the subtle identity-related activity that often precedes a ransomware event.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="check-against-delivery"&gt;Check against delivery&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-tyler-outlier/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;David Tyler&lt;/a&gt;, founder of tech consultancy Outlier Technology, warns that some vendors slap the label ‘AI’ on existing capabilities while adding a higher price tag combined with solid product development and real advances from others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A lot of what’s being sold as breakthrough AI is actually decades-old technology finally being implemented properly; this isn’t necessarily bad, as good product management matters as much as novel algorithms,” Tyler says. “But if a vendor’s ‘AI security solution’ appeared overnight in the last couple of years, you’re probably looking at rebranding rather than genuine capability building.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="2025 Security Priorities AI Benefits Slide 24" class="wp-image-4120224" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/25-ai-benefits-R-PP_CSO_Security_Priorities_2025.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;CSO / Foundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSOs should be asking how long the vendor has been investing in these capabilities and what their product evolution looks like, according to Tyler.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Companies that have been building graph-based correlation, adaptive baselining, and behavioral analytics for a decade are very different from those who just added an AI chat function to their user interface and called it innovation,” Tyler says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewbolster/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Dr. Andrew Bolster&lt;/a&gt;, senior manager of R&amp;amp;D at application security vendor Black Duck, also warns CISOs about vendors slapping neural networks onto existing tools without fixing underlying data quality issues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Your AI-powered authentication system is only as good as your identity data hygiene,” Dr. Bolster says. “Your AI-powered malware detection is only as good as your sample corpus quality and labelling accuracy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dr Bolster adds: “Before signing contracts for AI security platforms, audit your data governance maturity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bolster also argues that CISOs themselves should focus more on how to build an AI-ready security data platform rather than which security tools they need to buy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“CISOs should invest in data mesh architectures that treat security telemetry as a first-class data product with defined ownership, quality SLAs [service level agreements], and standardized schemes,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-an-ai-security-platform"&gt;Building an AI security platform&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/merlingillespie/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Merlin Gillespie&lt;/a&gt;, operations director at managed security services provider Cybanetix, sees the AI security market maturing — and moving away from point solutions that offer reduced operational expenditure toward a more integrated approach. Gillespie warns that this shift creates fresh challenges for security leaders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These days every security tool has a layer of AI ‘assistance’ but instead of simplifying operations this is creating overlapping tools, inconsistent reporting, and unclear provenance of data,” according to Gillespie. “The learning is that AI-labelled tools are helpful but aren’t a solution in themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The exercise most organizations face is classifying which processes are eligible for automation, and which of these are enhanced by the determinism and reasoning of AI, Gillespie advises.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security teams should apply the same top-down analysis used across their wider business to support software and personnel efficiency, rather than being led by vendor tooling which can result in further siloing,” Gillespie says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="potential-pitfalls"&gt;Potential pitfalls&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Halcyon’s Newbury warned that these issues were far from the only potential pitfalls that come from deploying AI systems. For example, over-reliance on AI systems can lead to greater risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI shouldn’t replace the fundamentals such as asset management, patching, identity governance, proper segmentation, or tested recovery plans,” Newbury says. “Those disciplines matter even more as attackers adopt AI at speed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Issues inherited from the inadequate training of AI systems can also create problems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“AI systems can easily inherit blind spots if they’re trained on narrow or unrealistic datasets,” he says. “CISOs must understand how models are trained and where their assumptions break down.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ransomware remains the clearest test of whether AI investment is being prioritized in the right places, Newbury argues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Most modern [ransomware] incidents are effectively identity-based attacks,” Newbury says. “Attackers are logging in rather than ‘hacking in,’ often armed with credentials harvested at scale by &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3951147/infostealer-malware-poses-potent-threat-despite-recent-takedowns.html"&gt;infostealers&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Newbury adds: “As adversaries fold AI into their operations, you’ll see more of these attacks landing faster and hitting harder. That makes the resilience question far more urgent.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Newbury concludes: “AI is worth the investment but only where it sharpens decision-making, reduces noise, and gives teams the time and clarity to act before a problem becomes a crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120218/73-of-cisos-more-likely-to-consider-ai-enabled-security-solution.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.13</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warum Microsoft-365-Konfigurationen geschützt werden müssen</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120020/warum-microsoft-365-konfigurationen-geschutzt-werden-mussen.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Microsoft 365 Outlook" class="wp-image-4097409" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2108335628.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Lesen Sie, warum CISOs den M365-Tenant stärker in den Blick nehmen müssen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;IB Photography – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Im Jahr 2010 war Office 365 eine einfache Suite mit Office-Anwendungen und zusätzlicher E-Mail-Funktion. Das hat sich 15 Jahre später mit Microsoft 365 geändert: Die Suite ist ein wesentliches Element in den Bereichen Kommunikation, Zusammenarbeit und Sicherheit. Dienste wie Entra, Intune, Exchange, Defender, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4077862/microsoft-stoppt-ransomware-angriffe-auf-teams-nutzer.html" target="_blank"&gt;Teams&lt;/a&gt; und SharePoint verfügen über Tausende von Konfigurationsdetails, die dafür sorgen, dass Unternehmen reibungslos und sicher laufen. Wenn diese verloren gehen, versehentlich gelöscht oder absichtlich geändert werden, hat das enorme Auswirkungen auf die Geschäftsabläufe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dabei geht es um weit mehr als nur um Daten. Die Tenant-Konfigurationen sind die Blaupause für den Betrieb der M365-Umgebung. Einfach ausgedrückt: Wenn der Microsoft-365-Tenant ausfällt, fällt auch der Geschäftsbetrieb aus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trotz dieser enormen Bedeutung der Tenant-Konfigurationen ist in der IT-Welt eine Fehlannahme weit verbreitet: Rund die Hälfte aller IT-Verantwortlichen geht fälschlicherweise davon aus, dass die nativen Backup-Lösungen von Microsoft einen umfassenden Schutz für wichtige Tenant-Konfigurationen, -Einstellungen und -Richtlinien bieten. Um es deutlich zu sagen: Microsoft sichert die Konfigurationen nicht und kann sie folglich auch nicht wiederherstellen. Dies liegt gemäß dem Modell der „shared responsibility“ in der Verantwortung der Anwender.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="die-bedeutung-der-tenant-konfigurationen"&gt;Die Bedeutung der Tenant-Konfigurationen&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tenant-Konfigurationen sind die digitale Grundlage für die Sicherheitslage und die betriebliche Integrität eines Unternehmens. Sie umfassen über 10.000 einzigartige Richtlinienelemente für kritische Dienste. Sie regeln den Benutzerzugriff, die Compliance und das Anwendungsverhalten, also alles, was für den reibungslosen Ablauf eines Unternehmens unerlässlich ist:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sicherheitseinstellungen&lt;/strong&gt;: Diese erste Verteidigungslinie umfasst Richtlinien für den bedingten Zugriff, die festlegen, wer von wo aus auf was zugreifen darf, sowie Regeln für die Multi-Faktor-Authentifizierung (&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495262/multi-faktor-authentifizierung-so-finden-sie-die-passende-mfa-losung.html" target="_blank"&gt;MFA&lt;/a&gt;). Gehen diese Einstellungen verloren oder werden sie manipuliert, haben Angreifer ein leichtes Spiel und können Perimeter-Kontrollen einfach umgehen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identitätsmanagement&lt;/strong&gt;: Nahezu jedes Unternehmen (95 Prozent) war in den vergangenen 18 Monaten von einer Cloud-bezogenen Sicherheitsverletzung betroffen, wobei die meisten davon auf unsichere Identitäten zurückgeführt werden konnten. Benutzer- und Gruppeneinstellungen, Administratorrollen und App-Berechtigungen in Entra ID (ehemals Azure AD) bilden den Kern der Identitätssicherheit. Wenn diese kompromittiert werden, bricht das gesamte Framework zusammen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance-Richtlinien&lt;/strong&gt;: In regulierten Branchen ist der Nachweis der Regeltreue unverzichtbar. Policies zum Schutz vor Datenverlust (Data Loss Prevention, DLP) verhindern, dass sensible Informationen das Unternehmen verlassen, während Aufbewahrungsrichtlinien sicherstellen, dass Daten für rechtliche und Prüfungszwecke aufbewahrt werden. Kann ein Unternehmen die Einhaltung der Vorgaben nicht nachweisen, drohen empfindliche Strafen.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Einstellungen für die Zusammenarbeit&lt;/strong&gt;: Richtlinien in Teams, SharePoint und Exchange regeln die externe Freigabe, den Gastzugriff und den Datenfluss. Wenn diese Einstellungen fehlen oder falsch konfiguriert sind, riskieren Unternehmen eine unkontrollierte Offenlegung von Daten. Dadurch vergrößert sich die Angriffsfläche erheblich.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Integrität dieser Einstellungen ist das Rückgrat jeder &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491851/was-ist-zero-trust.html" target="_blank"&gt;Zero-Trust&lt;/a&gt;-Architektur. Ohne korrekte Konfigurationen lassen sich weder das Least-Privilege-Prinzip durchsetzen noch die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3494023/cybersicherheitsvorschriften-so-erfullen-sie-ihre-compliance-anforderungen.html" target="_blank"&gt;Compliance einhalten&lt;/a&gt;. Entsprechend ist der Verlust der Konfigurationen keine bloße Unannehmlichkeit, sondern bedeutet einen erheblichen Kontrollverlust über die gesamte digitale Infrastruktur.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="haufig-ubersehen-aber-essenziell"&gt;Häufig übersehen, aber essenziell&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Fehlen von Konfigurations-&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495970/die-besten-cyber-recovery-anbieter.html"&gt;Backups&lt;/a&gt; ist nicht nur eine potenzielle Security-Katastrophe, sondern spiegelt auch ein fundamentales Missverständnis darüber wider, was Microsoft 365 eigentlich ist. Dabei handelt es sich eben nicht um eine einfache Lösung. Vielleicht kann man es sich wie ein Glas Wasser vorstellen: Der Tenant ist das Glas und das Wasser sind die Daten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nicht alle Vorfälle, die Konfigurationen gefährden, sind gleich schwerwiegend. Auf der einen Seite des Spektrums können geringfügige Manipulationen an wichtigen Konfigurationen zwar ärgerlich sein, stellen jedoch keine existenzielle Bedrohung für das Unternehmen dar. Auf der anderen Seite könnten Sicherheitsverantwortliche damit konfrontiert werden, dass die Identitätsinfrastruktur und Sicherheitsvorkehrungen großflächig gelöscht worden, was eine Katastrophe mit potenziell existenzbedrohenden Folgen für das Unternehmen darstellt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Treten kleinere Fehlkonfigurationen auf, wie zum Beispiel versehentlich geänderten Berechtigungen eines einzelnen Benutzers, kann die Fehlerbehebung zwar Stunden dauern, stellt aber letztlich keine existenzielle Krise für das Unternehmen dar. Es ist vergleichbar mit einem angestoßenen Glas: Man kann es problemlos und ohne Risiko nutzen, auch wenn es nicht ideal ist.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn ein fehlerhaftes PowerShell-Skript einen bestimmten Dienst für eine begrenzte Anzahl von Benutzern unterbricht, verlangsamt dies die Produktivität und führt zu Störungen des Geschäftsbetriebs. Allerdings kann das Skript wiederhergestellt werden, auch wenn der Ausfall unbequem und zeitaufwändig ist. Dies ist vergleichbar mit einem gesprungenen Glas. Es ist zwar noch verwendbar, aber das Risiko für die Stabilität des Glases steigt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein vollständiger Verlust der Tenant-Konfigurationen führt schließlich zu massiven Ausfallzeiten und bedeutet für Unternehmen ohne Konfigurations-Backups das reine Chaos. Bedeutende Richtlinien wie Authentifizierung, E-Mail-Fluss oder Zugriffskontrolle wurden beschädigt, manipuliert oder versehentlich gelöscht, wodurch der gesamte digitale Arbeitsbereich unbrauchbar ist. Das Glas ist zerschellt. Erst wenn ein neues zur Verfügung steht, also der Tenant auf sichere Weise wiederhergestellt wurde, kann man auch wieder mit den Daten arbeiten (also das Wasser einfüllen, ohne dass es gleich wieder irgendwo ausläuft).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ohne Konfigurations-Backups, einschließlich Richtlinien, Berechtigungseinstellungen und Benutzerrollen, können Unternehmen nur mit enorm hohem Zeit- und Ressourcenaufwand zum sicheren Ausgangszustand zurückkehren. Deshalb führt an einem intelligenten Konfigurations-Backup kein Weg vorbei. Seit Jahren ist die Sicherung kritischer Daten für Unternehmen eine Selbstverständlichkeit. Es ist höchste Zeit, dass auch die Sicherung des Tenants flächendeckend umgesetzt wird. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120020/warum-microsoft-365-konfigurationen-geschutzt-werden-mussen.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.16</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actively exploited Cisco UC bug requires immediate, version‑specific patching</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120613/actively-exploited-cisco-uc-bug-requires-immediate-version%e2%80%91specific-patching.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco has released patches for a critical remote code execution vulnerability in its unified communications products that attackers are actively exploiting. The US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency has added the flaw to its Known Exploited Vulnerabilities catalog, confirming the exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco disclosed &lt;a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2026-20045" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CVE-2026-20045&lt;/a&gt; along with patches for Unified Communications Manager, Unity Connection, and Webex Calling Dedicated Instance. The company assigned the vulnerability a “Critical” severity rating despite its CVSS score of 8.2.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Cisco has assigned this security advisory a Security Impact Rating (SIR) of Critical rather than High as the score indicates,” &lt;a href="https://sec.cloudapps.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-voice-rce-mORhqY4b" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the company said in its advisory&lt;/a&gt;. “The reason is that exploitation of this vulnerability could result in an attacker elevating privileges to root.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA’s addition of the vulnerability to its KEV catalog confirms attackers are exploiting it in the wild. “This type of vulnerability is a frequent attack vector for malicious cyber actors and poses significant risks to the federal enterprise,” &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2026/01/21/cisa-adds-one-known-exploited-vulnerability-catalog" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CISA said in its alert.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the second actively exploited Cisco vulnerability CISA has added to its KEV catalog in recent weeks. Last week, the agency added &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4118159/cisco-finally-patches-seven-week-old-zero-day-flaw-in-secure-email-gateway-products-2.html"&gt;CVE-2025-20393&lt;/a&gt;, affecting Cisco’s AsyncOS software.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Other collaboration products, including Contact Center Enterprise, Emergency Responder, Finesse, Unified Intelligence Center, and Unified Contact Center Express, are not vulnerable to CVE-2026-20045,” the advisory added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="root-level-compromise-with-no-user-interaction"&gt;Root-level compromise with no user interaction&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability stems from improper validation of user-supplied input in HTTP requests. “An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a sequence of crafted HTTP requests to the web-based management interface of an affected device,” Cisco explained in the advisory. “A successful exploit could allow the attacker to obtain user-level access to the underlying operating system and then elevate privileges to root.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attack requires no user interaction and can be carried out by unauthenticated remote attackers, making it particularly dangerous for internet-facing unified communications deployments, the advisory added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco’s Product Security Incident Response Team added that it is “aware of attempted exploitation of this vulnerability in the wild,” underscoring the urgency of patching.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="no-workarounds-available"&gt;No workarounds available&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco confirmed in the advisory that there are no workarounds or mitigations available for CVE-2026-20045. The company has released fixes specific to each product version.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For Unified Communications Manager, IM&amp;amp;P, SME, and Webex Calling Dedicated Instance running version 14, the company suggested administrators can upgrade to version 14SU5 or apply a version-specific patch file. Organizations running version 15 can apply version-specific patches for 15SU2 and 15SU3a, with a full release of version 15SU4 expected in March 2026, the company added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unity Connection administrators have similar options, with version-specific patch files available for releases 14SU4 and 15SU3.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Organizations still running version 12.5 face a harder choice: Cisco won’t release patches for this version and recommends migrating to a supported release.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Customers are advised to migrate to a supported release that includes the fix for this vulnerability,” Cisco said in the advisory. Patches are version-specific, and administrators should consult the README files attached to each patch for deployment details, the advisory added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="federal-agencies-face-a-deadline"&gt;Federal agencies face a deadline&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA’s inclusion of CVE-2026-20045 in the KEV catalog triggers mandatory remediation timelines for Federal Civilian Executive Branch agencies under Binding Operational Directive 22-01. Federal agencies must patch the vulnerability within two weeks of its January 21 addition to the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While BOD 22-01 applies specifically to federal agencies, CISA “strongly recommends” that all organizations treat KEV-listed vulnerabilities as high-priority patching targets. The catalog tracks flaws with confirmed active exploitation, making them significantly more likely to be weaponized against a broader range of targets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-to-patch"&gt;How to patch&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cisco said organizations should check for signs of potential compromise on all internet-accessible instances after applying mitigations. The company advised administrators to review system logs and configurations for any unauthorized changes or suspicious activity that may indicate prior exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For organizations unable to immediately upgrade to fixed releases, the company said version-specific patch files offer an interim remediation option. However, Cisco noted that patches must match the exact software version running on the device, and administrators should verify compatibility before deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120613/actively-exploited-cisco-uc-bug-requires-immediate-version%e2%80%91specific-patching.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.30</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spanish e-retailer PcComponentes denies report it was hacked</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120572/a-hacker-using-the-alias-daghetiaw-claims-to-have-breached-the-security-of-pccomponentes.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Spanish online electronics retailer PcComponentes has denied a hacker’s claims to have stolen data on its customers. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hackrisk.io, a strategic cyber threat intelligence platform developed and maintained by Hackmanac, reported that a malicious actor using the alias ‘daghetiaw’ claimed to have hacked the e-commerce company, adding that it was attempting to verify the claim.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Hackrisk.io, the hacker allegedly stole data relating to 16.3 million people, including tax identification numbers, orders, invoices, addresses, contact details, Zendesk tickets, credit card metadata, IP addresses, and purchase information. The platform notes that the hacker has shared a sample of 500,000 lines as proof of the data theft from PcComponentes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CSO contacted PCComponentes, which issued a &lt;a href="https://www.pccomponentes.com/actualizacion-importante-oficial-seguridad-datos" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; explaining that there had been no unauthorized access to its databases or internal systems. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“What we have detected is a phenomenon known in cybersecurity as credential stuffing. This means that a third party has used email addresses and passwords obtained from security breaches in compromised databases outside of PcComponentes,” the statement said, adding, “The categories of data affected are: name, surname, ID number (in cases where the customer has entered it), address, IP, email, and telephone number.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PcComponentes said, “The figure of 16 million customers allegedly affected is false, as the number of active accounts on PcComponentes is significantly lower. Furthermore, the illegitimate access has not been widespread, meaning that only some customers have been affected.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It also explained that bank details have not been compromised in any case, “since PcComponentes does not store them, but only keeps a security code (&lt;em&gt;token&lt;/em&gt;) that is used to identify the payment, but does not allow the card to be viewed or charges to be made on its own. This code has no value outside the payment system and cannot be used fraudulently. For this reason, there is no risk of bank details being stolen”; nor are customer passwords, as “they are never stored in our database. Instead, they are converted into a secret, encrypted code (&lt;em&gt;hash&lt;/em&gt;). This code is irreversible, which means that neither we nor anyone else can see the original password.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, PcComponentes reports that it has implemented a series of measures aimed at minimizing the impact of this incident, which “significantly strengthen account protection and reduce the risk of illegitimate access from compromised databases outside PcComponentes that are published on the internet.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.computerworld.es/article/4119855/un-hacker-que-utiliza-el-alias-daghetiaw-afirma-haber-violado-la-seguridad-de-pccomponentes.html"&gt;Computerworld/CSO España&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4120572/a-hacker-using-the-alias-daghetiaw-claims-to-have-breached-the-security-of-pccomponentes.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-033)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-033</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-033</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-034)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-034</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-034</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-035)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-035</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-035</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–036)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-036</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-036</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-037)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-037</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-037</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-038)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-038</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-038</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.67</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-039)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-039</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-039</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-040)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-040</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-040</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 wichtige Security-Eigenschaften: So setzen Sie die Kraft Ihres IT-Sicherheitstechnik-Teams frei</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492187/10-wichtige-security-eigenschaften-so-setzen-sie-die-kraft-ihres-it-sicherheitstechnik-teams-frei.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lesen Sie, worauf es bei der Zusammenarbeit zwischen Ihrem IT-Security- und Engineering-Team ankommt." src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3357587/1200x.jpg" title="Lesen Sie, worauf es bei der Zusammenarbeit zwischen Ihrem IT-Security- und Engineering-Team ankommt." width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Lesen Sie, worauf es bei der Zusammenarbeit zwischen Ihrem IT-Security- und Engineering-Team ankommt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Lipik Stock Media – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security-Teams bestehen in erster Linie aus Mitarbeitern, die für den Betrieb und die Einhaltung von Vorschriften und Richtlinien zuständig sind. IT-Sicherheitstechnik-Teams, neudeutsch Security-Engineering-Teams, hingegen sind Konstrukteure. Sie entwickeln Dienste, automatisieren Prozesse und optimieren Bereitstellungen, um das zentrale IT-Sicherheitsteam und seine Stakeholder zu unterstützen. Das Security-Engineering-Team bestehen in der Regel aus Software- und Infrastrukturingenieuren, Architekten und Produktmanagern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="technische-fhigkeiten-im-bereich-it-sicherheitstechnik"&gt;Technische Fähigkeiten im Bereich IT-Sicherheitstechnik&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security Engineering ist im Wesentlichen eine technische Disziplin, so dass eines der grundlegenden Elemente dieser Rolle natürlich in der Technologie verwurzelt ist. Dies sind die wesentlichen Fähigkeiten, die CISOs in ihren Security-Engineering-Teams vermitteln und entwickeln sollten:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="verstehen-des-technischen-umfelds"&gt;Verstehen des technischen Umfelds&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dass es von entscheidender Bedeutung ist, die technische Umgebung zu verstehen und in ihr zu arbeiten, scheint eine Selbstverständlichkeit zu sein. Doch wenn ein Unternehmen beispielsweise Dienste in Kubernetes bereitstellt und das Technikteam noch nie mit Containern gearbeitet hat, ist das ein Problem. Ein hohes Maß an technischem Verständnis der gesamten IT-Umgebung wirkt sich positiv auf das Security-Team aus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Kontrapunkt dazu ist die Förderung eines vielfältigen Teams in Bezug auf die Fähigkeiten, Problemlösungsperspektiven und Erfahrungsstufen in den verschiedenen Bereichen eines Unternehmens. Es gibt natürlich viele Möglichkeiten, diese Vielfalt in einem Team anzustreben und zu fördern, vom Geschlecht und der ethnischen Zugehörigkeit über den Bildungshintergrund bis hin zu früheren Berufserfahrungen und dem Alter. Diversität kann die kreative Energie eines Teams stark erhöhen, wenn Ideen in Frage gestellt, debattiert und wiederholt werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Allerdings sollten Führungskräfte mit der Vielfalt an Perspektiven und Erfahrungen sorgfältig umgehen. Ein übermäßiges Maß an Variation und Reibung im Denk- und Kooperationsprozess kann zum Gegenteil der gewünschten Wirkung führen. Häufig kommt es zu einer Analyse-Paralyse, bei der die Teams in einem Zustand des Nachdenkens über das Tun statt des Tuns stecken bleiben. Ein ähnlicher Zustand, der sich aus übermäßig unterschiedlichen Teams ergeben kann, ist eine komplexe Reihe von voneinander abhängigen Ergebnissen, die miteinander verbundene Fehlerbedingungen aufweisen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="den-gesamten-stack-beherrschen"&gt;Den gesamten Stack beherrschen&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT-Sicherheitstechnikteams sollten in der Lage sein, die von ihnen entwickelten Dienste zu erstellen und zu betreiben. Dieses Maß an Eigenverantwortung innerhalb einer Gruppe ist aus Sicht der technischen Kompetenz und aus kultureller Sicht von entscheidender Bedeutung, da es den Ton in Bezug auf die Verantwortlichkeit angibt. Technisch gesehen wird ein Team, das in der Lage ist, seine Dienste selbst zu verwalten, die Infrastruktur, die CI/CD-Tools, die Security-Tools, den Anwendungscode, die Deployments und die von einem Dienst ausgehenden operativen Telemetriedaten kompetent verwalten. Darüber hinaus sind die Fähigkeiten, die hinter der Unterstützung durch ein Team stehen, in hohem Maße übertragbar, um andere Gruppen im Unternehmen zu unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="das-entwicklererlebnis-miteinbeziehen-devx"&gt;Das Entwicklererlebnis miteinbeziehen (DevX)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security-Teams, die das Entwickler-Tool DevX verstehen, annehmen und optimieren, werden wahrscheinlich besser zusammenarbeiten. Darüber hinaus wird ein besonderer Schwerpunkt auf der Beseitigung von Reibungsverlusten liegen. Reibung führt dazu, dass Dinge länger dauern und mehr kosten, dass sich Lernzyklen verlängern und dass Frustration auftritt. Weniger Reibung wird dazu führen, dass die Dinge im Allgemeinen viel besser ablaufen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Manchmal sind Reibungen aber auch notwendig und sollten gewollt sein. Ein Beispiel ist eine erzwungene Codeüberprüfung von kritischem Code, bevor er zusammengeführt wird. Wenn diese Unterbrechung, Überprüfung und Zusammenführung auf einer bewussten Entscheidung beruht, ist das eine gerechtfertigte, bewusste Reibung. Wenn das IT-Sicherheitsteam Reibungsverluste im Freigabeprozess von Entwicklern anstrebt, sollten diese auf spezifischen Anforderungen beruhen, zum Beispiel auf einer Compliance-Kontrolle, die eine manuelle Überprüfung als Teil des Change Managements vorschreibt. Diese Kontrollen sollten nicht unüberlegt eingesetzt werden. Die Reibungsverluste, die den Entwicklern entstehen, stellen Nachteile dar, die jedes vom IT-Sicherheitsteam in Betracht gezogene, nicht definierte Risiko aufwiegen könnten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IT-Sicherheitsteams, die die Erfahrung der Entwickler als oberste Priorität betrachten, müssen die Werkzeuge und Abläufe verstehen, die für das Schreiben von Qualitätssoftware auf verschiedenen Ebenen des Stacks erforderlich sind. Die Übernahme dieser Denkweise, bei der der Entwickler im Vordergrund steht, erfordert möglicherweise Kenntnisse im Bereich Infrastruktur oder Plattform-Engineering. Andererseits kann sich der Output eines IT-Sicherheitstechnik-Teams auf andere auswirken, die ebenfalls mit der Automatisierung von Arbeitsabläufen, der Verbindung von Diensten untereinander und im Wesentlichen mit der gemeinsamen Instrumentierung einer immer größer werdenden Umgebung beschäftigt sind. All diese Arbeiten helfen den Entwicklern, schneller und mit weniger Reibungsverlusten zu arbeiten. Resultat sind mehr Flexibilität und ein schnelleres Deployment. Unabhängig davon ist dies eine Eigenschaft und ein Leitfaden, von dem ein Security-Engineering-Tem in seiner Produktivität profitiert und das Einfühlungsvermögen derer, denen es dient, fördert und kultiviert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="fhigkeiten-zur-fhrung-und-zusammenarbeit-in-der-sicherheitstechnik"&gt;Fähigkeiten zur Führung und Zusammenarbeit in der Sicherheitstechnik&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security-Entwickler-Teams arbeiten nicht im luftleeren Raum, unabhängig von ihrem Umfang und ihrer Projektauslastung. Die Arbeit an der Seite und im Dienste anderer ist ein wesentlicher Bestandteil des Auftrags. Sie ist ein notwendiger Teil des Ganzen und hilft anderen, erfolgreiche Ergebnisse zu erzielen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="kommunizieren-und-zusammenarbeiten"&gt;Kommunizieren und zusammenarbeiten&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Mitglieder des Security-Engineering-Teams sollten in der Lage sein, miteinander und mit den Beteiligten außerhalb der Gruppe zu kommunizieren. Darüber hinaus sollten sie die Fähigkeit besitzen, gut zusammenzuarbeiten, um die gemeinsamen Ziele zu erreichen. Verstehen der Probleme, der Reibungspunkte, der Beschränkungen und der Möglichkeiten der IT-sicherheitsorientierten Entwicklung. Letztendlich ist es wichtiger, die richtigen Dinge zu tun, als einfach nur effizient zu arbeiten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All diese Fragen müssen durch gezielte Kommunikation und Zusammenarbeit erforscht werden. Dies kann sich in menschenzentrierten Gestaltungsprinzipien, matrixbasierten Ressourcen oder einer auf Teamtopologien basierenden Ausrichtung manifestieren. Natürlich gibt es kein Patentrezept für die Kommunikation und Zusammenarbeit in und zwischen Teams. Unabhängig von der Herangehensweise sind Vertrauensbildung, Einfühlungsvermögen, Interesse an gemeinsamen Zielen und die Bereitschaft, den eigenen Stolz zugunsten der Mission zurückzustellen, die Grundlage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="fhren-und-andere-beeinflussen"&gt;Führen und andere beeinflussen&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Seth Godin, Bestsellerautor und Marketingexperte, vertritt die Ansicht, dass jeder eine Führungspersönlichkeit sein kann – es ist eine Entscheidung, kein Titel. Es geht um das Zusammentreffen von Ideen, eine Lücke in der Richtung und jemanden, der motiviert genug ist, sich zu engagieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Erfolg von Security-Engineering-Teams ist, wie bei anderen Cybersecurity-Bereichen auch, von anderen abhängig. Er ist jedoch unabhängig von der Leistung des Teams, so optimal diese auch sein mag. Anders ausgedrückt: Man kann nicht einfach etwas bauen und dann gehen. Sie müssen anderen zuhören, sie einbeziehen, sie zur Übernahme bewegen und vieles mehr.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All das erfordert Führung. Genauer gesagt, Führung ohne Autorität. Die Mitglieder eines leistungsstarken Teams sollten in der Lage sein, das IT-Sicherheitstechnikteam selbst zu leiten und außerhalb der Gruppe Einfluss aufzubauen und zu nutzen. Das kann mit anderen Beteiligten oder mit internen Kunden eines Dienstes geschehen. Führen ohne Autorität bringt das Team dem Erfolg näher. Starke Beziehungen, organisatorisches Wissen und Kontext sowie technisches Fachwissen sollte zusammengebracht werden, um andere zu beeinflussen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="soft-skills-fr-sicherheitsingenieure"&gt;Soft Skills für Sicherheitsingenieure&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Fähigkeiten eines Security Engineers und des gesamten Teams sollten über Kommunikation und Zusammenarbeit hinausgehen. In diesem Zusammenhang bezieht sich der Begriff “Soft Skills” auf die zahlreichen nichttechnischen Fähigkeiten, die eher nach innen gerichtet sind und die technischen Fähigkeiten ergänzen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="zeit-und-priorittenmanagement"&gt;Zeit- und Prioritätenmanagement&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security-Entwickler werden immer viel zu tun haben. Die technischen Fähigkeiten führen dazu, dass häufig Anfragen zum Erstellen, Härten, Patchen oder allgemein zum Einmischen in die Software einer Umgebung eingehen werden. Zeit ist eine universelle Einschränkung für alle Teams. Aus diesem Grund müssen sowohl Einzelpersonen als auch Teams effektiver darin werden, Prioritäten zu setzen. Effizient zu sein, aber die falschen Dinge zu tun, bringt keinen Fortschritt. Es gibt viele Techniken, um Arbeit zu priorisieren, Wert gegen Komplexität abzuwägen und sich auf die Kundenzufriedenheit zu konzentrieren oder verschiedene Faktoren zu gewichten. Kunden- und Compliance-Anforderungen sind oft die treibende Kraft hinter den Prioritäten des Teams. Die Art der Prioritätensetzung ist weniger wichtig als die rücksichtslose Einhaltung der Prioritäten und der Schutz vor dem endlosen Ansturm von Anfragen, die mehr wertvolle Zeit in Anspruch nehmen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="anpassungsfhigkeit"&gt;Anpassungsfähigkeit&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security-Engineering-Teams sollten in der Lage sein, sich an veränderte Anforderungen, Technologien und Umstände anzupassen. Anpassungsfähigkeit bedeutet mehr als die Priorisierung einer Aufgabe gegenüber einer anderen: Entscheiden ist die Anpassung der Herangehensweise an ein Problem auf der Grundlage der Bedürfnisse der Beteiligten. IT-Sicherheitstechnikteams müssen sich an die Eigenverantwortung auf der Grundlage des Teamwachstums und der sich ändernden Bedürfnisse der Interessengruppen sowie an die bewusste Einbeziehung einer vielfältigen Gruppe von Stimmen in den Problemlösungsprozess anpassen. Der Nutzen für die Beteiligten und die gesamte IT-Sicherheitsorganisation liegt dabei in der Agilität und Flexibilität. Ein agiles Team ist ein widerstandsfähigeres Team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="kontinuierliches-lernen"&gt;Kontinuierliches Lernen&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein Team, das in der Lage ist, ständig neue Fähigkeiten, organisatorische Zusammenhänge, Richtlinien und Arbeitsweisen zu erlernen, ist in der heutigen schnelllebigen Welt unbedingt notwendig. So sollten sich Mitglieder des Security Engineering-Teams ständig weiterentwickeln, sich selbst erneuern und auf bestehenden mentalen Modellen und Erfahrungen aufbauen. Dieses Konstrukt mentaler Modelle ermöglicht es Menschen, in Situationen einzutreten, die ähnliche Eigenschaften aufweisen wie etwas, an dem sie zuvor gearbeitet haben, und damit zu beginnen, etwas beizutragen, zu erforschen und zu tun.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kontinuierliches Lernen kann sich auch auf die Kultur in einer Organisation auswirken. Wissen führt zum Austausch, Austausch führt zu Diskussionen und die Diskussion über neue Dinge weckt Interesse und Gespräche. Diese kollektive Entwicklung der mentalen Modelle, die das Unternehmen durchdringen, und der Art und Weise, wie Teams mit IT-Sicherheit umgehen und sich darauf beziehen, bringt die Kultur der Zusammenarbeit voran.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Arbeit in diesem hoch spezialisierten Bereich bedeutet nicht, dass sich ein leistungsstarkes Team nur auf die Technologie konzentrieren kann. Menschen, die Erforschung von Problemen, der Aufbau von Beziehungen und die Festlegung von Prioritäten sind allesamt wesentliche Bestandteile eines leistungsstarken Sicherheitstechnikteams. Achten Sie beim Aufbau Ihres Teams darauf, diese Elemente zu investieren und zu pflegen. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesetipp:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492380/applikation-security-per-devsecops-fehlendes-knowhow-eine-gefahr-fur-die-anwendungssicherheit.html" target="_blank" title="Fehlendes Knowhow – eine Gefahr für die Anwendungssicherheit"&gt;Fehlendes Knowhow – eine Gefahr für die Anwendungssicherheit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3687180/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-an-effective-security-engineering-team.html" target="_blank" title="Dieser Beitrag basiert auf einem Artikel unserer US-Schwesterpublikation CSO Online."&gt;Dieser Beitrag basiert auf einem Artikel unserer US-Schwesterpublikation CSO Online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492187/10-wichtige-security-eigenschaften-so-setzen-sie-die-kraft-ihres-it-sicherheitstechnik-teams-frei.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.88</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juniper Networks security advisory (AV26-041)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-041</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/juniper-networks-security-advisory-av26-041</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – January 2026 quarterly rollup (AV26-042)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-january-2026-quarterly-rollup-av26-042</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.59</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-043)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-043</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-043</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-044)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-044</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.60</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV26-045)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av26-045</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-046)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-046</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNU security advisory (AV26-047)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gnu-security-advisory-av26-047</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV26-048)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av26-048</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-002 -Vulnerability affecting GNU Inetutils Telnetd - CVE-2026-24061</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-002-vulnerability-affecting-gnu-inetutils-telnetd-cve-2026-24061</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISC BIND security advisory (AV26-049)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/isc-bind-security-advisory-av26-049</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Spot at RSAC 2026 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10654428.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
