<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:41:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-749)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-749</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-749</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.31</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 arrested for smuggling migrants from Türkiye to France and Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</link>
      <description>On 13 November 2025, the German Federal Police, in close cooperation with French border police and with the support of Europol and Eurojust, have dismantled a criminal network believed to have smuggled nearly 600 people into Europe between 2021 and 2023.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/6-arrested-for-smuggling-migrants-turkiye-to-france-and-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.33</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV25-750)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-750</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av25-750</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV25-751)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-751</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av25-751</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sneaky2FA phishing tool adds ability to insert legit-looking URLs</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094165/sneaky2fa-phishing-tool-adds-ability-to-insert-legit-looking-urls.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of multi-factor authentication (MFA), threat actors have been finding ways to get around what can be an effective defense against phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In their latest move, those behind the Sneaky2FA phishing-as-a-service (PhaaS) kit have added browser-in-the-browser (BITB) functionality to help crooks design phishing pages that fool victims.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This function allows the crook to embed a browser window on the victim’s desktop containing a phishing page that includes a URL address bar that can be customized by the attacker to look like a legitimate address to, for example, Microsoft online. BITB differs from attacker-in-the-middle (AITM) attacks, where the threat actor creates an embedded browser window that contains the actual phishing page. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Employees trained to look for suspicious URLs might even be fooled, because the internet address looks real. However,  the pop-up window, enabled through a reverse proxy, contains an iframe pointing to a malicious server that captures credentials and MFA codes entered by the unwitting victim. Then the attacker can steal the live session of the account being targeted, as well as user credentials, by logging in in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-warning-to-csos"&gt;A warning to CSOs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report this week &lt;a href="https://pushsecurity.com/blog/analyzing-the-latest-sneaky2fa-phishing-page/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;from researchers at Push Security &lt;/a&gt;describing the Sneaky2FA browser-in-the-browser capability is a warning to CSOs that they have to adapt their employee security awareness training as well as their defensive technology.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;BITB tactics are spreading, says the report. It notes that Raccoon0365 was another PhaaS service that has utilized BITB functionality after announcing a ‘BITB mini-panel’ would be added to its offerings. In September, Cloudflare and Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4058634/microsoft-and-cloudflare-execute-rugpull-on-massive-phishing-empire.html" target="_blank"&gt;dismantled that gang’s IT infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;BITB has been known as a concept since 2022, notes David Shipley, head of Canadian-based security awareness training firm Beauceron Security. In fact, he added, it is increasingly used by advanced red teams in penetration tests to defeat security controls like MFA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It hasn’t been widely used because it hasn’t been needed to get the job done when it comes to compromising organizations,” he said. But as defenses improve, he’s seen use of this technique increase.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What’s dangerous, he said, is that phishing-as-a-service tools are making it easier for entry-level criminals to use these more advanced techniques. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is why I’ve always hated it when people use language like ‘phishing resistant,’ or even worse, ‘phishing proof’ solutions. Additional identity controls like MFA add more friction and resiliency, but can still be bypassed by clever attackers. That’s why it’s critical organizations have both robust technology security control as well as an aware community.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That means CSOs and infosec leaders have to do more than just annual compliance-driven security training, Shipley said, instead motivating employees to keep an eye out for unusual things in messaging so they spot and stop phishing and other cyber attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“That’s where many organizations are struggling,” he said. “Not in instructing people or passing on knowledge, but in creating a security culture that motivates people to apply knowledge.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570795/how-to-hack-2fa.html" target="_blank"&gt;Related content: How MFA gets hacked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The addition of BITB, along with the improvement of detection evasion techniques, means that traditional security controls such as email gateways, web filters, and signature-based defenses will continue to be reliably bypassed, Push Security’s report says. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-look-at-sneaky2fa"&gt;A look at Sneaky2FA&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sneaky2FA operates through a full-featured bot on Telegram, says the report. Customers reportedly receive access to a licensed, obfuscated version of the source code and deploy it independently. This means they can customize it to their needs. On the other hand, the report notes, Sneaky2FA implementations can be reliably profiled and tracked due to the codebase similarities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sneaky2FA has been frequently seen using anti-analysis techniques to detect or disable browser developer tools so they can block attempts to analyze the page for malicious content, the report adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Defenders should note that the HTML and JavaScript of Sneaky2FA pages are heavily obfuscated to evade static detection and pattern-matching, the report says. This includes using tactics such as breaking up UI text with invisible tags, embedding background and interface elements as encoded images instead of text, and other changes that are invisible to the user, but make it hard for scanning tools to fingerprint the page.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Campaigns are also known to use a ‘burn-and-replace’ tactic, hiding behind a fresh, long, randomized URL that lies dormant or serves harmless content until right before the attack, and then quickly vanishes. This is to defeat domain reputation or pattern-matching defense technologies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-game-of-cat-and-mouse"&gt;A game of cat and mouse&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-g-/"&gt;Dan Green&lt;/a&gt;, author of the Push Security report, told &lt;em&gt;CSO &lt;/em&gt;in an email that email isn’t the only way BITB attacks are spreading. In the past several months, his firm has seen LinkedIn Messenger and Google Search being used as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We would encourage security teams to re-evaluate how they approach phishing detection,” he said. “[Phishing] is becoming increasingly sophisticated, it’s no longer just an email problem, and the risks are significant. A compromised enterprise cloud account (for example, Microsoft or Google Workspace) is effectively the key to everything you access in the course of the modern workday. This isn’t just the direct access to your enterprise cloud suite, but the downstream application access via SSO (single sign-on) that can be hijacked by the attacker. Most breaches start with compromised identities today, compared with software exploits or malware execution.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.knowbe4.com/author/roger-grimes"&gt;Roger Grimes&lt;/a&gt;, data driven defense CISO advisor at security awareness training provider KnowBe4, noted that browser vendors have worked for decades trying to prevent malicious popup boxes from appearing because they are so tricky. However, he added, criminals keep on figuring out ways to bypass the protections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, he added, it is getting ever harder for criminals to create malicious popup boxes. Users still have a chance to see what is happening if they are aware, he said. “Sadly,” he said, “a large percentage of users don’t.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Educating users by providing information and examples of how browser pop-up attacks work is key, he said. In addition, CSOs should make sure browsers used by employees are as well configured as they can be to prevent these types of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Browser vendors will respond and close the holes, but it’s always a reactive game of cat-and-mouse with the defenders always behind.” he said. “Pretty soon AI-enabled defense tools will do a better job at preventing them from happening at all. We just have to cover the gap for now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094165/sneaky2fa-phishing-tool-adds-ability-to-insert-legit-looking-urls.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 02:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV25-752)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-752</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av25-752</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Rockwell Automation security advisory (AV25-753)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-rockwell-automation-security-advisory-av25-753</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-rockwell-automation-security-advisory-av25-753</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 21:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So rechtfertigen Sie Ihre Security-Investitionen</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4051211/so-rechtfertigen-sie-ihre-security-investitionen.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;


&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Investitionen" class="wp-image-4051223" height="576" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/shutterstock_2544942275.jpg?quality=50&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;Lesen Sie, welche Aspekte entscheidend sind, um die Investitionen in die Cybersicherheit im Unternehmen zu rechtfertigen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt;Miha Creative – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In modernen Unternehmensumgebungen werden Investitionen in Sicherheitstechnologien nicht mehr nur anhand ihres technischen Reifegrades beurteilt. Die Finanzierung hängt vermehrt davon ab, inwieweit sich damit Umsatz generieren lässt, Risiken gemindert und Mehrwerte für Aktionäre geschaffen werden. Von CISOs wird erwartet, dass sie ihre Strategien nicht als technische Upgrades, sondern als Wegbereiter für Umsatzsteigerungen präsentieren. Die Herausforderung besteht dabei nicht nur darin, die richtigen Investitionsentscheidungen zu treffen, sondern diese auch auf Vorstandsebene zu rechtfertigen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Am Anfang muss die Herausforderung stehen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISOs geraten oft in Erklärungsnot, wenn sie Lösungen präsentieren, bevor die Herausforderung definiert ist. Ein solches Vorgehen schafft Distanz anstelle von Übereinstimmung. Vorstände wollen verstehen, was ihre Organisation mit einem neuen Lösungsansatz erreichen kann, welche Fallstricke vermieden werden und warum Cybersecurity-Investitionen nicht aufschiebbar sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bei der Präsentation einer Cybersicherheitsstrategie wie &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3491851/was-ist-zero-trust.html" target="_blank"&gt;Zero Trust&lt;/a&gt; sollte deshalb der Kommunikationsschwerpunkt mit dem Vorstand darauf liegen, wie das Cyberrisiko-Profil des Unternehmens zum Positiven verändert werden kann.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technologie mit strategischen Prioritäten verknüpfen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Um in der Vorstandsetage glaubwürdig zu sein, müssen CISOs ihre geplanten Ausgaben anhand der Unternehmenszielsetzung definieren. Der Vorstand konzentriert sich auf Prioritäten wie neue Märkte zu erschließen, die Margen zu verbessern, die Widerstandsfähigkeit zu steigern und die Compliance zu gewährleisten. Ein gut durchdachter Vorschlag knüpft direkt an diese Anliegen an.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn eine Sicherheitsplattform die Reaktionszeit bei Vorfällen verkürzt, ist das Ergebnis operative Stabilität und damit eine höhere &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4004443/operationelle-resilienz-koordination-kooperation-im-fokus.html" target="_blank"&gt;Resilienz&lt;/a&gt;. Wenn sie Tools konsolidiert, sorgt sie für Kosteneffizienz. Wenn sie eine sichere Expansion in neue Regionen ermöglicht, ist Umsatzwachstum die Folge. Eine solche Argumentationskette schafft Glaubwürdigkeit und hilft dabei, Investitionen bewilligt zu bekommen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eine Sprache für Risiken und Rendite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vorstände treffen Entscheidungen unter der Berücksichtigung von Begrifflichkeiten wie Risiko und Rendite. Dazu gehören finanzielle Risiken, operative Risiken und Reputationsrisiken für das Unternehmen. Vorstandsmitglieder bewerten Wahrscheinlichkeit, Exposition und Auswirkungen von Vorfällen in jedem dieser Bereiche. Dementsprechend besteht die Aufgabe des CISOs darin, zu verdeutlichen, wie eine vorgeschlagene Investition Schwachstellen reduziert, Auswirkungen von Vorfällen begrenzt oder die Resilienz der Infrastruktur erhöht.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Gespräche sollten Kostenmodelle, Szenarien für mögliche Sicherheitsverletzungen, Zeitpläne für die &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495970/die-besten-cyber-recovery-anbieter.html" target="_blank"&gt;Wiederherstellung nach einem Cyberangriff&lt;/a&gt; und den geschäftlichen Nutzen aufzeigen. Das Ziel sollte sein, Ausfallzeiten zu vermeiden und dabei die Sprache der Vorstände zu sprechen, ohne die technische Integrität zu vernachlässigen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shareholder Value bedenken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Reifegrad und auch die Denkweisen von Vorständen in Bezug auf die Cybersicherheit variieren deutlich. Einige Kontrollgremien reagieren erst nach einem größeren Cybervorfall oder einem nicht bestandenen Audit. Andere sind sehr viel proaktiver in ihrer Vorgehensweise und fordern Cybersicherheitsbewertungen als Teil ihrer Marktexpansion oder M&amp;amp;A-Aktivitäten. Andere beziehen Cybersicherheit in Simulationen ein und stellen zukunftsorientierte Fragen zur Widerstandsfähigkeit angesichts potenzieller Angriffsszenarien.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das Verständnis dieses Reifegrades hilft dabei, die Kommunikationsstrategie anzupassen. Ein reaktiver Vorstand benötigt möglicherweise eine klare Erklärung der negativen Folgen. Ein informierter Vorstand erwartet eher quantifizierbare Ergebnisse und eine Roadmap. Die besten Vorstandsdiskussionen finden statt, wenn sich der CISO an das Technologieverständnis des Vorstands anpasst und gleichzeitig dessen Perspektive behutsam erweitert.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lesetipp: &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3492322/cybersecurity-messen-10-kennzahlen-die-cisos-weiterbringen.html" target="_blank"&gt;10 Kennzahlen, die CISOs weiterbringen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operative Exzellenz als Ergebnis positionieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eines der wirksamsten Argumente in den Gesprächen mit dem Vorstand zum Thema Cybersicherheit ist operative Exzellenz. Wenn Unternehmen in unterschiedlichen Regionen und Branchen tätig sind, müssen sie agil, abgesichert und kontrolliert arbeiten. Eine IT-Architektur sollte&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;globale Anforderungen adressieren und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;dabei Mitarbeitende unterstützen, die von überall aus arbeiten,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Drittparteien integrieren,&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;eine Reihe von regulatorischen Anforderungen erfüllen und&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;geistiges Eigentum schützen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ein derart umfangreiches Anforderungsprofil kann sehr schnell zu einer komplexen Umsetzung und dadurch zu Ineffizienzen führen. CISOs setzen mit einer starken Technologiestrategie auf eine vereinfachte Infrastruktur, ermöglichen sichere globale Datenflüsse und verkürzen Markteintrittszeiten. Eine solche Positionierung hebt die Diskussion von der Systemauswahl auf eine strategische Ebene.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zukünftige Risiken im Fokus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Von einem Vorstand wird erwartet, dass er sich nicht nur auf aktuelle Risiken konzentriert, sondern auch auf zukünftige Szenarien. Dazu gehören beispielsweise die Regulierung der ethischen &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4030328/so-verandert-ki-ihre-grc-strategie.html" target="_blank"&gt;Nutzung von KI&lt;/a&gt;, das Verständnis der Auswirkungen von Datenmissbrauch und die Vorbereitung auf die Auswirkungen des Quantencomputings. Der Vorstand wird für den sicheren und regulierten Umgang mit Daten verantwortlich und sogar haftbar gemacht. Dies sind keine abstrakten Themen mehr. Deshalb sollten sie bereits jetzt als künftige technologische Herausforderungen auf der CISO-Agenda stehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die Nutzung von KI hat in Unternehmen zugenommen und Vorstände haben für die Verwendung von Daten geradezustehen. Quantencomputing ist zwar noch im Anfangsstadium, aber das Risiko der zukünftigen Technologie für heutige Verschlüsselungen macht es schon jetzt zu einem notwendigen Bestandteil jeder langfristigen Planung. Viele CISOs nutzen die Chance bereits, das Thema beim Vorstand zu positionieren und zu erklären, welche Maßnahmen in absehbarer Zukunft zum Schutz der Daten erforderlich sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Die Macht der Zahlen&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die finanzielle Ausgestaltung ist genauso wichtig wie die strategische Vorgehensweise. Da immer mehr Unternehmen von hardwareintensiven Architekturen zu Cloud-nativen SaaS- Modellen übergehen, verändert sich die Wirtschaftlichkeit der Sicherheit. Die Kosten verlagern sich von Kapitalausgaben zu Betriebsausgaben. Dies kann zwar zunächst zu einer Verringerung des EBITDA (betriebswirtschaftliche Kennzahl/Earnings Before Interest,Taxes, Depreciation and Amortization) führen, eliminiert jedoch auch Hardware-Erneuerungszyklen, verbessert die Prognosegenauigkeit und senkt die langfristigen Gesamtbetriebskosten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Abrechnungsmodelle pro User für Cloud-Services sorgen für Vorhersehbarkeit und höhere Flexibilität als Reaktion auf Veränderungen. Weiteres Einsparpotenzial besteht in der Konsolidierung von Tools auf wenige Plattformanbieter. Zusätzlich kann die Automatisierung von Prozessen den Service Desk entlasten und die Produktivität verbessern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Letztlich sollten CISOs aufzeigen, wie potenzielle Investitionen in neue Technologien den Cashflow verbessern, Margen sichern und mit dem Unternehmenswachstum skalieren. CFOs und Prüfungsausschüsse möchten wissen, wie sich jeder Vorschlag auf die Finanzergebnisse auswirkt. Sie möchten auch verstehen, was kapitalisiert werden kann, welche Ausgleichseffekte zu erwarten sind und wie sich die Investitionen mit der Nachfrage entwickeln werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fazit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Letztendlich geht es bei der Rechtfertigung von Security-Investitionen nicht um Überzeugungsarbeit, sondern um Einflussnahme. Es geht darum, die Geschäftsprioritäten mit sicheren, skalierbaren und kostengünstigen Lösungen in Einklang zu bringen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dementsprechend müssen CISOs eine Strategie präsentieren, die Risiken reduziert, die Agilität verbessert und das Unternehmen für langfristigen Erfolg positioniert. Wenn die IT-Führungsriege die Sprache des Mehrwerts von Lösungsansätzen spricht, klingen ihre Vorschläge nicht mehr wie technische Anforderungen, sondern wie geschäftliche Notwendigkeiten. (jm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4051211/so-rechtfertigen-sie-ihre-security-investitionen.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.43</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splunk security advisory (AV25-754)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-754</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/splunk-security-advisory-av25-754</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-755)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-755</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-755</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.47</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-756)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-756</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-756</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV25-757)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-757</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av25-757</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-758)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-758</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-758</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.48</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL25-017 - Vulnerability impacting Fortinet FortiWeb – CVE-2025-64446</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-017-vulnerability-impacting-fortinet-fortiweb-cve-2025-64446</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al25-017-vulnerability-impacting-fortinet-fortiweb-cve-2025-64446</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco security advisory (AV25-759)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-759</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/cisco-security-advisory-av25-759</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.50</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 arrests in Bulgaria in a large art trafficking investigation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</link>
      <description>On 19 November 2025, a coordinated effort led by Bulgarian authorities and supported by Europol, resulted in the dismantling of a criminal network involved in large-scale trafficking of cultural goods across Europe and beyond. This operation was conducted under the framework of a Europol operational taskforce. The action day involved law enforcement and judicial authorities from Albania, France, Germany, Greece,...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/35-arrests-in-bulgaria-in-large-art-trafficking-investigation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 years on: remembering the victims of the 13 November terrorist attack in Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</link>
      <description>Today marks ten years since one of the deadliest terrorist attacks in recent European history was carried out in Paris - at the Stade de France, in the streets and inside the Bataclan concert hall. On 13 November 2015, 132 people lost their lives and many more were injured during what became a night of profound tragedy for France and...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/10-years-remembering-victims-of-13-november-terrorist-attack-in-paris</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europol and partner countries combat online radicalisation on gaming platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</link>
      <description>Conducted on 13 November 2025, this operational action by the European Union Internet Referral Unit (EU IRU) involved the referral of thousands of URLs leading to dangerous and illicit online material. This includes around 5 408 links to jihadist content, 1 070 links to violent right-wing extremist and terrorist content, and 105 links to racist and xenophobic content.This joint action...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-and-partner-countries-combat-online-radicalisation-gaming-platforms</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EUR 47 million in crypto traced to disrupt digital piracy services</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November, Europol, in collaboration with the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO) and the Spanish National Police (Policía Nacional), organised an "Intellectual Property Crime Cyber-Patrol Week”. A total of 30 investigators participated in this operation hosted at the EUIPO headquarters in Alicante, Spain, where they used advanced Open-Source Intelligence Techniques (OSINT) and cutting-edge online investigative tools...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eur-47-million-in-crypto-traced-to-disrupt-digital-piracy-services</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the winners of the 2025 Europol photo competition</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</link>
      <description>Three awards were given out, each decided by a different group of voters:the international law enforcement community represented at Europol’s headquarters,members of the public,and the Heads of Communication of the European law enforcement authorities.The winners of Capture25The Europol Community Vote by the Liaison Bureaux went to Johan Jacob Kleist from Denmark with his photo of a ‘police officer patrolling beneath...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/announcing-winners-of-2025-europol-photo-competition</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognizing and responding to cyber threats: What differentiates NDR, EDR and XDR</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4091641/recognizing-and-responding-to-cyber-threats-what-differentiates-ndr-edr-and-xdr.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The constantly growing number of acronyms in cyber security makes it difficult to maintain an overview and compare individual technologies. One example is the three closely related technologies for threat detection: network detection and response (NDR), &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/568045/what-is-edr-endpoint-detection-and-response.html" target="_blank"&gt;endpoint detection and response&lt;/a&gt; (EDR) and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574295/11-top-xdr-tools-and-how-to-evaluate-them.html" target="_blank"&gt;extended detection and response&lt;/a&gt; (XDR). Each of them offers a comprehensive solution for detecting and responding to different cyberattacks. Although they are based on similar approaches, there are some differences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="edr-identifies-noticeable-changes-at-the-endpoint"&gt;EDR identifies noticeable changes at the endpoint&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;EDR, the oldest of the three detection technologies, monitors endpoints to mitigate attacks on them. Endpoints are network devices such as PCs, file servers, smartphones and IoT devices that connect to the network to communicate. A software agent is used to inventory EDR malware and suspicious activity detected on the endpoint, such as registry changes and key file tampering.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As network environments become more complex over time and threat actors and malware become more sophisticated, EDR faces the following challenges:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Required EDR agents cannot be deployed on all devices or in all environments, leaving gaps in visibility and opening the door for attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some common applications can bypass EDR. For example, Microsoft SQL Server has administrative access to the underlying Windows operating system without using any of the EDR-monitored environments mentioned above, allowing an attacker to bypass endpoint detection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Malware and attackers are becoming more sophisticated and are able to detect anti-malware software on the endpoint or hide evidence of endpoint compromise altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While EDR is a necessary component of a modern cybersecurity strategy, it cannot be used alone for comprehensive cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="xdr-offers-holistic-protection"&gt;XDR offers holistic protection&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many people mistakenly think of XDR as a product or an evolution of EDR. However, XDR is a strategy that consists of a combination of security-related telemetry data coupled with high-fidelity detection to enable faster and more effective incident response.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are different types of XDR. There is a proprietary XDR strategy that focuses on a single vendor or an “all-in-one” platform that provides telemetry data from a vendor’s various products, for example, their firewalls, EDR, NDR and so on. There is also an open XDR strategy that consists of multiple vendors or “best-of-breed” technologies or tools. Here, telemetry data is provided by different product types (such as firewall, intrusion detection system [IDS], EDR and NDR) and vendors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many organizations believe that an EDR-centric XDR strategy is sufficient, but this leads to a problematic blind spot. If the EDR agent overview is lost, there is no other way to find or investigate a potential critical security breach. With this single-point focused telemetry strategy, attackers only need to bypass one technology or defense to penetrate the network. Cybersecurity managers need to detect changes in network activity and compare it to endpoint and cloud data. This is where NDR solutions can provide the context needed to focus on potential cyber threats.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading tip:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4012841/6-key-trends-redefining-the-xdr-market.html"&gt;6 key trends redefining the XDR market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ndr-detects-threats-at-packet-level-and-reacts-in-real-time"&gt;NDR detects threats at packet level and reacts in real time&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike EDR or XDR solutions, NDR focuses on analyzing packet data in network traffic to detect potential cyberthreats, rather than endpoints or other data streams. By combining NDR with other solutions such as log analysis tools via &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/524286/what-is-siem-security-information-and-event-management-explained.html" target="_blank"&gt;security information and event management&lt;/a&gt; (SIEM) and EDR, organizations can mitigate blind spots in their networks. Together, NDR solutions increase security capabilities by providing network context and automating responses to threats, enabling better collaboration between network and IT security teams and faster mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, in the context of NDR, it is important to differentiate the capabilities of advanced platforms that provide features that modern cybersecurity stacks should include. For example, when evaluating different NDRs, it is important to ensure that they offer reliable forensics with long-term data retention. It is also crucial that they do not rely on NetFlow-based data. These are not supported in all environments and offer opportunities for sophisticated tunneling-based attacks. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Advanced NDR systems should even provide a retrospective view of network traffic to examine threat behavior before, during and after attacks. So if an indicator of compromise (IOC) is detected, security teams can examine the compromised hosts’ communications, detect lateral movement and determine if a data breach has occurred.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="edr-xdr-ndr-together-they-are-strong"&gt;EDR, XDR, NDR: Together they are strong&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To summarize, EDRs are designed to monitor and mitigate attacks on endpoints via connected computers and servers. However, only where agents can be deployed. Therefore, EDR does not work in some cloud-based hosting environments, for example. In contrast, XDRs provide a more unified platform approach to monitoring devices and data streams, but often lack the network context that NDRs provide through real-time packet monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most large organizations today require a more comprehensive solution that combines network and endpoint data with other security solutions to provide a more robust, real-time view of the ever-changing threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Advanced NDR solutions provide a high level of network intelligence and effectively complement the rest of the security stack. In addition to SIEM, an advanced NDR solution can also be integrated into &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3622920/soar-buyers-guide-11-security-orchestration-automation-and-response-products-and-how-to-choose.html" target="_blank"&gt;security orchestration, automation and response&lt;/a&gt; (SOAR) or firewall platforms to initiate immediate blocking at the network perimeter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After all, it is impossible to cover your tracks on the network and cyber attacks are becoming increasingly sophisticated. Working together, these systems provide a complete overview of attacker behavior and indicators of compromise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Advanced NDR makes an important contribution to the overall cyber security strategy and helps to minimize operational risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4091641/recognizing-and-responding-to-cyber-threats-what-differentiates-ndr-edr-and-xdr.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End of the game for cybercrime infrastructure: 1025 servers taken down</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down</link>
      <description>Between 10 and 14 November 2025, the latest phase of Operation Endgame was coordinated from Europol’s headquarters in The Hague. The actions targeted one of the biggest infostealers (Rhadamanthys), the Remote Access Trojan VenomRAT, and the botnet Elysium, all of which played a key role in international cybercrime. Authorities took down these three large cybercrime enablers. The main suspect for VenomRAT was also arrested in Greece on 3 November 2025.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/end-of-game-for-cybercrime-infrastructure-1025-servers-taken-down</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware gangs seize a new hostage: your AWS S3 buckets</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094475/ransomware-gangs-find-a-new-hostage-your-aws-s3-buckets.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ransomware operators are shifting their focus from traditional on-premises targets to cloud storage services, especially S3 buckets used by Amazon Web Services (AWS), cybersecurity researchers have warned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A recent Trend Micro report outlined a new wave of attacks, where attackers integrate with cloud-native encryption and key management services rather than merely stealing or deleting data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Malicious activity targeting S3 buckets isn’t new, although the techniques continue to evolve as organizations harden their cloud environments,” said Crystal Morin, senior cybersecurity strategist at Sysdig. “As defenders adopt stronger perimeter protections, these attackers are starting to abuse built-in capabilities, such as encryption management and key rotation, to make data unrecoverable.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Trend Micro, attackers are probing a range of S3 setups, from buckets with AWS-managed KMS keys to customer-provided keys, imported key material, and even entirely external key stores.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-s3-is-the-new-ransomware-battleground"&gt;Why S3 is the new ransomware battleground&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On-premise ransomware traditionally involved dropping malware, encrypting desktops or servers, and threatening payment. But as organizations have migrated critical workloads and backups to cloud services, researchers noted, attackers are &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4033018/ransomware-goes-cloud-native-to-target-your-backup-infrastructure.html"&gt;following the data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Trend Micro report lists several prime cloud targets, including compute snapshots, static storage (S3) buckets, databases, containers/registries, and backup vaults. Among these, S3 is especially valuable because it often holds backups, logs, configuration data, and static assets–things an organization most wants back.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To succeed, attackers typically look for S3 buckets that have: versioning disabled ( so old versions can’t be restored), object-lock disabled ( so files can be overwritten or deleted), wide write permissions (via mis-configured IAM policies or leaked credentials), and hold high-value data (backup files, production config dumps).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Once inside, the attackers try to impose a “complete and irreversible lockout” of data, which may involve encryption objects with keys inaccessible to the victim, deleting backups, and scheduling key deletion so AWS and the customer can’t recover the data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This research is a systematic and theoretical threat modelling exercise on how an attacker might encrypt and ransom an AWS environment within an account boundary–something we’ve talked about over the last 10 years,” said Trey Ford, chief strategy and trust officer at Bugcrowd.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="weaponizing-cloud-encryption-and-key-management"&gt;Weaponizing cloud encryption and key management&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Trend Micro has &lt;a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/k/s3-ransomware.html" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;identified&lt;/a&gt; five S3 ransomware variants that increasingly exploit AWS’s built-in encryption paths. One abuses default AWS-managed KMS keys (SSE-KMS) by encrypting data with an attacker-created key and scheduling that key for deletion. Another uses customer-provided keys (SSE-C), where AWS has no copy, making recovery impossible. The third one exfiltrates S3 bucket data (with no versioning) and deletes the originals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The final two variants go deeper into key management infrastructure. One relies on imported key material (&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/how-to-byok-bring-your-own-key-to-aws-kms-for-less-than-15-00-a-year-using-aws-cloudhsm/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BYOK&lt;/a&gt;), letting attackers encrypt data and then destroy or expire the imported keys. The other abuses AWS’s External Key Store (XKS), where key operations happen outside AWS, which means that if attackers control the external key source, neither the customer nor AWS can restore access. Together, the techniques reveal that attackers are using AWS itself as the encryption mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I can’t recall having seen this done in the wild,” Ford added. “This specifically targets the use of external or customer-provided keys (SSE-C or XKS, respectively) to assert control over key management for the cryptography used in storage.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers urge customers to harden their &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3816939/abandoned-aws-s3-buckets-open-door-to-remote-code-execution-and-supply-chain-compromises.html"&gt;S3 environments&lt;/a&gt; by enforcing least privilege access, enabling protective controls like versioning and Object Lock, and closely regulating the use of customer-provided or external key sources that can undermine recovery. Isolating backups in separate accounts and continuously monitoring cloud audit logs for signs of suspicious key activity, mass encryption, or large-scale object deletions was also recommended.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“An ‘assume breach’ mindset is essential in the cloud: runtime environments should be immutable, identities must have tightly scoped permissions and short-lived credentials, networks need meaningful segmentation, and critical datasets must have backups,” Morin added. “Modern operations depend on complex supply chains, and a ransomware affecting a key partner can disrupt your business just as completely as a direct compromise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094475/ransomware-gangs-find-a-new-hostage-your-aws-s3-buckets.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help4U: A new digital platform to support young people facing online sexual abuse</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</link>
      <description>A new digital platform, Help4U, developed by Europol and CENTRIC, has been launched to support children and teenagers facing sexual abuse or online harm. Designed to be simple, private, and accessible, Help4U supports young people with finding trusted advice, understanding their rights, and connecting with people who can help. The platform offers clear, practical guidance for anyone under 18 who needs help, as well as information for parents, teachers, and professionals supporting them.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/help4u-new-digital-platform-to-support-young-people-facing-online-sexual-abuse</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 01:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OAuth token compromise hits Salesforce ecosystem again, Gainsight impacted</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094506/oauth-token-compromise-hits-salesforce-ecosystem-again-gainsight-impacted.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salesforce has disclosed yet another security incident involving unauthorized access to customer data through compromised third-party applications, this time implicating Gainsight-published apps connected to its platform through OAuth integrations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salesforce said it detected unusual activity involving Gainsight applications that integrate with its customer relationship management platform. “Upon detecting the activity, Salesforce revoked all active access and refresh tokens associated with Gainsight-published applications connected to Salesforce and temporarily removed those applications from the AppExchange while our investigation continues,” a Salesforce spokesperson told CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The company emphasized that the issue does not stem from its platform. “There is no indication that this issue resulted from any vulnerability in the Salesforce platform,” the spokesperson added. “The activity appears to be related to the app’s external connection to Salesforce.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="gainsight-engages-mandiant-for-forensic-investigation"&gt;Gainsight engages Mandiant for forensic investigation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gainsight confirmed the incident in &lt;a href="https://status.gainsight.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;status page updates&lt;/a&gt;, stating it has engaged Mandiant, a cybersecurity firm owned by Google Cloud, to assist in a comprehensive forensic investigation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Our current findings indicate that the activity under investigation originated from the applications’ external connection — not from any issue or vulnerability within the Salesforce platform,” the company said in a Thursday update.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The customer success software vendor acknowledged that access to Gainsight via Salesforce remains unavailable. As a precautionary measure, Gainsight also disclosed that its Zendesk connector access has been revoked, and its app has been temporarily pulled from the HubSpot Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="google-threat-intelligence-ties-attack-to-shinyhunters"&gt;Google threat intelligence ties attack to ShinyHunters&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The disclosure marks the latest chapter in an escalating pattern of attacks targeting OAuth tokens of trusted third-party SaaS integrations with Salesforce. According to Austin Larsen, principal threat analyst at Google Threat Intelligence Group, the campaign is tied to threat actors associated with ShinyHunters. This notorious extortion group has repeatedly targeted the Salesforce ecosystem over the recent months.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Our team at Google Threat Intelligence Group has observed threat actors, tied to ShinyHunters, compromising third-party OAuth tokens to potentially gain unauthorized access to Salesforce customer instances,” Larsen said in a &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/austinlarsen_we-are-monitoring-an-emerging-campaign-targeting-activity-7266130819987574784-9hKE" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt;. “Salesforce and Mandiant are actively notifying potentially affected organizations.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Larsen noted the incident mirrors the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4042191/shinyhunters-strike-again-workday-breach-tied-to-salesforce-targeted-social-engineering-wave.html"&gt;recent campaign targeting Salesloft Drift&lt;/a&gt;, where adversaries exploited OAuth tokens of legitimate SaaS integrations to bypass traditional security controls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to DataBreaches.net, ShinyHunters has &lt;a href="https://databreaches.net/2025/11/20/threat-actors-have-reportedly-launched-yet-another-campaign-involving-an-application-connected-to-salesforce/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; involvement in the Gainsight campaign and claims the combined Salesloft and Gainsight campaigns affected almost 1,000 organizations, with victims including Verizon, GitLab, F5, and SonicWall.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, neither Salesforce nor Gainsight attributed this incident to ShinyHunters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="august-breach-enabled-a-cascading-attack"&gt;August breach enabled a cascading attack&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The technical connection between the current incident and the August breach became clearer through analysis from Nudge Security, a SaaS security platform. According to &lt;a href="https://www.nudgesecurity.com/post/suspected-compromise-of-gainsight-connected-salesforce-instances-via-oauth-tokens" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nudge Security’s security alert&lt;/a&gt;, ShinyHunters obtained Gainsight OAuth tokens through secrets stolen from Salesloft/Drift support case data. Using those compromised tokens, the attackers allegedly issued refresh tokens for up to 285 Salesforce instances linked to Gainsight.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Salesloft Drift breach in August exposed approximately 760 companies to data theft, with attackers stealing OAuth tokens and using them to access Salesforce instances across hundreds of organizations. Victims included major enterprises such as Google, Cloudflare, Qantas, Cisco, and TransUnion. Gainsight itself was among the victims of that earlier campaign.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="supply-chain-risks-in-saas-integrations"&gt;Supply chain risks in SaaS integrations&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gainsight, a customer success platform widely deployed among enterprise Salesforce customers, provides tools that integrate directly with Salesforce to sync customer data and automate engagement workflows. These integrations typically require OAuth access to account information, contact records, opportunity data, and usage metrics for health scoring and retention analytics.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The incident underscores the growing risk posed by the supply chain of SaaS integrations, where a single compromised vendor can serve as a gateway into dozens of downstream environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For CISOs and security teams, Larsen emphasized the need for immediate action beyond just the Gainsight incident. “All organizations should view this as a signal to audit their SaaS environments,” he said, recommending that security teams regularly review all third-party applications connected to Salesforce instances, investigate and revoke tokens for unused or suspicious applications, and assume compromise if anomalous activity is detected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The attacks prove effective because OAuth tokens operate beneath traditional authentication layers, according to Sanchit Vir Gogia, chief analyst and CEO at Greyhound Research. “OAuth token compromise is one of the most dangerous attack vectors in the modern SaaS ecosystem because it abuses trust rather than breaking through defences,” Gogia said. “Once an attacker acquires a token, they gain the ability to impersonate a legitimate app or user at the API layer, where most enterprises have the least monitoring coverage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most OAuth tokens are long-lived, often without expiration, and carry broader permissions than administrators realize, Gogia noted. “Because these tokens function as infrastructure rather than monitored user accounts, compromises enable silent, high-value data exfiltration over extended periods. The attacks don’t behave like typical intrusions but rather operate with inherited legitimacy, making them particularly difficult to detect.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This incident follows a series of Salesforce-related security events throughout 2025, including an &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4063044/vulnerability-in-salesforce-ai-could-be-tricked-into-leaking-crm-data.html"&gt;AI agent vulnerability in September&lt;/a&gt; that could be exploited through prompt injection attacks, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4006341/salesforce-industry-cloud-riddled-with-configuration-risks.html"&gt;configuration risks discovered in Salesforce Industry Cloud&lt;/a&gt; that could expose encrypted customer information. In October, ShinyHunters &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4067846/extortion-gang-opens-data-leak-site-to-squeeze-victims-of-its-salesforce-attacks.html"&gt;launched a dedicated data leak site&lt;/a&gt; attempting to extort Salesforce and its customers with stolen data from earlier campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094506/oauth-token-compromise-hits-salesforce-ecosystem-again-gainsight-impacted.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.66</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to turn threat intel into real security wins</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4093927/how-to-turn-threat-intel-into-real-security-wins.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security leaders aren’t short of data, they’re short of decisions. Here’s how to turn threat feeds into an operating model that measurably reduces loss, accelerates response and earns board confidence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-problem-isnt-data-its-conversion"&gt;The problem isn’t data, it’s conversion&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern security operations centres ingest torrents of artefacts: Indicators of compromise, suspicious domains, sandbox reports, takedown notices and headlines about the latest campaign. Much of it is relevant in theory; too little of it turns into consistent action. Alert queues swell, analysts burn out and executives receive dashboards that never quite answer the only question that matters: What changed in our risk profile? The recent &lt;a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/2025-dbir-executive-summary.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2025 Verizon Data Breach Investigations Report&lt;/a&gt; analyzed &lt;strong&gt;22,052 incidents &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; 12,195 breaches&lt;/strong&gt;, noting &lt;strong&gt;third-party involvement doubled to 30%&lt;/strong&gt;, a stark reminder that decisions (not dashboards) move risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Operationalising CTI is the fix. Not “more feeds”, but a disciplined way to turn intelligence into repeatable decisions across detection engineering, incident response and investment governance. When done well, CTI becomes a business function, not a side project: a capability that helps you avoid loss, protect revenue and demonstrate resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-ciso-mandate-risk-efficiency-investment-response"&gt;The CISO mandate: Risk, efficiency, investment, response&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="reduce-operational-risk-and-financial-loss"&gt;Reduce operational risk and financial loss&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Intelligence-led detection and response aim to prevent or minimise data loss and business disruption. The downstream effects, smaller blast radii, fewer regulatory headaches and lower recovery bills, are what boards recognise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="maximise-staff-efficiency"&gt;Maximise staff efficiency&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Manual validation and correlation drive alert fatigue. Automating the plumbing, collection, normalization, enrichment and scoring frees analysts to do high-value work: scoping incidents, testing hypotheses and advising the business. The outcome is fewer swivel-chair tasks and more time on the activities that move risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="make-better-investment-calls"&gt;Make better investment calls&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Strategic intelligence clarifies which adversaries, techniques and sectors matter to you. That clarity shapes roadmaps and spend, uplifting the controls most likely to reduce your top loss scenarios. CTI becomes a lens for budget prioritization, not a cost centre.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="strengthen-incident-response"&gt;Strengthen incident response&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During an investigation, context is everything. CTI shortens decision time by linking artefacts to known tactics, techniques and procedures (TTPs) and likely objectives, informing containment and eradication with confidence. It also feeds the learning loop after an incident, improving detections and playbooks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-teams-drown-overload-chaos-and-waste"&gt;Why teams drown: Overload, chaos and waste&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="information-overload"&gt;Information overload&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Uncurated feeds generate volume, not value. Without scoring, de-duplication and relevance filtering, your SIEM and SOAR become conduits for noise. The result is longer queues and slower response, not better coverage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="unstructured-chaos"&gt;Unstructured chaos&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Intel arrives as PDFs, emails, blog posts and social snippets. Without a way to structure, categorise, search and correlate across sources and internal telemetry, analysis becomes ad hoc and outcomes vary by individual analyst.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="inefficient-resource-use"&gt;Inefficient resource use&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hours disappear into manual lookups and copy-paste tasks. That time is lost to threat hunting, detection tuning and rehearsing scenarios that reduce loss. The opportunity cost is real.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-feeds-to-decisions-an-operating-model-that-works"&gt;From feeds to decisions: An operating model that works&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-start-with-priority-intelligence-requirements-pirs"&gt;1) Start with priority intelligence requirements (PIRs)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Translate business risk into focused questions that guide everything else. Examples:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Which ransomware affiliates target our sector and identity stack?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“What initial access vectors are trending against our cloud collaboration tools?”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;“Which suppliers expose us to the most likely attack paths this quarter?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PIRs are the north star for collection, automation, reporting and stakeholder alignment. If a feed or task doesn’t serve a PIR, stop doing it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-engineer-the-plumbing-once-apply-it-everywhere"&gt;2) Engineer the plumbing once; apply it everywhere&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collection &amp;amp; normalization:&lt;/strong&gt; Ingest sources via APIs and standardise where practical (e.g., &lt;a href="https://www.oasis-open.org/2021/06/23/stix-v2-1-and-taxii-v2-1-oasis-standards-are-published/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;STIX/TAXII&lt;/a&gt;). Prioritise curated sources (sector ISACs/ISAOs, trusted vendors, national advisories) over sheer volume.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated enrichment:&lt;/strong&gt; WHOIS, passive DNS, malware family classification, internal sightings, asset context and exposure data.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scoring &amp;amp; prioritization:&lt;/strong&gt; Weight by PIR relevance, actor confidence, recency and internal visibility (e.g., “seen in our estate”).&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOAR orchestration:&lt;/strong&gt; Pre-approved playbooks push high-confidence items to blocklists, EDR, mail gateways and detection backlogs with sensible human checkpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The goal: Analysts spend their time on judgment and synthesis, not plumbing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-build-detections-around-behaviours-not-just-iocs"&gt;3) Build detections around behaviours, not just IOCs&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Indicators are perishable. Behaviours persist. Map adversary tradecraft to &lt;a href="https://attack.mitre.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK&lt;/a&gt; and write analytic stories that chain techniques (for example, phishing → token theft → conditional access bypass → exfiltration). Indicators support the story; they are not the story. This shift reduces alert noise and increases durability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-integrate-cti-with-ir-and-threat-hunting"&gt;4) Integrate CTI with IR and threat hunting&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before incidents:&lt;/strong&gt; Hunters use PIRs to form hypotheses; detection engineers validate coverage against priority techniques and known gaps.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During incidents:&lt;/strong&gt; The intel desk provides live context: likely objectives, lateral movement patterns, command-and-control families and exfil destinations.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After incidents:&lt;/strong&gt; Lessons learned feed back into PIRs, detection content and control tuning. Intelligence isn’t a weekly PDF; it’s woven into the incident timeline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-tie-it-to-familiar-frameworks-and-obligations"&gt;5) Tie it to familiar frameworks and obligations&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Use CTI to focus uplift efforts for recognized frameworks and controls (for example, aligning ATT&amp;amp;CK techniques to your control catalogue; steering patching towards actively exploited vulnerabilities; mapping improvements to &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/cyberframework" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NIST CSF 2.0&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.cyber.gov.au/business-government/asds-cyber-security-frameworks/essential-eight" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ACSC Essential Eight&lt;/a&gt;). CTI becomes evidence for audits, regulatory queries or board reviews and a rationale for retiring low-value tools.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-good-looks-like-signals-of-maturity"&gt;What ‘good’ looks like: Signals of maturity&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source rationalization:&lt;/strong&gt; Every source maps to at least one PIR; unused feeds are retired.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frictionless ingestion:&lt;/strong&gt; IOC intake is automatically enriched, scored and de-duplicated before any human sees it.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behaviour-first detections:&lt;/strong&gt; Coverage is ATT&amp;amp;CK-mapped, versioned and reviewed on a cadence with drift alarms for stale content.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embedded in IR:&lt;/strong&gt; Intel summaries appear in incident timelines and post-incident reports by default.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Executive clarity:&lt;/strong&gt; Reporting is one slide: decisions made, risk reduced, efficiency gained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These are practical markers a CISO can ask for and a SOC can deliver.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-questions-cti-must-answer"&gt;The questions CTI must answer&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who&lt;/strong&gt; is targeting us (actors, affiliates, ecosystems)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; methods are they using (TTPs, tooling, infrastructure)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where&lt;/strong&gt; are we exposed (control gaps, external attack surface, supplier risk)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When&lt;/strong&gt; is activity likely (campaign tempo, seasonal patterns, triggers)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt; are we attractive (industry, data, geo-political context, monetization path)?&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; do we prevent or disrupt this (detections, controls, playbooks, takedowns)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If your program can’t reliably answer these six, you have feeds, not intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pitfalls-to-avoid-and-how-to-sidestep-them"&gt;Pitfalls to avoid (and how to sidestep them)&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ioc-only-thinking"&gt;IOC-only thinking&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Problem:&lt;/em&gt; Chasing disposable indicators floods tooling and burns people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Prioritise behavior-based analytics; let indicators be supporting evidence fed by automated pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="feed-sprawl"&gt;Feed sprawl&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Problem:&lt;/em&gt; “Because we can” is not a strategy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Tie every source to a PIR and a decision path. If it doesn’t contribute, switch it off.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="manual-everything"&gt;Manual everything&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Problem:&lt;/em&gt; Copy-paste culture never scales.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; Automate collection, normalization, enrichment and scoring. Reserve human time for investigation and synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="reporting-that-doesnt-drive-a-decision"&gt;Reporting that doesn’t drive a decision&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Problem:&lt;/em&gt; Dashboards tell you the weather; executives need the forecast and the flight plan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fix:&lt;/strong&gt; End every intel output with a recommendation: block, monitor, hunt, tune, invest or rehearse and track whether the decision happened.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="metrics-that-matter-to-the-board"&gt;Metrics that matter to the board&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="risk-outcomes-loss-avoidance"&gt;Risk outcomes (loss avoidance)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tie CTI to reduced exposure in top scenarios (for example, ransomware or business email compromise). Show how intelligence prompted tangible changes, conditional access uplift, macro controls tightened, vulnerable components patched and estimate the reduction in probable loss. This is the CFO-friendly narrative.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="operational-efficiency-capacity-reclaimed"&gt;Operational efficiency (capacity reclaimed)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Measure what changed in the SOC when CTI engaged: percentage of alerts auto-enriched or auto-closed, mean time to detect/respond (MTTD/MTTR) deltas and analyst hours redirected from triage to hunting and engineering. Pair numbers with one concrete case study per quarter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="detection-efficacy-coverage-and-freshness"&gt;Detection efficacy (coverage and freshness)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Track the proportion of detections mapped to ATT&amp;amp;CK, coverage of priority techniques for your sector and drift alarms for stale content. Demonstrate that your detection catalog evolves with adversary behavior, not yesterday’s indicators.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="investment-quality-spend-that-follows-risk"&gt;Investment quality (spend that follows risk)&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Show budget alignment to PIRs, retirement of low-value tools or feeds and targeted control uplift tied to intelligence findings. This proves CTI informs governance, not just operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="high-impact-use-cases-you-can-start-now"&gt;High-impact use cases you can start now&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ransomware-affiliate-watchlist"&gt;Ransomware affiliate watchlist&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maintain current TTPs for affiliates most active in your sector. Convert them to block rules, analytic stories and tabletop scenarios. Pair with conditional access reviews and data exfiltration detections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="brand-and-executive-impersonation"&gt;Brand and executive impersonation&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Monitor look-alike domains, app store abuse and executive impersonation patterns. Automate takedown requests; feed patterns into mail and web gateways; brief the communications team.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="supplier-and-saas-exposure"&gt;Supplier and SaaS exposure&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Use CTI to score supplier risk, known compromises, actively exploited components, leaked credentials and exploit development appetite. Prioritize compensating controls and procurement clauses that demand transparency and response commitments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="phishing-to-ransomware-chain"&gt;Phishing-to-ransomware chain&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Correlate lure themes, payload families and command-and-control infrastructure. Pre-position email filters, endpoint detections and a targeted awareness burst that reflects current lures, then measure click-through and reporting behavior.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Each use case is deliberately narrow, measurable and PIR-aligned, the opposite of “boil the ocean.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-bottom-line"&gt;The bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CTI delivers value only when it changes what you detect, how you respond, what you buy and what you rehearse. The shift from raw feeds to an operational capability isn’t about tools or volume; it’s about disciplined focus (PIRs), behavior-first detections, automation that removes toil and reporting that triggers decisions. Get those right and you move from chasing yesterday’s indicators to interrupting tomorrow’s attacks, while giving executives the one thing they want most: proof that resilience is improving.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4093927/how-to-turn-threat-intel-into-real-security-wins.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From code to boardroom: A GenAI GRC approach to supply chain risk</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094519/from-code-to-boardroom-a-genai-grc-approach-to-supply-chain-risk.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I know the pressure chief information security officers face right now. We spent years hardening our own perimeter, then a few more managing the third-party vendor risk. Now, we are facing an existential threat from the fourth, fifth and nth parties in a supply chain that’s quietly, enthusiastically adopting generative AI (GenAI).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We treat supply chain GRC as a paperwork exercise: a cycle of quarterly questionnaires and compliance reports. But here is the critical truth: Traditional GRC is failing against GenAI-driven supply chain complexity. Our current tools only tell us what was true yesterday. The speed of GenAI implementation and the insidious new risks it creates, from training data poisoning to shadow AI adoption, mean that by the time a CISO reads a compliance report, the systemic failure is already in motion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the knowledge gap I want to fill. It is time we stop managing code risk with checklists and start managing strategic resilience with intelligence. My central thesis is clear: The integration of GenAI into GRC (GenAI GRC) is not about automating form-filling; it is the only viable path to move supply chain risk from a tactical technical problem (code) into a continuously monitored, strategic imperative presented to the boardroom. We need an active defense powered by the very technology that generates the threat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-unseen-attack-vector-model-drift-and-shadow-ai"&gt;The unseen attack vector: Model drift and shadow AI&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new, most critical threats in our extended supply chain are now entirely digital and almost invisible to traditional controls. I am not talking about a simple phishing attack or an unpatched server. I am talking about risks embedded in the very fabric of our vendor’s operations through GenAI adoption.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First, consider shadow AI. Your key software vendor is using a public LLM to rapidly generate new code for your core product. They didn’t tell you because it sped up their delivery timeline. But now, that model’s proprietary training data, potentially scraped from compromised sources, is woven into your production environment. If a third-party developer incorporates noncompliant code from an LLM, your enterprise is immediately exposed to intellectual property, licensing and security risks — risks that current due diligence contracts simply can’t catch (see the discussion on AI-generated liabilities in the &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/396933448_AI_in_Personalized_Financial_Advisory_Services_Robo-Advisors_and_Ethical_Considerations"&gt;Journal of AI Risk&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second, we must recognize model drift. A vendor’s core business logic, like fraud detection or optimization, might rely on a deployed AI model. Over time, that model can drift in its behavior due to subtle changes in its operating environment or data flow, potentially exposing confidential data or introducing biases that violate new regulatory requirements. This is a subtle systemic risk that an annual audit cannot flag. CISOs need to understand that the supply chain risk surface is now fluid, defined by the behavior of external algorithms, not just external firewalls.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-genai-grc-mandate-from-reporting-to-prediction"&gt;The GenAI GRC mandate: From reporting to prediction&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To counter a threat that moves at the speed of computation, our GRC must also become generative and predictive. The GenAI GRC mandate is to shift the focus from documenting compliance to predicting systemic failure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Current GRC methods are designed for documentation. They verify that a policy exists. GenAI GRC is designed for intelligence. It verifies that a policy is effective and anticipates when it will fail. I see this happening in three critical ways:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-contextual-intelligence"&gt;1. Contextual intelligence&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We must use large language models (LLMs) to ingest diverse, unstructured data: supplier incident reports, geopolitical news feeds, dark web chatter, financial health indicators and code repository activity. An LLM can then contextualize these disparate signals faster than any human team, identifying emerging risk correlations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, the LLM might flag that a key semiconductor supplier facing sudden financial stress and seeing a high volume of unreviewed open-source code commits presents a high, immediate risk a signal that would be missed if analyzed in isolation, &lt;a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/quantumblack/our-insights/the-state-of-ai"&gt;see McKinsey’s analysis on AI for risk management.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-continuous-monitoring"&gt;2. Continuous monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We must implement a digital trust ledger. This isn’t a blockchain ledger, but a conceptual system where GenAI continuously scores and quantifies the trust quotient of every major vendor. This quotient, expressed as a dynamic risk metric, is calculated by automatically comparing vendor-provided documents against real-world external signals. If a vendor claims minimal technical debt, but the GenAI engine ingests a spike in their public-facing bug reports, the trust quotient dips, triggering an immediate, targeted audit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-regulatory-synthesis"&gt;3. Regulatory synthesis&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;New, complex regulations like the EU’s Digital Operational Resilience Act (DORA) and the AI Act demand a level of synthesized compliance that manual teams can’t maintain. I use GenAI to cross-reference our supply chain dependencies against these global regulatory shifts instantly, identifying and prioritizing where a vendor’s failure means immediate, enterprise-level noncompliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="translating-code-risk-into-boardroom-resilience"&gt;Translating code risk into boardroom resilience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The biggest failure in modern GRC is communication. We take technical vulnerabilities and present them as technical problems. The board doesn’t care about the number of unpatched servers; they care about impact, velocity and shareholder value. My role and yours is to translate technical risk into strategic resilience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;When presenting GenAI GRC initiatives, I advise CISOs to stop talking about cost and start framing the spend as strategic capital allocation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of reporting: “We have 50 high-priority supply chain vulnerabilities,” I suggest you report on the risk velocity metric (RVM): “Our GenAI GRC framework indicates that the probability of a catastrophic supply chain interruption (costing $$X) has been reduced by 18% over the last quarter, moving this risk below the board’s acceptable threshold.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The digital trust ledger provides these quantifiers. It allows you to shift the discussion from an operational cost center to a strategic resilience engine that protects market cap. I believe this strategic framing is what secures budget and earns a true seat at the C-suite table. It allows the CISO to move from being an emergency responder to a business growth enabler (a concept well-supported by &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/gartner-s-top-strategic-predictions-for-2024-and-beyond"&gt;Gartner’s latest CISO guidance&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-time-for-systemic-change-is-now"&gt;The time for systemic change is now&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am not suggesting we dismantle our current GRC programs, but that we immediately overlay them with a GenAI-powered strategic layer. Waiting for a perfect solution is equivalent to accepting defeat. The supply chain has already been digitized and the risk has already been injected into your core systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Your call to action is simple and immediate: Pilot the digital trust ledger concept now. Start small by using GenAI to monitor the difference between vendor self-attestations and their public digital footprint. Identify the four or five critical vendors whose failure would halt your business entirely. Make them your pilot project.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The supply chain is a web of dependencies woven from code, data and human judgment. If we do not leverage generative intelligence to navigate this complexity, we are passively waiting for the next systemic failure. I urge you to lead this change and ensure your resilience strategy reflects the pace of the modern threat landscape &lt;a href="https://natlawreview.com/article/examining-cybersecurity-critical-infrastructure-regulations-us-and-eu#:~:text=Securing%20critical%20infrastructure%20is%20not,already%20be%20subject%20to%20abroad."&gt;explore regulatory changes related to critical infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; for context. Transform GRC from a compliance burden into a predictive safeguard, moving your strategic defense from the code to the boardroom today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;Want to join?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="_msocom_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094519/from-code-to-boardroom-a-genai-grc-approach-to-supply-chain-risk.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.77</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV25-760)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av25-760</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV25-761)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av25-761</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV25-762)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av25-762</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.99</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV25-763)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av25-763</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.00</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV25–764)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av25-764</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FCC reversal removes federal cyber safeguards targeting telecom weaknesses post-Salt Typhoon attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094745/fcc-reversal-removes-federal-cyber-safeguards-targeting-telecom-weaknesses-post-salt-typhoon-attacks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The US federal government is rolling back mandates intended to protect critical infrastructure following the widespread &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4048548/chinese-hacking-group-salt-typhoon-expansion-prompts-multinational-advisory.html" target="_blank"&gt;Salt Typhoon&lt;/a&gt; attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Federal Communication Commission (FCC) has &lt;a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-415455A1.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;reversed&lt;/a&gt; a January 2025 Declaratory Ruling requiring US telecom providers to adopt and certify stricter cybersecurity measures. The ruling took effect under the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA), which requires telecom providers and manufacturers to design their services and equipment in a way that allows for surveillance when legally requested by law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the reversal has been slammed by the FCC’s own commissioner, and security experts are looking askance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is the cyber equivalent of hanging a ‘come kick me’ sign on critical infrastructure and national cyber security,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbshipley/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;David Shipley&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Beauceron Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="fcc-declaratory-ruling-unlawful-and-ineffective"&gt;FCC: Declaratory Ruling ‘unlawful and ineffective’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4047953/salt-typhoon-apt-techniques-revealed-in-new-report.html" target="_blank"&gt;Salt Typhoon attacks&lt;/a&gt;, disclosed in October 2024, have impacted some of the largest US communication companies, and countless others, with hackers accessing core systems used by the US government and potentially intercepting highly-sensitive information related to high-ranking officials.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3805081/us-hits-back-against-chinas-salt-typhoon-group.html"&gt;January &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3805081/us-hits-back-against-chinas-salt-typhoon-group.html" target="_blank"&gt;Declaratory Ruling&lt;/a&gt; established legal obligations for telecom carriers to secure their networks against “unlawful access and interception,” underscoring that they are responsible for not only their equipment, but how they manage their networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The decision included a &lt;a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-408015A1.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Notice of Proposed Rulemaking&lt;/a&gt; (NPRM) requiring telecom companies to create, update, and implement cybersecurity risk management plans, and certify them annually.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, this week the FCC claimed that the Declaratory Ruling “misconstrued” CALEA, calling it “flawed,” and “unlawful and ineffective.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the agency, their action follows “months-long engagement with communications service providers” in which they have demonstrated a “strengthened cybersecurity posture” following Salt Typhoon.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These providers have agreed to undertake “extensive, urgent, and coordinated efforts” to protect their networks against cyberattacks, mitigate operational risks, protect consumers, and preserve national security interests, according to the FCC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Commission added that it has taken “a series of actions” to harden communication networks and improve security. This includes establishing a &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/fcc-council-national-security" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Council on National Security&lt;/a&gt; that engages with security partners, and adopting targeted rules for critical infrastructure that don’t impose “inflexible and ambiguous requirements,” such as a mandate that submarine cable licenses only be granted after risk management plans are in place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Further, the FCC has banned “bad labs,” equipment-testing companies owned or controlled by foreign adversaries (notably China), from its equipment authorization program to ensure “no such entities are subject to untrustworthy actors that pose a risk to national security.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="salt-typhoon-still-reverberating"&gt;Salt Typhoon still reverberating&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salt Typhoon impacted major carriers including AT&amp;amp;T, Charter Communications, Consolidated Communications, Lumen Technologies, T-Mobile, Verizon, and Windstream. But law enforcement and intelligence agencies caution that its impact is far more widespread, exposing at least 200 US organizations, plus entities in 80 other countries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to federal investigations, the attack allowed the Chinese government to record phone calls, geolocate millions of individuals, and target specific individuals including the US president and vice president. The group initially exploited the routers of telecom providers, using the devices and trusted connections to move into other networks and, among other actions, access information on wiretap systems used by federal law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salt Typhoon is “one of the worst cyberattacks in history,” &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2025/11/cantwell-slams-efforts-by-brendan-carr-s-fcc-to-roll-back-network-protection-rules-put-in-place-after-salt-typhoon-hacks" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said US Senator Maria Cantwell&lt;/a&gt;, ranking member of the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation, who strongly opposed the ruling’s reversal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;FCC &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/about/leadership/anna-gomez" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Commissioner Anna M. Gomez&lt;/a&gt;, the only FCC member who voted against the decision, &lt;a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-415409A1.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;noted that the move&lt;/a&gt; “will leave Americans less protected than they were the day the Salt Typhoon breach was discovered.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="reversal-leaves-the-country-less-secure"&gt;Reversal ‘leaves the country less secure’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The January Declaratory Ruling was the “only concrete federal regulatory action” taken in response to the Salt Typhoon attack, she noted. The attempt by the Chinese-backed group will not be the last, she emphasized; in fact, without stronger security controls, it will also “not be the last successful one.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The FCC leaves the country less secure at the very moment when these threats are increasing,” said Gomez.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Senator Cantwell pointed out that the reversal has come after “heavy lobbying” to reverse it from the very telecom providers targeted by Salt Typhoon. She had previously demanded that CEOs at Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T document how they were remediating exploits that “deeply penetrated their networks,” but they have failed to provide this information.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I am concerned that [the FCC] move to drop cybersecurity requirements on carriers is part of a pattern of weakness on national security issues,” Cantwell argued.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beauceron’s Shipley was less measured in his criticism of the reversal. He called it “shockingly incompetent,” particularly in light of how much damage Chinese nation state hackers have done in the telecommunication sector over the past two years. Hopefully, Congress will step in, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, he said, “I would struggle to find a dumber idea than rolling back the cyber security standards for telecommunications providers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4094745/fcc-reversal-removes-federal-cyber-safeguards-targeting-telecom-weaknesses-post-salt-typhoon-attacks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.02</comments>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV25-765)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av25-765</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.04</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel security advisory (AV25-767)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/zyxel-security-advisory-av25-767</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.29</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-768)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-768</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.37</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV25-769)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av25-769</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.38</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Root causes of security breaches remain elusive — jeopardizing resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4093403/root-causes-of-security-breaches-remain-elusive-jeopardizing-resilience.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Post-incident analysis remains a critical concern at most security organizations today. According to Foundry’s Security Priorities study, 57% of security leaders report their organization struggled to find the root cause of security incidents experienced in the past year, leaving them at heightened risk of getting breached again.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Security experts tell CSO the finding underscores that the immediate pressure to firefight often leaves post-incident learning under-resourced. Organizations need to treat &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4009438/how-to-conduct-an-effective-post-incident-review.html"&gt;incident response&lt;/a&gt; as a continuous learning cycle, not a one-time clean-up exercise if they are to reduce the likelihood of repeat breaches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many organizations are stuck in a reactive cycle, focusing solely on containing the immediate breach, which comes at the expense of a crucial forensic investigation, leaving the ‘patient door’ wide open for the next attacker to walk right back in,” &lt;a href="https://www.huntress.com/authors/dray-agha"&gt;Dray Agha&lt;/a&gt;, senior manager of security operations at managed security response firm Huntress, tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Without a thorough postmortem to pinpoint the root cause, companies are essentially defending themselves blindfolded, destined to repeat the same mistakes,” Agha says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="resilience-through-root-cause-analysis"&gt;Resilience through root cause analysis&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other experts agree that too many enterprises treat incident response as an operational exercise rather than an analytical one. As a result, containment and recovery actions might be well-rehearsed while deeper forensic investigation and post-incident learning lag.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Without a disciplined approach to evidence preservation and &lt;a href="https://www.cio.com/article/350219/what-is-root-cause-analysis-a-proactive-approach-to-change-management.html"&gt;root cause analysis&lt;/a&gt;, valuable insights are lost,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomas-moore-724212/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Tom Moore&lt;/a&gt;, director of digital forensics and incident response at managed security services vendor BlueVoyant. “Robust incident response isn’t just about getting systems back online — it’s about using lessons learned to inform detection, prevention, and risk mitigation strategies.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Moore adds: “That continuous feedback loop ultimately drives long-term resilience and is particularly valuable when the cyber threat landscape is evolving and adapting so quickly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mariehargraves/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Marie Hargraves&lt;/a&gt;, principal crisis management consultant at cloud security vendor Semperis, agrees that “most organizations focus on fighting fires instead of learning from the flames.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every crisis has three phases: detection, response (the acute phase), and review.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s the third phase, the post-crisis review, where resilience is built,” Hargraves says. “Organizations that capture real-time data, analyze it rigorously, and act on lessons identified recover faster and emerge stronger.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Incident response isn’t just about surviving; it’s about adapting and building resilience,” Hargraves adds.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tracing-an-attack-path"&gt;Tracing an attack path&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Preparation is key, so businesses need to have dedicated tools and skills for digital forensics in place before an incident occurs through technologies such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/524286/what-is-siem-security-information-and-event-management-explained.html"&gt;security incident and event management (SIEM)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/566677/12-top-siem-tools-rated-and-compared.html"&gt;SIEM devices&lt;/a&gt; are important because, for example, many gateway and VPN devices have a local storage that overwrites itself within hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If a cybercriminal breaks in through the VPN and dwells for a day or so before they pivot to business-critical servers, then the VPN telemetry has evaporated into the abyss,” Huntress’ Agha explains. “The centralization and retention of VPN logs, like through a SIEM, allows for reactive detections but also stores valuable data and allows for root cause analysis to figure out how the initial breach [occurred].”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Statistics from Huntress show that near 70% of sophisticated cybercriminals break in through the VPN. “Where SIEM has been enabled, we are able to catch them much earlier in their attack path, but also deploy retrospective analysis to identify the exact root cause that led to the breach,” Agha says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Various services such as &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/573533/top-12-managed-detection-and-response-solutions.html"&gt;managed detection and response (MDR)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/574295/11-top-xdr-tools-and-how-to-evaluate-them.html"&gt;extended detection and response (XDR)&lt;/a&gt; can also include forensic capturing software — technology that enables providers to work hand in hand with forensic cyber investigators to identify the source of the breach and work to remediate it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Without tools such as this, trying to work back retrospectively to identify the ‘how’ becomes increasingly difficult,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rob-derbyshire-48291b25/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Rob Derbyshire&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at cybersecurity firm Securus Communication. “There are companies that offer incident response services when breaches occur, but the key to sorting it quickly, and preventing it from happening again, is ensuring you already have the tooling and processes to make any response significantly slicker.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eclecticiq.com/eclecticiq-intelligence-research-team-arda-b%C3%BCy%C3%BCkkaya"&gt;Arda Büyükkaya&lt;/a&gt;, senior cyber threat intelligence analyst at EclecticIQ, points out that without thorough root-cause analysis the “actual cause of the attack remains unknown and potentially still active.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Best practices should include digital forensics expertise, root cause analysis processes, and threat intelligence integration to connect incidents to broader attacker tactics and campaigns,” Büyükkaya advises. “This approach allows organizations to build resilience from every incident.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="robust-planning"&gt;Robust planning&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;An incident response team, typically led by the CISO, should be designated to take charge during an incident. The plan should also specify roles and responsibilities for each stakeholder, from IT staff to legal advisors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Experts quizzed by CSO say an incident response playbook boils down to a few key steps:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparation:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain a tested incident response plan, clear roles, and escalation paths.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detection and analysis:&lt;/strong&gt; Centralize monitoring, leverage threat intelligence, and ensure forensic capability.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Containment and recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; Act fast but preserve evidence; validate systems before restoration.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postmortem:&lt;/strong&gt; Conduct structured reviews, document findings, and feed them into security architecture and training.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Improvement:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrate threat modeling, automate containment, and invest in skills development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many organizations opt to use established frameworks and ISO standards as templates for their incident response plans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These frameworks offer a structured approach, providing sections and subsections that cover all essential areas, from governance to technical responses,” says &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-ford-a4026421/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Richard Ford&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at Integrity360. “By using a recognized framework, you not only ensure completeness but also facilitate easier communication with external parties who may be familiar with the framework.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-organizational-resilience"&gt;Building organizational resilience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Effective incident response should be geared toward building a structured, repeatable, and intelligence-driven process that strengthens resilience over time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Incident response plans should be regularly tested, refined, and updated — for example, through simulations or &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570871/tabletop-exercises-explained-definition-examples-and-objectives.html"&gt;tabletop exercises&lt;/a&gt; — as part of a wider business continuity and organizational resilience strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bharat-mistry-952414/?originalSubdomain=uk"&gt;Bharat Mistry&lt;/a&gt;, field CTO at cybersecurity vendor Trend Micro, says many organizations suffer from a maturity gap in their incident response — which should extend beyond simply containment and recovery to encompass forensic analysis and postmortems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When organizations bypass root cause analysis, they are only treating symptoms,” Mistry warns. “This challenge stems from a combination of issues: fragmented visibility due to siloed tools that prevent accurate attack reconstruction, a skills gap that leaves teams short on forensics and threat hunting expertise, and process weaknesses where postmortems are often informal or simply skipped.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="breaking-the-cycle-of-breach-patch-repeat"&gt;Breaking the cycle of ‘breach, patch, repeat’&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In many cases, evidence is inadvertently destroyed, such as when servers are wiped, logs are lost, and forensic trails disappear, because the emphasis is on restoring operations quickly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is compounded by pressure from the business, time constraints, as well as limited resources, which push teams to move on to the next urgent task rather than learning from the incident,” Mistry adds. “As a result, retrospective scans, root cause analysis, and updates to procedures are frequently skipped.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The initial attack vector and lateral movement often remain unknown, leaving vulnerabilities unaddressed and creating a cycle of “breach, patch, repeat.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“To break this cycle, organizations must embed forensic readiness into their response strategy: preserve evidence, conduct structured postmortems, and ensure lessons learned are fed back into security architecture and training,” Mistry concludes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4093403/root-causes-of-security-breaches-remain-elusive-jeopardizing-resilience.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian security advisory (AV25-770)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/atlassian-security-advisory-av25-770</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.68</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV25-771)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av25-771</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.71</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SolarWinds security advisory (AV25-772)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/solarwinds-security-advisory-av25-772</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-773)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-773</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV25-766) - Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av25-766</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall security advisory (AV25-774)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sonicwall-security-advisory-av25-774</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.10</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV25-775)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av25-775</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.15</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV25-776)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av25-776</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.72</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-777)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-777</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grafana security advisory (AV25-778)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/grafana-security-advisory-av25-778</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle security advisory – October 2025 quarterly rollup (AV25-688) – Update 2</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/oracle-security-advisory-october-2025-quarterly-rollup-av25-688</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Dark Reading Virtual Event] Cybersecurity Outlook 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/dark-reading-virtual-event-cybersecurity-outlook-2026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/dark-reading-virtual-event-cybersecurity-outlook-2026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 56.40</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
