<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Security + Policy + Governance News Aggregator</title>
    <link>https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml</link>
    <description>Curated Security, Cybersecurity Policy, and Governance news from trusted international sources</description>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/unChained-int/rss-feed-generator/releases/latest/download/cached_feed.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Python Security Feed Aggregator</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:52:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Europol-supported operation takes down key figures of ‘Balkan Cartel’ in Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</link>
      <description>The coordinated operation targeted several High Value Targets (HVTs) residing in Germany, who are believed to be key figures within the Balkan Cartel. The investigation revealed that this criminal cell was responsible for multi-tonne cocaine shipments originating from Colombia and utilising various methods to smuggle drugs into Europe. The network also engaged in money laundering through companies and real estate...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/europol-supported-operation-takes-down-key-figures-of-balkan-cartel-in-germany</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 arrests in Spain during action against the ‘Black Axe’ criminal organisation</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</link>
      <description>The criminal network is known for its involvement in a wide range of criminal activities, including cyber-enabled fraud, drug trafficking, human trafficking and prostitution, kidnapping, armed robbery and fraudulent spiritual practices. The group's annual criminal proceeds are estimated to be in the billions of euros, generated through many small-scale operations that collectively have a significant impact.Arrests and further investigationsA total...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/34-arrests-in-spain-during-action-against-black-axe-criminal-organisation</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Most Wanted website revamped with new fugitives added</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</link>
      <description>A key recent addition to the website is the new email alerts feature, allowing users to sign up for notifications whenever new fugitives are added. This feature ensures the public stays informed on the latest updates and can act quickly if they recognise any of the individuals featured, providing critical information that could lead to arrests.The update also sees 18...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/eu-most-wanted-website-revamped-new-fugitives-added</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-002)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-002</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-002</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub security advisory (AV26-003)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-003</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/github-security-advisory-av26-003</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.55</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>n8n security advisory (AV26-004)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-004</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/n8n-security-advisory-av26-004</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-005)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-005</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/android-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-005</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualcomm security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-006)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/qualcomm-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-006</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung mobile security advisory (AV26-007)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/samsung-mobile-security-advisory-av26-007</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veeam security advisory (AV26-008)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/veeam-security-advisory-av26-008</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.58</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement challenges major cocaine supply chains into Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</link>
      <description>Law enforcement authorities across Europe and South America continue to put sustained pressure on the criminal networks responsible for moving cocaine into Europe. Three recent actions coordinated by Europol, one targeting a Dutch-led network embedded in Colombian supply chains, another dismantling a Brazilian maritime trafficking operation and a third disrupting a Greek at-sea transfer criminal operation, highlight the ongoing efforts to disrupt the routes and structures used by organised crime.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-challenges-major-cocaine-supply-chains-europe</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity risk will accelerate this year, fueled in part by AI, says World Economic Forum</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116270/cybersecurity-risk-will-accelerate-this-year-fueled-in-part-by-ai-says-world-economic-forum.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity risk will accelerate this year, fueled by advances in AI, deepening geopolitical fragmentation and the complexity of supply chains, the World Economic Forum (WEF) says in its annual Global Cybersecurity Outlook.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The way to combat it, however, isn’t new, the report adds. “Ultimately, strengthening collective cyber resilience has become both an economic and a societal imperative. Cybersecurity is a frontier where collaboration remains not only possible, but powerful — a reminder that, even amid fragmentation, economic strain and uncertainty, collective action can drive progress for all.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The coming year will test not only global technological preparedness but also the capacity to align policy, ethics, and collaboration in defending an increasingly digital world, the report says.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://reports.weforum.org/docs/WEF_Global_Cybersecurity_Outlook_2026.pdf" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Issued Monday&lt;/a&gt;, the 64 page report is based partly on answers to 19 questions from a survey last fall responded to by 804 C-suite executives, academics, civil society and public-sector cybersecurity leaders in 92 countries. That included 316 CISOs. Additional material was gathered from workshops, including a session with 21 executives from the forum’s Centre for Cybersecurity’s CISO community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the fifth annual cybersecurity report from the WEF. Last year’s edition found that a series of compounding factors — geopolitical tension, intricate supply chains, regulatory proliferation and rapid technological adoption — were creating an era of escalating complexity and unpredictability, and this year’s continues the theme.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the latest report’s main findings:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI is anticipated to be the most significant driver of change in cybersecurity in 2026, according to 94% of survey respondents;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;87% of respondents said AI-related vulnerabilities had increased in the past year. Other cyber risks that had increased were (in order) cyber-enabled fraud and phishing, supply chain disruption, and exploitation of software vulnerabilities;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;confidence in national cyber preparedness continues to erode, with 31% of survey respondents reporting low confidence in their nation’s ability to respond to major cyber incidents, up from 26% last year. Confidence levels vary greatly across regions, with 84% of respondents from the Middle East and North Africa being confident in their country’s ability to protect critical infrastructure, and only 38% of North American respondents confident their countries were prepared;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;asked to rate their own organization’s cyber resilience, 23% of representatives from public sector and international organizations thought their readiness was insufficient. By contrast, only 11% of private sector respondents thought negatively about their firms;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;91% of organizations with more than 100,000 employees have changed their cybersecurity strategies due to geopolitical volatility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, CEOs and CISOs weren’t always on the same page when it came to rating cyber risks for their organizations. In the 2025 survey, most CEOs said ransomware, cyber-enabled fraud and phishing, and supply chain disruption were their biggest cyber concerns. This year, cyber-enabled fraud and phishing shifted to number one, followed by AI vulnerabilities and exploitation of software vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, while most CISOs also said ransomware was their top concern in the 2025 survey, they reversed the CEO’s order to list supply chain disruption second, then cyber-enabled fraud and phishing. And in the latest survey, ransomware and supply chain disruption were still the top two, but the third worry is now exploitation of software vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This suggests that CEOs tend to be more concerned about the broader business impacts of frauds, the report says, while for CISOs, the concern over ransomware reflects the significant operational disruption a successful ransomware attack can inflict on the availability of critical information technology (IT) and operational technology (OT) systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4110699/8-things-cisos-cant-afford-to-get-wrong-in-2026.html" target="_blank"&gt;Related content: 8 things CISOs can’t afford to get wrong in 2026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The WEF report focuses on AI because leaders believe it will be the most significant driver of change in cybersecurity this year. The widespread integration of AI systems adds an expanded attack surface that creates novel vulnerabilities that traditional security controls were not designed to address, the report says. In addition, threat actors are leveraging AI to enhance the scale, speed, sophistication, and precision of their attacks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, defenders can also use AI, to strengthen their cyber capabilities. But, the report stresses, “AI’s benefits are contingent on disciplined execution. Poorly implemented solutions can introduce new risks — misconfiguration, biased decision‑making, over‑reliance on automation, and susceptibility to adversarial manipulation — unless organizations embed robust guardrails, security‑by‑design practices and continuous monitoring.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The implication is clear,” says the report. “AI can improve cybersecurity, but only when deployed within sound governance frameworks that keep human judgement at the center. At the same time, too many controls can create friction, so it is essential to strike a careful balance.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One sign this may already be happening: 64% of respondents said their organization has a process in place for assessing the security of AI tools before deploying them, up from 37% in the previous survey in the fall of 2024.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The survey data shows 77% of respondents said their organizations have adopted AI for cybersecurity, primarily to enhance phishing detection (52%), intrusion and anomaly response (46%), and user behavior analytics (40%).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But when asked about the practical challenges of adopting AI for cybersecurity, respondents listed insufficient knowledge and/or skills (54%), the need for human oversight (41%), and uncertainty about risk (39%) as the main hurdles. These findings indicate that trust is still a barrier to widespread AI adoption, the report concludes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As organizations navigate the integration of AI into their security operations, the balance between automation and human judgement becomes increasingly critical,” says the report. “While AI excels at automating repetitive, high-volume tasks, its current limitations in contextual judgement and strategic decision making remain clear. Over-reliance on ungoverned automation risks creating blind spots that adversaries may exploit.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4045782/cybercrime-beyond-economics.html" target="_blank"&gt;Related content: Cybercrime is moving beyond financial gains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While AI continues to dominate the cybersecurity landscape, several other technologies and threat vectors are quietly gaining traction in the background and are expected to affect cybersecurity by 2030, says the report.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These include autonomous systems and robotics, quantum technologies, digital currencies, space technologies and undersea cables, and natural disasters and climate change. By the end of the decade, autonomous systems will be a near-term factor, from AI assisting in analysis to its directing of physical actions in factories, logistics, healthcare and public spaces. This evolution could create a new cyber‑physical risk profile, where machine‑executed decisions can alter safety and service quality within seconds, compressing detection and response windows.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By 2030, quantum technology will have evolved from a theoretical disruptor into a selective but material threat to cryptography, the report predicts. State-level or well-resourced actors may be capable of quantum-accelerated attacks on high-value targets, even as full-scale code breaking remains rare. At the same time, defenders will harness quantum-enhanced analytics and sensing for anomaly detection, creating a dynamic attacker-defender race.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the report concludes, building a secure digital future requires more than technical solutions. “It calls for decisive leadership, shared accountability, and a commitment to lifting the collective baseline — ensuring that resilience is accessible to all, not just the most well-resourced. As the boundaries between digital and physical worlds continue to blur, the organizations that thrive will be those that recognize cyber resilience as a shared, strategic responsibility — one that underpins trust, enables innovation and safeguards the interconnected foundations of global society.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116270/cybersecurity-risk-will-accelerate-this-year-fueled-in-part-by-ai-says-world-economic-forum.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.64</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV25-844) – Update 1</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av25-844</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.70</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitLab security advisory (AV26-009)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/gitlab-security-advisory-av26-009</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.73</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenable security advisory (AV26-010)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/tenable-security-advisory-av26-010</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.74</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] ABB security advisory (AV26-011)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-abb-security-advisory-av26-011</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trend Micro security advisory (AV26-012)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/trend-micro-security-advisory-av26-012</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security-KPIs und -KRIs: So messen Sie Cybersicherheit</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495619/security-kpis-und-kris-so-messen-sie-cybersicherheit.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage"&gt;&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cybersicherheit zu messen, ist kein Kinderspiel." src="https://images.computerwoche.de/bdb/3357513/1200x.jpg" title="Cybersicherheit zu messen, ist kein Kinderspiel." width="1200" /&gt;&lt;figcaption class="wp-element-caption"&gt;&lt;p class="foundryImageCaption"&gt;Cybersicherheit zu messen, ist kein Kinderspiel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="imageCredit"&gt; Foto: Ultraskrip – shutterstock.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eine wichtige Säule jedes ausgereiften Cyberrisk-Programms ist die Fähigkeit, die Performance der IT-Security und registrierte Bedrohungen zu messen, zu analysieren und zu melden. Die Cybersecurity zu messen, ist allerdings kein leichtes Unterfangen: Einerseits, weil sich viele Führungskräfte ohne entsprechenden Background schwer tun, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3498091/verantwortung-ubernehmen-so-werden-chefs-zu-security-vorbildern.html" target="_blank" title="IT-Risiken zu verstehen"&gt;IT-Risiken zu verstehen&lt;/a&gt;. Andererseits verstricken sich Sicherheitsprofis auch zu oft in technische Details, die die Stakeholder verwirren und auf den falschen Weg führen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Das ideale Szenario: Security-Experten messen und reporten die Cybersicherheit auf eine Art und Weise, die für Führungskräfte leicht verständlich und nützlich ist – was zu umsetzbaren Ergebnissen führt. Klingt gut? Dieser Artikel vermittelt Ihnen, wie Sie das anstellen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="messkategorien-der-it-sicherheit"&gt;Messkategorien der IT-Sicherheit&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Die meisten &lt;a href="https://www.cio.de/a/so-identifizieren-sie-projektbeteiligte,3644693" target="_blank" title="Stakeholder"&gt;Stakeholder&lt;/a&gt; beschäftigen Fragen zu Risiken, Compliance oder Sicherheit. Diese lassen sich jedoch in der Regel nicht mit einem einzigen Datenpunkt beantworten. Doch es gibt eine Reihe von Dingen, die Security-Profis messen können, um auf die Fragen und Bedenken der Stakeholder einzugehen. Diese lassen sich (grob) in folgende Kategorien einordnen:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kontrollen:&lt;/strong&gt; Maßnahmen, die ergriffen werden, um Bedrohungen abzuwehren und Risiken zu reduzieren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assets:&lt;/strong&gt; Jeder Gegenstand, der für die Organisation einen Wert besitzt, beziehungsweise sich in ihrem Besitz befindet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerabilities:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495294/schwachstellen-managen-die-6-besten-vulnerability-management-tools.html" target="_blank" title="Schwachstellen"&gt;Schwachstellen&lt;/a&gt; in einem System, die ausgenutzt werden können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat Events:&lt;/strong&gt; Von einer Bedrohung ausgelöste Ereignisse, die Assets potenziell Schaden zufügen können.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sicherheitsvorfälle:&lt;/strong&gt; Ereignisse, die “erfolgreich” Wirkung auf das Unternehmen entfaltet haben, etwa in Form von (System-)Ausfällen, Datenschutzverletzungen oder &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3577944/diese-unternehmen-hats-schon-erwischt.html" target="_blank" title="Cyberangriffen"&gt;Cyberangriffen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diese Kategorien lassen sich weiter nach verschiedenen Faktoren aufschlüsseln: Zahlen, Zeit oder Kosten.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zahlen&lt;/strong&gt; könnten beispielsweise in Form des Prozentsatzes der ungepatchten Server gemessen werden. Eine weitere Möglichkeit: Sie messen die &lt;strong&gt;Zeit&lt;/strong&gt;, die benötigt wurde, um einen Sicherheitsvorfall zu identifizieren. Schließlich könnten &lt;strong&gt;Kosten&lt;/strong&gt; – zum Beispiel in Form von Wiederherstellungs- oder Ausfallkosten – Aufschluss über die finanziellen Auswirkungen von Security-Ereignissen geben.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cybersicherheits-metriken-kpis-und-kris"&gt;Cybersicherheits-Metriken, -KPIs und -KRIs&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn Security-Profis oder -Entscheider an Business Teams berichten, sollten sie dazu möglichst relevante Messerwerte wählen. Dabei konzentrieren sich die meisten Sicherheitsteams auf Metriken, die Low-Level-Messungen bezüglich Assets, Schwachstellen und Threat Events abbilden. Auf Führungs- und Vorstandsebene sind hingegen vor allem &lt;a href="https://www.computerwoche.de/article/2795253/die-wichtigste-security-kpi.html" target="_blank" title="KPIs"&gt;KPIs&lt;/a&gt; (Key Performance Indicators) und KRIs (Key Risk Indicators) entscheidend, weil diese dazu beitragen können, spezifische Fragen in Bezug auf IT-Risiko, -Status und -Vorbereitung zu beantworten. Beispielsweise: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sind wir sicher?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liefern die Sicherheitsinvestitionen dem Unternehmen Mehrwert?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erfüllen wir aus Sicherheitsperspektive alle regulatorischen Anforderungen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wie gut sind wir auf Ransomware- oder Supply-Chain-Angriffe vorbereitet?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Deshalb sollten sich Security-Praktiker auch auf KPIs und KRIs konzentrieren.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio foundryde-block"&gt; &lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video"&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sie wollen weitere interessante Beiträge rund um das Thema IT-Sicherheit lesen? Unser kostenloser Newsletter liefert Ihnen alles, was Sicherheitsentscheider und -experten wissen sollten, direkt in Ihre Inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn btn-danger" href="https://www.csoonline.com/de/newsletters/signup/" target="_blank"&gt;Jetzt CSO-Newsletter sichern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cybersecurity-messen-in-5-schritten"&gt;Cybersecurity messen in 5 Schritten&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Der Aufbau des richtigen Messrahmens ist ein schrittweiser, iterativer Prozess. Im Folgenden die fünf wichtigsten Schritte, um einen Security Measurement Cycle aufzubauen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Anforderungen definieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sprechen Sie mit relevanten Stakeholdern, um deren Bedürfnisse zu definieren und zu verstehen. Diese haben zu diesem Zeitpunkt möglicherweise noch kein umfassendes Verständnis über IT-Risiken – oder ihre eigenen Anforderungen. Deshalb ist für Security-Praktiker ein Bottom-Up-Ansatz empfehlenswert, bei dem sie selbst die Initiative ergreifen und Fragen zu stellen, um die Anforderungen definieren zu können.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Key Indicators auswählen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sobald die Anforderungen der Stakeholder definiert sind, sollten Sicherheitsexperten diejenigen Key Indicators auswählen, die auf diese einzahlen. Dabei sollten die Stakeholder konsultiert und über die beabsichtigten, späteren Messungen informiert werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wenn die Stakeholder die Key Indicators kennen, können sie Maßnahmen ergreifen oder Entscheidungen treffen. Die Schlüsselindikatoren sollten auf hoher Ebene angesiedelt sein – und ihre Anzahl überschaubar bleiben. Das Ziel besteht schließlich darin, die Entscheidungsfindung zu erleichtern.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Metriken identifizieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nachdem Ziele und Key Indicators festgelegt sind, gilt es für die Sicherheitsteams, die Low-Level-Messgrößen zu fokussieren, die dabei unterstützen, die Indikatoren zu reporten. Das kann – je nach Art des Indikators – bedeuten, dass Dutzende von Metriken aus den verschiedenen oben beschriebenen Messkategorien erforderlich sind.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Metriken sammeln und analysieren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Da die Anforderungen nun feststehen, die Schlüsselindikatoren ausgewählt und die Messgrößen festgelegt sind, können die Praktiker nun damit beginnen, Daten auf dieser Grundlage zu sammeln und zu analysieren. Metriken dürfen dabei nur aus Daten abgeleitet werden, die akkurat, aktuell, relevant und vertrauenswürdig sind. Anderenfalls kann es zu Entscheidungen kommen, die schwerwiegende Folgen für die Sicherheitslage des Unternehmens nach sich ziehen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Es ist die Aufgabe der Security-Teams, Wege zu finden, Daten kontinuierlich zu sammeln (die meisten Messungen erfordern einen Überblick über Trends im Zeitverlauf) und den Prozess vorzugsweise so weit wie möglich zu automatisieren (ein manueller Prozess kann ermüdend und zeitaufwändig sein).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Key Indicators reporten&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Key Indicators müssen zeitnah an die Entscheidungsträger reported werden. Dabei sollten sich Security-Profis und Stakeholder auf einen zeitlichen Rhythmus einigen – ebenso wie über die Art der Berichterstattung: Sind Dashboards erforderlich oder reichen Powerpoint-Präsentationen aus? Die Schlüsselindikatoren sollten deutlich sichtbar und leicht verständlich sein, um zu Entscheidungen oder Maßnahmen zu führen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Darüber hinaus ist es wichtig, nach jedem Berichtszyklus die Key Indicators zu überprüfen und sie (unter Einbeziehung der Stakeholder) neu zu bewerten. Haben sich die geschäftlichen Anforderungen tatsächlich geändert, müssen die Anforderungen erneut definiert und ein anderer Satz von Indikatoren und Messgrößen erarbeitet werden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unternehmen, Stakeholder und Sicherheitsexperten sollten keine Angst vor Rückwärts- oder Vorwärtsschritten haben: Die Fähigkeit, nach einem schnellen Fail direkt weiterzumachen, zu improvisieren oder sich neu auszurichten sind entscheidende Fähigkeiten, wenn es darum geht, Cybersicherheit erfolgreich zu messen. (fm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio foundryde-block"&gt; &lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video"&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.csoonline.com/article/3687733/measuring-cybersecurity-the-what-why-and-how.html" target="_blank" title="Dieser Beitrag basiert auf einem Artikel unserer US-Schwesterpublikation CSO Online."&gt;Dieser Beitrag basiert auf einem Artikel unserer US-Schwesterpublikation CSO Online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3495619/security-kpis-und-kris-so-messen-sie-cybersicherheit.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.84</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firm stand against migrant smuggling: global alliance convened in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</link>
      <description>On 10 December 2025, Europol participated in the second International Conference of the Global Alliance to Counter Migrant Smuggling, hosted by the European Commission. Over 80 delegations, including EU Member States, EU agencies, third party countries, international organisations, and private parties attended the event. During this high-level conference, over 50 delegations endorsed a joint declaration, pledging to strengthen cooperation along migrant smuggling routes and tackle the growing digital dimension of these criminal activities. The declaration underscores new preventive measures, including a crackdown on online advertisements promoting migrant smuggling and the disruption of underground banking systems fuelling the criminal business.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/firm-stand-against-migrant-smuggling-global-alliance-convened-in-brussels</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.91</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercrime Inc.: When hackers are better organized than IT</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116508/cybercrime-inc-when-hackers-are-better-organized-than-it.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What once began in forums with self-written malware has evolved into a globally networked underground economy that surpasses many companies in efficiency, speed, and scalability. Hacker groups today divide labor, utilize distribution channels, provide support, share revenue with partners, and invest in research and development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The crucial question is no longer whether a company will be the target of an attack, but how long it remains at a standstill after an attack — and whether it is able to recover from it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="structured-shadow-industry"&gt;Structured shadow industry&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybercrime has transformed from isolated incidents into an organized industry. The large groups operate according to the same principles as international corporations. They have departments, processes, management levels, and KPIs. They develop software, maintain customer databases, and evaluate their success rates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Attacks have long since adopted a business logic. Behind every phishing campaign, every data leak, and every extortion attempt lies a meticulously organized supply chain. Developers deliver malware, access brokers sell login credentials, logistics providers supply servers, and communications specialists negotiate ransoms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This gave rise to an efficient shadow economy with enormous scalability. Sales take place via closed forums, payments via cryptocurrencies, and accounting via encrypted communication channels.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ransomware-as-a-service-the-amazon-of-crime"&gt;Ransomware-as-a-service: The Amazon of crime&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/559049/ransomware-as-a-service-fuels-explosive-growth.html"&gt;ransomware-as-a-service&lt;/a&gt; (RaaS) model has also revolutionized the cybercrime business. Criminal groups offer their malware like a software product. Attackers can license the code, select targets, and launch attacks — all without in-depth programming knowledge. The operator receives a commission for this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thus, a marketplace developed where services, tools, and data are traded like products. Access costs a fee, but updates are included. There are manuals, discounts, and support forums. Even the marketing is professionally done: “Reliable decryption, fast response, fair distribution” — these are advertising slogans on the darknet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The parallels to the legitimate economy are striking. Partnerships, distribution networks, and bonus schemes exist. Ransomware is no longer an isolated incident, but a sophisticated business model with a clear profit strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="attack-as-a-service"&gt;Attack as a service&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybercrime now functions like a service chain. Anyone planning an attack today can purchase all the necessary components — from initial access credentials to leak management.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Access brokers sell access to corporate networks. Botnet operators provide computing power for attacks. Developers deliver turnkey exploits tailored to known vulnerabilities. Communication specialists handle contact with the victims.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this parallel economy, almost any role can be outsourced. The effect is the same scaling that has made legal platform companies strong — only operating in the shadow of the law.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-role-of-states"&gt;The role of states&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, state-tolerated or actively controlled groups are interfering in this ecosystem. Attacks on energy suppliers, hospitals, and public administration institutions demonstrate that cybercrime has long since become part of geopolitical power strategies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The lines between criminal and state actors are blurring. Certain groups operate under the protection of regimes or on their behalf. This creates hybrid structures that intertwine economic interests, political goals, and criminal profits.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This development makes the situation particularly critical. Cyberattacks today not only threaten IT systems, but also supply chain, public order, and economic stability.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="efficient-attackers"&gt;Efficient attackers&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What makes cybercrime so dangerous today is not just the technology itself, but the efficiency of its use. Attackers are flexible, networked, and eager to experiment. They test, discard, and improve — in cycles that are almost unimaginable in a corporate setting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recruitment is handled like in startups. Job offers for developers, social engineers, or language specialists circulate in darknet forums. There are performance bonuses, training, and career paths. The work methods are agile, communication is decentralized, and financial motivation is clearly defined.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These structures create a pressure for innovation that extends far beyond technical attacks. Cybercrime groups are investing in AI, automation, and machine learning. They analyze data to exploit vulnerabilities in a targeted manner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="slow-defenders"&gt;Slow defenders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The situation is different for those who are attacked. Many companies operate in defensive mode — slowly, bureaucratically, and often reactively. Security concepts are reviewed annually, but attacks are adapted daily. On average, over 200 days pass between an attack and its detection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This lag doesn’t stem from ignorance, but from structures. While criminals operate independently, companies have to check compliance, approve budgets, and clarify responsibilities. The attackers profit from the inertia of their victims.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The greatest risk is not a lack of technology, but a lack of responsiveness. This makes &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2111061/cyber-resilience-a-business-imperative-cisos-must-get-right.html"&gt;cyber resilience a crucial factor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="humans-as-a-gateway"&gt;Humans as a gateway&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over 80% of all successful attacks begin with human error. Phishing, social engineering, and manipulated chat messages remain the easiest ways to infiltrate networks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, the quality of these deception attempts has changed dramatically. &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3850783/11-ways-cybercriminals-are-making-phishing-more-potent-than-ever.html"&gt;Thanks to AI advances&lt;/a&gt;, cybercriminals’ social engineering emails, voice recordings, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3982379/deepfake-attacks-are-inevitable-cisos-cant-prepare-soon-enough.html"&gt;deepfakes&lt;/a&gt; appear authentic. Even experienced employees can hardly detect attacks anymore.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3604803/security-awareness-training-topics-best-practices-costs-free-options.html"&gt;Security awareness&lt;/a&gt; must therefore no longer be seen as a bothersome obligation. It must be part of the corporate culture. Only those who understand attacks as an everyday risk can react appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-as-weapons"&gt;Data as weapons&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ransomware groups today rely on double and triple extortion. First, systems are encrypted, then data is stolen, and finally sensitive information is published if no ransom is paid.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just about money, but about reputational damage. Confidential communications, confidential research results, or personal data are deliberately published to generate maximum pressure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This mechanism makes cybercrime a modern form of industrial espionage. Any piece of information can become a weapon, any company a target.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-ai-race"&gt;The AI ​​race&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence is an accelerator on both sides. Criminals use AI to perfect phishing, optimize malicious code, and bypass security mechanisms. At the same time, defenders use AI systems to detect anomalies and automatically isolate incidents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the dynamics are asymmetrical. Attackers can experiment freely, without regulatory or ethical constraints. Defenders, on the other hand, must consider data protection, liability, and compliance. This imbalance gives cybercrime groups a constant speed advantage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The next step is foreseeable: fully automated attack chains that make decisions in real-time based on machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-prevention-to-resilience"&gt;From prevention to resilience&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Given this development, absolute security is unattainable. The crucial factor is the ability to quickly regain operational capability after an attack. Cyber ​​resilience describes this competence — not only to survive crises but also to learn from them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A resilient company knows its critical processes, regularly tests recovery plans, and has a &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3851840/prepared-for-cyberattacks-crisis-communication-according-to-plan.html"&gt;clear communication strategy&lt;/a&gt;. Incident response teams &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829684/how-to-create-an-effective-incident-response-plan.html"&gt;must be trained before an emergency occurs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s not just about technology. Leadership, decision-making ability, and internal transparency are key success factors. Those who communicate during a crisis, instead of remaining silent, maintain control and trust.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-as-an-asset"&gt;Security as an asset&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, cybersecurity should no longer be seen as a cost factor, but rather as a strategic capability. It not only protects systems, but also safeguards competitiveness, customer data, and brand value.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The increasing professionalism of attackers forces companies to become more professional themselves — in structures, processes, and mindset. Only those who integrate security into the DNA of their organization can survive in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By 2026, cybercrime will no longer be a temporary risk, but a permanent part of the economic ecosystem. Companies that are prepared will survive. The others will become part of a statistic that grows year after year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cybercrime has adapted to the rules of the digital economy — efficiency, networking, automation. While many companies still think in outdated security paradigms, a global industry has long since formed underground.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It acts faster, is more adaptable, and more uncompromising. The difference between victim and survivor no longer lies in defense, but in the ability to get back on their feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116508/cybercrime-inc-when-hackers-are-better-organized-than-it.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.92</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US cybersecurity weakened by congressional delays despite Plankey renomination</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116477/us-cybersecurity-weakened-by-congressional-delays-despite-plankey-renomination.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The White House &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2026/01/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-078c/"&gt;moved&lt;/a&gt; to restart an urgent stalled priority by renominating well-regarded Coast Guard and Energy Department cyber veteran Sean Plankey as CISA director. Experts say the step offers some relief but does not go far enough to resolve the broader congressional inaction still straining the nation’s cyber defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some have faulted the White House for a lack of engagement in cyber issues and their advancement through Congress, while others say congressional dysfunction is the larger problem. Referring to the Trump administration’s broader approach to cyber policy, &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/james-andrew-lewis"&gt;Jim Lewis&lt;/a&gt;, SVP and director of the technology and public policy program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), tells CSO, “Cyber isn’t a priority for these guys.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href="https://www.venable.com/professionals/s/ari-schwartz"&gt;Ari Schwartz&lt;/a&gt;, managing director of cybersecurity services at Venable, views Congress as the greater culprit. “It is very difficult to get bills passed in Congress, and it turns out it’s very difficult to get some of these nominees through as well, even when they have bipartisan support. That signals we cannot get stuff done and is extremely problematic,” he tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Problems stemming from inaction across these areas could begin to emerge as soon as next month and compound thereafter if no further action is taken. Some experts are hopeful Congress or the administration will step in to address the lapses, although they warn solutions will not emerge quickly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cisa-leadership-swift-confirmation-needed-to-limit-damage"&gt;CISA leadership: Swift confirmation needed to limit damage&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The end of the year for Congress on Dec. 31 allowed &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3844343/trump-nominates-cyber-vet-sean-plankey-for-cisa-chief-amid-doge-cuts-and-firings.html"&gt;the nomination&lt;/a&gt; of Plankey &lt;a href="https://www.nextgov.com/cybersecurity/2025/12/senate-adjourns-without-confirming-cisa-director/410345/"&gt;to lapse&lt;/a&gt;, requiring a new nomination process. Experts say the longer Plankey waits for confirmation, the more adrift CISA and US cyber policy will be.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Amid budget cuts driven by Elon Musk’s Department of Government Efficiency, which &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3844047/cisa-cybersecurity-workforce-faces-cuts-amid-shifting-us-strategy.html"&gt;sharply reduced CISA’s staffing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3829710/firing-of-130-cisa-staff-worries-cybersecurity-industry.html"&gt;and institutional capacity&lt;/a&gt;, the ongoing lack of leadership at CISA accelerated the loss of invaluable expertise and created a three-level cybersecurity failure — internal, domestic, and international — for the US, according to &lt;a href="https://securityandtechnology.org/person/meganstifel/"&gt;Megan Stifel&lt;/a&gt;, chief strategy officer at the Institute for Security and Technology.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Not having confirmed leadership undermines CISA’s ability to meet its statutory obligations,” Stifel tells CSO. She adds that the lack of confirmed leadership complicates interagency coordination and weakens US credibility on critical infrastructure security abroad.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even with Plankey’s renomination, the damage caused by the prolonged leadership vacuum at the agency will still take time to rectify, according to CSIS’s Lewis. “They already hollowed out CISA, right? One CISA person who just left the agency told me that 40% of the career staff was gone. There’s not going to be a team to hand off to. They’ll need to do a lot of rebuilding.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the chairman of the House Homeland Security Committee, Andrew Garbarino (R-NY), Plankey’s renomination came none too soon. Speaking &lt;a href="https://mccraryinstitute.com/event/protecting-against-the-prc/"&gt;at an event&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the McCrary Institute on Dec. 16, Garbarino said he was disappointed that Plankey’s nomination had languished but that he would be confirmed “hopefully soon.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Confirmation holds on both sides of the aisle in the Senate played a significant part in the failure to confirm Plankey. Sen. Rick Scott (R-FL) blocked Plankey’s nomination due to &lt;a href="https://cyberscoop.com/sean-plankey-cisa-nomination-stalled-senate-holds/"&gt;a Coast Guard issue&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR) &lt;a href="https://www.wyden.senate.gov/news/press-releases/wyden-places-hold-on-top-cybersecurity-nominee-to-force-release-of-important-details-on-security-threats-to-us-phone-networks"&gt;held up&lt;/a&gt; Plankey’s nomination to force CISA to release an unclassified report on telephone network security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CISA &lt;a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/politics/articles/2025-07-30/senate-committee-advances-trump-nominee-to-lead-cybersecurity-agency-that-protects-election-systems"&gt;promised in July&lt;/a&gt; that it would release the report, but has yet to do so. Keith Chu, a spokesperson for Wyden, tells CSO the senator will continue to object to confirming any CISA director until the telecommunications security report is released.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cisa-2015-reauthorization-likely-but-late-and-suboptimal"&gt;CISA 2015 reauthorization: Likely, but late and suboptimal&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A major cybersecurity bill called the &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4065998/cisa-2015-cyber-threat-info-sharing-law-lapses-amid-government-shutdown.html"&gt;Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015&lt;/a&gt; (CISA 2015), which expired on Sept. 30, was &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/119/bills/hr5371/BILLS-119hr5371eas.pdf#page=26"&gt;temporarily revived&lt;/a&gt; on Nov. 13 and given a two-month lease on life through Jan. 30, 2026. The law provides critical legal liability protections that enable cyber threat information sharing among organizations and the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The short-term extension seemed to ensure a longer-term renewal of the legislation, as lawmakers, the administration, and industry broadly agree that failure to extend the legal liability protection under CISA 2015 is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s very important,” US Representative Garbarino said at the McCrary event. “It is imperative that it gets passed, and it gets extended. I don’t know how it gets done on its own. I feel like we have to attach it to another must-pass piece as legislation, whether that’s government funding, but we need it passed.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an emailed statement, CISA Director of Public Affairs Marci McCarthy tells CSO, “Reauthorizing the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 is vital to sustaining this progress — enabling industry and government to share information, respond to incidents, and mitigate cyber risks with speed and precision.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;White House National Cyber Director Sean Cairncross has &lt;a href="https://www.hstoday.us/subject-matter-areas/cybersecurity/national-cyber-director-outlines-vision-for-new-cybersecurity-strategy/"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, “I just want to be abundantly clear that we are for, and the White House is for, a 10-year clean reauthorization of CISA 2015.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With this tight level of agreement and support, odds are good that Congress will eventually reauthorize the legislation, although it is likely to be less than the 10-year renewal period advocates of the bill’s reauthorization seek.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Our colleagues in the Senate have different ideas,” Garbarino said. “Some of them want to do a 10-year clean reauthorization. I don’t know if I can get that passed in the House with concerns from the Freedom Caucus chairman,” &lt;a href="https://clayhiggins.house.gov/2025/09/03/higgins-leads-freedom-caucus-letter-urging-house-leadership-not-to-rush-cisa-reauthorization/"&gt;Andy Harris&lt;/a&gt; (R-MD), who has urged a go-slow approach to CISA 2015.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Even if Garbarino gets CISA 2015 through the House, some experts say a clean reauthorization would likely still be opposed by Senate Homeland Security Committee Chair Rand Paul (R-KY), who &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/10/rand-paul-blocks-senate-extension-of-cyber-information-sharing-law-00597017"&gt;blocked&lt;/a&gt; the Senate from passing a bill to extend the law.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="state-and-local-cyber-grants-effectively-dead-for-now"&gt;State and local cyber grants: Effectively dead for now&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A murky picture emerges for another piece of unfinished business in Congress: a state and local cybersecurity grant program (SLCGP) &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/cybergrants/slcgp"&gt;administered&lt;/a&gt; by CISA. Most of the remaining funds in the $1 billion program were hollowed out via Elon Musk’s Department of Government Efficiency in early 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In November, the House of Representatives passed the &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/house-bill/5078"&gt;PILLAR Act,&lt;/a&gt; which extended the program until 2033, but did not specifically allocate a dollar amount for future grants. Chairman Garbarino thinks there’s a good chance that the SLCGP could get funded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I have a great partner on appropriations, Chairman Amodei,” he said at the McCrary event, referring to Mark Amodei (R-NV), who is Chairman of the House Appropriations Homeland Security Subcommittee. “We’re trying to find a vehicle to attach it to and get it done.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some experienced Washington hands, such as CSIS’s Lewis, are skeptical. “I don’t think they’re [the state and local grants] ever coming back,” he tells CSO.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-will-washington-move-forward"&gt;When will Washington move forward?&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s unclear whether or when the remaining unresolved issues might move forward.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I think the Congress is probably going to do the right thing, but it will take longer because you don’t have executive branch leadership,” Lewis says. “Then they still have to [understand where] the White House is coming from, which is no money, no new authorities, and smaller agencies, before they can get anything in place. If we’re lucky, we’ll see it before the summer break, but it’s going to be a slow process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also possible that &lt;a href="https://cyberscoop.com/trump-national-cybersecurity-strategy-2025-release/"&gt;an upcoming&lt;/a&gt; White House cybersecurity strategy might touch on some of these programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some experts say the bipartisan nature of cybersecurity gives them hope. “Cybersecurity and, particularly, protecting critical infrastructure and defending US networks, remain a bipartisan issue,” Schwartz says. “That makes me feel better about the possibility of getting to a point where we are moving forward again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116477/us-cybersecurity-weakened-by-congressional-delays-despite-plankey-renomination.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.93</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control Systems] Moxa security advisory (AV26-013)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-013</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-moxa-security-advisory-av26-013</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 7.97</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity at the state and local level: Washington has the framework, it’s time to act</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116303/cybersecurity-at-the-state-and-local-level-washington-has-the-framework-its-time-to-act.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The White House’s March 2025 Executive Order (EO) on “&lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/achieving-efficiency-through-state-and-local-preparedness/"&gt;Achieving Efficiency Through State and Local Preparedness&lt;/a&gt;” raised an issue of utmost importance for national security and our critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As noted in the order, “federal policy must rightly recognize that preparedness is most effectively owned and managed at the state, local and even individual levels, supported by a competent, accessible and efficient federal government.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite claims from various cybersecurity leaders that the March EO is a federal retreat on information technology security, has funding gaps and lacks implementation clarity and expertise at the local level, the president is correct: Local jurisdictions are best positioned to anticipate their electronic security needs, understand their unique weaknesses, vulnerabilities and risks, and are best suited to develop and implement an incident response, mitigation and recovery plan based on their unique circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Congress is right, too. In 2021, it established the State and Local Cybersecurity Grant Program (SLCGP) to “award grants to eligible entities to address cybersecurity risks and cybersecurity threats to information systems owned or operated by, or on behalf of, state, local or tribal governments.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SLCGP authorizes $1 billion over four years to help state, local, tribal and territorial governments reduce systemic cyber risks and requires a pass-through of at least 80 percent of those funds to local governments, while reserving 25 percent of those funds for rural jurisdictions. A key component of the SLCGP ties any disbursement of funds to the Cybersecurity Infrastructure and Security Agency’s (CISA) approval of a state’s cybersecurity plan. That proposal must meet the requirements set forth in the SLCGP, such as implementation of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) cybersecurity framework.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This September, the Homeland Security Committee — with bipartisan support — introduced the Protecting Information by Local Leaders for Agency Resilience Act(PILLAR Act, H.R. 5078), which seeks to not only extend SLCGP for 10 years, but also provide long‑term stability and funding, strengthen milestone‑based accountability, expand its scope to AI and operational technology, and clarify cost‑sharing between federal and state governments. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Combined, the March 2025 EO and the SLCGP create a framework that will succeed if implemented in tandem. Unfortunately, that’s not what happened. In January 2025, the Office of Management and Budget directed all federal agencies to “temporarily pause all activities related to obligations or disbursement of all federal financial assistance.” This effectively ended all SLCGP disbursements and left it and the EO as unfunded mandates. But that’s not quite where this story ends. As part of the re-opening of the government in November, the SLCGP was potentially resurrected when its authorization was extended to January 30. This is a crucially important development. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to act and bring SLCGP fully back to life through the PILLAR Act. With our adversaries already embedded in our critical infrastructure (see Salt and Volt Typhoon, advanced persistent threat actors tied to China’s government), and the recent deployment of AI as a cyber-super-weapon — as demonstrated by Anthropic’s recent announcement of how its Claude AI was manipulated by Chinese state-sponsored hackers to conduct a large-scale attack executed almost entirely by AI agents — states and local jurisdictions are even more vulnerable. This is not simply a matter of funding; it’s a matter of national security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There should not be much debate as to whether states will utilize SLCGP effectively; they already have the data. As of August 1, 2024, according to the Government Accountability Office, “the Department of Homeland Security provided approximately $172 million in grants to 33 states and territories” and “[t]he grants are funding 839 state and local cybersecurity projects that align with core cybersecurity functions as defined by [NIST],” including developing cybersecurity plans and policies, employing cybersecurity contractors, upgrading equipment and implementing multi-factor authentication. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The passage of the PILLAR Act will also enhance CISA’s reach, even with its reduced workforce and limited resources, by making it a force multiplier because it can now focus on oversight — approving state cybersecurity tactics, setting standards and guiding and monitoring priorities — while state, local and tribal governments execute the day-to-day implementation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not mentioned in the PILLAR Act, but something practical and easily executed as part of the SLCGP, is local governments partnering with private and public universities to tap into a pipeline of students trained in cybersecurity strategy (e.g., law, policy, risk management, governance) and emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, resulting in lower costs for the local governments, hands-on experience for students and community building and outreach between local governments and universities. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The PILLAR Act has bipartisan support, and the president’s March 2025 EO reinforces everything contained within it. We now have the framework for securing our state, local and tribal governments. Let’s get this done immediately, as the stakes have never been higher and our national security depends on it. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/expert-contributor-network/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to join?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116303/cybersecurity-at-the-state-and-local-level-washington-has-the-framework-its-time-to-act.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.03</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike to add browser security to Falcon with Seraphic acquisition</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116703/crowdstrike-to-add-browser-security-to-falcon-with-seraphic-acquisition.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CrowdStrike has agreed to acquire Israel-based Seraphic Security, a browser runtime security company, to extend its Falcon platform to browser-native enterprise security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Expected to close by April, the acquisition will allow CrowdStrike to integrate Seraphic’s browser-native protection with its Falcon endpoint telemetry and threat intelligence capabilities. The move comes just days after CrowdStrike announced plans to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4114957/crowdstrike-to-acquire-sgnl-for-740m-expanding-real-time-identity-security.html" target="_blank"&gt;acquire&lt;/a&gt; SGNL, a continuous identity authorization company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="browser-as-attack-surface"&gt;Browser as attack surface&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With web browsers increasingly serving as the primary interface for enterprise work, communication, SaaS applications, and AI tools, they are emerging as one of the most exposed layers in corporate IT environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Traditional endpoint controls like EDR focus on the OS level and miss in-session browser activity, while network tools like firewalls can’t inspect HTTPS-encrypted sessions or user actions within apps. They lack visibility into browser telemetry, shadow IT, malicious extensions, and data flows, leaving gaps that attackers exploit via phishing, session hijacking, and zero-days,” said &lt;a href="https://ankura.com/experts-and-advisors/amit-jaju" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amit Jaju&lt;/a&gt;, global partner/senior managing director – India at Ankura Consulting. He added that web browsers pose risks even in controlled environments because they inherently process untrusted internet code, enabling zero-day exploits, malicious extensions acting as supply chain attacks, and credential theft that bypasses perimeter defenses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CrowdStrike &lt;a href="https://ir.crowdstrike.com/news-releases/news-release-details/crowdstrike-acquire-seraphic-turning-any-browser-secure" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the Seraphic acquisition will allow it to extend the Falcon platform deeper into in-browser activity.  With Seraphic, the company aims to transform the SOC by correlating trillions of endpoint signals with deep, in-session browser telemetry. This will allow the Falcon platform to understand user intent, application context, and data flow in real time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Seraphic’s true USP lies in its ability to make the browser session itself a governable security surface, rather than treating the browser as a passive extension of the endpoint,” said &lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research. “Most enterprise security stacks stop at device health and identity validation. They confirm who logged in and from what device, but they lose visibility once the user begins interacting inside SaaS applications. Seraphic addresses this by enforcing policy inside the live browser session, covering user actions, session behaviour, and data movement that never touches disk and never triggers network anomalies. When integrated into CrowdStrike Falcon, it moves from detecting threats around user activity to governing behaviour during it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="gen-ai-altering-browser-risk"&gt;Gen AI altering browser risk&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Generative AI has fundamentally altered the browser risk profile. Gogia noted that the browser is now a bidirectional data exchange, where employees routinely feed sensitive context into AI systems. Most of this activity happens outside formal enterprise governance. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Copying internal data into AI prompts, uploading files for summarisation, or using AI-enhanced browser features has become one of the fastest-growing data leakage paths in organisations. As a result, browser-level enforcement is one of the few practical ways to address this without resorting to unrealistic bans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;CrowdStrike will also integrate SGNL’s continuous authorization technology, enabling permissions to be dynamically granted or revoked on a per-session and risk-level basis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The two solutions combined will create what the company described as a unified security fabric.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The integration will be designed to secure how generative AI applications and agents are accessed, to prevent shadow AI tools from scraping or exfiltrating sensitive enterprise data. It will also aim to prevent the copying, uploading, or screen-grabbing of sensitive data using AI-based content filtering and granular execution-layer controls, stop session hijacking, sophisticated phishing, and man-in-the-browser attacks at the point of execution by randomizing the browser’s JavaScript engine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition, CrowdStrike will extend protection to unmanaged and BYOD devices by securing the browser session without requiring a full endpoint agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116703/crowdstrike-to-add-browser-security-to-falcon-with-seraphic-acquisition.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.09</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpyCloud Launches Supply Chain Solution to Combat Rising Third-Party Identity Threats</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116536/spycloud-launches-supply-chain-solution-to-combat-rising-third-party-identity-threats.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpyCloud&lt;/a&gt;, the leader in identity threat protection, today announced the launch of its &lt;strong&gt;Supply Chain Threat Protection&lt;/strong&gt; solution, an advanced layer of defense that expands identity threat protection across the extended workforce, including organizations’ entire vendor ecosystems. Unlike traditional third-party risk management platforms that rely on external surface indicators and static scoring, &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/products/supply-chain-threat-protection/?utm_medium=pr&amp;amp;utm_source=cybernewswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=supply-chain-launch-2026" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SpyCloud Supply Chain Threat Protection&lt;/a&gt; provides timely access to identity threats derived from billions of recaptured breach, malware, phished, and combolist data assets, empowering organizations – from enterprise security teams to public sector agencies – to act on credible threats rather than simply observe and accept risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Supply Chain Threat Protection addresses a critical gap in enterprise security: the inability to maintain real-time awareness of identity exposures affecting third-party partners and vendors. According to the 2025 Verizon Data Breach Investigations Report, &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/blog/verizon-2025-data-breach-report-insights/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;third-party involvement in breaches&lt;/a&gt; doubled year-over-year, jumping from 15% to 30% primarily due to software vulnerabilities and weak security practices. As supply chain compromises continue to escalate, security teams need intelligence that goes beyond questionnaires and external scans to reveal active threats like phishing campaigns targeting their trusted partners, confirmed credential theft, and malware-infected devices exposing critical business applications to criminals. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/wo7MqWbUCZ4?utm_medium=pr&amp;amp;utm_source=cybernewswire&amp;amp;utm_content=video&amp;amp;utm_campaign=supply-chain-launch-2026"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video"&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For government agencies and critical infrastructure operators, supply chain threats present national security risks that demand heightened vigilance. Public sector organizations managing sensitive data and critical services increasingly rely on contractors and technology vendors whose compromised credentials could provide adversaries with pathways into classified systems or essential infrastructure. Last year alone, the top 98 &lt;a href="https://engage.spycloud.com/rs/713-WIP-737/images/spycloud-2025-infographic-DIB.pdf?_gl=1*29lkhl*_gcl_au*MzgxMTg0NjkyLjE3NjE5MjE3NTg." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Defense Industrial Base suppliers&lt;/a&gt; had over 11,000 dark web exposed credentials – an 81% increase from the previous year. SpyCloud Supply Chain Threat Protection enables federal, state, and local agencies to identify when suppliers or contractors have been compromised – allowing them to take proactive measures before an identity exposure escalates into a matter of national security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Third-party threats have evolved far beyond what traditional vendor assessment tools can detect,” said Damon Fleury, Chief Product Officer at SpyCloud. “Public and private sector organizations need to know when their vendors’ employees are actively compromised by malware or phishes, when authentication data is circulating on the dark web, and which partners pose the greatest real downstream threat to their business. Our new solution delivers those signals by transforming raw underground data into clear, prioritized actions that security teams use to protect their organization.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Supply Chain Threat Protection enables organizations and agencies to continuously monitor thousands of suppliers, with each company’s threats enumerated in detail, and also represented in an at-a-glance Identity Threat Index. The Index is a comprehensive and continuously updated analysis that quantifies vendor security posture through the lens of identity exposure, from both active and historical phishing, breach, and malware sources, and surfaces which partners pose the most significant risk based on verified dark web intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Capabilities Include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class="wp-block-list"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real Evidence of Compromise:&lt;/strong&gt; Timely recaptured identity data from breaches, malware, and successful phishes collected continuously from the criminal underground, with context that gives security teams enhanced visibility into the identity threats facing suppliers today.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Threat Index:&lt;/strong&gt; Aggregates multiple verified data sources weighted by the recency, volume, credibility, and severity of compromise, emphasizing verified identity data over static breach records for more robust and real-time visibility into vendor risk.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compromised Applications&lt;/strong&gt;: Identifies the internal and third-party business applications exposed on malware-infected supplier devices to support deeper investigation and risk assessment.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Vendor Management and Communications:&lt;/strong&gt; Facilitates sharing of actionable evidence and detailed executive-level reports directly with vendors to collaboratively improve security posture, transforming vendor relationships from adversarial scoring to collaborative protection.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated Response: &lt;/strong&gt;Leveraging SpyCloud’s console, teams now have access to identity threat protection beyond the traditional employee perimeter with this extension to suppliers, allowing analysts to respond to workforce identity threats within a single tool. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpyCloud Supply Chain Threat Protection is designed to support multiple use cases across Security Operations, Infosec, Vendor Risk Management, and GRC teams. Organizations can leverage the solution for vendor due diligence during procurement and onboarding, continuous risk reviews to strengthen vendor relationships, and accelerated incident response when vendor exposures threaten their own environments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Security teams and their counterparts across the business are overwhelmed with vendor assessments, questionnaires, and risk scores that often don’t translate to real prevention,” said Alex Greer, Group Product Manager at SpyCloud. “Our customers have often reported that when they’re evaluating doing business with a new vendor, they lack the actionable data their legal and compliance teams need for evidence-based decision making. That’s where SpyCloud stands out. Surfacing verified identity threats tied directly to vendor compromise, letting teams escalate to leadership when to restrict data access and prioritize efforts for the greatest impact on reducing organizational risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike existing solutions that rely on external surface indicators and static scoring, SpyCloud provides threat data derived from underground sources – the same recaptured darknet identity data that criminals actively use to target organizations and agencies. This fundamental difference enables SpyCloud customers to move from passive risk acceptance to proactive and holistic identity threat protection.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more about defending organizations from the exposures of vendors and suppliers, registration is open for SpyCloud’s upcoming Live Virtual Event, &lt;a href="https://spycloud.com/events/how-to-solve-the-hidden-identity-crisis-in-your-supply-chain/?utm_medium=pr&amp;amp;utm_source=cybernewswire&amp;amp;utm_campaign=supply-chain-launch-2026" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond Vendor Risk Scores: How to Solve the Hidden Identity Crisis in Your Supply Chain, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, January 22, 2026, at 11 am CT&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SpyCloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpyCloud transforms recaptured darknet data to disrupt cybercrime. Its automated identity threat protection solutions leverage advanced analytics and AI to proactively prevent ransomware and account takeover, detect insider threats, safeguard employee and consumer identities, and accelerate cybercrime investigations. SpyCloud’s data from breaches, malware-infected devices, and successful phishes also powers many popular dark web monitoring and identity theft protection offerings. Customers include seven of the Fortune 10, along with hundreds of global enterprises, mid-sized companies, and government agencies worldwide. Headquartered in Austin, TX, SpyCloud is home to more than 200 cybersecurity experts whose mission is to protect businesses and consumers from the stolen identity data criminals are using to target them now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more and see insights on your company’s exposed data, users can visit &lt;a href="http://spycloud.com" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;spycloud.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h5 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Specialist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phil Tortora&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REQ on behalf of SpyCloud&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spycloud@req.co&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116536/spycloud-launches-supply-chain-solution-to-combat-rising-third-party-identity-threats.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.12</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s partial internet shutdown may be a windfall for cybersecurity intel</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116890/irans-partial-internet-shutdown-may-be-a-windfall-for-cybersecurity-intel.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The near-total internet blackout imposed by the Iranian government starting January 8, reportedly due to a crackdown on protesters, may offer a rare opportunity to SOC staffers and other cybersecurity analysts, briefly allowing all government traffic sources to be identified and digitally fingerprinted, a massive help in tracking Iranian state actors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3595792/nation-state-actors-increasingly-hide-behind-cybercriminal-tactics-and-malware.html" target="_blank"&gt;global malicious state actors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4115379/iran-linked-muddywater-apt-deploys-rust-based-implant-in-latest-campaign.html"&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt; is near the top, behind &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/653302/chinese-state-actors-behind-espionage-attacks-on-southeast-asian-government.html" target="_blank"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4107406/russian-apt-group-pivots-to-network-edge-device-misconfigurations.html" target="_blank"&gt;Russia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4090979/north-koreas-job-test-trap-upgrades-to-json-malware-dropboxes.html" target="_blank"&gt;North Korea&lt;/a&gt;, which suggests that this kind of intel on Iranian systems might prove useful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One cybersecurity vendor CEO argues that it is indeed a potential threat intel goldmine.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In an almost-total internet blackout, “the attack surface available to state hackers shrinks. They can no longer hide in the noise of millions of residential IPs. They are forced to route their attacks through the few remaining whitelisted pipes, which are exactly those boring government agencies such as Agriculture, Energy, Universities,” said &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kakooch" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kaveh Ranjbar&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Whisper Security. “Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) groups routinely co-opt benign government infrastructure to launch attacks because it looks clean. When the rest of the country is dark, those boring servers become the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; available launchpads. A connection from the Ministry of Agriculture might not be a farmer. It’s likely a tunnel for a state actor who needs an exit node.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ranjbar said the removal of the traffic from millions of routine Iranian business and residential users allows a powerful visibility into Iranian government traffic patterns, thereby allowing SOCs to flag those sources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For a CISO, the calculus is simple: User traffic is zero. If Amazon or a bank sees traffic from Tehran during a blackout, it is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a customer buying books or checking a balance. It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a remote employee. [All] of the traffic is machine-generated and state-sanctioned. Even if it’s just a misconfigured cron job at the Ministry of Water, it is an anomaly. But more often, it is scanning, probing, or reconnaissance,” Ranjbar said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“You don’t need a list of malicious agencies,” he observed. “You need to know that the entire visible IP space of Iran is currently a privileged enclave. If a server is allowed to speak to the outside world while 80 million citizens are silenced, that server is, by definition, an asset of the state. In a zero-trust environment, that makes it a high-confidence Indicator of Compromise (IoC) if it touches your network.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Analysts and consultants, however, were reserved about the approach, but pointed out that, on an ROI basis, it will typically require minimal effort to capture that data during the blackout, so it can’t hurt much to do so. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think there’s any downside to capturing it,” said &lt;a href="https://moorinsightsstrategy.com/team/robert-kramer/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Robert Kramer&lt;/a&gt;, vice president/principal analyst at Moor Insights &amp;amp; Strategy. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-might-be-of-limited-value"&gt;Data might be of limited value&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, Kramer and other experts said, the nature of state actors today may make that captured data of limited value. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;State actors for those four countries are among the most sophisticated, experienced, and best-financed attackers anywhere. One of their top skills is not only knowing how to cover their tracks, but how to create false logs and other deceptions to make the attack look like it is being launched from anywhere &lt;em&gt;other than &lt;/em&gt;its true source. In short, if the logs point to the attack coming from China, a CISO knows that the attack almost certainly wasn’t launched by China. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://greyhoundresearch.com/svg/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sanchit Vir Gogia&lt;/a&gt;, chief analyst at Greyhound Research, said that he sees some of the potential value, but added that it is limited. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this kind of blackout, “the few packets that escape become disproportionately meaningful. You’re looking at whitelisted ASNs, state-controlled telecoms and government-operated services. That residual traffic helps map adversary digital infrastructure with surprising clarity. The presence of DNS queries, passive malware beacons, or control-plane BGP signals during a blackout gives analysts a blueprint of national priorities.” Gogia said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, he stressed, that’s where the value may stop. “Residual traffic does not readily convert into block rules or SIEM logic. It does not hand you command-and-control servers on a silver platter. Most of it is either benign or diagnostic. And unless correlated with strong behavioral signals, it rarely survives the trip from strategic context to operational action,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Yes, you might find an Iranian IP that kept chattering when no one else could. But was it a threat actor’s box, or just a government website? Without high-confidence enrichment, it’s guesswork. Worse, if that same IP goes back to hosting payroll services a week later, your SOC is stuck chasing shadows. That’s why this intelligence is best used for threat modelling, not triage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Gogia added that the captured data is also likely to expire relatively quickly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Routing anomalies and observable proxies are equally unstable. During partial shutdowns, traffic might reroute through unexpected neighbors or temporarily migrate to backup ISPs,” he noted. “A sharp analyst might catch an Iranian subnet using a German transit point during a blackout. But once service restores, that path disappears. If you treated it as a long-term IoC, it would quickly become a dead end.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Setting aside deliberate deception, there is also a lot of legitimate traffic coming from Iranian government agencies, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthewestern/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew Stern&lt;/a&gt;, CEO at CNC Intelligence, pointed out. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This may offer short-term insight into routing behavior, protocol usage, and infrastructure dependencies that Iranian state-linked operators may later reuse. However, this should not be overstated,” Stern said. “Government traffic is not inherently malicious and sophisticated Iranian cyber actors frequently operate through foreign infrastructure, compromised hosts, and third-party services outside Iran, which significantly limits the long-term defensive value of domestic traffic fingerprinting.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, cybersecurity consultant &lt;a href="https://formergov.com/directory/brianlevine" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brian Levine&lt;/a&gt;, executive director of FormerGov, said the rare nature of this shutdown makes it worth performing whatever data capture is viable. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-signal-to-noise-ratio-flips"&gt;The signal to noise ratio flips&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“From an intelligence perspective, this is one of the rare moments when the signal‑to‑noise ratio flips. If traffic is flowing out of Iran right now, odds are high it’s state‑linked, and that alone makes it worth capturing,” Levine said. “Even legitimate Iranian government activity can be valuable to SOCs. State actors tend to reuse infrastructure, routes, and operational patterns. Today’s ‘normal’ traffic can become tomorrow’s attribution breadcrumb.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although Levine agreed that the quantity of actionable long-term data is likely small, he thinks it is still worth capturing. “Collecting digital fingerprints during a blackout won’t solve attribution on its own, but it can sharpen it. In cyber defense, even a few percentage points of clarity can make the difference between catching an intrusion early and missing it entirely.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, two VP analysts with Gartner, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/jeremy-dhoinne" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jeremy D’Hoinne&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/akif-khan" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Akif Khan&lt;/a&gt;, were more skeptical of the data’s value and discouraged CISO teams from pursuing it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Attribution is dangerous based on fragmented technical evidence,” D’Hoinne said. “Don’t get distracted.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Khan was more blunt. “In the fog of war, trying to find verifiable information is very challenging. Without being able to corroborate, I don’t think this goes beyond an intellectual exercise. If people in your enterprise SOC have the time to do this, they need to refocus their priorities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116890/irans-partial-internet-shutdown-may-be-a-windfall-for-cybersecurity-intel.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.34</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophisticated VoidLink malware framework targets Linux cloud servers</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117038/sophisticated-voidlink-malware-framework-targets-linux-cloud-servers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers have uncovered a new sophisticated and modular malware framework designed to operate stealthily inside Linux systems and containers. The framework seems to have been designed by Chinese developers with in-depth knowledge of Linux internals and was created to be used against cloud servers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The framework, internally referred to by its original developers as VoidLink, is a cloud-first implant written in Zig and designed to operate in modern infrastructure,” researchers from security firm Check Point said in their &lt;a href="https://research.checkpoint.com/2026/voidlink-the-cloud-native-malware-framework/"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. “It can recognize major cloud environments and detect when it is running inside Kubernetes or Docker, then tailor its behavior accordingly.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Check Point only found samples of the malware that appear to be an in-progress project rather than a completed product. However, the project is mature, and the company’s researchers suspect it won’t be long before the malware is used in real-world attacks, possibly for cyberespionage or supply-chain compromises because it harvests credentials for cloud environments and source code repository management systems.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="highly-extensible-and-customizable"&gt;Highly extensible and customizable&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;VoidLink draws inspiration from the beacon implant of Cobalt Strike, an adversary simulation framework that has been widely adopted and misused by attackers over the years. The malware uses an API to communicate with additional plug-ins that add a diverse set of capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By default, the platform comes with 37 plug-ins that can be selected and delivered to the victim to enable additional capabilities. However, the operator can also deliver custom plug-ins. This is controlled through a professional-looking web-based command-and-control (C2) dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This interface is localized for Chinese-affiliated operators, but the navigation follows a familiar C2 layout: a left sidebar groups pages into Dashboard, Attack, and Infrastructure,” the researchers said. “The Dashboard section covers the core operator loop (agent manager, built-in terminal, and an implant builder). In contrast, the Attack section organizes post-exploitation activity such as reconnaissance, credential access, persistence, lateral movement, process injection, stealth, and evidence wiping.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware framework is written in Zig, a relatively new programming language that’s an alternative to C and is an unusual choice for malware development. However, the developers have also shown proficiency in other languages such as Go, C, and JavaScript frameworks such as React.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The researchers note that VoidLink is much more advanced that typical Linux malware, with a well-designed core component handling state, communication and task execution that is delivered through a two-stage loader. Operators can deliver additional code to be executed in the form of plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-reconnaissance-and-adaptability"&gt;Cloud reconnaissance and adaptability&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware was designed to detect whether it’s being executed on various cloud platforms such as AWS, GCP, Azure, Alibaba, and Tencent and then to start leveraging those vendors’ management APIs. The code suggests the developers plan to add detections for Huawei, DigitalOcean, and Vultr in the future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware collects extensive amounts of information about the machine and environment it runs in, including whether it’s a Docker container or a Kubernetes pod. It then can execute post-exploitation modules that attempt privilege escalation through container escapes or lateral movement to other containers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Ultimately, the goal of this implant appears to be stealthy, long-term access, surveillance, and data collection,” the researchers said, adding that developers might be a target for initial delivery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another interesting aspect is that the malware has a sophisticated algorithm through which it adapts its operations based on the security posture of the environment. It will scan for common Linux endpoint and detection response (EDR) tools and kernel hardening technologies and then calculate a risk score for the environment, which is then used to select a detection evasion strategy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The malware also has multiple rootkit components with deployment strategies for different versions of the Linux kernel and will deploy them based on the environment in which it runs. These rootkit modules hide the malware’s processes, files, and network sockets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;C2 traffic is hidden in multiple ways, including as encrypted data in PNGs or JS, HTML, or CSS files, making it hard to detect at the network layer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“VoidLink aims to automate evasion as much as possible, profiling an environment and choosing the most suitable strategy to operate in it,” the researchers said. “Augmented by kernel mode tradecraft and a vast plugin ecosystem, VoidLink enables its operators to move through cloud environments and container ecosystems with adaptive stealth.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While malware for Linux is less common and often less sophisticated than malware programs for Windows, VoidLink stands out as a unique and highly capable framework. Even if it’s not totally clear whether this malware is intended to be a product for cybercriminals or as future commercial penetration testing framework of sorts, it serves as an example of the type of threats organizations should be prepared to defend in their Linux-based cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117038/sophisticated-voidlink-malware-framework-targets-linux-cloud-servers.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.51</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware gangs extort victims by citing compliance violations</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116976/ransomware-gangs-blackmail-victims-with-compliance-violations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/563507/what-is-ransomware-how-it-works-and-how-to-remove-it.html"&gt;Ransomware attacks&lt;/a&gt; remain among the most common attack methods. As recent analyses show, cyber gangs are increasingly threatening their victims with reporting violations of regulations such as the GDPR to supervisory authorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the security provider Akamai have observed an increasing trend in this tactic over the past two years. As an example, the security vendor points to ransomware group Anubis. Its members reportedly focus primarily on industries with high compliance risks, such as healthcare. The notorious &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2139658/new-ransomhub-ransomware-gang-has-ties-to-older-knight-group.html" target="_blank"&gt;Ransomhub&lt;/a&gt; gang also allegedly employs this method, explicitly encouraging its partners to threaten hacked companies with regulatory penalties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="consequences-for-companies"&gt;Consequences for companies&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This puts companies under a double pressure that is almost impossible to manage,” Klaus Hild, manager of solution engineering for enterprise at SailPoint, explained to CSO. They have to weigh the risk of paying ransoms against potentially ruinous penalties and reputational damage. “This ‘compliance extortion’ is no longer a theoretical threat — it has become standard practice for ransomware cartels,” Hild added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tim Berghof, security evangelist at G DATA, confirmed to CSO that while this approach is technically just an extension of the “industry-standard” double extortion, it can have massive consequences. “Even if a complaint turns out to be unfounded, official investigations generate attention, tie up resources, and potentially become public,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-amplifies-attacks"&gt;AI amplifies attacks&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hild points to another problem: “AI-powered tools dramatically accelerate these attacks. Criminals can now screen stolen documents for ‘material’ compliance violations within hours of a data breach — faster and more accurately than many companies can audit their own systems.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The SailPoint specialist explains: “They create detailed, legally sound complaints for authorities and set tight deadlines. With new regulations like &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570091/eus-dora-regulation-explained-new-risk-management-requirements-for-financial-firms.html" target="_blank"&gt;DORA&lt;/a&gt; in the EU and stricter SEC reporting requirements, the arsenal of these extortionists is constantly growing.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Berghoff summarizes: “The question remains which has the less severe consequences for companies: a self-report or an anonymous report to the relevant authority by a group of criminals. Since there is still a great deal of uncertainty surrounding compliance in some areas, threats involving authorities potentially fall on fertile ground.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4116976/ransomware-gangs-blackmail-victims-with-compliance-violations.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.75</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From typos to takeovers: Inside the industrialization of npm supply chain attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117139/from-typos-to-takeovers-inside-the-industrialization-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div id="remove_no_follow"&gt;
		&lt;div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"&gt;
					  &lt;div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"&gt;
						&lt;div class="article-column__content"&gt;
&lt;section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"&gt;&lt;div class="container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A massive surge in attacks on the npm ecosystem over the past year reveals a stark shift in the software supply‑chain threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What once amounted to sloppy typosquatting attempts has evolved into coordinated, credential-driven intrusions targeting maintainers, CI pipelines, and the trusted automation that underpins modern development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For security leaders, these aren’t niche developer mishaps anymore — they’re a direct pathway into production systems, cloud infrastructure, and millions of downstream applications.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The goal is no longer to trick an individual developer, but to quietly inherit their authority. And with it, their distribution reach.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“NPM is an attractive target because it is the world’s largest JavaScript package repository and a key control point for distributing software,” said Melinda Marks, cybersecurity practice director at Enterprise Security Group. “Security teams need an understanding of dependencies and ways to regularly audit and mitigate risk.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="structural-weaknesses-in-the-npm-infrastructure"&gt;Structural weaknesses in the npm infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly every enterprise relies on npm, whether directly or indirectly. According to &lt;a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=US51141024"&gt;IDC&lt;/a&gt;, 93% of organizations use open-source software, and npm remains the largest package registry in the JavaScript ecosystem. “Compromising a single popular package can immediately reach millions of downstream users and applications,” IDC’s research manager (DevSecOps), Katie Norton, said, turning one stolen credential into what she described as a “master key” for distribution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That scale, however, is only part of the risk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The exposure is amplified by structural weaknesses in how modern development pipelines are secured, Norton remarked. “Individual open-source maintainers often lack the security resources that enterprise teams rely on, leaving them susceptible to social engineering,” she said. “CI/CD runners and developer machines routinely process long-lived secrets that are stored in environment variables or configuration files and are easily harvested by malware.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Build systems also tend to prioritize speed and reliability over security visibility, resulting in limited monitoring and long dwell times for attackers who gain initial access,” Norton added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While security leaders can’t patch their way out of this one, they can reduce exposure. Experts consistently point to the same priorities: treating CI runners as production assets, rotating and scoping publish tokens aggressively, disabling lifecycle scripts unless required, and pinning dependencies to immutable versions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“These npm attacks are targeting the pre-install phase of software dependencies, so typical software supply chain security methods of code scanning cannot address these types of attacks,” Marks said. Detection requires runtime analysis and anomaly detection rather than signature-based tooling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;From typo traps to legitimate backdoors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For years, &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/570173/what-is-typosquatting-a-simple-but-effective-attack-technique.html"&gt;typosquatting&lt;/a&gt; defined the npm threat model. Attackers published packages with names just close enough to popular libraries, such as “lodsash,” “expres,” “reacts,” and waited for automation or human error to do the rest. The impact was usually limited, and remediation straightforward.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That model began to break in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Instead of impersonating popular packages, attackers increasingly compromised real ones. Phishing &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4028412/supply-chain-attack-compromises-npm-packages-to-spread-backdoor-malware.html"&gt;campaigns&lt;/a&gt; spoofing npm itself harvested maintainer credentials. Stolen tokens were then used to publish trojanized updates that appeared legitimate to every downstream consumer. The Shai-Hulud &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4095578/new-shai-hulud-worm-spreading-through-npm-github.html"&gt;campaign&lt;/a&gt; illustrated the scale of the problem, affecting tens of thousands of repositories and leveraging compromised credentials to self-propagate across the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The npm ecosystem has become the crown jewels of modern development,” said Kush Pandya, a cybersecurity researcher at Socket.dev. “When a single prolific maintainer is compromised, the blast radius spans hundreds of downstream projects.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The result was a quiet but powerful shift: attackers no longer needed to create convincing fakes. They could ship malware through &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4026380/prettier-eslint-npm-packages-hijacked-in-a-sophisticated-supply-chain-attack.html"&gt;trusted channels&lt;/a&gt;, signed and versioned like any routine update.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="developer-environments-over-developer-laptops"&gt;Developer environments over developer laptops&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Modern npm &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3506897/github-actions-typosquatting-a-high-impact-supply-chain-attack-in-waiting.html"&gt;attacks&lt;/a&gt; increasingly activate inside CI/CD environments rather than on developer laptops. Post-install &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3995813/hackers-drop-60-npm-bombs-in-less-than-two-weeks-to-recon-dev-machines.html?utm=hybrid_search#:~:text=post%2Dinstall%20scripts"&gt;scripts&lt;/a&gt;, long treated as benign setup helpers, became an execution vector capable of running automatically inside GitHub Actions or GitLab CI. Once inside a runner, malicious packages could read environment variables, steal publish tokens, tamper with build artifacts, or even push additional malicious releases under the victim’s identity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Developer environments and CI runners are now worth more than end-user machines,” Pandya noted. “They usually have broader permissions, access to secrets, and the ability to push code into production.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Several campaigns observed in mid-2025 were explicitly &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4088529/malicious-npm-package-sneaks-into-github-actions-builds.html"&gt;CI-aware&lt;/a&gt;, triggering only when they detected automated build environments. Some included delayed execution or self-expiring payloads, minimizing forensic visibility while maximizing credential theft.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For enterprises, this represents a fundamental risk shift. CI systems often operate with higher privileges than any individual user, yet are monitored far less rigorously. “They are often secured with weaker defaults: long-lived publish tokens, overly permissive CI secrets, implicit trust in lifecycle scripts and package metadata, and little isolation between builds,” Pandya noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to IDC Research, organizations allocate only about 14% of AppSec budgets to supply-chain security, with only 12% of them identifying CI/CD pipeline security as a top risk.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class="wp-block-heading"&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Evasion as a first-class feature&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As defenders improved at spotting suspicious packages, attackers adapted too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recent npm campaigns have used invisible Unicode characters to &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4082195/malicious-packages-in-npm-evade-dependency-detection-through-invisible-url-links-report.html"&gt;obscure&lt;/a&gt; dependencies, multi-stage loaders that fetch real payloads only after environment checks, and &lt;a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4050956/malicious-npm-packages-use-ethereum-blockchain-for-malware-delivery.html"&gt;blockchain-hosted &lt;/a&gt;command-and-control (C2) references designed to evade takedowns. Others deployed worm-like behavior, using stolen credentials to publish additional malicious packages at scale.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Manual review has become largely ineffective against this level of tradecraft. “The days when you could skim index.js and spot a malicious eval() are gone,” Pandya said. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Modern packages hide malicious logic behind layers of encoding, delayed execution, and environment fingerprinting.” Norton echoed the concern, noting that these attacks operate at a behavioral level where static scanning falls short. “Obfuscation techniques make malicious logic difficult to distinguish from legitimate complexity in large JavaScript projects,” she said. “CI-aware payloads and post-install scripts introduce behavior that only manifests under specific environmental conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.csoonline.com/article/4117139/from-typos-to-takeovers-inside-the-industrialization-of-npm-supply-chain-attacks.html</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.79</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM security advisory (AV26-014)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ibm-security-advisory-av26-014</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell security advisory (AV26-015)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/dell-security-advisory-av26-015</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.95</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu security advisory (AV26-016)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/ubuntu-security-advisory-av26-016</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge security advisory (AV26-017)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-edge-security-advisory-av26-017</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware security advisory (AV26-018)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/vmware-security-advisory-av26-018</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.96</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] CISA ICS security advisories (AV26–019)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-cisa-ics-security-advisories-av26-019</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 8.98</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AL26-001 – Vulnerabilities affecting n8n – CVE-2026-21858, CVE-2026-21877 and CVE-2025-68613</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/al26-001-vulnerabilities-affecting-n8n-cve-2026-21858-cve-2026-21877-cve-2025-68613</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.01</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Siemens security advisory (AV26-020)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-siemens-security-advisory-av26-020</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.49</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAP security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-021)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/sap-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-021</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.52</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow security advisory (AV26-022)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/servicenow-security-advisory-av26-022</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.53</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortinet security advisory (AV26-023)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/fortinet-security-advisory-av26-023</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.62</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft security advisory – January 2026 monthly rollup (AV26-024)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/microsoft-security-advisory-january-2026-monthly-rollup-av26-024</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.63</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HPE security advisory (AV26-025)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/hpe-security-advisory-av26-025</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 9.65</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome security advisory (AV26-026)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/google-chrome-security-advisory-av26-026</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.19</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe security advisory (AV26-027)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/adobe-security-advisory-av26-027</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.20</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla security advisory (AV26-028)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/mozilla-security-advisory-av26-028</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.21</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Control systems] Schneider Electric security advisory (AV26-029)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/control-systems-schneider-electric-security-advisory-av26-029</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.22</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drupal security advisory (AV26-030)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/drupal-security-advisory-av26-030</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.35</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat security advisory (AV26-031)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/red-hat-security-advisory-av26-031</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.36</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Networks security advisory (AV26-032)</title>
      <link>https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber.gc.ca/en/alerts-advisories/palo-alto-networks-security-advisory-av26-032</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity Policy &amp; Governance</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 10.39</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Spot at RSAC 2026 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</link>
      <description>No description available</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.darkreading.com/events/rsac-2026-conference</guid>
      <category>Cybersecurity</category>
      <comments>Score: 73788818.56</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
